<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16881205-13">
               <interp inst="t16881205-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881205-13" type="year" value="1688"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881205-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16881205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881205-13" type="date" value="16881205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16881205-13-off54-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881205-13-defend67 t16881205-13-off54 t16881205-13-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t16881205-13-defend67" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Baker
                  <interp inst="t16881205-13-defend67" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-defend67" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-defend67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             an Irish-man, was Tryed for <rs id="t16881205-13-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seditiousWords"></interp>
               speaking dangerous and seditious Words, tending to the Terror and Disturbance of the King's Liege Subjects, and a Threatning the Subversion of the Protestant Religion
            </rs>, on the <rs id="t16881205-13-cd55" type="crimeDate">30th of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881205-13-off54 t16881205-13-cd55"></join> last. Against whom, upon Tryal, it appeared, That being at the <placeName id="t16881205-13-crimeloc56">Six-Bells, an Ale house in Lombard-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16881205-13-crimeloc56" type="placeName" value="Six-Bells, an Ale house in Lombard-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16881205-13-crimeloc56" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881205-13-off54 t16881205-13-crimeloc56"></join>, there, upon some Discourse that arose touching Religion, and the present Juncture of Affairs, the Prisoner seeming inraged that the Pope and his Priests were disparaged by some of the Company, said, with an Audible Voice, That they who were not in Communion with the Church of Rome, were Hereticks; and deserved to have their Bellies ripped up; And that he shortly hoped to see their Bellies ripped up. And being reproved for these uncharitable Expressions, he went away in a Rage, and being found some time after upon the Exchange, he obstinately persevered in what he had said, urging, as before he had done, That he had been bred up in the Roman Catholick Religion, and that We, meaning the Protestants, were Heretick Dogs, &amp;c. or words to the same effect. Whereupon being seized, he was committed: To his he pleaded Ignorance, utterly denying to have spoken the words; but confessing he was warmed to hear the Pope, &amp;c. vilified, and on that score he might speak unadvisedly, but that he meant no harm to the Protestants, as being obliged to them in doing Business for several Eminent of that Persuasion in London. However, the Court highly resenting the Expression, and representing the anger of such Liberty of Speech against an Established Religion, the Jury found him <rs id="t16881205-13-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of the misdisdemeanor.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16881205-13-punish58" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-punish58" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881205-13-punish58" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881205-13-defend67 t16881205-13-punish58"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
