<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16881010-9">
               <interp inst="t16881010-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881010-9" type="year" value="1688"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881010-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16881010"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16881010-9" type="date" value="16881010"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16881010-9-off48-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881010-9-defend64 t16881010-9-off48 t16881010-9-verdict49"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16881010-9-defend64" type="defendantName">
                  Josias 
                  Best
               <interp inst="t16881010-9-defend64" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-defend64" type="given" value="Josias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-defend64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t16881010-9-deflabel47" type="occupation">Doctor of Physick</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881010-9-defend64 t16881010-9-deflabel47"></join>, was Indicted and Tryed for High-Treason, in <rs id="t16881010-9-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               Clipping and Coyning of Money, the last Fact being done about January last, viz. forty Pieces of King Charles the First's Shillings, and forty other Pieces of the King's Coin called Half Crowns, with certain Sheers and other Instruments fit for the purpose, diminishing from each Piece the value of 2 d.
            </rs> The Counsel for the King opened the Cause to the Jury, and called some Witnesses against the Prisoner, the chief of which was 
               <persName id="t16881010-9-person65">
                  Stephen 
                  Bayley
               <interp inst="t16881010-9-person65" type="surname" value="Bayley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-person65" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was taken on the First of May last in Red-lyon Fields, who said that he had been a Dealer with him, and that he had known him to have Clipp'd Money several times, and to change Broad Money for Clipp'd, at the rate of 1 s. 6 d. advantage in the Pound; and several Filings and other Pieces of Silver were found in his Custody when he was Taken; and Bayley further said that he had bought several Lumps of Silver of the Prisoner, and that he owned them to be of his own doing and Clipping; and that the Lumps were of the value of about 40 or 50 s. and that he confessed to Bayley further, that he got about 100 l. peranum by it: All which was very fully and strenuously Evidenced against him, &amp;c. Thus far was the Evidence for the King against him. But the Prisoner would perswade the Court that he never, knew any thing of what was charged against him, and denied all the matter of Fact, and argued very weakly in his own Defence. Whilest he was Trying, the Court ordered Mr. Massey and some others to go to one Turner's in Milk-street where he had lately Lodged, where was found two bits of Silver in the Closet, and some Filings were seen upon the Ground, and a Hole made in the Wall, and the Room left in a kind of a Suspicious sort; all which was additionally Sworn against him; but he denied it all, and stood as it were one Stupified, having nothing material to offer for himself. So upon a very full and clear Hearing on both sides, he was at last brought in <rs id="t16881010-9-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not Guilty
            </rs>; but yet was <rs id="t16881010-9-punish50" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-punish50" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16881010-9-punish50" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16881010-9-defend64 t16881010-9-punish50"></join>
               ordered to prepare very good Sureties, (at least 300 l. each) for his good Behaviour for the time to come
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
