<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16870831-1">
               <interp inst="t16870831-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16870831-1" type="year" value="1687"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16870831-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16870831"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16870831-1" type="date" value="16870831"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16870831-1-off1-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-defend28 t16870831-1-off1 t16870831-1-verdict4"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16870831-1-off1-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-defend29 t16870831-1-off1 t16870831-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16870831-1-defend28" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Griffith alias <rs id="t16870831-1-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-defend28 t16870831-1-alias-1"></join>Griffin</rs>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend28" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend28" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend28" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t16870831-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Houghton
               <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend29" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-defend29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were Indicted together with one Johanes In Nubibus, or a person not yet found or taken, for the <rs id="t16870831-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murthering of 
                     <persName id="t16870831-1-victim30" type="victimName">
                        Richard 
                        Stockall
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-victim30" type="surname" value="Stockall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16870831-1-victim30" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16870831-1-victim30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-off1 t16870831-1-victim30"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , of the Parish of <placeName id="t16870831-1-crimeloc2">St. Andrews Holbourn</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-crimeloc2" type="placeName" value="St. Andrews Holbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-crimeloc2" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-off1 t16870831-1-crimeloc2"></join>, on the <rs id="t16870831-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">10th of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-off1 t16870831-1-cd3"></join> last, by giving him a Mortal Wound near the Right Pap, of which he instantly Dyed
            </rs>; and putting themselves upon their Tryal, it appeared that on the day before-mentioned being Sunday, between two and three of the Clock in the Afternoon, divers Boys, and some Men, were a washing themselves in a Pond Scituate in the Ground of Mr. Griffith, at what time one Bob a Servant of his coming by, seized on the Cloaths of one 
               <persName id="t16870831-1-person31">
                  John 
                  Hind
               <interp inst="t16870831-1-person31" type="surname" value="Hind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-person31" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-person31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a little Lad, who was about to wash amongst the rest, and carried them into his Master's house, and soon after Mr. Griffith with two other persons and a Dog coming out, he set the Dog upon the Naked Boy, which yet did no other harm than take him by the Hair of the Head, and so passing on towards Lambs Conduit, at his return he found the Boy had just gotten his Shirt of his Wife, upon which he again set the Dog upon him, who served him as before, and cryed after him stop Thief, upon which the Boy made his escape to the house of one Mr. Smith near to Griffiths; but upon the Rumour of what had happened, the Rable began to gather about Griffith's house to demand the Boys Cloaths, which being refused they fell to breaking the Windows, upon which Griffith sent for the Neighbouring Constables, and with their help seized upon several of the assailants, and forcing them into his house, kept them there Prisoners, but the Rable increasing every Moment and assaulting his house with greater violence, and he remaining obstinate as to the setting at liberty those he had taken, unless they would tell him their Names, or the Names of their Masters, &amp;c. he at that time insisting much upon satisfaction for the Damage sustained, Mr. Houghton the other Prisoner, fetch'd about five files of Granadiers when as Mr. Griffith leaving two of them to guard his house, marched with the rest up Grays-Inn Lane to oppos the Rable, which were Numerous, but were so ho dy-charged from the Banks and advantageous places with Stones, Brickbats, &amp;c. that one of the Souldiers was knock'd down, and others bruised at what time they Fired three Pieces but only with Powder, but the Storm increasing, Griffith bad them charge with Ball and Fire, and further said, as it was Sworn viz. We shall be Kill'd, Fi e and Kill the Dogs, or they't kill us and thereupon Johane In. Nubibus gave Fire, by which Shot Stockall was Killed. Griffith coming to make his Defence, after he had declared what Damage he sustained, by his Cattle refusing to drink the Water, by reason of the Boys frequently washing in it, and how he was assaulted in his house, and divers persons to prove that he was not present when the Gun went off that killed Stockdale but being Bruised and Wounded, he retired to the house of one Mr. Roxfords, and stayed there till he sent home for the two Grannadiers that were left behind to fetch him off, and there he had the first news brought him that a Man was killed; but the Evidence for King being possitive that they heard him give order Charge and Fire with Ball, and one of them attesting that he was present when Stock all was Killed, he was found <rs id="t16870831-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-verdict4" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>. As for Mr. Houghton there being no other proof against him, than that fetch'd the Granadiers, he was <rs id="t16870831-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16870831-1-punish6" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-punish6" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16870831-1-punish6" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16870831-1-defend28 t16870831-1-punish6"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
