<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16920831-38">
               <interp inst="t16920831-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920831-38" type="year" value="1692"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920831-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16920831"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920831-38" type="date" value="16920831"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16920831-38-off166-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920831-38-defend116 t16920831-38-off166 t16920831-38-verdict169"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16920831-38-defend116" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Cole
               <interp inst="t16920831-38-defend116" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-defend116" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-defend116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was Committed not long since upon Suspicion of being one of the Ruffians that committed that Horrid, Barbarous and most Hellish <rs id="t16920831-38-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder, upon the Body of the Late Famous <rs id="t16920831-38-viclabel167" type="occupation">Doctor</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920831-38-victim117 t16920831-38-viclabel167"></join> 
                  
                     <persName id="t16920831-38-victim117" type="victimName">
                        Andrew 
                        Clench
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-victim117" type="surname" value="Clench"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920831-38-victim117" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920831-38-victim117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920831-38-off166 t16920831-38-victim117"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , of the Parish of St. Andrew's Holbourn, in the County of Middlesex, for which, not long since one Mr. Harrison was Executed in Holbourn, was on Friday, the third day of the Sessions, Tryed for the same
            </rs>. The Witnesses were a Child, one Mrs. Miller, Wife of one Miller lately Deceased, and several others who Declared in Court, That her Husband Miller told her upon his Death Bed, a little before he Departed; That he himself and Mr. Cole the Prisoner at the Bar, were the two who were in the Coach with the Doctor, and Murthered him by Strangling him with a Handkerchief tyed about his Neck; with a hard Sea-Cole in the same, placed upon his Wind-pipe, as appear'd to be so when the Doctor was found Dead in the Coach in <placeName id="t16920831-38-crimeloc168">Leaden-Hall-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16920831-38-crimeloc168" type="placeName" value="Leaden-Hall-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16920831-38-crimeloc168" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920831-38-off166 t16920831-38-crimeloc168"></join>; this was all that she could attest in the Matter; so the Court were pleased to tell her, that if she could say no more than that, it was no Evidence in Law, neither could any Jury whatsoever find any Person Guilty upon such a slender Testimony, for that a Dying Man's words in the case of Murder, was no Evidence at all: There were two or three more Witnesses Sworn and Examined, who said, That the Prisoner was in Company with the said Miller at the Blew Boar's Head on the back-side of <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16920831005"></xptr> of St. Clements, that Night the Murder was done; and that there was another Person on Company with him, who went by the name of Harper, that the Prisoner did not know; all the Acquaintance he had was with the said Miller, and that the Prisoner came into the aforesaid House, about Eight a Clock, and never departed out of it till almost Twelve a Clock the same Night; but withal the Witness declared that the said Miller went away from him about Nine a Clock, and came no more till almost Twelve, and that when he came in, he was in a great Heat, and lookt as if he had been about some Extraordinary Business that might put him into such a Fermentation; and that he brought in with him two Persons in Red Coats like Soldiers, which in all probability Harrison was one; and that after this time the said Miller was very much concerned, and would look into all Gazettes and News Papers, to see if he were not inquired after, and said that he look'd to be taken up for it, or words to the same Effect; so that the Court concluded, that the said Miller was certainly one of the Assassinates and Harrison the other, not withstanding his indiscreet denial of it at his Death; and if he were not, yet the Murderers would surely be detected &amp;c. So after the Court had gave their Opinions to the Jury as to matter of Law, and they having considered of the whole, returned a Verdict, That the Prisoner Mr. Cole was <rs id="t16920831-38-verdict169" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920831-38-verdict169" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
