<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16921012-52">
               <interp inst="t16921012-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16921012-52" type="year" value="1692"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16921012-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16921012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16921012-52" type="date" value="16921012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16921012-52-off245-c148" targOrder="Y" targets="t16921012-52-defend148 t16921012-52-off245 t16921012-52-verdict246"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16921012-52-defend148" type="defendantName">
                  Billidge 
                  Clayton
               <interp inst="t16921012-52-defend148" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-defend148" type="given" value="Billidge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-defend148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was Indicted for a <rs id="t16921012-52-off245" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-off245" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-off245" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seditiousWords"></interp>
               Misdemeanor against the present Government, which Indictment consisted of Three Parts; The First set forth that the Prisoner did procure a certain small Vessel, (under a Pretence of making her a Cruising Privateer) to convey and carry over several Persons into France, who were profest Enemies to our present King and Queen. The Second part was for Drinking a Health several times, in several places, to the French K. the late K. James, his Queen, to the Hans in Kelder, and to the Prosperity and good Success of all their Designs. The Third part was for Drinking a Health to the Confusion of the present Government, adding, That Hunch'd Nose William's Forces would not fight, but would go over to the French K. and hoped withal that King James would be here within this Twelve Month
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Evidence for the King and Queen, to prove this, declared upon Oath, That the Prisoner had drank the abovementioned Health several times in his company, and that he had made an Agreement with him to carry several persons into France, particularly he was to carry the Lord Preston, and Will. Penn, and for his Incouragement in so doing, was to have 20 Guineas a Man for every person he should carry; Nay, that he should have a French Commission so to do, brought to him by the first Passenger the prisoner should send on Board the said Ship, and that if he met with a Tartar (meaning thereby the French Privateers) he should not fear, for the Prisoner would find out away speedily to clear him, as appeared by several Letters written by the prisoner; The prisoner called several Witnesses on his behalf, who strived to bring a Reproach and Scandal upon the King Evidence, which avail'd him nothing, for it was so frivelous, that it was of no force on the prisoners side,</p>
               <p>Then the Court proceeded to sum up the Matter of Fact, on both sides very distinctly to the Gent. of the Jury, telling them of the evil Example, and bad Consequence such Presidents are of, and how it tended only to foment and to stir up heats and divisions amongst the Kings Subject, and that the Prisoner had great favour shewed him in that it was made but a Misdemeanor, and that such Persons ought to be exemplarily punished, &amp;c. The Jury having well considered of the matter of Fact, brought in a Verdict, that the Prisoner was <rs id="t16921012-52-verdict246" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-verdict246" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of a Misdemeanor.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16921012-52-punish247" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-punish247" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-punish247" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16921012-52-defend148 t16921012-52-punish247"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16921012-52-punish248" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-punish248" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16921012-52-punish248" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16921012-52-defend148 t16921012-52-punish248"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
