<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16910115-29">
               <interp inst="t16910115-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16910115-29" type="year" value="1691"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16910115-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16910115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16910115-29" type="date" value="16910115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16910115-29-off128-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t16910115-29-defend111 t16910115-29-off128 t16910115-29-verdict129"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16910115-29-off128-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t16910115-29-defend112 t16910115-29-off128 "></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16910115-29-off128-c113" targOrder="Y" targets="t16910115-29-defend113 t16910115-29-off128 t16910115-29-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>On Fryday, the 2d day of this Sessions, my Lord Preston, 
               <persName id="t16910115-29-defend111" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Ashton
               <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend111" type="surname" value="Ashton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend111" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t16910115-29-defend112" type="defendantName">
                  Edmund 
                  Elliot
               <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend112" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend112" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were all Arrained for High Treason, my Lord Preston was Tryed on Saturday by the name of Sir 
               <persName id="t16910115-29-defend113" type="defendantName">
                  Richard 
                  Graham
               <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend113" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend113" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-defend113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Ashton on Monday. The Indictments against them consisted of Two Parts, the First of which set forth, That they had a <rs id="t16910115-29-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="treason"></interp>
               Treasonable Design carrying on to Depose the King and Queen, and to Subvert and Alter the Government of the Kingdom of England, and to raise War and Rebellion in the same; which said Traiterous and Wicked Designs and Purposes to bring to pass, they did, on the 29th of December last, Meet and Conspire together, with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="16910115004"></xptr>several other Traitors not yet discovered, and did Compose several Treasonable Letters, Notes and Memorandums in writing, which set forth the most effectual way and means how they might Dethrone and Depose our Most Gracious Sovereign Lord and Lady the King and Queen, and further describing therein how the Affairs of this Kingdom stood, and of what Strength and Force our Shipping was; as also the Fortifications of several Sea-Port-Towns within this Kingdom. The Second Part was their adhering to the Kings's Enemies: And to that end, that they might Acquaint Lewis the French King of the same, they did hire a Boat and Embarque themselves in order to Transport themselves and Pacquet of Treasonable Letters into France
            </rs>, agreeing to pay for their said Passages the Sum of One hundred Pound; and, in order to their Treasonable Voyage, they had made their Passage as far as below Gravesend, but were then Taken by Captain Billop, who Cruised abroad to search for them.</p>
               <p>After this the Evidence for the King being called, gave an Account particularly from Step to Step, how cunningly and subtilly they managed this horrid Conspiracy, by hiring the Smack called the Thomas and Elizabeth, to convey them secretly into France; in order to which they took Water in a Skuller at Surrey-Stairs, and went on Board the aforesaid Vessel, which lay in the River of Thames over against the Tower: From thence they set Sail down the River, till coming within the View of the George Frigate, lying in Long-reach, they desired the Master of the Smack to hide them under the Quarter-Hatches; which was done, they having some Fear of being discovered: There they remained till past that Danger, and then came up; but when they were within Sight of Gravesend they hid again, and a little below it Captain Billop came aboard them, under Pretence of Pressing the Masters two Men, who were assistants to him; but indeed his Design and real Intention was to find out those Traytors, which, upon Search, he found lying along under the Hatches; and after their being haled up he search'd them, and found a Pacquet of Treasonable Papers in Mr. Ashton's Bosom: which he with the Prisoners carried before my Lord Nottingham; who examined the Papers, and after being examined by the Cabinet Council they were committed to the Tower. The Evidence was very full and plain against them both, much to the same effect and purport: The Letters being also Read against them in Court, were adjudged to be of no less Import than High-Treason. Upon the whole they had nothing material to offer in their Defence; so after a very long hearing, they were both found <rs id="t16910115-29-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of High Treason. Edmond Elliot was ordered to remain till further order.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16910115-29-punish130" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-punish130" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16910115-29-punish130" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="drawnAndQuartered"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16910115-29-defend111 t16910115-29-punish130"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16910115-29-defend113 t16910115-29-punish130"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
