<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16920115-7">
               <interp inst="t16920115-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920115-7" type="year" value="1692"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920115-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16920115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920115-7" type="date" value="16920115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16920115-7-off34-c41" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-defend41 t16920115-7-off34 t16920115-7-verdict39"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16920115-7-defend41" type="defendantName">
                  Judith 
                  Bayly
               <interp inst="t16920115-7-defend41" type="surname" value="Bayly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-defend41" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-defend41" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t16920115-7-deflabel33" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-defend41 t16920115-7-deflabel33"></join> of 
               <persName id="t16920115-7-person42">
                  Edward 
                  Bayly
               <interp inst="t16920115-7-person42" type="surname" value="Bayly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-person42" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken, was Indicted for the <rs id="t16920115-7-off34" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-off34" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-off34" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murther of one 
                     <persName id="t16920115-7-victim43" type="victimName">
                        Richard 
                        Tate
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-victim43" type="surname" value="Tate"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920115-7-victim43" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920115-7-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-off34 t16920115-7-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                   a <rs id="t16920115-7-viclabel35" type="occupation">Boy</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-victim43 t16920115-7-viclabel35"></join>
               
                  </rs>, on the <rs id="t16920115-7-cd36" type="crimeDate">11th. of December</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-off34 t16920115-7-cd36"></join> last, in manner following; the said Tate was a poor Parish Boy, who was set <rs id="t16920115-7-deflabel37" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-defend41 t16920115-7-deflabel37"></join> to the Prisoners Husband, he being a Broad Weaver in <placeName id="t16920115-7-crimeloc38">Bishopsgate Parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16920115-7-crimeloc38" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate Parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16920115-7-crimeloc38" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920115-7-off34 t16920115-7-crimeloc38"></join>: It was sworn by the Kings Witness, that he the said Edward Baily took a Coach Whip value 6 d. and gave the said Tate several Stripes upon the Shoulder Loyns and Buttocks and after that, his prodigious Malice and Wicked Tyranny not being qualified, he took an Iron Spindle heated in the Fire, and with the same he did burn the Deceased Tate, in several places, in and about his Body; of which blows with the Whip aforesaid, and Malitiously burning, he died on the 13th. Instant; It was particularly made appear, That the Master of the boy was wont to beat him in a most inhumane manner with the Whip and sometimes with a Stick; pretending that he did not follow his Work, so close as he expected: And he had another way whereby he was wont to punish the boy, which hath scarce ever been heard of before; he had a Stone that he used about his Work, which weighed Seven Stone and two pound, and that he would frequently tye it about his Neck, and make him carry it about, Lashing him forwards, with the Coach Whip aforesaid, telling the boy, that if he was able to carry that Stone, he was able enough to work, &amp;c. And when the Prisoner saw it (instead of endeavouring to allay his Passion) she added Fuel to the Fire by crying out, give him more: Another way he had to Exercise his unparalell'd Cruelty, was by burning him with a hot Iron; upon the Back and Thighs: Also several times he would prick the boy with an Iron Spindle, &amp;c. in several places of his Body. All this Cruel usage was performed upon the poor Boy, for a considerable time, before he died, by Reason of which, he was brought so Low and Weak, that he was not able to subsist any longer; but being burnt by his Mrs. on the Saturday in the Afternoon, he went to bed, and there continued till Sunday Night, Speechless, and then died: The Chief Evidence against the Prisoner was, That she was seen to burn him with the hot Iron, and to urge her Husband to be more Cruel to him; all which was Resented by the Court, as very Unreasonable, Illegal, Inhumane, and most brutish Correction. It was also sworn, That the Master was wont to hang a Curtain before the boys Face, that he might not see him when he came to correct him; and lest the aforesaid Stone should not be ponderous enough; He would add another little one to it; &amp;c. The Prisoner made great Protestations, that she never did any harm to the boy, and called some Witnesses, who declared in the General, that the boy never wanted any necessary Provisions, and that the boy was a sickly distempered boy, troubled with Ulcers, and Runing Sores in his Legs, and elsewhere, about his Body; so the Gent. of the Jury being directed seriously to weigh the Matter; they gave in their Verdict, that she was <rs id="t16920115-7-verdict39" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920115-7-verdict39" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
