<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16920629-35">
               <interp inst="t16920629-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-35" type="year" value="1692"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16920629"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-35" type="date" value="16920629"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16920629-35-off182-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-defend105 t16920629-35-off182 t16920629-35-verdict186"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16920629-35-defend105" type="defendantName">
                  George 
                  Pitts
               <interp inst="t16920629-35-defend105" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-defend105" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the Parish of <placeName id="t16920629-35-defloc180">St. Dunstans in the West</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-35-defloc180" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstans in the West"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-35-defloc180" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-defend105 t16920629-35-defloc180"></join>, <rs id="t16920629-35-deflabel181" type="occupation">Gentleman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-defend105 t16920629-35-deflabel181"></join>, was Arraingned upon two Indictments for <rs id="t16920629-35-off182" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-off182" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-off182" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Killing 
                     <persName id="t16920629-35-victim106" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Hoyle
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-victim106" type="surname" value="Hoyle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920629-35-victim106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t16920629-35-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-off182 t16920629-35-victim106"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t16920629-35-viclabel183" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-victim106 t16920629-35-viclabel183"></join> of the Temple in London, the first Indictment was laid for the Murther at Common Law, the second upon the Statute of Stabbing
            </rs>, but the Grand-Jury committing an Error, (which was by Endorsting Billa Vera on that Bill for Stabbing, when it was really agreed by all of them, that it should have been an Ignoramus, and Billa Vera, should have been upon the Bill at Common Law) this did occasion a great Controversie in Court; the Jury acknowledged that it was a great Mistake, committed by one of their Brethren, who did plead perticularly for himself, telling the Court that he was the only Person, that had the Misfortune to make that Error, which he was heartily sorry for, and hoped therefore that the Gentleman who was to be Tryed, would suffer no particular Damage, withal excusing the rest of his Brethren, upon this the Judges did differ somewhat in their Opinions, fearing that if it should be altred it might make a President for the future: So at last did agree to try the Prisoner upon both the Indictments, which set forth that on the <rs id="t16920629-35-cd184" type="crimeDate">27th day of May</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-off182 t16920629-35-cd184"></join> last, about two of the Clock in the Night of the same day in the Parish aforesaid, the Prisoner in his Rage and Malice before-thought, In and upon the said John Hoyle, did make an Assault, and with a Sword value 5 s. upon the Left side of the Body of the said John Hoyle, did Strike, Stab and Thrust in the said John Hoyle, having no Weapon drawn, giving him one Mortal Wound of the breadth of one Inch, and of the depth of five Inches, of which the said John Hoyle then and there instantly died: The matter of Fact was thus. That the said Mr. Pitts and two or three more Gentlemen, being drinking at the Young Devil-Tavern in Fleet-street, Mr. Hoyle was sent for, who came, and after some time, Mr. Hoyle, without any Provocation, began to talk very scurrilously against the present Government, and spake very unbecoming words against the Person of King William, whereupon Mr. Pitts replied, That he was very hard to be pleased if this King would not please him who was now hazarding his Life for Us, and Mr. Hoyle continuing to rail against all Government, Mr. Pitts endeavoured to perswade Mr. Hoyle to lay by such discourse, but he would not, but gave the Prisoner, Mr. Pitts, very unworthy Language and provoking Words, calling him Coward, or to that effect, thereupon Mr. Hoyle and Mr. Pitts rising up, Mr. Clarke (one of the Gentlemen in the company) put himself between them, and desired Mr. Pitts to be pacified, then said Mr. Pitts (Mr. Clarke) pray take my Sword, for you know it is not fit for a Gentleman to hear this Language with a Sword by his side, then Mr. Hoyle went away, but after a little time he came back again, and forced himself into the company, and then gave the Lye to Mr. Pitts three times, when he said nothing to him, whereupon Mr. Pitts told him this is meer Madness, and took the Glass and said here's to you Mr. Hoyle, and drank to him; then Mr. Pitts paid for the Wine and went away, and Mr. Hoyle and the rest followed him, after this there were some Proposals made of a Place to Fight on the Morrow, and then they two going along the street together, (the other two Gentlemen going towards Temple-Barr) when they came over against the <placeName id="t16920629-35-crimeloc185">Temple-Gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-35-crimeloc185" type="placeName" value="Temple-Gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-35-crimeloc185" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-35-off182 t16920629-35-crimeloc185"></join>, they fell foul upon each other, Mr. Hoyle first taking Mr. Pitts by the Crevate, tore it, and almost strangled him, then struck him over the Head with a Stick, upon which Mr. Pitts was forced to stand upon his Guard and drew his Sword, not knowing but the Deceased had drawn his; so at length Mr. Hoyle received the Wound aforesaid, which the Chirurgeon gave account was Mortal, then Mr. Pitts went off: It was fully proved that Mr. Hoyle first began, and was the occasion of all the Quarrel, and several Witnesses were called, who gave account that Mr. Hoyle, in his life-time, was a Person much addicted to quarrelling, &amp;c. Whereas, on the contrary, Mr. Pitts called seven Peers, and several Persons of Quality, who satisfied the Court that Mr. Pitts had always been a Gentleman of a very obliging, peaceable, quiet and moderate Behaviour in all Company, no ways given to Passion or Revenge, and the Prisoner himself did very affectionately declare that he had no manner of Antipathy, against Mr. Hoyle, nor never but once before was in his company, and that what he did was in his own defence, for which great Misfortune he was heartily sorry, for he did not intend any such thing that happened: He produced the Gentlemen who were at the Tavern with him, and saw all that passed, who gave a fair account of the matter of Fact, as aforesaid, which was of great Satisfaction to the Court, how that Mr. Pitts was much abused, Mr. Hoyle calling Mr. Pitts, Poultroon, Rascally Coward, &amp;c. telling him his Sword was Rusty, with such like aggravating Language, &amp;c. The Tryal was very long, and great Care was taken on both sides; So the Gentlemen of the Jury having withdrew for a small time, and being returned, gave in their Verdict that Mr. Pitts was only <rs id="t16920629-35-verdict186" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-verdict186" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-35-verdict186" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>After which he petitioned the benefit of his Clergy, and desired his Prayer might be Recorded, which was done accordingly, and an Appeal for Murther was brought against him: He gave sufficient Bail to answer the same at the next Sessions, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
