<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16911209-34">
               <interp inst="t16911209-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16911209-34" type="year" value="1691"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16911209-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16911209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16911209-34" type="date" value="16911209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16911209-34-off141-c103" targOrder="Y" targets="t16911209-34-defend103 t16911209-34-off141 "></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16911209-34-defend103" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Franks
               <interp inst="t16911209-34-defend103" type="surname" value="Franks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16911209-34-defend103" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16911209-34-defend103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a reputed <rs id="t16911209-34-deflabel140" type="occupation">Jesuite</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t16911209-34-defend103 t16911209-34-deflabel140"></join>, was Indicted for a high Misdemeanor, for that he being an evil disposed Person, and of very ill Fame, <rs id="t16911209-34-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16911209-34-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16911209-34-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               intending to disquiet and disturb the Peace and Tranquility of the Kingdom of England, and to deter Their Majesties Liege people from their Obedience to our most Gracious Lord and Lady, King William and Queen Mary. Did on the <rs id="t16911209-34-cd142" type="crimeDate">5th. day of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t16911209-34-off141 t16911209-34-cd142"></join> last, hire a Ship to convey several persons into France, who were open and prosest Enemies to our King and Queen whose Names were particularly mentioned in the Charge against him, being Collonel Graham (the Lord Preston's Brother) Mr. William Penn, Sir William Wallis, and the late Lord Bishop of Ely, who were all to be conveyed in the Ship aforesaid, which he the said Franks hired of one Mr. Low, at a House where he met him in Fullers Rents, when he bargained with for 16 Guineas, out of which he was to have one for himself, and because Collonel Grynes and the Bishop of Ely. were pusilanimous Men, there were Blinds to be contrived in the Rounds of the same Ship, to keep them from being discovered, and to give them Air, and one was to be on the one side, and the other on the other side; and furthermore, the King's Council gave the Jury to understand, that the prisoner was guilty of speaking very Scandalous and Seditious Words against the Government, viz. That Sir William Wallis, was to be a leading Man, and after he had been with King James and the French King. He was to return into Scotland, and there to head an Army, against our King and Queen
            </rs>; and one Major he said, was to head an Army of
<note>[Pages missing in original.]</note>
               </p>
            </div1>
