<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t16920629-32">
               <interp inst="t16920629-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-32" type="year" value="1692"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/16920629"></interp>
               <interp inst="t16920629-32" type="date" value="16920629"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t16920629-32-off164-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-32-defend97 t16920629-32-off164 t16920629-32-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t16920629-32-defend97" type="defendantName">
                  Ruth 
                  Phillips
               <interp inst="t16920629-32-defend97" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-defend97" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-defend97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the Parish of <placeName id="t16920629-32-defloc163">St. Andrew Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-32-defloc163" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t16920629-32-defloc163" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-32-defend97 t16920629-32-defloc163"></join>, was Tryed for Felony, in <rs id="t16920629-32-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               Clipping the Current Coin of this Kingdom
            </rs>; there were several Instruments found in a Trunk in her House, as Files and Rubbing-stones, but no Sheers, but a pair of Weights and some Clipp'd Money were found. Another Evidence was one of the Prisoners Maids, who Swore that comming into the Kitchen, she saw the Prisoners Arm move up and down as if she Clipp'd Money or somewhat else like it; and that she saw both Broad Money and Clipp'd Money lie before her, but she could not say that she saw any Shears in her Hands, neither did she see her actually Clip: But another Witness Swore that she saw not only the Money, but a pair of Shears lie by her, and some Clippings, some of which were produced in Court, and a pair of Scales and Weights, and after she heard a snapping of Shears: There were other concurring Evidence in the matter, who swore plainly to the matter of Fact aforesaid, and the Bag of Clipp'd money was produced in Court, which was very rough, being newly Clipp'd.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner urged that her Servants had been hired to convey such things into her House, and that she new not how the Bag of Clip'd money came there, (and that Nurse who was her Servant and had Sworn against her) had Robbed her of a Pillow-beer, a Frock, and a Set of Window Curtains, which the Prisoner owned to be hers: Another Evidence on the Prisoners side, swore that the Nurse declared that she must go out of Town and abscond her self, for that she had stolen some things from her Mistress, and she would Prosecute her for the same, therefore she feared her, &amp;c. Some other Witness said that they had dealt with the Prisoner and took good money of her, and that they never knew any evil by her. The Prisoner still urged her Innocency, and declared that the Bag of mony which proved to be Clipp'd, was left at her House, by one 
               <persName id="t16920629-32-person98">Cha. Phillips</persName>
             who was gone into the Country, to whom she had sent a Letter, but could not hear of him, and could not prove any thing on her behalf to any purpose; so after a very long and fair Tryal, she was found <rs id="t16920629-32-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of High Treason.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t16920629-32-punish166" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-punish166" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t16920629-32-punish166" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t16920629-32-defend97 t16920629-32-punish166"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death -respited for pregnancy. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
