<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350911-69">
               <interp inst="t17350911-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-69" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-69" type="date" value="17350911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350911-69-off304-c302" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-defend455 t17350911-69-off304 t17350911-69-verdict307"></join>
         
               <p>83. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-defend455" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Conyer  otherwise <rs id="t17350911-69-alias-10" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-defend455 t17350911-69-alias-10"></join>Connor</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-defend455" type="surname" value="Conyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-defend455" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-defend455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17350911-69-defloc302">Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-69-defloc302" type="placeName" value="Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-69-defloc302" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-defend455 t17350911-69-defloc302"></join>, <rs id="t17350911-69-deflabel303" type="occupation">Sawyer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-defend455 t17350911-69-deflabel303"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17350911-69-off304" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-off304" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-off304" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17350911-69-victim456" type="victimName">
                        Isabel
                         his 
                        <rs id="t17350911-69-viclabel305" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-victim456 t17350911-69-viclabel305"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-69-victim456" type="surname" value="his"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-69-victim456" type="given" value="Isabel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-69-victim456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-off304 t17350911-69-victim456"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , by giving her with both his Fists, and with a Shoe, several Mortal Bruises on the Head, Breast, and Stomach, <rs id="t17350911-69-cd306" type="crimeDate">August 31</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-off304 t17350911-69-cd306"></join>, of which Bruises she languished till the first of September, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroners Inquisition for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person457">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person457" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person457" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person457" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that she saw the Deceased on the thirty first of August, between ten and eleven in the Morning; and that the Deceased was then in perfect health; but that this Witness know of no Quarrel between the Deceased and the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person458">
                  Brudenell 
                  Exton 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person458" type="surname" value="Exton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person458" type="given" value="Brudenell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that about nine o'Clock on Sunday Night, August 31. the Prisoner's Mother came to his Master (an Apothecary)'s Shop, and said, that her Son had beat his Wife. That he went to visit the Deceased, and found her weak and languishing. He asked her if her Husband had struck her? she said, yes. And where was the chief Blow? she answered, in the Pit of her Stomach. That he perceived no Bruise that Night. That he bled her, That he went again between nine and ten the next Morning, when she complained that nothing would stay in her Stomach. At three in the Afternoon she had cold clammy Sweats, complained of her Head, and that sue was sore within - that she died about ten that Night - That on Friday he saw her Body before she was buried, and observed a large Contusion on her Left side as broad as his Hand. Being asked if he thought that Contusion might be the cause of her Death. He answered, if she was well before, it was suspicious, for by the communication it had with her Stomach, it might be the occasion of her vomiting - . That that Contusion might not be perceived after had been buried.</p>
               <p>Mr. Middleton the Surgeon deposed, that after the Deceased had been interred a Week, she was taken up again, and he open d her Body. That the Coroner's Jury suspecting a Fracture in her Skull, he opened the Scalp, but found nothing like it - That in opening the Abdomen, he found the Intestines were inflamed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173509110026"></xptr>Mr. Lewis deposed, that he being in the Garden, he heard the Deceas'd squall out, and say, that he should not kill the Child if he killed her - But that he did not hear any Blows, nor any Cry of Murder - That she had then lain in about eleven Weeks - That he had often heard her cry out before that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person459">
                  Sarah 
                  Simcocks 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person459" type="surname" value="Simcocks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person459" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person459" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that on the Tuesday after the Deceased died, she laid her in the Coffin, and found several Black and Blue Marks, one on her Temples near her Eye, another on her Forehead, one on her Shoulder, one under her Left Arm, and another as big as half a Crown under her Left Breast, and several down her Arms.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person460">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person460" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person460" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person460" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that as she stood at the Prisoner's Door, he and his Wife being in the Ground Room, she heard her call him Dog, and Son of a Bitch, and bid him Murder her and the Child at once, and be hanged for them both. That then this Evidence went in and desired him to be easy, and come away. That one Mr. Powel came in, and took the Prisoner out with him. That the Prisoner threatned to Sclat his Wive's Brains out with a Board, but he did not strike her.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner said in his Defence, that at about five o'Clock as he was going out to a Sawyer's Burial, his Wife desired him to correct his Son, who is about six Years old, for calling her Bitch. That thereupon he catched up a Shoe and struck at him, but she got between and so might receive a Blow on her Shoulder. That then he took a Cat-of-nine-tails to beat him, but she still endeavouring to save the Boy, might accidentally get several Blows on her Arm. That on the Monday following he went to work at Mile-End, but hearing that his Wife was ill, he went home and sent for a Pint of Wine; she drank to him, and said she was sorry the Neighbours should reflect on him as to his beating of her, and should they bring him into any trouble about it, she should not rest in her Grave.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Mother deposed, that she did not see the Prisoner beat the Deceased; but that about five or six in the Afternoon, the Deceased sent for her, and said Mother, I am very bad in my Bowels, I wish you would get something hot for me; but she did not complain that he had beat her; nor did this Evidence tell the Apothecary's Man that her Son had beat his Wife; but only said that that they had had Words.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person461">
                  Susan 
                  Blissard 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person461" type="surname" value="Blissard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person461" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person461" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, that between ten and eleven on Monday Morning, when the Apothecary was there, they turned down the Cloaths and saw that her Arms were black and blue with the Blows her Husband had given her with the Cat-of-nine-tails. But excepting that thing, he had a very honest Character in the Neighbourhood, and behaved very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person462">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person462" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person462" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person462" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Midwife, farther deposed, the Deceased was delivered on a Monday Evening between six and seven. That on the Thursday following, she washed her Weeks Clothes, and was well till Saturday, when the Prisoner came home and surprised her - She did not say that he struck her, but that he frighted and surprised her, so that she was taken ill and continued so for a Fortnight. That she cried, and said, My Husband thinks I sham Sick - I asked him to give me a little small Beer, and he swore Water was too good; and then I asked him for a little Water, which he gave me, and I drank plentifully.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-69-person463">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17350911-69-person463" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person463" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-person463" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             again deposed, that the Deceased in the second Week of her lying in complained that she was very ill, and said that the Prisoner asked her how she thought he could maintain her and her four Children.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner said that the Surprize the Midwife spoke of, was by telling the Deceased that there was a Fire in the White-Lyon-Yard.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17350911-69-verdict307" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-verdict307" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350911-69-punish308" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-69-punish308" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-69-defend455 t17350911-69-punish308"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
