<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-4">
               <interp inst="t17361208-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-4" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-4" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-4-off19-c56" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-defend65 t17361208-4-off19 t17361208-4-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-defend65" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph
                      Wells, otherwise <rs id="t17361208-4-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-defend65 t17361208-4-alias-2"></join>Weld</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-defend65" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-defend65" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-defend65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            . was indicted for <rs id="t17361208-4-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver Tankard, value 6 l. a Quart silver Mug, value 6 l sixteen Silver Spoons, value 8 l and two Silver Strainers, value 20 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-4-victim67" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Barton 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-4-victim67" type="surname" value="Barton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-4-victim67" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-4-victim67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-off19 t17361208-4-victim67"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17361208-4-cd20" type="crimeDate">July 22, 1734</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-off19 t17361208-4-cd20"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-person68">
                  William 
                  Barton 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person68" type="surname" value="Barton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person68" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I <rs id="t17361208-4-viclabel21" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17361208-4-crimeloc22">Swan Tavern in Change-Alley</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Swan Tavern in Change-Alley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-off19 t17361208-4-crimeloc22"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-4-victim67 t17361208-4-viclabel21"></join>. On a Sunday Evening, the 21st or 22d of July, 1734, I was robbed of a Parcel of Plate, it was taken out of a Room behind the Bar; I advertis'd it, and on the Tuesday following 12 Spoons were brought from the Pawnbrokers; I desired them to secure the Person that brought them if they could. About three Months after, 
               <persName id="t17361208-4-person69">
                  Mary 
                  Spratley 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person69" type="surname" value="Spratley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person69" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to redeem the rest of the Spoons, and the Pawnbroker took her up: I lost sixteen Spoons, a Tankard, a Quart Mug, and two Strainers. Spratley carried a Silversmith's Man with her to the Pawnbrokers, who was to redeem the Plate, and buy it of her out-right. She escaped from the Constable that Time, and the Silversmith came to me, and desired me to go with him to find out Wells the Prisoner; telling me, the Plate came from him, and that he had bought the Tankard of him, which was mark'd PBD We could not find the Prisoner then, for he was gone to Sea with Captain 
               <persName id="t17361208-4-person70">
                  Braund
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person70" type="given" value="Braund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person70" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Spratley was fled into the Country; but hearing that Wells was return'd to England, and that Spratley was in Town, I found her out, and she confessed she had these Spoons of Wells; two of them were mark'd EAD, and two of them WBA. The Prisoner brought these four Spoons to the Woman, himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-person71">
                  Zephaniah 
                  Crofton 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person71" type="surname" value="Crofton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person71" type="given" value="Zephaniah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't remember any thing of Wells; the Woman ( Spratley ) brought me these four Spoons, and pawned them in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17361208-4-person72">
                  Mary 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person72" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person72" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , July 22, 1734, she had 16 s. upon two of them, and 15 s. upon the other two at two different Times. About the latter End of October, Spratley came with a Silversmith's Man to redeem them; I charged a Constable with her, and sent for Mr. Barton, but she escaped from the Constable, and I saw no more of her, till I saw her in the Compter about a Fortnight or three Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-person73">
                  Mary 
                  Spratley 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person73" type="surname" value="Spratley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person73" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17361208-4-person74">
                  Joseph 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person74" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person74" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave me the four Spoons tied with a Blue String, to pawn for him; I was a Servant to him in his Mother's Time, and after he broke I used to go of his Errands He directed me to Grafton's, and bid me say they were for one Mary Matthews, who lay-in; and, says he, they will make no Scruple of letting you have Money upon them; this was about two Years and a half ago; I pawn'd them, and he had the Money; it was 30 Shillings or thereabouts. He told me the Spoons had been there before, and I must take what they had before leat upon them. After I had given him the Money, he went to Sea. - Oh! no, no, he was not gone to Sea, but was up and down. - He told me he was going to Sea with Captain Massey, but the Captain went without him He told me he had sold a Tankard in Whitechapel, and I must go with him there When we came to the Silversmith's, Wells told him I had pawn'd four Spoons, and desired his Man to go with me and redeem them, and then they should be sold to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you had pawned them?</p>
               <p>Spratley. God Almighty bless you; I don't know, about four or five Months I believe. I was to have a Crown of the Money, that I was indeed. The Silversmith could not send any Body with me then, but next Morning his Man and I went to redeem them, and the Pawnbroker sent for a Constable and charged him with me, and carried me to an Alehouse in Bunhill-Field, where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080008"></xptr> some Gentlemen knowing me, got me into the Buffet unseen by the Constable, and so I escap'd that Time. I lived two Years with him in his Mother's Time as a Servant, and some Time I was with him otherwise, and now what a fine Scrape he has brought me into?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her if I ever directed her to take the Silversmith's Man with her, Thee or Thou?</p>
               <p>Spratley. Yes, my Lordship, here is the Man that went with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-person75">
                  George 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person75" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person75" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd at that time with 
               <persName id="t17361208-4-person76">
                  John 
                  Lepar 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person76" type="surname" value="Lepar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person76" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Silversmith, without Aldgate He has been dead about half a Year. I went with Spratley to the Broker to redeem some Spoons, and my Master was to have them at a Market-price. She said she had pawn'd them for her Master Wells, who was under Misfortunes, and was then going abroad. She asked the Pawnbroker for the four Spoons, he desired us to sit down a little, and so he got a Constable and charged him with her. The Constable carry'd us to the Angel in Bunhill-Fields; the Broker went for the Prosecutor, and I went for my Master; but when we came back the Prisoner had escap'd. It is probable my Master might know something of Wells, for he had been a Neighbour, and kept a Cook's Shop in Leadenhall-Street.</p>
               <p>Capt. Braund. The Prisoner behaved well, during the time he was on board with me?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-4-person77">
                  Judith 
                  Bleeze 
               <interp inst="t17361208-4-person77" type="surname" value="Bleeze"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person77" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-person77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That Spratley was a wicked Woman in Leadenhall-Market, for she had a Warrant against me for striking her. <rs id="t17361208-4-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-4-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
