<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-63">
               <interp inst="t17360610-63" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-63" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-63" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-63" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-63-off259-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-63-defend434 t17360610-63-off259 t17360610-63-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-63-defend434" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Bannister 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-63-defend434" type="surname" value="Bannister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-defend434" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-defend434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of London, <rs id="t17360610-63-deflabel258" type="occupation">Packer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-63-defend434 t17360610-63-deflabel258"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-63-off259" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-off259" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-off259" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 30 Books intitled, The Laws and Customs of the Stannaries, in Sheets, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-63-victim436" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim436" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim436" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-63-victim438" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Trimly 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim438" type="surname" value="Trimly"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim438" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-63-victim440" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Newton 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim440" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim440" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . One other Book intitled, A Practical Exposition of the Church Catechism by 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person441">
                        Matthew 
                        Hole 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person441" type="surname" value="Hole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person441" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , D. D. One other Book intitled, A Practical Exposition of the Church Catechism, with several Discourses on all the Parts of it, by Matthew Hole. D D. One other Book intitled, Four Treatises on the Doctrine, Discipline, and Worship of the Mahometans. One other Book intitled, Marcus Antoninus his Conversation with himself, with Preliminary Discourses. &amp;c. to which is added, The Mythological Picture of Cebes translated into English by 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person442">
                        Jeremy 
                        Collier 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person442" type="surname" value="Collier"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person442" type="given" value="Jeremy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . One other Book intitled, 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person443">
                        Lex 
                        Constitutionis 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person443" type="surname" value="Constitutionis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person443" type="given" value="Lex"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person443" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , or the Gentleman's Law, &amp;c. by 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person444">
                        Giles 
                        Jacob 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person444" type="surname" value="Jacob"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person444" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Gent. One other Book intitled, The Fable of the Bees; Part the 2d by the Author of the first, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-63-victim446" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Clay 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim446" type="surname" value="Clay"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim446" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-63-victim448" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Birt 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim448" type="surname" value="Birt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim448" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-victim448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person449">
                        Daniel 
                        Brown 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person449" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person449" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the Warehouse of 
                     <persName id="t17360610-63-person450">
                        Daniel 
                        Brown 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person450" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person450" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-63-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17360610-63-cd260" type="crimeDate">April 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-63-off259 t17360610-63-cd260"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. About the middle of April last, I saw a Catalogue of Books which were to be sold by Mr. Osborne, at Gray's-Inn, and among them, I saw The Laws of the Stannaries; I question whether there was one single Book under this Title to be sold but what was the Property of 
               <persName id="t17360610-63-person451">
                  John 
                  Trinley 
               <interp inst="t17360610-63-person451" type="surname" value="Trinley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person451" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-63-person452">
                  James 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17360610-63-person452" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person452" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and my self. I apply'd to Mr. Osborne to know if he had a Num-ber of them to sell; he said he had several, and that he bought them of one Whitaker. I went to Whitaker, and he told me he had them of one Savage a Book-binder in Lothbury; and Savage told me he had them of Mr. Bannister, the Prisoner at the Bar: Mr. Whitaker inform'd me he had sold 18 of these Books to Mr. Wer-ral in Bell-Yard. When Mr. Savage informed me about these Books, I asked him if ever he had had any more, or any other, from the Prisoner: and he gave me an account of 49 different Books, every one of which I am satisfy'd had been in the Warehouse; among them, there are four or five which are mention'd in the Indictment, and to which my Servant will speak more particularly. The Laws of the Stannaries were printed for Mr. Newton, and my Father a dozen Years ago; and they have lain in Stock (as we call it) ever since. The Books are the Property of Mr. Trinley, my self, and Mr. Newton; the Warehouse belongs to Mr. Trinley and I. The Prisoner made use of a large long Room, as a Warehouse, and at the End of it there is a Room, which we make use of as our Warehouse: There is another Warehouse<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100020"></xptr> up three or four Steps, at some Distance from this; and when I sent the Laws of the Stannaries, by my Servant, they were put in either of the Warehouses, as there was room; and the Doors were secur'd by Padlocks. I let to the Prisoner the Room which he occupy'd, and his Room is situate between the two Rooms we make use of. I had miss'd several Books out of the Warehouse, but the Laws of the Stannaries I did not miss, 'till I happened to see them in a Catalogue, and I knew there were none of these Books in Trade, but what were in my Custody. I traced the Matter, and found Mr. Osborne had bought 14 of Mr. Whitaker and 18 more that Mr. Whitaker had. I miss'd Hole on the Catechism, 2 Vols. Lex Constitutionis, t'e Gentleman's Law. Marcus Antoninus. The Fable of the Bees, Part the Second; and Discourses on the Doctrine of the Mahometans.</p>
               <p>In order to prove the Property of the Books, (the Laws of the Stannaries) the Original Agreement between Mr. Newton and Mr. Brown was produced, and being prov'd, was read.</p>
               <p>Council. This shews the Property to be in two, and they have laid it to be in three in the Indictment. Did not you know that the Prisoner made use of waste Paper in his Business?</p>
               <p>Mr. Newton. I don't know whether he does or not.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you never hear that your Porter had sold him waste Paper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. No.</p>
               <p>Mr. Riley. I printed part of these Books; they were printed for Mr. Brown and Mr. Newton, the Father of this Gentleman; he died before they were finished; and he as Executor to his Father, is entitled to the Pro-perty.</p>
               <p>Mr. Newton. I don't say I was Executor to my Father; I paid for them myself. I was Partner with my Father; when he died, my Mother was left Executrix; I had, as a Partner, a Share in the Stock, and the other Part I purchased of my Mother.</p>
               <p>Mr. Osborne. I bought fourteen of the Laws of the Stanneries of Mr. Whitaker, who fre-quently came to my Shop to buy Books: He asked me several times if I cared to buy any of these; and one Day I told him if they did not come to much Money, I would take them; he brought 14; I paid him and took his Receipt. I bought them this Month was Twelve Months ago, and about three Months ago there was a Catalogue of Books published, which brought Mr. Brown to enquire of me, concerning these Laws of the Stannaries, which were in the Catalogue. I told him where I bought them, and shew'd him Mr. Whitaker's Receipt. I ordered my Man to put my Seal upon them, and I am positive these are the very books I bought of him; they have been in my Custody ever since, and are entered in my Quire Book. These Books were objected to, the whole Tities not being set forth.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. Here is the Practical Exposition of the Church Catechism, &amp;c. This was objected to, on the same Account</p>
               <p>The next is the Emperor Marcus Antoninus, his Conversation with himself. &amp;c supported by the Authorities of Dr. Stanhope, &amp;c. 10 which is added, The Mythological Picture of Cabes. This was objected to likewise.</p>
               <p>Council. The next is Lex Constitutionis, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Council. There is no Name in the Indictment, who it was printed for; nor to the next Book, The Fable of the Bees.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17360610-63-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-63-verdict261" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               The Indictment being defective, the whole Titles of the Books not being set forth, the Court directed the Jury to acquit the Prisoner
            </rs>; and inform'd the Prosecutors they might prefer a new Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
