<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-4">
               <interp inst="t17370216-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-4" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-4" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-4-off16-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-defend43 t17370216-4-off16 t17370216-4-verdict20"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-4-off16-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-defend45 t17370216-4-off16 t17370216-4-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>4, 5. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-defend43" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Dodson 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend43" type="surname" value="Dodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend43" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-defend45" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Carter 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend45" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend45" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-defend45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17370216-4-defloc14">St. Anne's, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-defloc14" type="placeName" value="St. Anne's, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-defloc14" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-defend43 t17370216-4-defloc14"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-defend45 t17370216-4-defloc14"></join>, were indicted, for that they not having the Fear of God before their Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17370216-4-cd15" type="crimeDate">14th Day of January</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-off16 t17370216-4-cd15"></join>, <rs id="t17370216-4-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370216-4-victim47" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Whitesides 
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-victim47" type="surname" value="Whitesides"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-victim47" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-victim47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-off16 t17370216-4-victim47"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an Assault; and that 
                     <persName id="t17370216-4-person48">
                        Henry 
                        Dodson 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person48" type="surname" value="Dodson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-person48" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on a certain Pavement of Stones, did cast and throw down the said Whitesides, and by such casting and throwing down, he, the said Whitesides, did receive a mortal Wound and Bruise, which fractured his Skull, of which mortal Wound and Bruise, the said Whitesides did languish, and languishingly lived from the said 14th of January, to the 17th of the same Month, and then died; and 
                     <persName id="t17370216-4-person49">
                        Henry 
                        Carter 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person49" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-person49" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-4-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , at the Time of committing this Felony, was present, aiding and comforting the said Dodson in the said Murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They were a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for feloniously staying the said Whitesides.</p>
               <p>Mr. How. January 14, about three or four in the Afternoon, I sent 
               <persName id="t17370216-4-person50">
                  George 
                  Hart 
               <interp inst="t17370216-4-person50" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person50" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (who was my Apprentice) to the Barber's with my Wig, and hearing a Hubbub, I opened my Window, and saw the Prisoner Carter beating him; I came down Stairs, and told the Deceased, (who was likewise my <rs id="t17370216-4-viclabel17" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-victim47 t17370216-4-viclabel17"></join>) that somebody was beating the Boy; I ran to Carter, and asked him, why he beat my Apprentice; he would have run away,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160003"></xptr> but I tripped up his Heels, and resolved to carry him before Justice Deveil. But he not being at Home, I brought him back, in order to have him before some other Magistrate; as we were going along he desired me not to haul him, he would walk very civilly he said, and would-not run away, but the Minute I had loosen'd my Hold, he ran away from me, and Dodson ran after him: The Deceased seeing Carter run, pursued him, and had taken him if Dodson had not with a Jostle thrown him down. I went after Carter, but being informed that both the Prisoners lived with Mr. Leeson a Baker, I returned Home, and at the Door I met an Apothecary, who desired me to send for a Surgeon immediately, for my Servant was Speechless and his Skull broke. He lived till Monday, and never had his Senses all that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Dodson throw the Deceased down?</p>
               <p>How. When Carter took to his Heels, I cry'd out, Stop him, - and the Deceased ran after him; as he passed Dodson he gave him a Hunch, which turned him quite round, and I saw him falling, but did not see him come to the Ground. I saw him (Dodson) put out his Foot and trip up his Heels; 'twas done in a Trice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-person51">
                  Richard 
                  Cajor 
               <interp inst="t17370216-4-person51" type="surname" value="Cajor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person51" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Afternoon, between three and four o'Clock (I don't remember the Day of the Month) I heard a Bustle in the Court, - 'twas in <placeName id="t17370216-4-crimeloc18">Sidney's Court, by Leicester-Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Sidney's Court, by Leicester-Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-4-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-off16 t17370216-4-crimeloc18"></join>, - I was coming through the Court, and saw the Prisoner Carter beating George Hart. Mr. How (Hart's Master) came up, and asked Carter why he beat his Apprentice; he seized him, and told him he should go before Mr. Deveil, but he not being at Home, Mr. How brought the Prisoner Carter back, and as they came up the Court, he desired not to be held, and said he would walk very civilly; but when Mr. How let him loose, away he ran, and Whitesides the Deceased ran after him; but passing by Dodson, he gave him a Jostle as he ran, which turned him quite round, and he fell down backwards with his Head upon the Pavestones; I helped to take him up, he was stunn'd with the Fall, and his Head was very bloody. This happened on Friday, and on Sunday Night following I went to see the Deceased, and was to have sat up with him the next Night, but he died on Monday Morning.</p>
               <p>How. He was in very good Health when I called him out on this Occasion, and was a sober, sedate, good Servant, as any Man could have; he never spoke but once to a young Man after he had received this Hurt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-person52">
                  John 
                  Hulet 
               <interp inst="t17370216-4-person52" type="surname" value="Hulet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Deceased immediately after the Fall; the Blood ran down from the back Part of his Head, and he sighed and sweat extreamly, and was in an Agony with the Pain; after we had lifted him out of the Kennel, he desired we would let him sit still a little, and in about four or five Minutes he walked Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-person53">
                  Philip 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17370216-4-person53" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person53" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As Mr. How was bringing the Prisoner Carter through the Court, he desired he might walk without being held, and in two or three Minutes he ran away; the Deceased ran after him, and as he ran, the other Prisoner gave him a Jostle, which threw him down; I can't be sure whether he jostled him down or tripped him up, but he was the Occasion of his Falling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-4-person54">
                  John 
                  Ormered 
               <interp inst="t17370216-4-person54" type="surname" value="Ormered"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was called to the Deceased, I found his Skull fractured and a Concussion upon the Brain, he languished till Monday and then died. I performed the Operation of the Trepan, and after his Death I took off the Top of the Skull. The Fall was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Dodson's Defence.</p>
               <p>I live with Mr. Leeson, and Carter is my Fellow <rs id="t17370216-4-deflabel19" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-4-defend45 t17370216-4-deflabel19"></join>. Mr. How's Apprentice was coming along with a Whig upon his Hand, and Carter struck it in his Face, upon that the Apprentice struck him, so the Fray began. Mr. How came and hauled Carter about, and he desired he might be let go, and when he was at Liberty he ran away, I ran after him, and the Deceased ran between me and a Bulk, and so threw himself down.</p>
               <p>Carter's Defence.</p>
               <p>I happened to touch the Wig with my Hand as I went along, and the Boy flew upon me and struck me.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17370216-4-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-4-verdict20" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               acquitted the Prisoners, and on the Coroner's Inquisition found the Deceased's Death Accidental
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
