<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-54">
               <interp inst="t17380222-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-54" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-54" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-54-off233-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-54-defend337 t17380222-54-off233 t17380222-54-verdict237"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-54-off233-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-54-defend339 t17380222-54-off233 t17380222-54-verdict237"></join>
         
               <p>62 63. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-defend337" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Lovell 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend337" type="surname" value="Lovell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend337" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-defend339" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Staines 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend339" type="surname" value="Staines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend339" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-defend339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17380222-54-person340">
                  William 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person340" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person340" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken) for <rs id="t17380222-54-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting Ann the <rs id="t17380222-54-viclabel234" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-54-victim343 t17380222-54-viclabel234"></join> of Sampson Lowry , in a certain Street, and on the King's common Highway, putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from her a Pocket Book, value 6d. the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17380222-54-victim341" type="victimName">
                        Sampson 
                        Lowry 
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim341" type="surname" value="Lowry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim341" type="given" value="Sampson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-54-cd235" type="crimeDate">Jan. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-54-off233 t17380222-54-cd235"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-victim343" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Lowry 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim343" type="surname" value="Lowry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim343" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-victim343" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . About the Beginning of January my Husband was in Company with one Hart, a  vile Fellow, at the White Swan, in Fitter-Lane; Hart having occasion'd him to spend 20 l. I went to the House to persuade him to come Home. This Fellow, Hart, told me, I had no Business there; I said, - no! - what have I no Business with my Husband! Well; I got a Fowl for Supper and order'd it to be dress'd, thinking to entice him Home. At last he did come Home; and I told him, I hop'd he was in a good Humour now. Aye, - come let's go to supper, said he, and I thought all was over; but this Hart came into the Room, and persuaded him to go out again; I spoke to Hart, and my Husband made me get out of the Room, and would not let me come in again; so they eat the Fowl themselves. 'Twas but a little before, that I had pass'd a Fine, before the Lord Chief Justice Willes, to raise Money that he might pay off his Debts, and I was afraid of his embezzeling what he had about him, so I got to him again, and perswaded him to come Home: He told me, he would give me some Money, and he pull'd out 11 Guineas which I took, and 20 l. Bill likewise. I asked him for the 40 l. Bill he had about him, - Pray my Dear give them me, - you'll then have 20 l. behind. He had at this Time, only his Gown and Waistcoat on, and wanted his other Cloaths; I went back to fetch them, and when I returned, I found his Night Gown and Waistcoat in a young Fellows Hands, and my Husband was going to fight in the Publick Room. I knew there was a Pocket<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220017"></xptr> Book in the Waistcoat Pocket, with a 20 l. and a 40 l. Bill in it, and other Notes and Bonds, so I took the Things from the young Man, and put the Pocket Book into my Bosom, pinning my Gown over it. There was a Bag of Guineas in the other Pocket; however I put the Pocket Book for safety between my Breast and my Shirt, and was going Home with it, but my Husband came after me, and stopp'd me. I said to him, - my Dear, you are foolish, - and in Liquor, and should not shew such Things in a publick Room. Then I got out of the House, and two Men cross'd the Way after me. Lord thinks I, - I hope these Men don't come after me; and presently I was knock'd down. The Blow stunn'd me, and I have since had an Imposthume in my Head, which, had it not broke at my Nose, would have killed me. I can't tell who knock'd me down, but I think it was Lovell that took me up. Lord thinks I! this Fellow has got my Pocket Book! for I found a Man take it out of my Breast when I was down. I cry'd out immediately, - my Pocket Book! my Pocket Book! and Lovell immediately ran away. I call'd out as much as my Spirits would let me, - for I had receiv'd a sad Blow on my Head, by falling upon the Stones. 'Twas about eight or nine o'Clock at Night, and the Lamps were lighted, and I look'd upon his (Lovell's) Face. In the Croud there happen'd to be an Excise-man, who told me where he lodg'd; so about a Week after, I went to the House, and his Landlady carry'd me to his Wife, who told me that her Husband (Lovell) was gone into the Country. I carry'd her before Mr. Justice Margets, and she at last told us, that she would help me to the Pocket Book in three or four Hours. I would not leave her, so after she had carry'd me up and down a great Way, we went to the Horse and Groom in St. Giles's, where I saw Lovell, and knew him again. He deny'd having the Pocket Book, and got out into the Street; I ran after him and held him, crying out, - a Thief! a Thief! he was too strong for me and got away, but this Man took him, and the Pocket Book was found upon him, by the Constable. When it was in the Constable's Hand, he snatch'd it from him and gave it me himself. There were all my Papers in it but the 20l. Note; that he had got paid. I had advertised it as dropp'd, - not stolen, for Fear I should never have it again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Lovell. If you knew you was robb'd of the Book, why did you go out to look for it with Lights?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lowry. I immediately cry'd out, I would give any body half a Guinea, if they would help me to it again; and some People came and told me it was found. I desir'd Lights might be got, but when they came to the Place, there was nothing but some Pieces of Paper torn and thrown about.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person344">
                  Benjamin 
                  Ingram 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person344" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person344" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of January I was going up <placeName id="t17380222-54-crimeloc236">Bow street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-54-crimeloc236" type="placeName" value="Bow street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-54-crimeloc236" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-54-off233 t17380222-54-crimeloc236"></join>, to Bloomsbury, and there I saw Lovell, and his Landlady and Mrs. Lowry, talking together. I turn'd into Hind street, and before I got half way up the Street, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief; I turn'd and saw Lovell running and crying out Bailiffs! Bailiffs! He turn'd up the first Turning, and ran round the Fish-Market. I walked up the Corner, and met him, and laid hold of him. Mrs. Lowry came up and said God bless you, - he has robb'd me of 60 l. I had him into an Alehouse, where she charged a Constable with him. The Constable searched him, and in his right Hand Pocket, (in which the Prisoner constantly held his Hand) he felt something, and told us, he suppos'd 'twas the Pocket-Book. He was pulling it out, but the Prisoner snatched it from him, and gave it Mrs. Lowry, - Madam, said he, - there's your Book. 'Twas ty'd up in a Piece of brown Paper; this is the same, - I am positive to it. She open'd it, and there was a 40 l. Note in it, N.H. 29. Payable to 
               <persName id="t17380222-54-person345">
                  William 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person345" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person345" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Upon this we put the Note into the Book again, and carry'd him to Mr. De Veil, who committed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person346">
                  George 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person346" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person346" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was at Work in my Room at Bloomsbury, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief! I look'd out of the Window and saw Lovell turn up Soper's Row. I whipp'd up a Court and came upon him. Ingram was then coming through the Posts, so I laid hold of him, on one Side, and he on the other. When we took him he kept groping with his right Hand in his Pocket, I asked him what he had in that Pocket? Nothing (said he) that you shall see. I told him he should not take his Hand out of his Pocket, 'till I had got him into a House, out of the Mob. When we were in the Alehouse, Mrs. Lowry charg'd him with having robb'd her of 2 Bank Notes, and the Constable took the Pocket Book out of his Pocket, but he snatch'd it from him, and deliver'd it himself to Mrs. Lowry. The 40 l. Note was in it, but the 20 l. Note the Prisoner told her, was gone. He confess'd before Mr. De Veil, that he had given that, to Matthews, (the Person not taken) to get it chang'd away, and that Matthews had brought him mine Guineas and a Half out of it. Mr. De Viel asked him who had the rest of the 20 l.? He said, Matthews, and the Prisoner Staines had all the Remainder.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person347">
                  Joseph 
                  Armstrong 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person347" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person347" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I took Charge of the Prisoner Lovell, and took the Book out of his Pocket, as hath been related. Upon searching him farther, I found upon him a new Peruke, and 17s. and 5d. and a pair of metal Buckles. Mr. Deveil committing him to the Gate house, I carry'd him there, and found Dorrel confin'd upon the same Account. Dorrel was very desirous of being examin'd by Mr. Deveil, and the next Morning he sent for them both before him, and after Examination, Lovel was sent to Newgate, and Dorrel to the Gate house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person348">
                  William 
                  Dorrel 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person348" type="surname" value="Dorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person348" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday Jan. 13. the Prisoner Staines came to me in Brewer street, and told me a Friend of his had found a 20 l. Bank Note, and if I could get it changed, it would be of Service to us both. I said, I believ'd I could get it done; upon which he carry'd me to an Alehouse in Fleet street, where I saw Matthews, and the Prisoner Lovel. Staines told Matthews, that I was the Person that could get his Note chang'd. I thought I could perswade Mr. Lewis to do it for me; so we all went to his House, and I told him, if he would change a 20l. Bank Note I would pay him what I ow'd him. He consented, and Matthews catch'd up all the Money, but 4 Guineas, which Staines was to have for his Trouble, and out of these 4 Guineas I had 3, only I paid for a Bottle of Wine, and made Staines a Present of a Crown more. The next Morning I saw the Advertisement in the Daily Advertiser, and that Payment was stopp'd at the Bank. I advised Lewis to keep the Note for some Time, but the Sunday following he brought Capt. Lowry to an Alehouse in the Neighbourhood, and sent for me, and detained me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person349">
                  Ralph 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person349" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person349" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Dorrel having borrow'd 2 Guineas and 3 s. of me, he came to me 2 or 3 Days after, with 3 Men, and told me if I would change a Bank Note of 20l. he would pay me my Money. He told me 'twas a very good Note, but as I can't read my self, I shew'd it to a Man in the House, and he told me 'twas good. I fetch'd the Money, and Matthews took it all. The next Morning I asked Dorrel how he could serve me so villainous a Trick? and Mrs. Lowry coming to me, I inform'd her how to come at him.</p>
               <p>Lovel. The 7th of Jan in the Evening, Mrs. Lowry and her Husband were quarrelling at the White Swan in Fetter-Lane; she ran away with his Gown and Waistcoat, he followed her into the Street, and about 30 Yards from the Door she fell down, he dragg'd her thro' the Kennel to the White Swan, and then she said, she had dropp'd her Pocket Book and Notes. The People ran to look for it, and I among the rest, and 'twas my Fortune to find it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person350">
                  William 
                  Hadley 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person350" type="surname" value="Hadley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person350" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 7th of Jan. between 8 and 9 in the Evening, I saw a Man in his Shirt run along Fetter-Lane, and several People were with him; I ran with the rest, and saw the Gentlewoman fall down; I saw her when she was falling, and not before. She got up again, and the Man took hold of her, and forced her back again into the White Swan. I did not follow them into the House, but in about a quarter or half an Hour, I saw People with Lights, who said they were looking for a Pocket Book with Bank Notes in it; I believe Mrs. Lowry herself was among them. The beginning of the Week I saw an Advertisement in Lawrence's House, (the White Swan) stuck upon the Dial Case, - Lost on Saturday Night over against the Black Raven in Fetter-Lane, a Pocket Book with 3 Bank Notes in it, &amp;c. I saw Mrs. Lowry several Times that Week, and she never complain'd of its being taken out of her Bosom, as I heard. As soon as she heard of her Notes, then she said the Book was taken from her, and not before. I am a Porter, and work for Mr. Perry the Carrier.</p>
               <p>Jury to Mrs. Lowry. Was your Husband out with you that Night in the Street?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lowry. After I was got up again, and the Pocket Book was taken from me, they set a Bull Dog upon me, and I cry'd out, for God's Sake take off the Bull Dog.</p>
               <p>Jury. We ask you whether your Husband was with you in the Street when you was down?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lowry. I can't tell, - when I was down my Husband came to take me in.</p>
               <p>Jury. Are you sure it was not your Husband that knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lowry. That I can't say. I complain'd then that my Pocket Book was taken from me, but there was so much Mob, that my Husband could not come near me. I told them I would stop Payment at the Bank on Monday, and that the Notes would do none of them any good; I believe I said this in the Alehouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person351">
                  William 
                  Monk 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person351" type="surname" value="Monk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day the Prisoners were committed Mrs. Lowry told me, (talking with her about Lovell) - Lord bless me, I won't swear the Man robb'd me for the World. God forbid I should, - my Husband might take it from my Bosom, for ought I know. I am a Taylor by Trade, and live at the 3d House in Plow-yard, Fetter-Lane.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220019"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person352">
                  Michael 
                  Ryan 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person352" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person352" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Chairman My Partner (Brydon) and I carried the Gentlewoman from Brewers-street to Fetter Lane; when we set her down, she told us 'twas crossing that Kennel she lost her Pocket Book. Madam, says I, I thought you was robb'd of it; no, says she, I should be a very wicked Woman if I say so. I fell down and lost it out of my Bosom. At the same Time she clapp'd her Hand to her Breast, - but I can't swear whether it was her right - or her left Breast.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person353">
                  James 
                  Brydon 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person353" type="surname" value="Brydon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person353" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-54-person354">
                  William 
                  Hart 
               <interp inst="t17380222-54-person354" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person354" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Church Yard-Alley in Fetter Lane. This Gentlewoman's Husband was at any House to hide himself on Account of Debts On Saturday after Twelfth Day, his Wife and he had Words, so he asked me to go and drink with him at Lawrence's. While we were there, the Captain quarrell'd with a Gentleman, and got up and shewed his Wrists; he said he was a strong Man, and double jointed; at last he threw off his Gown and Waistcoat, and gave them to a Boy to hold; there being a Pocket-Book and a Purse in the Waistcoat Pocket, his Wife took them from the Boy and ran into the Street, he follow'd her, but I staid in the House. In a little while she came in again, complaining her Husband had abused her grosly, and had dragg'd her in the Kennel, by which Means she had lost her PocketBook; she gave a Boy 2 d. to buy a Link, and she went up and down the Street to look for it</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lowry. This is the Fellow that kept my Husband drinking Hot-pots and Gin; and was the Occasion of all this Affliction to us both. Both <rs id="t17380222-54-verdict237" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-54-verdict237" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
