<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-9">
               <interp inst="t17370706-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-9" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-9" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-9-off48-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-9-defend85 t17370706-9-off48 t17370706-9-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>10 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-defend85" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Leng 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-9-defend85" type="surname" value="Leng"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-defend85" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-defend85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370706-9-defloc47">St. John Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-9-defloc47" type="placeName" value="St. John Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-9-defloc47" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-9-defend85 t17370706-9-defloc47"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-9-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               that certain evil disposed Persons having made and forged the last Will and Testament, of a certain Person therein described, she being a Person of evil Fame and Disposition, on the <rs id="t17370706-9-cd49" type="crimeDate">14th of October 1736</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-9-off48 t17370706-9-cd49"></join>, in the Parish of St. Mary le Bow, in the Ward of Cheap, with an Intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-9-victim87" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Spencer 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim87" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim87" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , of Monies due to 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-9-victim89" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Bulleton 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim89" type="surname" value="Bulleton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim89" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-9-victim89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , for Service done on Board the Prince Augustus, the said forged Will did utter and publish; by Vertue of which said forged Will, she the said Catherine did receive of the said John Spencer, the Sum of 19 l 4 s. 6 d. pretending the said Money was due to her, as Executrix of the said Joseph Bulleton, &amp;c whereas in Truth and in Fact, the said Bulleton never made such Will, but is still alive, &amp;c. against the Peace of our Sovereign
            </rs>, &amp;c</p>
               <p>The Councel having open'd the Charge the Witnesses were call'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person90">
                  Walter 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person90" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person90" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is an Original Will from Doctors-Commons; I am a Clerk in the Prerogative-Office. 'Tis endorsed after the common Manner. 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person91">
                  Joseph 
                  Bellton 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person91" type="surname" value="Bellton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person91" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             otherwise Belleton, 8 Octo. 36. Here is the Probat, and the Prisoner was sworn, duly to administer before Dr. Foulkes, Octob. 8. 1736.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person92">
                  Joseph 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person92" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person92" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Will was brought to the Commons, for the Writing on the Back, is mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought that Will to the Commons?</p>
               <p>Hughes. The Prisoner brought it, in Order to prove it. Here is the Jurat, and whenever I write the Jurat on Wills, 'tis in order to their being proved.</p>
               <p>Q. When a Person brings a Will to be prov'd, is there not an Oath administer'd to that Person?</p>
               <p>Hughes. Yes, always; we first write the Jurat, and then have them before a Doctor of Laws, where they are sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Purport of the Oath?</p>
               <p>Hughes. The Purport of the Oath is, - that the Paper before them, contains the last Will and Testament of the Person deceased, and that you are<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060008"></xptr> one of the Executors named therein, and will truly perform the Contents.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go with the Prisoner before the Doctor?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I can't tell whether 'twas I or my Master that went with her, - but there's Doctor 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person93">
                  Foulke
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person93" type="given" value="Foulke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Hand to the Will. I have done the like Business for her 20 or 30 Times, she has been at the Commons upon such Business as this, - to prove Wills of deceased Persons since this Time. When they receive Probats from us, they carry them to the India-House, and receive the Deceased's Pay.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Discourse with her, concerning the Use she was to make of this Will?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, not of this.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she pretend that Paper to be, when she brought it to you?</p>
               <p>Hughes. The last Will of the Person therein named. We always repeat the Oath to them before they go to the Doctors; I always do to every one without Exception, and I believe it was done to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Oath was read to her?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I can't charge my Memory with this particular Will, but 'tis always done.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person94">
                  Emanuel 
                  Walkett 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person94" type="surname" value="Walkett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person94" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Name is here, as a Witness to this Will, but I did not write it, - this is none of my Writing. The first Time I saw this Will was about a Fortnight ago, at the Commons. I never saw any Person execute it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Walkett and Mrs. Anderson were my opposite Neighbours, and he was Witness to this Will; they have signed a great many for me before this. Will either Mr. Walkett or Mrs. Anderson say I would forge their Hands?</p>
               <p>Walkett. I am sworn: - that's none of my Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one Williamson?</p>
               <p>Walkett No, I know nothing of that Person.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Anderson. My Name was Coutes, but I never signed that Will, this is the Mark indeed, that I use, but I never signed this. This is not my Name, - 'tis spelt here with an L, I spell my Name C, O, U, T, E, S.</p>
               <p>Joseph Bulleton. I never put my Name to this Paper - no, I never did, - I know nothing of it. Here's the same Mark that I make, set against the Seal, - but I did not make the Mark. I never made any Will in my Life, and the first Time I saw this was in Doctors-Commons.</p>
               <p>C. Let the Will be read.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads.</p>
               <p>'' In the Name of God, Amen. I Joseph Ballton, '' now belonging to the East-India Ship the '' Pc Augustus, Capt. Gasling Commander, and '' not knowing how it may please God to deal '' with me - but considering the Uncertainty '' of this transitory Life, do make and declar '' this Presence to contain my last Will and '' Testament in Manner and Form following. '' First, I commend my Soul to the Hands of Almighty '' God, hoping to be saved thro' the Merits, '' Death, Passion and Resurrection of Jesus '' Christ my only Saviour, and my Body to be '' - I give, devise (demise) and bequeath '' to 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person95">
                  William 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person95" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person95" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Catherine his Wife of St. '' 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person96">
                  John 
                  Wapping 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person96" type="surname" value="Wapping"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Middl all soul Exseckter such '' Wages, Sum and Sums of Money, Lands, Tenements, '' Goods, Chattels and Estates whatever, '' wherewith at the Time of my Decease I shall '' be possessed or invested, which then belong or '' appertain to me, I give, demise, and bequeath '' to 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person97">
                  William 
                  Leng 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person97" type="surname" value="Leng"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person97" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Catherine his Wife, and '' revoke all former Wills heretofore by me made. '' And I do make and ordain this, to stand as my '' last Will and Testament, to stand for ever. '' Witness my Hand the Day and Year above '' written the sixt Day of November, Anno Dom '' 1732, and in the Sekest Yrre of the Rine of '' his Magiste George the Second.</p>
               <p>Josph Ballton.</p>
               <p>Witness</p>
               <p>Jennet Clouts,</p>
               <p>Emanual Walkett.</p>
               <p>Witness.</p>
               <p>Q. To Bulleton. Did you serve on Board any of the East-India Company's Ships?</p>
               <p>Bulleton. Yes, on Board the Prince Augustus, Captain Goslin Commander. I went out in this Ship about 5 Years ago, and when I came Home there was 19 l. 4 s. due to me for Wages</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no more due to you?</p>
               <p>Bulleton. I don't mention the rest; I mention the 4 l afterwards. When I came Home I apply'd for Payment at the India-House, and they told me so much had been paid.</p>
               <p>Swift Fleet. Mr. Spencer is dead, I knew him well, he was Joint Pay-master of the India-House; his Business was to pay the Sailors their Wages. Here is the Book where the Receipts are enter'd, and here is Catherine Leng's Hand to the Receipt for this Money. I cannot say I saw her write it, but by comparing her Hand, I think 'tis the same, and the Body of the Receipt is Mr. Spencer's own Writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person98">
                  James 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person98" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person98" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen the Prisoner write, and I believe the Name at the Bottom of this Re-ceipt<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060009"></xptr> is her Hand-writing. I have had Dealings with her these 9 Years, and on my Oath I believe she wrote that Name.</p>
               <p>Read the Receipt.</p>
               <p>'' Received the 14th of October 1736. per me '' Catherine Leng, the Sum of 25 l 14 s being in '' full for Wages, Debts, and all Demands, for '' Service perform'd on Board the Ship Prince '' Augustus, Captain 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person99">
                  Francis 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person99" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person99" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Commander, '' by Joseph Bulleton per me, (to whom I am Executrix) '' Catherine Leng</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what was due to Bulleton when the Ship came Home?</p>
               <p>Fleet. This was the Ballance of his Account, for Service on Board the said Ship 19 l 4 s. 9 d. there was 25 l. 14 s. due for Service, but upon the Ballance, she received neat Money 19 l 4 s. 9 d.</p>
               <p>Bulleton. When I return'd Home in the Prince Augustus, I was press'd on Board the Britannia Man of War in Sir 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person100">
                  John 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person100" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Fleet, which was then going out for Lisbon: I was carried to Spithead, and there the Prisoner came to me, and asked me for a Power to receive my Wages. I denied to make her a Power, and she offered me 2 Guineas to do it; but I knew her Character, and would not consent, for she had used me ill before this, and the People assured me she was a bad Woman, and they bid me take Care of my self. I have Witness that she went angry away from me because I would not consent.</p>
               <p>Q. Did her Husband apply to you for such a Power?</p>
               <p>Bulleton. No, only she. She only asked me to make her a Power; I don't remember a Word about a Will, nor did I hear any Thing of her having received my Money, till I came Home in the Britannia from Lisbon.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Why 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person101">
                  Joseph 
                  Bulleton 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person101" type="surname" value="Bulleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person101" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - when I heard of your Arrival, I was not confirmed of your Life, - 'till my Son Charles saw you at Sheerness, and then I bid him tell you I had received your Wages, and what Ballance was between us, I would pay you, and I desired you to come Home, and I would make all Things easy; I bid him tell you, that altho' it was not in my Power to pay you, I would give you a Note of my Hand for the Money. When you came up, I told you I was glad to see you, but I was sorry in another Respect, for thro' Information of your Death, I had administer'd for you; you told me I had done a base Action, and I said, I did it with no ill Intent, and I wished they had been dead that gave me Intelligence of your Death, and I told you farther, that whatever was due to you, when my Husband came Home, you should be paid with all the Pleasure in Life. Call 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person102">
                  Mark 
                  Weyland 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person102" type="surname" value="Weyland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person102" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for he was to sign this very Will, but only he could not write.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person103">
                  Mark 
                  Weyland 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person103" type="surname" value="Weyland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person103" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of this Will: I made her a Power my self, - one of the same sort, but I can say nothing to this.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that Bulleton made a Will in her Favour?</p>
               <p>Weyland. I saw him once writing there, but I can't swear to this Paper. - I can neither read nor write.</p>
               <p>C. You are charged with receiving 19 l. 4 s. 6 d due to Bulleton, of 
               <persName id="t17370706-9-person104">
                  John 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person104" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person104" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon a Will which you knew was forged: Can you call any Witnesses to induce a Belief, that you did not know it was forged; or that it was a true Will:</p>
               <p>Prisoner I had no Occasion to forge a Will of Bulleton's, because when I heard of his Death, I could have administer'd as chief Creditor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-9-person105">
                  Grace 
                  Farrell 
               <interp inst="t17370706-9-person105" type="surname" value="Farrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person105" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-person105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came to the Prisoner's House to work for her, and I saw some Papers lying there, and I asked her what they were, and she told me they were Wills; at the same Time she told me, I must not expect the Box which the young Man had promised to send me from Lisbon, for he was dead. I know nothing of this Will.</p>
               <p>Councel. To put the Matter out of all Doubt, here's a Man will prove the Body of the Will is filled up, with her own Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lewis. I have seen a great deal of her Writing, - (looking on the Will) I verily believe the whole filling up is by her own Hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Consider my Life's at Stake. I am a Foreigner; here's 4 more Wills, could I forge all these 4 Wills too?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I believe the whole of this to be her own Writing except this Name, (Williamson).</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Look at the rest of them for Christ's Sake. Examine these Wills.</p>

               <p>Lewis. I have look'd over this Will very carefully, and I take it to be filled up by her self. The Mark of Joseph Bulleton, that too is her own Writing.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did Bulleton owe her any Money when he went to Lisbon?</p>
               <p>Bulleton. Before I went to India I owed her 3 l. 5 s. and I gave her a Note of my Hand for the Money: After that she got 4 l. 12 s. of my Wages, so when I came Home, she owed me Money. She received 4 l. 12 s. while I was in India, for the 3 l. 5 s. so I thought she was very well paid. After she had received this 3 l. 5 s. I never ow'd her a Farthing.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060010"></xptr>Councel. (To Lewis) Look on these other Wills, Do you think they are fill'd up with her Handwriting.</p>
               <p>Lewis. Here's the Power by which she receiv'd the 4 l. 12 s. the Power and the Will I believe to be both wrote by the same Hand. <rs id="t17370706-9-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370706-9-punish51" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-9-punish51" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-9-defend85 t17370706-9-punish51"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
