<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351015-28">
               <interp inst="t17351015-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-28" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-28" type="date" value="17351015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-28-off111-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-defend234 t17351015-28-off111 t17351015-28-verdict116"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150013"></xptr>35. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     Julian 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-28-defend234" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-defend234" type="given" value="Julian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-defend234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             *, was indicted for <rs id="t17351015-28-off111" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-off111" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-off111" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               Ravishing and Carnally Knowing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351015-28-victim236" type="victimName">
                           Susan 
                           Marshall 
                        <interp inst="t17351015-28-victim236" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-28-victim236" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-28-victim236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-off111 t17351015-28-victim236"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17351015-28-viclabel112" type="occupation">an Infant of Eleven Years old</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-victim236 t17351015-28-viclabel112"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17351015-28-cd113" type="crimeDate">April 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-off111 t17351015-28-cd113"></join>.</p>
               <p> * In September 1731, Brown was tried for a Street-Robbery, but acquitted. And in July last he was one of the Evidences for Mac Cray.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person237">
                  Susan 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person237" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person237" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Night my Mother sent me to the Prisoner's Shop. - He <rs id="t17351015-28-deflabel114" type="occupation">keeps a Chandler's Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-defend234 t17351015-28-deflabel114"></join> the Corner of <placeName id="t17351015-28-crimeloc115">Plum-tree Court in Dyot-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-28-crimeloc115" type="placeName" value="Plum-tree Court in Dyot-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-28-crimeloc115" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-28-off111 t17351015-28-crimeloc115"></join>, - for two Red Herrings. When I had them, the Prisoner bid me carry them home, and come back again, and he would give me one for my self. So I came the second Time, and he bid me go into his Back Room, and he would bring me a Red Herring, but he brought me a Dram of Anniseed, and made me drink some of it. Then he set me on his Lap, and put his Hand up my Coats, and threw me on the Floor, and - and - I screamed out, and called him nasty Rogue. But he said, Hush! hush! I do so to my Wife. And then he made me promise to tell no body, and so I did not speak of it till Monday; but then I told Mrs. Bathaway, for I was so sore that I could not go about; and she told my Mother.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Vat'our it vas ven you come to mine Shop?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person238">
                  Susan 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person238" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person238" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What Hour? It was between Nine and Ten at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the first, or second Time of your being there?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person239">
                  Susan 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person239" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person239" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first, for it was about Ten when I went the second Time, and I saw no body else was then in the Shop. He shut the Hatch and bolted it, and when he came to me in the Back Room he latched the Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You vas in mine Shop but von Time dat Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not complain before Monday?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person240">
                  Susan 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person240" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person240" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Because I was afraid my Mother would beat me.</p>
               <p>Q. On your Oath did not you consent?</p>
               <p>Susan Marshall. No. I cry'd out aloud.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ven you come again to my Shop?</p>
               <p>Susan Marshall. Not till Monday Morning.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You come on de Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go again to the House of a Man that had used you in such a Manner? Were you sent on an Errand?</p>
               <p>Susan Marshall. No. I went with two or three of my Play-fellows to drink a Dram.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bathaway. The Girl came to my Habitation on the Monday, and cried. I asked what was the Matter? and she told me that her Mother had sent her for two Herrings; that the Prisoner bid her come again and he would give her one for herself; that she went; that he took her into a Back Room, and gave her a Dram, and sat her in his Lap, and put his Hands up her Coats, and told her - I don't know how to speak it - but he told her he must - And that then he laid her on the Floor, and did as he said. That she cried out very loud, but no body heard her. Upon this I sent for her Mother, and upon examining we found that some Man had abused her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Marshall. My Girl told me that the Prisoner had used her in a violent Manner. I found her in a very bad Way, and was frighted to see that a Man had been medling with her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I send a Surshon?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Marshall. Yes, a Fortnight after, but I would not let him see the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you complain?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Marshall. This was done on the 11th of April. On the 18th I sent for a Surgeon, and the next Day I went to Hicks's Hall, and preferred a Bill for an Attempt.</p>
               <p>Q. How came a Bill afterwards to be found for a Rape?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Marshall. I left it to my Attorney.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person241">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person241" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person241" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Midwife. I searched the Girl on the 17th of April. She was very much torn, and had a foul Distemper. On the 19th I went to a Surgeon, and told him I fancy'd she was clapt, by what I found upon her Linnen. He said he believed the same. And I'll swear that a Man had enter'd her in a barbarous Manner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hawkins, Surgeon. The Girl complained of a Smart. I saw her Linnen turn'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150014"></xptr> up, and it was discolour'd with a Running. I was in some doubt as to her Disorder, but I gave her Medicines as for the French Disease, and the Distemper submitted to them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Matthews, Apothecary. I thought by her Linnen, that her Disorder was Venereal.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I brought an Action against deem in de King's Bench for Scandal, and den dey indict me for dis Rape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person242">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Frazier 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person242" type="surname" value="Frazier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person242" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the Prisoner's House. On the eleventh of April, I was in his little Room behind the Shop from eight in the Morning till eleven at Night, and was not out of it except twice or thrice in the Day-time, when I just stept into my own Room and down again. But from nine at Night to eleven I was not once out. The Girl came between nine and ten for two Herrings, and carried them away, but she came no more that Night, nor was she at all in the little Room. And Mrs. Tomson, who then lodged in the same House, but is since dead, was with me in that Room from eight till past ten: Next Day, as the Prisoner and I and the Spanish Embastinder's Silver Smith (who is now gone over Sea) were sitting in that Room, this Girl and another came in for a Quartern of Gin; they laughed and talked how they had served two Boys, and this Girl said, I paid his Shins with the Fire-shovel, I love to play at Man and Wife, but I do not like him. She came two or three times that Day for Gin, upon which the Prisoner said to his Wife, why do you let them Girls drink Gin? I would have you deny them. As to the Prisoner's Character, he is a very honest Man as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person243">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person243" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person243" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . So he is, and I lodge in his Cellar under that little Room, and I heard no Noise that Night - I saw the Girl on the fifteenth of April. She said the Prisoner had had to do with her to be sure. I asked her why she did not cry out. Because, says she, he gave me a Dram of Anniseed, and I shall have a pretty Baby of my own to nurse, and that will be better than crying out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person244">
                  John 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person244" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was desired on the third of May to search the Girl, but her Parents refused to let me see her. I examined the Prisoner the same Day; he was then found, and it did not appear that he had lately had a Clap.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person245">
                  Roger 
                  Ferris 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person245" type="surname" value="Ferris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person245" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person246">
                  Ann 
                  Fullerton 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person246" type="surname" value="Fullerton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person246" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person247">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person247" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person248">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person248" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person248" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed that the Prisoner had the general Character of an honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-28-person249">
                  Margaret 
                  Sampson 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person249" type="surname" value="Sampson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person249" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, that 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person250">
                  Suky 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person250" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person250" type="given" value="Suky"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was well known to every body for all manner of Impudence.</p>
               <p>In reply to which, 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person251">
                  Ann 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person251" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person251" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17351015-28-person252">
                  Hannah 
                  Edge 
               <interp inst="t17351015-28-person252" type="surname" value="Edge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person252" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that they knew Suky Marshall very well, and never saw any thing in her like Impudence or Forwardness, but that she was a very sober, modest, virtuous Girl, and that the Prisoner was a very litigious Man.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351015-28-verdict116" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-28-verdict116" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
