<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-42">
               <interp inst="t17370907-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-42" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-42" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-42-off216-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-42-defend304 t17370907-42-off216 t17370907-42-verdict219"></join>
         
               <p>45. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-42-defend304" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-42-defend304" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-defend304" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-defend304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370907-42-off216" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-off216" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-off216" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 5 l. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-42-victim306" type="victimName">
                           Willoughbey 
                           Merchant 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-42-victim306" type="surname" value="Merchant"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-42-victim306" type="given" value="Willoughbey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-42-victim306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-42-off216 t17370907-42-victim306"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, in the Parish of St. Katherine Creechurch, <rs id="t17370907-42-cd217" type="crimeDate">September 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-42-off216 t17370907-42-cd217"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Merchant. On Wednesday Night last, as I was going thro' the Postern at <placeName id="t17370907-42-crimeloc218">Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-42-crimeloc218" type="placeName" value="Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-42-crimeloc218" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-42-off216 t17370907-42-crimeloc218"></join>, the Prisoner and two more were quarrelling. I had not stepp'd above two steps within the Postern, but I felt my Watch slip out of my Pocket. There was no one near me but the Prisoner, therefore I clapp'd fast hold of him, and told him he was the Man. Another came up immediately, and cry'd - what's the Matter? I imagined him to be one of his Companions, so I seized him too, and brought them both out, from under the Postern. I had no sooner got them out, but says the Prisoner, - see what you have done, and immediately I looked down, and pick'd up the Watch from the Ground, between his Legs.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mann. I was going thro' the Gate at this Time, and 2 or 3 Men were making a Quarrel; as I shov'd thro', I heard Mr. Merchant say, - you're the Man. He seized him by the Collar, and was pulling him out, when another Man came up and made a Noise, upon which Mr. Merchant seized him too, and pull'd them both out. The Prisoner dropp'd the Watch upon the Ground, and said, - see what you have done, there's the Watch. Upon my Oath I saw him drop it from between his Legs.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this?</p>
               <p>Mr. Mann. 'Twas about Seven o'Clock, or a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070032"></xptr> quarter after; I swear positively I saw him ( between the 2 Lights) drop it from between his Legs, at the other End of the Passage.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by the 2 Lights?</p>
               <p>Mr. Mann. Between Day Light, and the Light of the Lamps; there was Light enough to see it very plainly, between the Prisoner's Legs.</p>
               <p>Constable. I was the Officer that took Charge of the Prisoner: the Gentleman had the Watch in his Hand, he charged the Prisoner with picking it out of his Pocket, and Mr Mann said he saw him drop it, - he said he saw it before it came to the Ground.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Gentleman took hold of another Man before he laid hold of me, and charg'd him with picking his Pocket.</p>
               <p>A.Witness. The Prisoner is reckon'd the Head of the Pick-pockets in my Neighbourhood - about Temple-Bar in general, every Shop-keeper thereabout knows him to be a Pick-pocket. <rs id="t17370907-42-verdict219" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-verdict219" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370907-42-punish220" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-42-punish220" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-42-defend304 t17370907-42-punish220"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
