<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370526-44">
               <interp inst="t17370526-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-44" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-44" type="date" value="17370526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370526-44-off192-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-44-defend287 t17370526-44-off192 t17370526-44-verdict195"></join>
         
               <p>54. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370526-44-defend287" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17370526-44-defend287" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-defend287" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-defend287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17370526-44-off192" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-off192" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-off192" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               he on the 25th of March, in the 8th Year of his Majesty's Reign, at the Parish of St. Sepulchre's, took to Wife 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370526-44-victim289" type="victimName">
                           Eleanor 
                           Steel 
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim289" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim289" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17370526-44-cd193" type="crimeDate">21st of Oct</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-44-off192 t17370526-44-cd193"></join>. last, in the Parish of St. Sepulchre's he took to Wife 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370526-44-victim291" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Benham 
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim291" type="surname" value="Benham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-44-victim291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and to her was then and there married, his former Wife being then alive
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-44-person292">
                  John 
                  Crossby 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person292" type="surname" value="Crossby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person292" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner was marry'd to Steel, I was present when that Affair was transacted. They were marry'd at a Brandy-shop at the Fleet, the Ceremony was perform'd by a Man in a Night Gown; whether he was a Parson or not, I can't tell. He pull'd a Book out of his Pocket, and read a little Bit of it to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the most material Parts of the Office read?</p>
               <p>Crossby. No, not all the Particulars of it; but he read some of it, and then told them they were marry'd. I am sure he did not read half so much as was read to me at Pancras when I was marry'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a Ring?</p>
               <p>Crossby. Yes, there was a Ring, but I don't know whether the Words, - I take you to be my Wife, and I take you to be my Husband, were said. In 2 or 3 Days after the Wedding, she went down to see her Friends in Cumberland, and there she was deliver'd of a Child, and left it there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she stay in Cumberland?</p>
               <p>Crossby. She went down 2 or 3 Days after the Wedding, which was in March, and she sta'd 'till November. After she came from Cumberland they liv'd together as Man and Wife 'till last June. They lodg'd in my House, and he acknowledged her publickly for his Wife, and she own'd him as her Husband; they both went by the same Name.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to part?</p>
               <p>Crossby. Why, after he had marry'd her, he found she was with Child, so that occasion'd the first Breach, and was the Reason of her going to Cumberland immediately after the Wedding. When he found how it was, he call'd me up into the Room, and told me of it; she was crying in Bed, and asking his Pardon; she told him if he would forgive her, she would be one of the best of Wives.</p>
               <p>Q. After this did he leave her?</p>
               <p>Crossby. No, she left him; she took away what Effects of his she could get, and took Passage with some Men for New England, but he found her out, and one of the Men was try'd here last July Sessions.*</p>
               <p>* 
               <persName id="t17370526-44-person293">
                  James 
                  English 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person293" type="surname" value="English"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person293" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was try'd for stealing several Things, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17370526-44-person294">
                  Robert 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person294" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person294" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in July Sessions, 1736. and acquitted. See Sessions Book, No VI. 1736. p. 154.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-44-person295">
                  Will 
                  Seymour 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person295" type="surname" value="Seymour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person295" type="given" value="Will"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the Prisoner was marry'd to his second Wife ( Benham ). They were marry'd (as they call it) at the <placeName id="t17370526-44-crimeloc194">Fleet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-44-crimeloc194" type="placeName" value="Fleet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-44-crimeloc194" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-44-off192 t17370526-44-crimeloc194"></join>, by an old Fellow in a black Gown, at an Ale-house.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173705260019"></xptr> The Parson said they were marry'd, but I am sure they were not marry'd as I was; the Parson's Wife lent them a Ring to put upon the Bride's Finger.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say, she took him for her Husband, and he - her for his Wife?</p>
               <p>Seymore. Yes, and he acknowledged her for his Wife; this was some Time last Winter, - If I had thought I should have been call'd upon to come here, I am sure, I would not have been at the Wedding.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-44-person296">
                  Ann 
                  TaHowgreen 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person296" type="surname" value="TaHowgreen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person296" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person296" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Benham's Wedding; the Ceremony was read over to them, and a Ring was put upon her Finger; they afterwards liv'd together as Man and Wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Steel living?</p>
               <p>Crossby. Yes; here she is; this is she, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner I know nothing of the Marriage with Benham; she nursed me when I had a Fever, and she told me I should get somebody to take Care of me constantly; I told her I had somebody that call'd me Husband, and she told me, - as long as she was gone away with other Men, I was divorced by the Laws of God and Man. So I met her one Day, when I was a little out of the way, a little in Liquor, and they got me to an Alehouse, but whether I was marry'd or no I cannot tell; indeed she told me we were marry'd, and we liv'd together afterwards. I did go with my first Wife to be marry'd, but what Sort of a Marriage it was, God knows; she left me and went away with other Men the 26th of June last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-44-person297">
                  Mary 
                  Crossby 
               <interp inst="t17370526-44-person297" type="surname" value="Crossby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person297" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-person297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew him but an honest Man, till this happen'd; the first Woman and he liv'd together as Man and Wife Benham knew he had a Wife when she marry'd him, but I have heard her say before she was marry'd, that if ever she came in Company with him, she would clap her Arms about him, and would never leave him nor forsake him. I know she interceeded with the first Wife to go away, that she might prevail with him for a Maintenance.</p>
               <p>A Witness. Benham told me, she would endeavour to get the first Wife's Name out of the Books; for, says she, I am starving and want a Maintenance. She's but an indifferent Sort of a Person. <rs id="t17370526-44-verdict195" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-verdict195" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17370526-44-punish196" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-punish196" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-44-punish196" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-44-defend287 t17370526-44-punish196"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
