<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350702-49">
               <interp inst="t17350702-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-49" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-49" type="date" value="17350702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350702-49-off228-c266" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-defend377 t17350702-49-off228 t17350702-49-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>59. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-defend377" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas
                      Martin * alias 
                     <rs id="t17350702-49-alias-14" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-defend377 t17350702-49-alias-14"></join>Pup's Nose</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-defend377" type="surname" value="Martin * alias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-defend377" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-defend377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17350702-49-defloc227">St. Georges in the East</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350702-49-defloc227" type="placeName" value="St. Georges in the East"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350702-49-defloc227" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-defend377 t17350702-49-defloc227"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17350702-49-off228" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-off228" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-off228" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Brown Mare
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-victim379" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Thorey 
                  <interp inst="t17350702-49-victim379" type="surname" value="Thorey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-victim379" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-victim379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-off228 t17350702-49-victim379"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17350702-49-cd229" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-off228 t17350702-49-cd229"></join>.</p>
               <p>* He was try'd in January 1733-4, with 
               <persName id="t17350702-49-person380">
                  James 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person380" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person380" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17350702-49-person381">
                  John 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person381" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person381" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for stealing a Money Drawer, and five Shillings, and Acquitted. In September 1734. he was tryed with Will. Newell alias Blackhead, for stealing Goods out of a Ship. Blackhead was found Guilty and Pup's Nose acquitted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-person382">
                  Thomas 
                  Thorey 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person382" type="surname" value="Thorey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person382" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the nineteenth of May, I mist my Mare out of Mr. Webb's Field, I advertised her, and heard she was at Halstead, I not being well Mr. Webb went down and brought her up to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-person383">
                  Thomas 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person383" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person383" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found the Mare at Mr. Newton's at Halstead - Hearing afterwards that the Prisoner was in the New Jail in Southwark, and ( not telling him that I knew where the Mare was) he told me that both the Mare and the Horse were at Halstead.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-person384">
                  John 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person384" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the fifteenth of May the Prisoner on the Mare, and Macdonald on a Back Gelding came riding to my Door in Halstead. I put the Horse and Mare in one Stable. The Prisoner and Macdonald were mighty Quisitive for a good Bed. They lay together, and next Morning the Prisoner offered to sell the Mare to a Butcher. Mr. Trahern, came to look at the Gelding and asked them if they could bring Voucher In six or eight Minutes after which, the Prisoner and Macdonald got off and went away together without paying their Reckoning. But they left the Horse and Mare, which the Justice advised me to keep till I found the Owners - I afterwards delivered the Mare to Mr. Webb.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What did I go for?</p>
               <p>Newton I thought they were Partners when they first came, but next Morning the Prisoner said that Macdonald was his Master. For the Prisoner offered to swop the Mare with me for a Horse, and says he, if this Mare wont do, my Master can help you to another for he has five or six at Braintree.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-49-person385">
                  Lynnell 
                  Lea 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person385" type="surname" value="Lea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person385" type="given" value="Lynnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Macdonald having made a Confession in hopes of saving himself, he desired us to secure the Prisoner. I and Mr. Webb enquired after him, and hearing he was in the New Goal, we went thither, and without letting him know we had been at Halstead, we asked him if he knew of such a Mare, he said, Yes, and told us in particular that he and Macdonald took her and a Gelding out of Mr Webb's Field, and then stole a Saddle, and rode to Brentwood, where they put up, and from thence rode to Halstead; and that he had made a Confession before Justice Lade in Order to hang Macdonald.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173507020022"></xptr>Prisoner. I used to Rig Ships, and carry them to Grave's End, and to work upon the Keys, and do business in the Country. And so upon Thursday Morning about six o'Clock, as I was going into Essex to see for Work, I happened to meet with one Macdonald with a Horse and a Mare, and he being upon the Horse, I asked him to let me ride the Mare to Brentwood, Well, says he, Get up Sirrah. So up I got, and when we came to Brentwood, I thanked him, and said, I was then far enough in the Country to find Work. Why I'll tell ye what my Lad, says he, If you ride the Mare farther, I'll give ye two Shillings, for I want to sell her and the Horse too. So I agreed, and when we came to Halsted I offered to sell her. But while we were making a Bargain, he went out and bid me follow him, which I did, and then says he, G - D - ye, ye Pup's Nose Son of a Bitch, (for that was the Name he gave me) we are both done for; we shall both be hanged, for I stole the Horses - Why are not you a vile Rogue now, says I, to bring an innocent young Fellow into such a scrape; suppose now that I really should be hanged for this, What a fine Jobb of Work there would be. Ye Dog, says he, If I am taken, I'll turn Evidence and hang ye my self Sure you wont be such a Villain, says I, when you know in your Conscience that I had no hand in it. It's no matter for that, says he, I know the way of it, for I have hanged three at the Old Baily. But I'll take care, says I, that you shan't hang me, for I won't be catch'd - And yet I am catch'd too, at last, for all I thought my self so cunning - So when we were got about a Mile and a half out of Town, I sees three Men coming after us on Horse-back; I guest what they wanted, and thought it was high time to take care of one, and so I left him to shift for himself, like a Rogue as he was, and got over a Hedge and run to London. Then I went to Mr. Lingards in Southwark, and told the People there what a hopeful Master I had met with, and how I had like to have been taken up for a Horse-stealer. When they had heard this, they told me truly that I must go with them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17350702-49-person386">
                  John 
                  Lade 
               <interp inst="t17350702-49-person386" type="surname" value="Lade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person386" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and tell him the whole Story; and when I had done that, Sir John Lade sent me to the New Jail, and there I soon heard that Macdonald was as vile a Dog as ever trod Shoe of Leather.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17350702-49-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350702-49-punish231" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350702-49-punish231" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-49-defend377 t17350702-49-punish231"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
