<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340424-44">
               <interp inst="t17340424-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-44" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-44" type="date" value="17340424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340424-44-off190-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-44-defend319 t17340424-44-off190 t17340424-44-verdict194"></join>
         
               <p>46. 
               <persName id="t17340424-44-defend319" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-defend319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17340424-44-off190" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-off190" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-off190" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               privately stealing 22 Dozen of Coat Buttons made of silver Wire and Thread, val. 5 l. 22 dozen of Breast-buttons made of silver Wire and Thread val. 40 l. 9 dozen of Coat buttons made of silver Wire and Thread gilt, val. 50 s. 7 dozen of great Buttons made of silver Wire and Thread gilt val. 16 l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340424-44-victim321" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cornthwaite 
                        <interp inst="t17340424-44-victim321" type="surname" value="Cornthwaite"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340424-44-victim321" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340424-44-victim321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-44-off190 t17340424-44-victim321"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17340424-44-cd191" type="crimeDate">Jan. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-44-off190 t17340424-44-cd191"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-44-person322">
                  William 
                  Cornthwaite 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person322" type="surname" value="Cornthwaite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person322" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17340424-44-viclabel192" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-44-victim321 t17340424-44-viclabel192"></join> by Trade, and the Prisoner is my <rs id="t17340424-44-deflabel193" type="occupation">Book-keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-44-defend319 t17340424-44-deflabel193"></join>, - I allow him 50 l. a year, On Friday-evening March 22. 
               <persName id="t17340424-44-person323">
                  James 
                  Trutor 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person323" type="surname" value="Trutor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person323" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Button-maker whom I deal with, came to me and said, he believ'd I had a Servant who is a great Rogue. Why so, says I, Because, says, he an old Man offer'd to sell me some Buttons for 3 s. and 6 d. a Dozen, which are worth 7 s. and 6 d. and I believe they were yours, because your Man D - came to me in August last, and shew'd me a Pattern of Buttons, and said, that such an old Man had got a Parcel to sell, and they would come cheap; and the old Man came accordingly, and I bought them. And the old Man coming to Day with more, I began to be suspicious, and so appointed him to come again to Morrow, at 2 a-Clock. This old Man is 
               <persName id="t17340424-44-person324">
                  Thomas 
                  Carver 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person324" type="surname" value="Carver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person324" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner's Father-in-law; he came at the time appointed, and was carry'd before Justice Deveil. I know the Buttons and Bags - Carver said, at first, that he had them from a Shop keeper in Brentford; but he deny'd that again and would not own where he had them, 'till the Prisoner came, and then said, he never saw the Buttons before.</p>
               <p>Court. What Carver said of the Prisoner is no Evidence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever miss any Buttons? And when?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwaite. On this Information I examin'd narrowly, and mist these and other Parcels - Indeed I had suspected the Prisoner some time before. For I had a Box in which I keep nothing but Gold and Silver-lace, and I trusted no body with the Key but the Prisoner. I look'd into this Box one day, and found a Gross of Gold Thread Buttons which I never put there. This made me suspect, that he had a design to carry them off. I ask'd him how they came there. He seem'd confus'd and made me no satisfactory Answer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever enquire after what you mist?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwaite. Yes; I have often enquir'd of you, but not of my Workmen.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. But did you ever tax me with wronging you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwait. No; for tho' I had long been jealous of you, I had no business to let you know it, because I wanted to make a Discovery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you miss that Gross before you found them in the Lace-box ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwaite. I can't say that I did, but when I found them, I knew they were taken <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173404240020"></xptr> out of my Drawers.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Is not that a Publick Drawer your Shop, where 30 Men are at Work.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwaite. Yes; I keep a Quantity there in readiness, if my Men should want any when I am out of the way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you order me to clear that open Drawer, and put the Buttons in the Lace-box to keep them from Tarnishing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwaite. I have order'd you to that Drawer, but not to put the Buttons the Box</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you take a Parcel of French Buttons out, and bid me put them by, and give me some odd Buttons to put into the Drawer?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cornthwite. I don't remember any such Circumstance, Mr. D -</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-44-person325">
                  James 
                  Trutor 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person325" type="surname" value="Trutor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person325" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know dis Man de Preeonar, dat he come to me last August, and ay, dat his Friend take some Buttong for a Debt, and he shew me de Pattern, and if I vill buy dem, his Friend dat vas an old Man vill come to Morrow. I ask a him, for vat he no sell dem to him Master. He say as he no care for dat. So dis Old Man came vid 12 Dozen of de Silver Coat Buttong, and 12 Dozen of de Silver Breast, and I give him 30 s. for dem. And he came again vid more de 22 of March; but I bid him come to Morrow, vish he did, and bring 10 Dozen of de Silver Coat, and 10 Dozen of de Silver Breast, and 5 Dozen de Gold Coat, and 5 Dozen de Gold Breast; and den I take him up vid de Coonstauble, and carry him before de Shustice, and dare he say dat he have dem from Brentford - And von Time in October. I bring mine Bill dat came to 24 l. to Mr. Cornthwaite, and de Presonar vas dare alone, and he avize me to put down 8 l. more into de Bill -</p>
               <p>Court. You must not proceed thus - 'Tis going into another Fact.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire he may be heard as to that, because it will shew the Falsehood of -</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The Prisoner recommended this Man to me, and now he would impeach his Character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I tell you that the Old Man was my Friend?</p>
               <p>Trutor. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What are you?</p>
               <p>Trutor. A Gold and Silver Buttong Maker. You know dat vary vell - vy you ask me den?</p>
               <p>Prisoner to the Prosecutor. Have not you trusted me with 2 or 300 l. at a Time, and particularly when you have been out of Town?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I may have trusted so much in your Hands, but not when I went out of Town.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not I always very sober and industrious.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Sober you were; but I can't commend your Industry; for you were very heedless, Mr. D -</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-44-person326">
                  George 
                  Verney 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person326" type="surname" value="Verney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person326" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I sold these Buttons to Mr. Cornthwaite; I know they are of my Making, and I can swear to the Bags.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Might not another Man make such Work.</p>
               <p>Varney. I know my own Work in particular.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. But have you sold none of the same Sort to other Persons?</p>
               <p>Varney. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Has not my Master told you, that I was a very honest Man?</p>
               <p>Varney. I don't remember - but if he did it, it is a good while ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-44-person327">
                  James 
                  Mailbet 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person327" type="surname" value="Mailbet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person327" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Old Man equivocated a good while before the Justice, and at last declared that he had the Goods of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Court. That's not Evidence.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I found some of my Lace on the Prisoner's Wife's Shoes.</p>
               <p>Court. That's not in the Indictment - Where is this Old Man Carver?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I call'd at his Lodging, and was told he was gone in the Country.</p>
               <p>Just. Deveil. I took his Inf rmation on Oath, and he sign'd it, and I bound him in 40 l. to appear here and give Evidence.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I would fain have had him secur'd, and offer'd Mr. De Veil 20,000 l. Security to <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173404240021"></xptr> indemnify him; but I found he could not do it.</p>
               <p>Court. Call 
               <persName id="t17340424-44-person328">
                  Thomas 
                  Carver 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person328" type="surname" value="Carver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person328" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Officer. 
               <persName id="t17340424-44-person329">
                  Thomas 
                  Carver 
               <interp inst="t17340424-44-person329" type="surname" value="Carver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person329" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ! Come forth, and give Evidence against Jacob D - or you forfeit your Recognizance. - Nobody Answers.</p>
               <p>Court. Record his Default - It seems to cast a Reflection on the Prisoner, that his Father-in-Law chuses to forfeit 40 l. rather than appear.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have put my Master in a Method of marking each Piece, and deducting what was cut off, to prevent his Servants from wronging him - He never pretended he had lost any Thing, till I was taken up - I submitted to the low Drudgery of cleaning out his Drawers, with no other Design, than to get an Insight into his Business, which I intended to set up for my Self; and when he heard of it, he shew'd his ill Will in aspersing and bespattering my Character.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Did you intend to turn Taylor? - My Lord he is not capable of it. He was brought up a Mercer; and I never heard a Word of his having such a Design before he was sent to Newgate-He has endeavour'd to throw an Imputation of Malice upon me; but -</p>
               <p>Court. You need not give your self any trouble about that, for he has made no such thing appear.</p>
               <p>The Reverend Mr. Morgan. I am desired to appear, and do that Justice to the Prisoner's Character as I believe he deserves. I have known him several Years. All his Acquaintance have represented his Character in a favourable Light. So far as my Station and Function can be supposed to have an Insight into a Man's Character, whom I have had a long Intimacy with, I believe him to be an honest Man, and I believe all his Acquaintance have the same Opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Truby. I served him with Wine when he kept a Coffee-house, and he paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>Mr. Newel. I lived with him at Mr. Langley's on Ludgate-Hill, and he behav'd well there.</p>
               <p>Mr. Herbert. He was my Apprentice, and served me 7 Years faithfully. He has been gone from me 7 or 8 Years, and I have heard nothing amiss of him since.</p>
               <p>Threeor four Witnesses gave him a good Character. The Jury <rs id="t17340424-44-verdict194" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340424-44-verdict194" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
