<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380518-1">
               <interp inst="t17380518-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-1" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-1" type="date" value="17380518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-defend30 t17380518-1-off2 t17380518-1-verdict7"></join>
         
               <p>1. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Wall 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-defend30" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380518-1-defloc1">St. Paul Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Paul Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-defend30 t17380518-1-defloc1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380518-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 39 Guineas, the Money of 
                     <persName id="t17380518-1-victim31" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17380518-1-viclabel3" type="occupation">Mr.</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-victim31 t17380518-1-viclabel3"></join> Lane<interp inst="t17380518-1-victim31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-off2 t17380518-1-victim31"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , in his Dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380518-1-cd4" type="crimeDate">May 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-off2 t17380518-1-cd4"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lane. On Saturday Se'nnight last I went out about some Business, from my House in <placeName id="t17380518-1-crimeloc5">Bow-street Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-1-crimeloc5" type="placeName" value="Bow-street Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-1-crimeloc5" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-off2 t17380518-1-crimeloc5"></join>; in the Evening I return'd Home, and missed 39 Guineas, which I had left in my Bureau. The next Day, (Sunday) the Prisoner who was then my <rs id="t17380518-1-deflabel6" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-defend30 t17380518-1-deflabel6"></join>, went out, and not coming Home all Day, I began to suspect he had taken the Money. In the Evening the Man who keeps the Black-Horse Ale-house in the same Street, came and told me the Prisoner was at his House; that he came thither in a Hackney Coach, and had chang'd a Guinea to treat the Coachman and a Soldier who were drinking with him. When he came Home, I sent for Mr. Morris the Constable, who search'd him, and in my Presence took a Guinea out of his Shoe. He did not confess any Thing at this Time; but when he was before Colonel Deveil, he own'd he took the Money out of my Bureau; that he had bought a Gold Watch, which cost him 13 Guineas and a half; that he had spent some of the Money, and the rest was hid with the Gold Watch in a Vacuity between the Bricks, in the Necessary House at the Black-Horse; and according to his Confession, the Gold Watch and 13 Guineas were found there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-1-person32">
                  Thomas 
                  Hancock 
               <interp inst="t17380518-1-person32" type="surname" value="Hancock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person32" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Soldier. I live in St. Anns Westminster. On the 7th of this Month, about 7 o'Clock in the Evening, the Prisoner sent for me to drink with him; while I was in his Company he pull'd out a Gold Watch, I told him he had got a very fine Watch. Yes, says he, I thank God. I am in a good Way of living now. When the Reckoning came to be paid, he pull'd out a Guinea, and chang'd it; and the Landlord seeing he had a Charge of Money about him, perswaded him to go Home. All this Time there was a Hackney Coach waiting for him at the Door, and as he had this Charge about him, I went into the Coach with him, and we rode to Westminster-Abbey, where he treated the Coachman and I with another Pot of Beer. He told me, that neither the Money nor the Watch were his own; and I asked him how he could make bold<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180003"></xptr> with what was not his own? I hope, says I, all's well; yes, yes, says he, all's well, I know I must make it good again. From Westminster we rode to the Black-Horse in Bow Street, where he treated us again with Beer, and paid the Coachman half a Guinea for his Days Work. After the Coach was gone, he asked me to smoak a Pipe with him, and while I was filling one, Mr. Lane's Servant came in, and I went out of the Prisoner's Company. He had about 12 or 14 Guineas in his Pocket when he paid the Coachman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-1-person33">
                  John 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17380518-1-person33" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. On Sunday was Se'ennight in the Evening I took Charge of the Prisoner, and found a Guinea in one of his Shoes. Upon which he was carried before Mr. Deveil, and charg'd with this Robbery. At first he would confess nothing, so he was committed for farther Examination; but when he was brought before Mr. Deveil the second Time, he told us where he had hid part of the Money and the Watch, and according to his Direction, I found 13 Guineas, a Six-pence, and a Penny, and the Gold Watch, behind some Bricks under the Seat in the Necessary House, at the Black-Horse in Bow-Street He acknowledged at this Time it was his Master's Money, and that he had bought the Watch with part of it. He confessed the whole again on the Thursday following, and that he took the Money out of Mr. Lane's Scrutore.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-1-person34">
                  Luke 
                  Hollis 
               <interp inst="t17380518-1-person34" type="surname" value="Hollis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person34" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry'd the Prisoner that Day from Place to Place, and I observ'd he was full of Money, for as I was driving along, he call'd out, - stop, stop Coachman; I got down to see what he wanted, and found him picking up Gold from the Bottom of the Coach.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in Liquor, and don't remember any Thing of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lane. He had been bottling some Ale that Saturday, if that Circumstance will be any Relief to him. The Jury found him <rs id="t17380518-1-verdict7" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-verdict7" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380518-1-punish8" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-1-punish8" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-1-defend30 t17380518-1-punish8"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
