<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-6">
               <interp inst="t17380222-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-6" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-6" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-6-off35-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-6-defend91 t17380222-6-off35 t17380222-6-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>7 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-6-defend91" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Jackson 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-6-defend91" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-defend91" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-defend91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380222-6-defloc34">St. George's Hanover-Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-6-defloc34" type="placeName" value="St. George's Hanover-Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-6-defloc34" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-6-defend91 t17380222-6-defloc34"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-6-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-6-victim93" type="victimName">
                           Catherine 
                           Peterson 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-6-victim93" type="surname" value="Peterson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-6-victim93" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-6-victim93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-6-off35 t17380222-6-victim93"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and putting her in Fear, &amp;c. in a certain Field and open Place near the King's Highway,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220008"></xptr> and taking from her a silk Purse, value 6 d. a silver Thimble, value 2 s. a silk Pincushion, value 1 d. and 4 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-6-cd36" type="crimeDate">Feb 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-6-off35 t17380222-6-cd36"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Peterson. I live at <placeName id="t17380222-6-crimeloc37">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-6-crimeloc37" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-6-crimeloc37" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-6-off35 t17380222-6-crimeloc37"></join>. On the 18th of Feb. I was going Home from London, in the Evening about three quarters of an Hour after 7. In the first Field I met 3 Men, I took them to be working People, so I went on to the second, and there the Prisoner came up to me, and clapp'd this Knife to my Breast, and with Oaths demanded my Money. I saw no Pistol, therefore I thought I might defend my self against his Knife, till some body should come up. I told him I had no Money; Why then, - d - mn you give me your Pocket, or I'll kill you. I bid him kill me if he dar'd, - I would not give him my Pocket. Then I will kill you, said he, and up he threw my Hoop, and thrust at me with this Knife; - I thought he had run it into my Guts, but I happen'd to have this Book in my Pocket, and the Knife run against that. I scream'd out, - Help! help! for God's Sake help! but he lugg'd me down, and tore my Pocket in this Manner; I continu'd crying out, till I heard some Voices call out, - what's the Matter? I cry'd, - for God's sake stop, for I am robb'd. When he had taken what I had about me, he ran away, I follow'd him, and 3 Men call'd out to me, - don't be 'frighted Madam, we have got him. They had stopp'd him and brought him up to me; I knew him again, for I have had a perfect Idea of him ever since, and I went with them to the Spot of Ground where he attack'd me, and there we found my Pincushion, some of my Papers, and the Knife that he threat'ned me with. The Moon shone very bright, and I knew both the Knife and the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I might perhaps meet her, but not to know her in any Particular; I never laid Hands on her.</p>
               <p>Peterson. I don't know what he calls laying Hands on me, but he jump'd out of a Ditch and tore me down upon the Ground; I lay with one Hand upon the Ground, and with the other I defended my self against his Knife. When he had robb'd me he ran away; I heard him run, and he was not out of my hearing when these Men took him. I saw him as plain when he committed the Fact as I do now; I took Notice of his Face, and of his Wig, and remember him particularly. A Woman came to me Yesterday, who said she was his Wife, and begg'd I would not prosecute him; or if I did, she desired me to say, I might be mistaken in the Person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-6-person94">
                  Edward 
                  Meredith 
               <interp inst="t17380222-6-person94" type="surname" value="Meredith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person94" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Three of us were coming from the Black-Lyon at Chelsea, about a quarter before 8, and in the next Field to the King's Head near the Park, we heard a Woman cry, - pray don't murder me! - for God's Sake don't murder me! We cry'd out, Help at Hand, - Help at Hand; immediately the Prisoner came running full Speed, and I ran after him and caught him. He trembled and quak'd, and when we asked him what the Matter was, he told me there was only a Disturbance between a Man and his Wife. We brought him back to the Gentlewoman, who was very much 'frighted; she knew him again, and as we were carrying him before a Justice, he desir'd me to let him go, for then he could get clear off. I did not stay to look at the Things that were found, I had enough to do to keep the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-6-person95">
                  Francis 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17380222-6-person95" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person95" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Constable. The three Men who took the Prisoner, brought him to my House, and this Gentlewoman with them, she was very much frighted, and shew'd me her Pocket; I took Charge of the Prisoner, and carry'd him before Justice Ellis. The Gentlewoman charged him with having robb'd her in the first Field, of 4 s. and some other, Things, and produced her Pocket which he had torn down in this Manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-6-person96">
                  James 
                  Hayes 
               <interp inst="t17380222-6-person96" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person96" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and my two Friends had been walking that Afternoon to Chelsea. We stopp'd at Mr. Holloway's House, the Black Lyon at Chelsea, and we drank Part of five Pots of Beer, and set out for London, about a Quarter after Eight. After we had pass'd the King's-Head Alehouse, we heard the Cry, for God's sake have Mercy; we call'd out, Help at Hand, and immediately the Gentlewoman cry'd out, stop Thief; the Man ran as fast as he could, and the first Witness caught him by one Arm, and I, by the other. We asked him what was the Matter, and he told us some People were quarrelling, and he was running from them. He was very unwilling to go back with us to the Gentlewoman, but we logg'd him along to her, and she told us he had robb'd her and threaten'd her Life; that he presented a Penknife to her Breast, and told her if she would not deliver her Money, she was a dead Woman that Moment. We hearing this, and seeing the torn Pocket, the Book, the Knife, and the other Things upon the Ground, we carry'd the Prisoner to the Constable's House. The Prisoner when he was examined did not own the Knife.</p>
               <p>- Harvey speak to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Defence. I solemnly declare I never was guilty; they swear in spight against me, because I had a Law Suit with the Man of the House, where they Lodge. When they took me, I did desire them<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220009"></xptr> to let me go, because I am 50 l. in debt, and there's an Execution out against me; and I thought if I should be confin'd for this, I should never get out of Goal again.</p>
               <p>- Watkins, a Taylor (with whom the Prisoner had work'd about 3 three Years) gave him an extraordinary good Character.</p>
               <p>Two other Persons appear'd to his Character.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17380222-6-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-6-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
