<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-41">
               <interp inst="t17361208-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-41" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-41" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-41-off231-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-defend373 t17361208-41-off231 t17361208-41-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>58. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-41-defend373" type="defendantName">
                     Gilbert
                      Fruer, otherwise <rs id="t17361208-41-alias-10" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-defend373 t17361208-41-alias-10"></join>Gill</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-defend373" type="surname" value="Fruer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-defend373" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-defend373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361208-41-off231" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-off231" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-off231" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-41-victim375" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Short 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-41-victim375" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-41-victim375" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-41-victim375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-off231 t17361208-41-victim375"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in an open Field near the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Hat value 12 d. a Cloath Coat value 10 s. a Linnen Shirt value 3 s. a Pair of Leather Breeches value 3 s. a Pair of Shoes value 2 s. a Knife value 2 d a Foot Rule value 6 d. a Silver Stud value 6 d. and 14 d. Half-penny in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17361208-41-cd232" type="crimeDate">Nov. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-off231 t17361208-41-cd232"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-41-person376">
                  Benjamin 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person376" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person376" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . November 23 I was coming from <placeName id="t17361208-41-crimeloc233">Highgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-41-crimeloc233" type="placeName" value="Highgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-41-crimeloc233" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-off231 t17361208-41-crimeloc233"></join>, and between the Half Way-House and <placeName id="t17361208-41-crimeloc234">Tottenham Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-41-crimeloc234" type="placeName" value="Tottenham Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-41-crimeloc234" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-off231 t17361208-41-crimeloc234"></join>, I was met in the Foot-way, between five and six in the Evening, by two Men, one of them laid fast hold of my Shoulder, and the other took me by the Right Arm; they carried me out of the Path as far as Mr. Lewis's Field, and under a Hedge I submitted to them. They demanded my Money and my Watch, I told them they should have what I had got, if they would not use me ill. The Man that seiz'd my Right Arm, pulled out a Pistol and held it to me while the Prisoner rifled me. He pulled off my Coat, - 'twas a Blue cap'd Coat, - and my Shirt, and my Breeches from my Backside, and my Shoes from my Feet: Then they made me untie my Garters (which were these) and I gave them to him; these won't do, says he, so he pulled off his own (which were these.) When they had pulled off my Shirt, my Shoes, and my Breeches, they ty'd my Hands together with these Garters behind me; the Prisoner ty'd me and the other stood over me with a Pistol; after that they pulled up my Left Leg behind me, and ty'd it very hard to my Hands: I had a Silk Handkerchief about my Neck which the Prisoner took off and put into his Pocket; then he took this out of his own, and ty'd it very close over my Mouth. I had 2 s. and Three Half-pence about me, and they took it all from me; there was a Pair of Silver Studs in my Sleeves, one of them they took away in the Shirt, and the other dropt on the Ground. After they had bound me, they desired me to be quiet (and indeed I could not be otherwise they had tied me so fast) telling me, the first Man they took they would come and release<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080027"></xptr> me; so away they went and left me. I lay near an Hour in this Condition, - the Wind blue very cold, and I had no Breeches nor Shirt; I struggled to get loose, and at last broke the Garter that ty'd up my Leg. I am positive the Prisoner is the Man that bound me, and left me in a large deep Ditch all done over (overgrown) with Bushes. 'Twas a Star-light Night, and but a little Duskish: I took what Remark I could of the Prisoner all the Way he carry'd me. He has a very remarkable Voice, speaks very hoarse, and Stammers.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at another Place from Four 'till Nine, that Evening.</p>
               <p>Short. When I got loose, I was afraid to go the Way I was brought, so I made over a Field or two, and came to an Alehouse, the Sign of the Queen's Head and Artichoak: My Hands were still ty'd, so I shov'd the Door with my Foot, 'tis a Sash Door - half Glass, and thro' the Glass I saw a Neighbour; but a little Boy coming to the Door, and seeing me in this frightful Condition, instead of opening the Door, he ran away surpriz'd at the Sight of me; but the Neighbour coming to the Door, he let me in; 'twas Mr. Girdler, the Farrier, he came to the Door and let me in; then the first thing he did, was to untie my Mouth and my Hands, then he got me some Relief, warm'd me some Beer, and sent three or four Men home with me, with Candles and Lanthorns. The next Morning I was at St. Giles's Pound, and Mr. Goddard at the Crown, call'd to me, - Ben, says he, you had a bad Time on't; how did you come off? I told him, I was in a miserable Condition last Night, and let him know what I had lost; he took it down in Writing, and I described the Prisoner to him, - a tall Man, with a thick hoarse Voice, and he found him out and took him: He got a Constable, and went out upon the Search after him; I was out with them my self one Night, but he was taken by them without me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-41-person377">
                  John 
                  Girdler 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person377" type="surname" value="Girdler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing by the Fire-side, at the Queen's-Head and Artichoak, Nov. 23, and I heard something knock at the Door; a little Boy went to the Door, but coming back frighted, I stepp'd to see what was the Matter; and the Man said (as plain as he could speak) Mr Girdler, I am glad to see you; I have been robb'd. I let him come in and unty'd his Mouth. He look'd very strange and frightful, lying so long in the Cold, and he had only a thin Coat on, no Shirt, no Breeches, nor Shoes; his Hands were ty'd very hard behind him, and when I had loosen'd them, they were so benumm'd, that he could scarce bring them forward. He told me he had been robb'd in Mr. Lewis's Field by two Men. I asked him if he should know either of them again. He said he should know one of them, - the tall Man, he should know by his Voice. Some of my Servants would have gone out directly, in search of the Men; but I said, they won't stay to be sure in the Place where they committed the Fact; and we had no Arms. After I had warm'd some Drink, and had given it him, I got him a Pair of Shoes, and three of my Men went home with him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goddard. I had heard that Mr. Short had been robb'd, and seeing him the next Morning, I call'd to him to know how he had far'd. He told me; and I took down an Account of what he had lost, and a Description of the Person. He said he had been robb'd by two Men, one a middle-siz'd Man, the other a tall Man, with such a very hoarse Voice, that he was sure he could remember him again particularly. I advis'd him to come again to me in the Evening, and I sent for Griffiths, and some more Friends, and we went out into the Fields: We divided our selves, but kept within Call. That Night we did nothing; and the next Morning Mr. Lewis, the Cow-keeper, call'd upon me, to know if we had not been in the Fields last Night: I told him Yes, we were searching after the Rogues, and we should be glad if we could find them. Says he, if you'll go up to my Farm at Kentish-Town, there's a Barn, which two or three Fellows had been observ'd to frequent, and to go into, and out of, arm'd, and at Two or Three o'Clock in the Morning. I did not know the Method of these Barns in the Night, so I and my Friends went to take a View of them the Day before, that we might know how to get off if we were over-power'd. We took a View of several Barns, and as we came home, we call'd upon a Constable at Kentish-Town, and were informed there was a House in the Town which was frequented by People of ill Fame: We went to this House, ('tis the Sign of Whittington and his Cat) about Six o'Clock; and I saw the Prisoner at the Bar sitting by the Fire, cutting Apples. I took a good View of him, and so did the rest of us; and imagining he answered the Description which Mr. Short had given me of him, I wanted to hear him speak, so I went up to the Fire-Side, but immediately got up, and without speaking a Word, was going out of the House: I faced him, and told him he must not be gone, I had a Mind to hear him speak: He asked me what Reason I had to prevent his going out; I told him I was an Officer, and had some Reason to detain<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080028"></xptr> him: I am informed, says I, that you have Run-Goods in your Custody, and I must seize them. He spoke pretty largely, and was provoked; but under this Pretence we searched the House. After we had talked to him some time, we all concluded he was the Man; so we brought him to my House, and sent for Mr Short, and before I let him see our Man, I told him, we had taken one that answer'd the Description he had given me; but for God's Sake take care what you do; don't deceive your self and me too: Take a View of the Man, and you shall hear him speak; and I will call you out again, and you shall tell me what you think of him. Mr. Short went into the Room to him, and staid some time; when he came out again, says he, Mr. Goddard, I can swear positively that is the Man that robb'd me: Justice De Veil hear him say the same. After this, Mr. Short desired to see the Prisoner's Garters; he let us see them: I ask'd him where he bought them; he said, he could not tell; but the Prosecutor knew them again, and before Justice De Veil, declared he remembered them again, and that he could swear to his Voice, for ever since he had been robb'd it had rung in his Ears, and terrify'd him; and the more he heard him speak, the more confident he was that the Prisoner was the Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I so hoarse as I am now?</p>
               <p>Goddard. I think not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-41-person378">
                  Owen 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person378" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person378" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for by Mr. Goddard, to whom Short had given the Description; and having heard how barbarously the Man had been used, I went along with them, (being an Officer) as Mr. Goddard has related. We searched the Barns that Mr. Lewis directed us to, and then we went to Mr. Wiblin's, who keeps the White-Horse at Kentish-Town, and we described the Man we were in search of, to him: He could give us no Account of him; but he and a Neighbour coming a little way over the Fields, they informed us that the Whittington and Cat was a House which was suspected of harbouring such Sort of People, we went there and found this Man, and thinking he answered the Description, we apprehended him.</p>
               <p>Q. After you brought him to Town, and Short had seen him, what pass'd then?</p>
               <p>Griffiths. Short said he was positive to the Man, and he told the Prisoner, he had not been so good as his Word; for, says he, you promis'd the next Man you took, you would come and release me; but you did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What Answer did the Prisoner make?</p>
               <p>Griffiths. He said we might do as we would; he had made no Confession.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in Eagle-street, behind the Blue-Boar-Inn in Holbourn, between Three and Four o'Clock in the Afternoon, and from thence I went to Mr. Upton's in Tower-street, the upper End of Mon-mouth-street, and I went with him to the Three-Tun Alehouse, and was there with six People, and never stirr'd out of the House 'till Nine.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Witnesses were examin'd apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-41-person379">
                  Richard 
                  Upton 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person379" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person379" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner, - may be two Years, up and down: He was an Acquaintance of my Journeyman. I am a Peruke-maker, and I live at the Corner of Tower-street, the upper End of Monmouth-street. I have kept a Shop there these seven Years.</p>
               <p>Q. In November last was the Prisoner in your Company?</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes; he came an Hour before dark, and I shav'd him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to be often at your House, or has he been there only once or twice?</p>
               <p>Upton I can't say I saw him, - but in that Month: It was last Tuesday was a Fortnight, the 23d of November.</p>
               <p>Q. When he was shav'd what did you do then?</p>
               <p>Upton. After he was shav'd, he stay'd some Time, and talk'd; and we went to a Publick House, with two more; he was at the Publick House, and at my House 'till almost Nine. As I am upon Oath, I am safe; - he came to my Shop a little after Four; - between Four and Five, and he staid at my Shop the best Part of an Hour, and then we went to the Ale-house, the Corner of Lombard Court in the same Street, - to one Mrs. Palmer's, in Tower-street, the Corner of Lombard-Court, and he staid at the Ale-house 'till between Eight and Nine.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were you in Company?</p>
               <p>Upton. Three besides my self: Four in all; - with others coming in and out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did those Three or Four stay with you all the Time, 'till Eight or Nine?</p>
               <p>Upton. Two of them went from the Shop with me; and one came to us afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were they that went from the Shop with you?</p>
               <p>Upton. 
               <persName id="t17361208-41-person380">
                  Tom 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person380" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person380" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17361208-41-person381">
                  George 
                  Dod 
               <interp inst="t17361208-41-person381" type="surname" value="Dod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person381" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Strock came to the Ale-house to us, and was with us all the Time.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080029"></xptr>Q. Who went from the Ale-house with you?</p>
               <p>Upton. Davis and Dod, went from the Ale-house with me.</p>
               <p>Q. I would have you speak to be understood: Who went with the Prisoner and you to the Alehouse?</p>
               <p>Upton. Strock and Davis went with him and me, and George Dod came to us afterwards, and we Four staid together.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you there, before Dod came to you?</p>
               <p>Upton. I met him going in along with us.</p>
               <p>Q. And so you Four were in Company together 'till Nine o'Clock?</p>
               <p>Upton Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And no Body else?</p>
               <p>Upton. Not to stay the whole Time: We staid there 'till between Eight and Nine, I believe 'till Nine, - but between Eight and Nine.</p>
               <p>Q. How come you to remember so particularly the Day of the Month, and the Day of the Week? You say he had not been there a great while before.</p>
               <p>Upton. If he had come often, I should not have remember'd the Day. He was afterwards taken before a Justice, and I was there, knowing him to be wrongfully accused.</p>
               <p>Q. And did not you hear then, the Day of the Week, or the Month mention'd, on which this Robbery was committed?</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes; but I did not observe it, nor remember it at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to take Notice of that, when you could remember what was said and done at your House?</p>
               <p>Upton. I could remember that by my daily Work.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at Work your self that Day?</p>
               <p>Upton. No, I was not at Work my self: there was weaving and mounting (I believe) going forwards. I shav'd the Prisoner; and I shav'd other Customers, and might stand still sometimes. Strock and Dod were weaving at the same Time. Sometimes they sit down for a Day's Work, or a Week's, as I have Occasion for them. I employed them both at that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. What Hour do they usually leave Work?</p>
               <p>Upton. They were not regular Journeymen by the Week; but sometimes they do a Job for me, and I pay them for it, ^ they were not at Work for Wages then, they only sat down to help me, and I gave them Victuals and Drink.</p>
               <p>^ See Dod's Evidence. p. 31</p>
               <p>Q. Had they been at Work for you in the beginning of the Day?</p>
               <p>Upton. The best Part of the Day they had, and Strock the best Part of the Week.</p>
               <p>Q. And did they work for nothing?</p>
               <p>Upton. I satisfied them one Way or other, at this Time they were to stand to my Generosity; there's a Reckoning between Strock and I, and I shall pay him what I agreed for.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you use to take your Journeymen from your Work and carry them to the Ale-house?</p>
               <p>Upton. 'Tis not to my Credit to do so, but I often have; especially when I meet with a Friend.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you acquainted with the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes; Dod brought him acquainted with me, he call'd upon him as he was at Work.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner a <rs id="t17361208-41-deflabel235" type="occupation">Peruke-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-defend373 t17361208-41-deflabel235"></join> .</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes, by Trade; as I have been informed by Dod. He has wove at my Shop, but I paid him nothing for it.</p>
               <p>Q. And did he do it for his Diversion?</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes; as any Body else may do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any Memorandum of the Day of the Month?</p>
               <p>Upton. Yes, I set it down in my Book, that I might be safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you set it down in your Book the Day he was at your Shop?</p>
               <p>Upton. No; - I know the Day by other Things I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the Prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Upton. I don't know; he came to me as a Stranger, and was a Stranger to me, but I have drank with him several Times.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Week was the 23d of November?</p>
               <p>Upton. I don't remember that.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you have drank with him several Times; can you remember any other Time, but this 23d of November?</p>
               <p>Upton. No; I cannot say I do. I did not think I should have had any Occasion to have taken Notice of any Thing farther; as he was call'd in Question soon after.</p>
               <p>Q. Who attended you at the Ale-house?</p>
               <p>Upton. Mrs. Palmer, she brought some of the Liquor, I can't say all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She brought us all the Liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Reckoning come to?</p>
               <p>Upton. A Shilling. I had no Money, so the Prisoner paid all: when we Brothers of the Trade<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080030"></xptr> meet, they that have most Money pay all.</p>
               <p>- Strock. I am a Peruke Maker; I was at Work at Mr. Upton's, -</p>
               <p>Q. And how are you employ'd? By the Day, or by the Piece, or how?</p>
               <p>Strock. I am employ'd by the Week, - at so much a Week. ^ I was employed at this very Time by the Week.</p>
               <p>^ See Upton's Evidence, p. 28.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this Time?</p>
               <p>Strock. The 2d of November, and all that Week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stay with him no longer?</p>
               <p>Strock. I worked Two Days with him last Week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you work with him about the middle, or the latter End of November?</p>
               <p>Strock. I worked with him that Week, and Two Days after that; and then I was employ'd by another Master; this was the Beginning of November. I worked with him no more than that Week, and Two Days last Week: then I was sent for by a Master in Bond-Street to do other Work.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the Days last Week, on which you work'd?</p>
               <p>Strock. Monday and Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. What Days of the Month were they?</p>
               <p>Strock. I cannot tell; but 'twas Monday and Tuesday last Week.</p>
               <p>Q. So when you was at work with Upton you saw the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Strock. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What, one of these Two last Days you worked with Upton?</p>
               <p>Strock. No, 'twas on the 3d of November that the Prisoner came to our Shop, and my Master shav'd him: 'twas on a Tuesday, and he complain'd his Face was sore, and desired a good Razor; after he was shav'd he staid half an Hour. Then he desired my Master to go and drink a Mug of Beer with him at the Three-Tuns, the Corner of Lombard-Court; so my Master and another young Man who was in the Shop went with him, and he desired me to go too.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not this above a Month ago?</p>
               <p>Strock. No; 'tis but a Fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it might be Monday or Tuesday last was a Month?</p>
               <p>Strock. No; it was a Fortnight ago, it was the 23d of November, - I believe it was the 24th of November when I came to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect your self; cannot you be certain?</p>
               <p>Strock. I came to work last Monday Fortnight, and the Prisoner came to be shav'd the next Day, the 23d. I never saw him but once before in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he your Master's Acquaintance or yours?</p>
               <p>Strock. He was my Master's Acquaintance, and none of mine; I did not go with them.</p>
               <p>Q. What, did not you go with them last Tuesday was Fortnight?</p>
               <p>Strock. - Yes, - the 23d.</p>
               <p>Q. Aye, - the 23d, you can remember pretty well; but who went with the Prisoner and your Master?</p>
               <p>Strock. Tom. Davis; and we staid 'till past Eight. I don't know what the Reckoning came to, - we had but Four full Pots, and (I believe) the Prisoner treated.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, you had but four Pots of Beer; do you go so often to the Ale-house, and yet not know what four Pots of Beer come to?</p>
               <p>Strock. I don't know. I believe a Shilling. I never saw him but once before.</p>
               <p>Q. How come you to remember the Day so particularly?</p>
               <p>Strock. Because I was before the Justice with him, when he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Day of the Month mentioned there?</p>
               <p>Strock. No; but he sent for my Master, and because I work'd there, therefore I remember'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. You said you were employ'd by the Week; has your Master paid you for the Work you did then?</p>
               <p>Strock. No; he said he would pay me when he got Money. - I got a Crown from him.</p>
               <p>Q. What! for Two Days Work?</p>
               <p>Tom. Davis. I know the Prisoner; I have seen him several and several Times at Upton's Shop. He came last Tuesday was a Fortnight to be shav'd; he staid better than half an Hour, and I shav'd Two or Three more, while he was there There was Strock and Upton, and one Harris a Rabbit Merchant, and another Man in the Shop. After he was shav'd, he said he would give Upton a Pot of Beer; he was a slender Acquaintance of my Master Upton's, - I had not seen him there before for a great while. I was there, helping him to make a Peruke.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you to be paid for your Work?</p>
               <p>Davis. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Upton go with the Prisoner to the Ale-house?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080031"></xptr>Davis. No, I went with him, and Upton followed by himself, and Strock came in afterwards; we left him at work in the Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else came into your Company?</p>
               <p>Davis. George Dod came to us, but he came from another Place where he had been at work, - from one Mr. Green's.</p>
               <p>Q. How came Dod into your Company?</p>
               <p>Davis. While we were drinking I went out for Oysters for the Prisoners, and I met Dod, and told him that Gill was at an Ale-house; so he went in with me, and we all staid together till almost Nine o'Clock; we had four Pots; I had no Money, so the Prisoner paid I believe - , no, - I won't say who paid.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Reckoning come to?</p>
               <p>Davis. I can't tell, but the Landlady, and her Daughter, and another Woman, waited on us. When we parted I went to my Lodging in Earl's-Court The Prisoner was none of my Acquaintance but my Master's. The Prisoner and I went first, my Master followed us in five Minutes, and Strock came in afterwards. I had been for Oysters and was putting them in the Fire to roast, when my Master came in.</p>
               <p>Q. How many had you in Company?</p>
               <p>Davis. Four; Strock, Upton, myself, and Dod, that's four, and the Prisoner, that makes five. I never knew the Prisoner to use the Shop before; he was Upton's Acquaintance, but I have drank with him at Kentish Town, for the Night we were drinking at the Three-Tuns, he desired me to go 16 Miles beyond Hounslow, to fetch a Horse for him, and I was to pay 13 s. 6 d. I went the next Morning to Staines for the Horse, and put him up at the Queens-Head and Cross-Keys in St. Martin's-Lane; then I went to Upton's, and he directed me to the Prisoner at the Whittington and Cat in Kentish Town, and he gave me 18 d. to fetch the Horse to him; this was on Thursday, and the next Day I heard he had been taken up that very Night.</p>
               <p>Goddard Have you never been at the Whittington and Cat before?</p>
               <p>Davis. No - Oh! yes, once before.</p>
               <p>Goddard. Did you ever eat Part of a Goose there:</p>
               <p>Davis. No; it was Mutton and not Goose.</p>
               <p>George Dod. I have known the Prisoner three or four Year; he is a Peruke Maker. I was in Company with him the 23d of last Month, it was Tuesday Night, and I was going thro' the Court and met Upton with him, going to the Ale-house; I went to Upton's Shop, and they sent for me from the Shop to come to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in Upton's Shop?</p>
               <p>Dod. There was Upton's Brother and one Robert, - I don't know t'other Name, Strock and another. Tom Davis came for me, and I went with him, and after that Davis was sent out for Oysters; I was in Company when he was sent for them, and staid till he came back - I was never out of the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you did not meet Davis in the Street that Evening?</p>
               <p>Dod. No, he came for me to Upton's Shop, and I went with him, and was not out of the Room 'till we all went away. The Prisoner talked about sending Tom Davis to Hounslow for a Horse. When we parted we all came out of the House together, and we left the Prisoner in Holbourn; the rest of us parted in Long-Acre. I remember the 23d of November, because I had been sent of an Errand, and staid so long, that when I came Home my Master gave me a good Box o'th' Ear, and said he'd make me remember the 23d of November.</p>
               <p>Mrs Palmer. (the Landlady.) I live in Lombard Court at the Three-Tuns. On the 23d of November there came a Man to my House to ask for a Man who was drinking with the Prisoner; I says, he's gone out with another Gentleman. If I had come sooner, says he, I would have given him a good Kick, and have made him remember the 23d of November, and at this very Time the Prisoner was in the House; he came about Candle light and staid three Hours. The Prisoner came in first of all by himself, and said there was Company coming to him. He was there by himself a Quarter of an Hour before any one came to him. - I can't say which of them came next, but Upton, Strock, and Dod, were together.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any Body sent for to come to them from Upton's?</p>
               <p>Palmer. No, not as I know of. They had three Pots of Ale, and the Prisoner brought Brandy in his Pocket to put into it. Mr. Upton and he had been acquainted together for some Time. When I was before Justice De Veil I could not remember the Day, but now I have recollected my Memory. <rs id="t17361208-41-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17361208-41-punish237" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-41-punish237" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-41-defend373 t17361208-41-punish237"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
