<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-3">
               <interp inst="t17360721-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-3" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-3" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-3-off12-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-3-defend41 t17360721-3-off12 t17360721-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>3. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-defend41" type="defendantName">
                     Avis 
                     Nutton 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-3-defend41" type="surname" value="Nutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-defend41" type="given" value="Avis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-defend41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-3-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing twelve yards of printed Callicoe Borders for Petticoats, value 10 s. and seven yards of Cambrick, value 3 l. 10 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-3-victim43" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Wiseham 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-3-victim43" type="surname" value="Wiseham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-3-victim43" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-3-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-3-off12 t17360721-3-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , out of his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-3-cd13" type="crimeDate">April 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-3-off12 t17360721-3-cd13"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Wiseham. The Prisoner came to my Shop, on Monday, April 5, between 3 and 4 in the Afternoon. I was full of Customers, so she told me she would stay till I had served the Ladies. After they were gone, she came up to the Compter, and said she wanted some printed Borders and printed Linnen; she bid me a Trifle for what I shewed her, and asked me for a little Beer. As she appeared well dress, I took a glass Mug, and went down my self to draw her some Beer; she met me at the Top of the Cellar stairs, drank the Beer and I asked her if she would have any more she curt'sied and said, if I pleased she would. I went down again, and gave her Beer the second time, which she drank, and then went out of the Shop as fast as she could, without buying any thing, but before she went, she told me if I thought she had robbed me I might search her. I told her she appeared to me to be another sort of a Woman. As soon as she was gone I missed the Borders. They are particular Things which none in England have besides myself D - her says I to my Brother, the Bitch has stollen them; I looked out after her, but she was gone.</p>
               <p>On Wednesday she came again, I was not at Home, but my Brother came to fetch me Home. Madam, says I, your humble Servant. You are mistaken Sir says she, I have not been at your Shop before, it was my Sister, we are very much alike. She said she wanted half a yard of Linnen, but she had left the Pattern at Home, and would fetch it. Three of us followed her that we might see where she lived, but we lost her. On the Friday the Week following, she came again for some Borders, and two Women were with her, she bid me a Price, which she said she had given me for the same things before. Then she asked me, what was become of the Borders that hung up when she was there before; Madam, says I, I will make you know you have robbed me of them, and sent for a Constable; she fell on her Knees, and begged me for God's Sake not to prosecute her, if I did, I should ruin an honest Man, who had been her Husband sixteen years. Some of my Borders she had sold to Mrs. Drake of Bow, who shew'd me them, and told me, she bought them of Mrs. Nutton.</p>
               <p>The Roll I lost came from the Printer's but the Saturday before; the Cambrick was worth 4 l. 10s. - and this I never found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person44">
                  William 
                  Wiseman 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person44" type="surname" value="Wiseman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person44" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Evidence was to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person45">
                  Mary 
                  Toller 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person45" type="surname" value="Toller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person45" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person45" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can only say, the Prisoner called to see me once with two Parcels of printed Linnen; that she said, she did not know what she had got, nor the Price; but that she had got those Things for a Debt; and as she did not know what to do with them herself, she would sell them. I took them to be Robeings of Gowns.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person46">
                  Isabella 
                  Kaywood 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person46" type="surname" value="Kaywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person46" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person46" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed Toller's Evidence, but could not swear these Goods to be the same that Mr. Wiseman produced.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210004"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person47">
                  Ann 
                  Drake 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person47" type="surname" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person47" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought these Borders of the Prisoner, and they are the same that the Constable took out of my House. I had six yards in all, at one shilling a yard, which was the Price she said she gave for them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person48">
                  Thomas 
                  Wiseham 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person48" type="surname" value="Wiseham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person48" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are the same I lost.</p>
               <p>Constable. These are the very Things we found at Mrs. Drake's.</p>
               <p>Rice Price. I was charged with her when she was taken, she did fall on her Knees, begged he would not prosecute her, and offered to pay what the Things came to.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-3-person49">
                  Sarah 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person49" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person49" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person49" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17360721-3-person50">
                  Sarah 
                  Harwood 
               <interp inst="t17360721-3-person50" type="surname" value="Harwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person50" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-person50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave an Account of the Prosecutor's harsh and passionate Behaviour, when the Prisoner was seized, and spoke to her Character.</p>
               <p>Several others gave her the Character of an honest reputable Woman. <rs id="t17360721-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-verdict14" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17360721-3-punish15" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-punish15" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-3-punish15" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-3-defend41 t17360721-3-punish15"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
