<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-44">
               <interp inst="t17370420-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-44" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-44" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-44-off238-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-44-defend381 t17370420-44-off238 t17370420-44-verdict241"></join>
         
               <p>54. * 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-defend381" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-44-defend381" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-defend381" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-defend381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-44-off238" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-off238" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-off238" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing 9 Yards of White and Silver Lustring, value 6 l. and 9 Yards of Green and Silver ditto, value 6 l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-44-victim383" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Hinchliffe 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-44-victim383" type="surname" value="Hinchliffe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-44-victim383" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-44-victim383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-44-off238 t17370420-44-victim383"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in his Shop
            </rs>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17370420-44-crimeloc239">St. Bride's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-44-crimeloc239" type="placeName" value="St. Bride's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-44-crimeloc239" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-44-off238 t17370420-44-crimeloc239"></join>, <rs id="t17370420-44-cd240" type="crimeDate">April 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-44-off238 t17370420-44-cd240"></join>.</p>
               <p>* The Prisoner was indicted and sentenced for Transportation by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17370420-44-person384">
                  Mary 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person384" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person384" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in February Sessions, 1736, for robbing Mr.Davis's Shop in Cheapside. See Sessions Book, p. 75.</p>
               <p>Spencer Morris. This Woman and another, and a Man came into our Shop, to look at some brown ground Brocades; they bid Money for some Silks, which I could not take, so they went out again. I had shew'd them the Goods in the third Shop, (that was the back Shop, the farthest from the Door,) where these Goods which the Prisoner stole, lay wrapt up in a Wrapper, with 14 Pieces more, -</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris Silver Lurstrings. - They were no sooner out of the Door, but a Person beckon'd me out, and bid me take Care of them, for they were all Thieves and Gamblers. Upon this, I call'd the Prisoner back again into the Shop, the Fellow came with her, but the other Woman walk'd off: I thought proper to tell Mr. Hinchliffe what I had heard, and while I was telling him, the Man went off, and left the Prisoner alone in the Shop. These 2 Pieces of Silk I saw directly under her Petticoats, and she stood directly over them; she had been in the Street, and was come into the Shop again. I took them from under her, and asked her how she came by them? She ask'd my Pardon, and said, she hop'd she had not daub'd them. O, they were pretty Things, (she said) pray, what were they a Yard!</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no one else in the Shop when you took the Silks off the Ground?</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris. No, the Man that came back with her was gone before we found them, and the other Woman did not come back at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her drop them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris. No, I can't say I saw her drop them, but they were taken from under her Petticoats, - she stood over them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Did not I stoop and take up one of the Pieces, and lay it on the Counter? Was not I the first Person that saw them on the Ground.</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris. No, I took them up my self; she never offer'd to take them up, - she stood exactly over them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person385">
                  Charles 
                  Enstone 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person385" type="surname" value="Enstone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person385" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner, with another Woman and a Man, came in, and desired to see some Brown-ground Silks: I carried them into the back Shop, where the Counter was quite clear, only 16 Pieces of these Silks were laid together behind the Counter, wrapt up in a Wrapper. I went into another Shop to look for more Things for them, and they bid me Money, but we could not agree, so they walk'd thro' the Shop to the Door, and while I was talking to the Prisoner at the Door, a Man desired Mr. Morris to take Care of them: upon this Notice, I call'd her into the Shop again, and told her I did not know but I might take her Money. They had been (all of them) out of the Shop, and I desired her to come in, and look at the Silks once more; she came back, and while she was looking at them again, Mr. Morris stoop'd down and took up her Petticoats (a little way) and these Pieces of Silk he pull'd from under them. He asked me if I had shewn them to her, I said no. (They lay in the Back Shop, wrapp'd up in a wrapper.) I hope, says she, that I have not dirted them: Upon this, I told over the Pieces in the wrapper and found these two wanting. These 16 Pieces were wrapp'd up and laid behind the Counter in the Back Shop, and were never shewn to them, nor had they been shewn to any one for a Fortnight, for they were laid by for a particular Purpose, and we were order'd not to meddle with them, nor shew them to any one.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200030"></xptr>Q. How long before this Time, had you seen them in the Wrapper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Eustone. I put them in my self about a Fortnight before, and we had positive Orders not to meddle with them. They were not out of the Wrapper, nor were any Goods upon the Counter, but what I had shew'd them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave them together in the Shop?</p> 
               <p>Mr. Enstone. I went into another Shop to fetch the Goods which they wanted to see.</p> 
               <p>Q. You say these Silks lay behind the Counter, did you observe, any of them go near the Wrapper.</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. No; but they could not get at them without going behind the Counter.</p>
               <p>Q. (To Mr. Morris) Did you see any of them go behind the Counter.</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris. No.</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. I was out of the Shop, and they were left entirely alone for some Time. The Prisoner, my Lord, was cast for Transportation about a Twelvemonth ago; the Gentleman is in Court for robbing of whom, she should have been transported.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. My Lord; last Wednesday was a Fortnight, a Gentlewoman that I have work'd for 5 Years, - her Brother came and desired me to go with him and the other Gentlewoman, to buy a Gown for his Sister, that I might give my Judgement on the Silks; so one of the Shops we went into, was this Gentleman's, and after we had pitch'd upon a Piece, he asked us 16 Shillings a Yard, we bid him 12, and the Gentleman that was with us bid him 12 s. 6 d and my Lord, he pulled out his Purse and offer'd to pay for it, if he would have taken the Money; but he refusing, we went out. Then a lusty Gentleman in the Shop, call'd us back again to look at the Flower, and as I came in, I saw these two Pieces lye upon the Ground, and I stooped down and took them up, and the Gentleman stooped down too.</p>
               <p>Q. (To the Prisoner) Where is the Man and the Woman that were with you?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Gentlewoman, - she lives at the Downs, and the Gentleman - he's in the Country.</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. My Lord, she told me her self, that the Man liv'd in Morefields, and the Woman in Drury-Lane.</p>
               <p>Jury Q. When they went out of the Shop into the Street, was there any Silks upon the Ground.</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. No, I should have seen them if there had been any, for I stood talking to them before they went out in the Place where they were dropp'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the Place where they lay, from the Place where they were dropp'd?</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. About 22 Yards; I measur'd it this Day.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had I any Thing about me proper to conceal these Things?</p>
               <p>Mr. Enstone. She had a very large Hoop; I told her she look'd big, and she said she was with Child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person386">
                  Joseph 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person386" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person386" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her between 4 and 5 Months; she lodges at Mrs. Fenns, in Castle-Street; about three Months ago she made a Stay for a Child of mine, and 3 Shirts and a Stock for me, and she brought these things Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person387">
                  Jane 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person387" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person387" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person387" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about a Year and half, she made a Gown for me within these three Months and three frocks.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her before she made your Gown?</p>
               <p>Brown. When she made my Gown, I had not seen her for 4 Months together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person388">
                  Michael 
                  Brownrigg 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person388" type="surname" value="Brownrigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person388" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Barber, and have seen the Gentlewoman - the Prisoner, at Mrs. Fenns: I have known her 2 or 3 Years, and have seen her frequently, during that Time. I never heard ill of her till now.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not she been abroad - in the Country - during this Time?</p>
               <p>Brownrigg. She may - for ought I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person389">
                  Ann 
                  Fenn 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person389" type="surname" value="Fenn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person389" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person389" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep an Alehouse in Castle street. I have known the Gentlewoman 2 Years - a very honest Gentlewoman, she is - in her Dealings. I never heard any Thing to her Character before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-44-person390">
                  Mary 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person390" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person390" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I knew her a twelve-month, and as any Mantua-maker's equal to me, I gan her a Gown, 'twas this said Gown to do, at Mrs. Fenns, I had no Acquaintance with her farther; but she bore an honest Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370420-44-person391">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17370420-44-person391" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person391" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the Bar, I Transported for Shoplifting. She robb'd me, last February was twelve-month, and was convicted and sentenced for Transportation; but I see she is return'd; She is known to have been a Shoplifter many Years. <rs id="t17370420-44-verdict241" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-verdict241" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17370420-44-punish242" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-punish242" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-44-punish242" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-44-defend381 t17370420-44-punish242"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
