<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-4">
               <interp inst="t17360610-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-4" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-4" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-4-off17-c39" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-defend47 t17360610-4-off17 t17360610-4-verdict21"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-4-off17-c40" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-defend49 t17360610-4-off17 t17360610-4-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100003"></xptr>5, 6. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-defend47" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Scott 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend47" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend47" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-defend49" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Macguineys 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend49" type="surname" value="Macguineys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend49" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-defend49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17360610-4-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entring the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-4-victim51" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Cotes 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim51" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim51" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   between the Hours of 2 and 3 in the Night and stealing 2 Velvet Coats lac'd, value 30 l. 2 pair Velvet Breaches, 2 Padesoy Wastcoats lac'd, a Gold Watch, a Silver Hilted Sword, a Hanger and a silk Belt, 18 Holland Shirts, 6 pair of Cotton Stockings, and one pair of silk Stockings, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-4-victim53" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Bailey 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim53" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim53" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-4-victim53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17360610-4-viclabel18" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-victim53 t17360610-4-viclabel18"></join>; and 4 large silver Spoons, and 2 Tea Spoons
            </rs>, the Goods of Robert Cotes, <rs id="t17360610-4-cd19" type="crimeDate">May 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-off17 t17360610-4-cd19"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baily. I live in Mr. Cotes's House in <placeName id="t17360610-4-defloc20">Bond-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-4-defloc20" type="placeName" value="Bond-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-4-defloc20" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-defend47 t17360610-4-defloc20"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-4-defend49 t17360610-4-defloc20"></join>. On Monday, May 10, about 3 o' Clock in the Morning, I wak'd and by the light of a dark Lanthorn, I saw 2 Men in my Chamber: I was very much surpriz'd, and got up; then they run out of the Room; one of them had my Sword, and the other had snatch'd up a Gold Repeating Watch which lay on the Table. I call'd out who's there? but they made no answer. I lost several Things more out of the same House, which were taken out of a Room at some distance from my Chamber; 2 Suits of Velvet Cloaths, one Dove Colour, embroider'd with Silver, and one Chocolate Colour lac'd, eighteen Holland Shirts; a Hanger mounted with Silver; eight pair of Cotton Stockings; a Dozen of Cambrick Stocks, and Padesoy Wastcoats to the Velvet Coats I know nothing of the Prisoners, but from the Information of the Accomplice.</p>
               <p>Council. D'd you take any particular Notice of the Men, that came into your Room?</p>
               <p>Baily. I could only observe that one was taller and thinner than the other; I saw them by the imperfect Light of their dark Lanthorn: the two Prisoners are near their Size and Shape.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know the Evidence that was the Accomplice?</p>
               <p>Baily. He was Mr. Cotes's Journeyman.</p>
               <p>Council. Have you made any Enquiry after the Goods?</p>
               <p>Baily. Yes; and some of them I have recover'd: I have got the Chocolate Velvet Suit, but all the Lace is stripp'd off it was found in one Davis's House, in Short's-Gardens, in a Box with four or five of my Shirts, a pair of my Stockings, my Gold Watch, Sword and Hanger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person54">
                  Patrick
                   O'Henlon
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person54" type="surname" value="O'Henlon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person54" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Mr. Cotes's Servant, in his Business as an Apothecary, and have been three Months acquainted with the Prisoners. Macguineys had got the Venereal Distemper and apply'd to me for Cure, so began our Acquaintance. About a Fortnight before the Fact was committed Macguineys came to me and desired me to swear something: I asked him what, he said I must swear never to discover what he had to propose: I did; and then he propos'd that I should let him in: The first Time I would not consent, but he was always at me; telling me he would get another Partner if I would not consent. I condescended at last to let him in, and it was agreed that I should leave the Kitchen Window open. It was the 10th of May (I think) that the Robbery was committed: Macguineys and Scott came in at the Window, and went up Stairs to Mr. Baily's Chamber directly, while I staid in the Shop: Macguineys carry'd the dark Lanthorn, and each of them a Pistol. I did not see that Night, the particular Things they took, but I saw them come down Stairs and go thro' the Shop with their Burden. I saw one of them have a Sword in his Hand as they were coming down the Stairs, but I can't swear that this Sword now in Court is the same: They had open'd the Street Door before they went up, that they might go out again without hindrance. I staid at Home all that Night; we had agreed not to meet for twelve Days afterwards to avoid Suspicion, but I thought proper to call at Macguineys House next Morning: He was not at Home, so I saw him not. I was taken up, before either of them came to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you taken up?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. Two Days after the Robbery; I had been nine or ten Days in Bridewell, before Macguineys came to me alone; and in Bridewell he told me, he was afraid I should discover: I assured him I would not: Then he told me what they had got, but said, he was very much afraid they would make me discover; I have consulted People about it, says he, and nothing can hurt us, if you can keep your own Counsel. He told me they had got two Velvet Suits, eighteen Shirts, eight pair of Stockings, a Sword and Hanger, a Gold Repeating Watch, three large silver Spoons, a Child's Spoon and a Tea Spoon, and he assured me the Goods were safe, and should not be touch'd, nor pawn'd for two Months, and after two Months, they should be equally divided. Scott did not come to see me all the Time I was in Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q When did you make the Discovery?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. About a Fortnight after the Fact was committed; I was eight Days in Bridewell, and was discharged before I made the Discovery.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see either of the Prisoners after you was discharged?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100004"></xptr>O'Henlon. I saw Macguineys at the Corner of Swallow-street, by Appointment, four Days after I was discharged; and he gave me a Shirt, and a pair of Stockings; he then told me he had advised me right, to keep my own Counsel, for now I saw they could not hurt me; and when he gave me the Shirt and the Stockings, he told me they were part of Mr. Bailey's Things, and if I wanted any Thing before I saw him again, I might come to his Lodgings in Piccadilly; assuring me again, that they would not touch the rest for two Months. I saw Scott likewise several times after the Robbery; about five Days after I came out of Bridewell, he and I dined together, and he told me the Things were all safe, and now there was no Danger.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure they both came into the House together?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. Yes, and Macguineys had a piece of black Crape over his Face.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you make the Discovery?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. At Justice De Viel's.</p>
               <p>Q. What, did you go of your own accord to him?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. I was carried before him by a Constable, and there I made a Confession, tho' Macguineys had persuaded me to keep my Counsel, and told me he had got another Patient for me, for he had given the Distemper to a young Woman where he liv'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any more of the Goods come into your Possession, besides the Shirt and the Stockings?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. Yes, one Stock, and nothing else.</p>
               <p>Council. Were either of the Prisoners with you at one Savage's House before, or after the Robbery?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. No; there was one Savage I let into the Secret; I was afraid they would wrong me, and I desired him to go to them, and get the Goods divided; this was after I came out of Bridewell, and I did not see Savage a-again till I was taken up the second time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you direct Savage to go?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. To Macguineys Lodgings, at the Queen's-Head in Piccadilly.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you never see Savage at one Davis's House?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. Yes, several times, but not after I had intrusted him with the Secret.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see any of the Goods at Davis's House when Savage was there?</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. No, but I brought the Shirt and Stockings to the House, when Savage was there, Macguineys when he gave me these Things gave me a Guiney and a half, and told me they had stript the Lace from one of the Suits of Cloaths, and that Money was for my Part.</p>
               <p>Mr. De Viel. After this Felony and Burglary had been committed, Mr. Bailey desired me to come to the House, to examine the Maid and this Fellow: the Maid I committed upon strong Circumstances; But on Re-examination, she was discharged: I examined this Spark, and he prevaricated very much, so I sent him to Bridewell, and he was there seven or eight Days, and there not being sufficient Proof to commit him, I discharged him. About a Week afterwards there came a Washerwoman with one of Mr. Bailey's Shirts, as she supposed; and she saying she had it from him, I gave a Warrant to bring him before me the 2d Time; then he made a voluntary Confession, and by this Confession the Goods were found at Davis's House in Short's-Gardens, and were brought to me by the Constable. He gave much the same Account before me that he has done now; and that he had acquainted Savage with the Affair, because he was afraid he should be cheated of his Part; and he look'd on Savage as a proper Person to secure it. He said, he was not sure where the Goods were, but believed they might be at this House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person55">
                  John 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person55" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. The Hanger, Sword, Velvet Coat, and Wastcoat, Gold Watch, and Spoons, we found in Davis's House, by a Search Warrant.</p>
               <p>Mr. De Viel. I make Oath this is the same Watch the Constable took out of the Box.</p>
               <p>Constable. I believe 'tis the same, and these five Spoons.</p>
               <p>Mr. Robert Cotes. These are my Spoons; they were lost out of my House, the same Night Mr. Bailey was robb'd. On Sunday, May 9. after Dinner, my eldest Son and I went to Dulwich, to see my Wife's Brother and Sister; we lay there that Night, and coming Home in the Morning, I called at my 
               <persName id="t17360610-4-person56">
                  Lord 
                  Tyrawley 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person56" type="surname" value="Tyrawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person56" type="given" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's in Somerset-House, where I was first informed of the Robbery. I came home and found the Fact had been committed in the same Manner that Mr. Bailey has told you, and my Spoons taken out of one of the back Kitchens.</p>
               <p>Council. How long has O'Henlon liv'd with you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cotes. About three Months; and his Behaviour during the time I could not find Fault with,</p>
               <p>- Smith. O'Henlon brought me a Guinea to keep for him, and told me his Mother had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100005"></xptr> sent him a Guinea and a half: I doubted the Truth o'n't, and the Day following I gave a Chairman half a Crown to follow him, that I might know his Haunts; he gave me an account of the Places he went to; Davis's House was one; we searched there, and I asked for Savage; the Man of the House said he was gone out half an Hour before. I searched Savage's Room, and seeing a Box there, I asked if that was Savage's Box, he told me, Yes; we broke it open and found the Goods, which we brought Box and all to Mr. Justice De Viel's. Davis followed us, and told us there were nine Shirts which Savage had sent to the Washer-woman's: we brought these Goods to the Justice, and went back to wait for Savage, but I suppose he had Intelligence of the Discovery, and so came no more to the House.</p>
               <p>Council. Has not O'Henlon been often at your House?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, but I never saw Macguineys with him. It was my Son and Daughter kept the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person57">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Strong 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person57" type="surname" value="Strong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person57" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the Prisoners; I had these nine Shirts to wash from Savage himself at Davis's</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person58">
                  John 
                  Dobein 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person58" type="surname" value="Dobein"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are my Master's Shirts.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask whether Macguineys used he House.</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. I never saw him there but once.</p>
               <p>Macguineys. I never drank with O'Henlon but in Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q Pray how come you to go to him in Bridewell?</p>
               <p>Macguineys. He had given me Physick before.</p>
               <p>Council. You have given the Answer, we wanted to come at.</p>
               <p>Macguineys's Defence. I was at Home in my Father's Room at 7 o'Clock, we had Bread and Cheese and Small Beer for Supper, and I went to Bed in my Father's Room at 10.</p>
               <p>Scott's Defence. I was at home, and was not out of the House from Sunday to Monday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person59">
                  Susannah 
                  Jephson 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person59" type="surname" value="Jephson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person59" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Macguineys's Father and Mother, and Macguineys lay with his Father and Mother that Night, and I lay in the same Room with them: We went to Bed about 10 o'Clock that Night. I was up at six the next Morning, and saw him in Bed. O'Henlon told us of the Robbery the next Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you liv'd with his Father and Mother?</p>
               <p>Jephson. About two Months. The Bed he and his Father and Mother lay in had blue Curtains, and they were drawn about the Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you open them?</p>
               <p>Jephson. An't please you, I see him get out of the Bed: I staid in the Room after I was up till he got up; he got up first, and left his Father and Mother in Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Month was this?</p>
               <p>Jephson. May 10. it was Monday. O'Henlon came that Morning, and spoke of this Robbery, when his Mother and I were in the Room. I had never seen him above once or twice before: young Macguineys was in an ill State of Health, and he came to bring him Physick.</p>
               <p>O'Henlon. I did tell them of the Robbery, but what she says of Macguineys's being at Home all Night, is not true; for Mr. Cotes's Maid knows he was talking with me at our Door at 11 o'Clock at Night; her Name is 
               <persName id="t17360610-4-person60">
                  Catherine 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person60" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person60" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             She was call'd but did not appear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person61">
                  Nicholas 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person61" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person61" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick House in Short's-Gardens; Savage lodged in my House; I never saw either of the Prisoners there: O'Henlon I have seen with Savage.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person62">
                  Mary 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person62" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person62" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Savage lodged with us: I never saw either of the Prisoners come to him; but I never took much Notice of People that went up Stairs. O'Henlon I have seen there three or four Times.</p>
               <p>C. How came you to take such Notice of him?</p>
               <p>M. Davis. Because he was so sober and serious, he never call'd for any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person63">
                  Daniel 
                  Mackenzie 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person63" type="surname" value="Mackenzie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person63" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Name is not Macguineys, but Mackenzie. I took Savage to be an honest Man, but now I believe him to be a Rogue. He offer'd two Shirts to my Wife to pawn.</p>
               <p>Dun. I never saw any Dealings between O'Henlon and Savage but once; and that time Savage went to a Box and gave him a pair of Stockings out of the Box.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person64">
                  John 
                  Penny 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person64" type="surname" value="Penny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person64" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-4-person65">
                  Peter 
                  Deloni 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person65" type="surname" value="Deloni"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person65" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-4-person66">
                  Matthew 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person66" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person66" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Artbur Hendrick, never heard ill of Macguineys before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person67">
                  William 
                  Archdeacon 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person67" type="surname" value="Archdeacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person67" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of May, I call'd Scott up early in the Morning to get him Labouring Work. He had a Soldier lay with him that Night, and he was subpoenaed but wou'd not come.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person68">
                  Mary 
                  Archdeacon 
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person68" type="surname" value="Archdeacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person68" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . May Day was Saturday, Scott came to live with us the next Day, and he made his Obligations known to me, that he had no where to get Victuals; on Sunday May<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100006"></xptr> the 9th, I let him in about 9 o'Clock in the Morning, and I remember his chipping Stocks to make a Fire, he sat up 'till 11 o'Clock, then I saw him go to Bed, I lock'd the Door and laid the Key by my Bedside.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-4-person69">
                  Susannah
                   But'cr
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person69" type="surname" value="But'cr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person69" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Andercen's Evidence, and Samuel A gin spoke to his Character. Both <rs id="t17360610-4-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>On Saturday Mr. Cotes mov'd by his Council for an Order of Court, that 
               <persName id="t17360610-4-person70">
                  Patrick
                   O'Henlon
               <interp inst="t17360610-4-person70" type="surname" value="O'Henlon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person70" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-4-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , might be continu'd in Custody, in Order to his being prosecuted for this Fact; but the Court was of Opinion that as he had been admitted an Evidence, such Order was not to be granted.</p>
            </div1>
