<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380518-16">
               <interp inst="t17380518-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-16" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-16" type="date" value="17380518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-16-off74-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-16-defend137 t17380518-16-off74 t17380518-16-verdict76"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-16-off74-c118" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-16-defend159 t17380518-16-off74 t17380518-16-verdict78"></join>
         
               <p>18. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-defend137" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Cross 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend137" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend137" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted, for that he being a Person of a wicked and corrupt Mind, greedy of Lucre, &amp;c. and <rs id="t17380518-16-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               unlawfully contriving and intending to cheat and defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380518-16-victim139" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Hoare 
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim139" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim139" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380518-16-victim141" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Hoare 
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim141" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim141" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380518-16-victim143" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Hoare 
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim143" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim143" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380518-16-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Christopher 
                           Arnold 
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim145" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim145" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , of a great Sum of Money, viz. 75 l. in Portugal Money, value 75 l. and to get and acquire to himself the said Sum of 75 l. the said Messieurs Hoare and Arnold, being then concern'd in Partnership, in the Banking Business, and keeping Cash, and also then keeping a publick Shop; on the 26th of Jan. in the Parish of St. Dunstan in the West, he the said Car, out of his wicked Mind, Intention, &amp;c. made and forged, and caused to be made and forg'd, in the Name of William Payne, a certain Paper in writing, purporting a Note, Order, Power or Authority, in the Name of the said Payne, for Payment of Money, bearing Date, <rs id="t17380518-16-cd75" type="crimeDate">Jan. 12, 1737</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-16-off74 t17380518-16-cd75"></join>. and directed to Messieurs Hoare and Company, in Fleetstreet, and authorizing them the said Benjamin Hoare, and Richard Hoare, and Christopher Arnold, under the Denomination of Messieurs Hoare and Company, to pay to 
                     <persName id="t17380518-16-person146">
                        Abram 
                        Irons 
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person146" type="surname" value="Irons"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-person146" type="given" value="Abram"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-16-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , or Berer (meaning Bearer) the said Sum of 75 l.
            </rs> which said false and forged Order, is contain'd in the Words and Figures following.</p>
               <p>Jan. 12, 1737.</p>
               <p>Pray Pay to Mr. Abram Irons, or Berer, the Sum of Seventy five Pounds, and place the same to the Account of your Humble Servant,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person147">
                  William 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person147" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person147" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>P. S. 75 l. Portugal Money.</p>
               <p>Thereby meaning and intending, that they the said Benjamin, Henry, and Richard Hoare, and Christopher Arnold, should pay him the said Cross, the said Sum of 75 l. Whereas in Truth and Fact,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180010"></xptr> the said Paper or Writing was never signed by the said William Payne, &amp;c. against the Peace, &amp;c. to the evil Example of others, &amp;c. in Contempt of our Lord the King, and his Laws, and against the Form of the Stature, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>2. The Jurors farther present, that 
               <persName id="t17380518-16-person148">
                  Tho 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person148" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person148" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being a Person of a wicked and corrupt Disposition, and unjustly contriving, &amp;c. to cheat and defraud Benjamin Richard, and Henry Hoare, and Christopher Arnold, of another great Sum of Money, viz. 75 l. in Portugal Money, and to get and acquire the same to himself, on the 26th of Jan &amp;c. out of his wicked Mind, assisted in making, and forging in the Name of William Payne, a certain Note and Writing, purporting in it self an Order, &amp;c. under the Hand of William Payne, bearing Date and directed, &amp;c. (as above) &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>3. The Jurors farther present, that he the said Cross, being a Person of a wicked and corrupt Mind, &amp;c. (as above) and wickedly intending to cheat and defraud Messrs. Hoare and Arnold, of another great Sum of Money, viz 75 l. in Portugal Money, and to get and acquire the same to himself, on the 26th of Jan. in the Parish and Ward aforesaid, did utter and publish a Paper in Writing, purporting in it self, an Order, &amp;c. under the Hand of William Payne, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. On Tuesday the 10th of Jan. 1737. Mr. Payne paid into our Shop 340 l. I receiv'd the Money from the Prisoner at the Bar, in Mr. Payne's Presence. I am Clerk to Messrs. Benjamin, Henry, and Richard Hoare, and Christopher Arnold, who is in Partnership with Messrs Hoare. I gave Mr. Payne a Note for this Money that he might draw it out again. By vertue of this forged Note, 74l. was paid to 
               <persName id="t17380518-16-person149">
                  Richard 
                  Car 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person149" type="surname" value="Car"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person149" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who told me, when I paid him, that he liv'd in Covent-Garden, I know Mr. Payne's Hand, and am positive this is not his Writing; I have seen him often write, and when the Prisoner came with him and paid me this 340 l. I got Mr. Payne to write his Name in our Book, and the Prisoner stood over him while he did it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire Mr. Atkinson may be asked, whether Mr. Payne was not to fetch the whole Sum away again? And whether he was not told that he must not draw for it in small Sums?</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. He was not forbid drawing for it in small Sums; I told him if he drew for it, he must draw for Portugal Money, he said, he should not have Occasion for it this Month or two, and that he should draw for it when he wanted it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would ask whether he did not give Mr. Payne an actual Promissory Note for this 340 l. for Value receiv'd?</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. 'Tis a common Thing in the Course of our Business to give Notes drawn on one's self, - I promise to pay to 
               <persName id="t17380518-16-person150">
                  William 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person150" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c. for Value receiv'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Is Mr. Atkinson positive that I saw Mr. Payne write his Name in the Book?</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. Yes, and the Prisoner look'd at the Book while I was making the Note for Mr. Payne.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did any one else hear Mr. Payne say he should draw for it as he wanted it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. I don't know. We have two other Clerks in the Shop, - they might, - or they might not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person151">
                  John 
                  Crull 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person151" type="surname" value="Crull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person151" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mr. Payne's Hand; the Name at the Bottom of this Note (looking upon it) is a Counterfeit; and for a Counterfeit, 'tis the worst I ever saw in my Life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Parker. I know Mr. Payne's Writing; this is not like it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person152">
                  Robert 
                  Ramsay 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person152" type="surname" value="Ramsay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person152" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner very well. The first Time I ever saw this Note was on Thursday the 26th of Jan. last. On that Thursday Morning, Car (who was try'd last Night for this Fact) and I, met according to Appointment in Guildhall. As we were walking on one Side of the Hall, we met the Prisoner and one Sands. After we had talked together for some Time, the Prisoner drew this Note out of his Pocket, and said if you'll undertake to receive this Note, I can draw for Thousands upon others. I said it would be hazardous and dang'rous, and that I did not Care to undertake it. We consulted together about it, and at last it was agreed that Car and I should go to the Chevalier's Billiard Table in Moorfields, and we were to Play. While we were at Play the Prisoner was to come in as a Stranger, and was to challenge Car; they two were to play 'till the Prisoner had lost a certain Sum to Car; then he was to offer Car the Note, and to tell him he might go and receive that Note, and he would pay him what he had lost. The Reason of this Proceeding was, that if Car should be detected when he went with the Note, or should be call'd in Question about it, the Woman who keeps the Billiard Table should be a Witness for him. According to our Agreement, Car and I went that Day to the Billiard Table and play'd: In some little Time, the Prisoner and his Friend Sands follow'd us, and he, (the Prisoner)<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180011"></xptr> challenged Car to play; in about an Hour Car won 30 l. of the Prisoner, and then Car demanding the Money he had won of the Prisoner, he threw down this Note, telling him he had not Money enough about him to pay him, but he might take that Note upon Mr. Hoare, and he might go and receive it, and might pay himself. Car told the Prisoner it was Dinner Time; however, if he would go to the Three Tuns in New-Street, Fetter-Lane, and take a Dinner, he would go when he had din'd. Upon this, the Prisoner, I, Car, and Sands, went to the Three Tuns, and called for a Room, and (I think) we had Part of a Fillet of Veal for Dinner: Before we had half din'd, the Prisoner seemed uneasy, upon which Car said, - give me the Note, - I'll go, and Fortune be my Guide.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner gave him the Note, and he immediately went out with it; Sands followed him at a Distance, and if he should be stopped, he was to have come back and given us Intelligence that we might have made off. The Prisoner and I waited for Car's Return some little Time, then I began to be uneasy, so I went down to the Door where I met Car; he was come back, and told us the Business was done, the Note would be paid, only it wanted a little Thing, - called an Endorsement, and when that was done it would be paid. With Persuasion I wrote on the Back of the Note, - Abram Irons. Then Car took the Note and went with it again Sands, followed him at a Distance, I followed Sands and the Prisoner followed me; but before we got near Mr. Hoare's, Car was come out with the Money in his Handkerchief; upon this we went back to the Three Tuns, where Cross (the Prisoner) told Car he had made a Blunder, for he had brought but 74 l. instead of 75. Upon dividing the Money, a Dispute arose whether we should all be equal Sharers, and the Prisoner insisted upon it, that as we were all equally concerned, we should all be equal Sharers.</p>
               <p>Councel. When the Prisoner first produced this Note, did he do it as a real or a forged Note?</p>
               <p>Ramsey. He produced it as a forged Note, and told us he had paid Money in at Mr. Hoare's for Mr. Payne some Time before, but he did not mention the particular Time. Out of the Money received, we had each of us Five Three Pound Twelve Pieces, and some small Money, and the Prisoner had his Share.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire he might be asked how long he has known me?</p>
               <p>Ramsey. I have been acquainted with him about ten Months; but the Time we all met at Guildhall, was in the Morning, Thursday the 26th of January last, as near as I can remember; I believe I may be very positive to that Day.</p>
               <p>Councel. Have you had any Conversation with the Prisoner since the Note was found to be forged?</p>
               <p>Ramsey. Yes; I met him at a Place called Eastham Boathouse, over against Liverpoole, and he told me he flew for fear any Accident should happen; he was afraid of Car (he said) more than of me. He did not know at that Time that he was described in the Advertisements, but I told him (at that Meeting) he was put in the Papers.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him why he left London with Car under Disguises.</p>
               <p>Ramsey. Because we were afraid of being taken for this Forgery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not abscond on Account of another Note of 125 l. which they sent to Mr. Hoare's, and the Messenger was detected?</p>
               <p>Ramsey. I was concerned in the 125 l. Note, and Car who carried it was stopped, but I did not forge any of them, nor did I fly immediately; I did not abscond till Advertisements were put in the Papers concerning Mr. Hoare's being defrauded of 212 l.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Smith. I keep the Billiard Table (he mentions) I know both the Prisoner and the Evidence Ramsey; I saw them together at my House some Time in January, but I can't remember the particular Day. Mr. Car was there likewise at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask Mrs. Smith, whether Car's Sister did not come with her to see me in the Counter? And whether Car's Sister did not point to me and tell her, I was the Person that was to save her Brother?</p>
               <p>Smith. Car's Sister was with me there, and she said, - Mr. Cross, this is the Gentlewoman that is to save my Brother's Life; but I knew the Prisoner before she said this.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Cloaths had I on when I was at your Billiard Table?</p>
               <p>Smith. A Blue Grey Coat, and a dark short Whig, to the best of my Remembrance, but I can't remember the Day of the Week, nor the Day of the Month.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Atkinson has sworn to Mr. Paine's Hand, and that he knows this was not his Writing. I desire he may be ask'd, how he came to be deceiv'd, and to pay this Note?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180012"></xptr>Mr. Atkinson. I was in a Hurry, and had 8 or 10 People about me, and I don't remember that I compar'd the Hand with Mr. Payne's Name in our Book. I had given a Note for 340 l. to be drawn out, and I thought I might safely pay a Draught of 75 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person153">
                  Edward 
                  Cotterel 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person153" type="surname" value="Cotterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person153" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Three Tuns in New Street; I have seen the Prisoner's Face, and I think I remember the Witness Ramsey and he were together at our House about four Months ago; there was four or five of them together, and I think they had Part of a Fillet of Veal. They came in about Eleven o'Clock in the Forenoon, and staid some Time, then they went out and came in again; they seem'd (all of them) to be in a Fluster, and I was afraid of losing the Silver Tankard and the Spoons which they had at the Table; I imagined they intended to steal the Plate, therefore I desired my Mistress to take Care of her Plate, for they went backwards and forwards and seem'd so fluster'd, that I did not like them. Two or three of them went out, and returned in a Quarter of an Hour. - I very much disliked their Behaviour, I remember.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person154">
                  Mary 
                  Macey 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person154" type="surname" value="Macey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person154" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember something of both their Faces, and that Cotterel told my Mistress he believed the Tankard and the Spoons were in Danger; he desired her to take Care of the Plate they were using; he attended them, and told her he did not like his Company, they seemed to be so uneasy. I remember this was in Jan. last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person155">
                  Robert 
                  Patterson 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person155" type="surname" value="Patterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person155" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner, and Ramsey, and Car. Ramsey and Cross the Prisoner I know are acquainted, but I can't say much to the Acquaintance between them and Car. I have been in Company with Ramsey and the Prisoner several Times about five or six Months ago, they were then young Acquaintances; I have not known any of them long, but at that Time I used to be often in their Company.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Patterson is a Judge of the Game at Billiards, ask him if ever he saw me play at Billiards for any Money?</p>
               <p>Patterson. He was always unwilling to play for Money.</p>
               <p>[The Note was read.]</p>
               <p>Pray pay Mr. Abram Irons, or Berer (Bearer) the Sum of 75 l. (in Figures) and Place the same to Account of</p>
               <p>Your Humble Servant,</p>
               <p>William Payne.</p>
               <p>To Mess. Hoare and Comp. in Fleet-Street.</p>
               <p>To be paid in Portugal Money.</p>
               <p>Endors'd, Abram Irons.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prisoner observ'd, (on a Point of Law) that the Charge in the Indictment was laid for 75 l. Portugal Money, value 75 l. English. The Objection was, that the Note read in Evidence, was not agreeable to the Indictment. That it appear'd the Note under Consideration was payable in Portugal Money, which is not the current Money of this Kingdom. That the Indictment therefore was defective. And that it ought to have charg'd, - that the Defendant intended and design'd to have defrauded Messieurs Hoare and Company of so many Pieces of Portugal Money, value so much: But the Indictment charges the Defendant plainly, with defrauding Messieurs Hoare and Company of 75 l. which must be understood, 75 l. current Coin; whereas, the Sum of 75 l. could not be paid in Portugal Money; no Pieces of that Coin making exactly that Sum.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution observ'd, that it was no Wonder a sinking Man caught hold of every Twig. That the Words of the Statute were, - if any Person should forge a Note, or Order, for Payment of MONEY, or Delivery of Goods, with Intent to defraud, &amp;c. That Money is Money, tho' not the current Money of this Kingdom, and that the Word in the Act, was Money, generally. That it was plain, the Act made it a Crime to forge a Warrant, for the Payment of Money, (generally.) That Portugal Coin, was Money, (and the Value was right in the Indictment,) - therefore, the Indictment charged the Defendant, according to the Act, and the Evidence had sufficiently supported the Indictment. The Councel observ'd further, that it was impossible to have laid it, in any other Manner; for it must have been laid for either Money, or Goods; and that Portugal Money could not be consider'd as Goods, was evident; because no one could say, - Pray pay Goods. Therefore, it must be consider'd as Money.</p>
               <p>Mr. Atkinson. But I did not pay all the Sum in Portugal Money, there were 4 Shillings in Silver.</p>
               <p>It was farther observ'd, that a former Act calls it foreign Coin; that Coin is Money, not Bullion. That the Cheat was the same if in Portugal Money, or British Money, and that when these Pieces were exported, they were consider'd as Money, or Coin, not as Goods. That there was another Act, which restrain'd People from counterfeiting the foreign Coins, which pass in this Kingdom, in these Words, - viz. Be it enacted, &amp;c. that if any Person shall forge or counterfeit any such Coins, as are not the proper Coins of this Kingdom,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180013"></xptr> but permitted to be current, they shall be judged guilty of High-Treason; and They, their Abettors, Assistants, &amp;c. being convict, shall forfeit, &amp;c. as in Case of High-Treason.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I shall call Witnesses to prove, that from the 20th of January, to February, I was out of Town.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person156">
                  Richard 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person156" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person156" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . But I can't be positive to the Day. I think it was about the latter End of January. I went into Wooburn, in Bedfordshire, in January, I think 'twas the latter End of the Month, and he was there very ill, and had a Doctor and a Nurse. I am his Taylor, and work for him.</p>
               <p>Councel. Has the Prisoner paid you any Money since January?</p>
               <p>Davis. Let me see, - yes, he paid me for making a Coat and Breeches, since that Time, - 'twas at Chester he paid me, - I can't remember the Time.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Coin did he pay you in?</p>
               <p>Davis. In Silver.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. The Prisoner calls me to shew, (I suppose) that on the 10th of January last, I had one Thousand Pounds paid to me, as a Trustee, for some particular Uses, by Mr. De la Hay in the City: and that I then had that Confidence in him, that I trusted him with a Bank Note of 500 l. to carry to Mr. Hoare, and exchange for a 400 l. Note, and a 100 l. Bank Bill. I did trust him, and 'twas this induced Mr. Payne to entrust him. The Prisoner liv'd with me about eleven Months, and during that Time I had no Reason to suspect him. He has left me now, and I will not impeach his Character. If I have Suspicions, they are out of the Case.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you believe him to have been a faithful Servant to you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. I have given him Money, while he was with me, to pay for Stamps; and since he left me, I have had a Bill brought in for them. He went away from me the 18th of January, on Account of the many Actions depending against him for Debt; he being disappointed of Money he expected to have received. I don't know where he has been since he left me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-person157">
                  Henry 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person157" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person157" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the Middle of January last, the Prisoner had the Misfortune to be arrested for 5.l was carry'd to a Spunging-House in Grocer's Alley. He sent for me thither, and I found Car and Ramsey with him. Among other Discourse, the Prisoner was mentioning what a large Sum he had been entrusted with the Day before, of Mr. Payne's, all in Portugal Money. Ramsey told him he was a Fool he did not run away with it. The Prisoner reply'd, he would not forfeit his Character for ten times that Sum.</p>
               <p>Patridge, Keeper of Chester Goal. About 6 Weeks ago the Prisoner was in my Custody, and behav'd well. Ramsey and Car I saw at Liverpool, they broke Gaol on Friday Night, and were taken again on Saturday Night.</p>
               <p>- Darnburgh. Ramsey, Peterson, Cross, and one Rosamond, with several of their Acquaintance, frequented my House in Arundel-Street. I never saw Car with them but once, and that was the Time the Advertisement came out, and he was in Fear I should take him. I never heard any Ill of them, 'till after Cross was gone out of Town.</p>
               <p>- Smallwood. I know nothing of this Affair concerning the Note; but I know Cross, he was some Time under my Care. I have had a liberal Education, and was brought up at the University, so I teach a School; and during the Time the Prisoner was with me, I look'd on him to be so honest, that I recommended him to Mr. Ford.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cecil. I knew the Prisoner when he liv'd with Mr. Pitt as a Footman, and the Family I believe always thought well of him, he liv'd with him about four Years ago.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17380518-16-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment. <rs id="t17380518-16-punish77" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-punish77" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-16-defend137 t17380518-16-punish77"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>19. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-16-defend159" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Car 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend159" type="surname" value="Car"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend159" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-defend159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted (in the same manner as above) for the same Fact, the Evidence against him was the same as in the foregoing Trial, and the Point of Law observ'd upon, was likewise the same. His Trial came on the Day before Cross's, and <rs id="t17380518-16-verdict78" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-verdict78" type="verdictCategory" value="specialVerdict"></interp>
               the Jury brought in their Verdict Special
            </rs>. The found the Facts as follows. That Richard Car on the 26th of Jan. last, utter'd and publish'd as true, the forged Note, set forth in the last Count in the Indictment, with Intent to deceive Messrs. Hoare and Arnold, of 75 l. That at that Time of uttering and publishing the same, he knew it to be false and counterfeit. That he, the said Car, by Vertue of that counterfeit Note, did receive of 
               <persName id="t17380518-16-person160">
                  William 
                  Atkinson 
               <interp inst="t17380518-16-person160" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person160" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-16-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , then Servant to Mr. Hoar and Comp. the Sum of 75 l. being the Money of Messrs. Hoare and Arnold. That 73 l. 16 s. Part of the said Sum, was paid him in Portugal Coin, and the remaining 4 s. in current and lawful Money of Great-Britain, referring Points of Law to the Judgment of the Court.</p>
            </div1>
