<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-34">
               <interp inst="t17360721-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-34" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-34" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-34-off159-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-34-defend258 t17360721-34-off159 t17360721-34-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>39 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-34-defend258" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Shelton 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-34-defend258" type="surname" value="Shelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-defend258" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-defend258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17360721-34-off159" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-off159" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-off159" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               whereas at the Sessions of Goal Delivery of Newgate, held at Justice Hall in the Old Bailey on Wednesday, May the 5th-last, before the Right Hon. Sir 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person259">
                        John 
                        Williams 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person259" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person259" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Knt. Lord-Mayor, &amp;c. the Right Hon. the Lord Hardwick. the Hon. Mr. Justice Cummins, the Hon. Mr. Justice Denton, and other Justices of our Lord the King, assigned to deliver the Goal of Newgate, one 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person260">
                        Daniel 
                        Malden 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person260" type="surname" value="Malden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person260" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise Morgan, otherwise Smith, was by due Form of Law convicted, for that he the 29th of February last, about the Hour of one in the Night, the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person261">
                        Mary 
                        Henshaw 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person261" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person261" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did break and enter, and 7 pair of Sheets, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person262">
                        John 
                        White 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person262" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 8 Aprons, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person263">
                        Sarah 
                        Bishop 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person263" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person263" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 3 Linnen Check-Aprons, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person264">
                        Sarah 
                        Hilder 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person264" type="surname" value="Hilder"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person264" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 3 Check-Aprons, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person265">
                        Ann 
                        Seal 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person265" type="surname" value="Seal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person265" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person265" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 1 Shirt, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person266">
                        Thomas 
                        Clark 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person266" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person266" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person267">
                        Mary 
                        Henshaw 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person267" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person267" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person267" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did steal, take, and carry away. And by a certain Jury of the Country, duly impanneled and sworn, he was legally tryed and convicted; and 
                     <persName id="t17360721-34-person268">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Shelton 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person268" type="surname" value="Shelton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person268" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-34-person268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   well knowing the said Malden otherwise Morgan, &amp;c. so as aforesaid, to have been attainted and convicted; she, the said Shelton, on the <rs id="t17360721-34-cd160" type="crimeDate">14th of June</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-34-off159 t17360721-34-cd160"></join> with Force and Arms, at the Parish of St. Mary White-chapel, the said Malden, &amp;c. feloniously did receive, house, lodge, comfort, maintain and harbour, against the Peace of Our Soveraign Lord the King, his Crown and Dignity
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alston. 
               <persName id="t17360721-34-person269">
                  Daniel 
                  Malden 
               <interp inst="t17360721-34-person269" type="surname" value="Malden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person269" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             escaped out of Newgate, after Condemnation, and was retaken: On Whitson-Monday Morning he made his Escape again, out of the Old Condemn'd Hold. I and several of our People made all the search we could after him, in order to retake him. On the Saturday before, he was brought down to this Court to receive fresh Judgment. After several Enquiries, I was informed, that one Germane a Smith, was sent for, to take his Fetters off, by Shelton: she confessed before my Lord-Mayor, that she harboured him, and she set her Name or her Mark to her Confession.</p>
               <p>Mr. Caldwell. She set her Mark to this Examination, and signed it voluntarily, after it had been read over to her.</p>
               <p>The Examination of Elizabeth Shelton s, taken the 17th of June before the Right Hon. Sir John Williams, Knt. Lord-Mayor, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Who saith, that on the 14th of June, about 11 o'Clock in the Evening, her Servant acquainted her, that Malden had again broke out of Newgate; and her Curiosity leading her to go to Malden's Room which joined to her House, she there saw him eating some Pig; and that she, this Examinant, applied to one Germane a Smith, to file off his Fetters, who refused, and said, he would not do it for an hundred Pounds; that she then returned to Malden, who said, D - n you all, you want me to stay 'till I am taken, and then he went away with his Irons on his Legs; and that she has not seen him since. She saith, that while she was in the Room, his Wife enquired how he made his Escape; he told her that pulling out a Knife, he loosened a Stone, and raised it with a Link of his Fetters; that he then went through into the Funnel, and let the Stone fall; that he stuck fast in the Funnel, and with Difficulty fell into the Common Shore; that when he got out of the Shore, he hid himself in an Engine, while the People that pursued passed by.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire he may be asked, if ever I came to see Malden while he was in Newgate?</p>
               <p>Alston. I cannot say I ever saw her with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-34-person270">
                  William 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17360721-34-person270" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person270" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Whitsun-Monday at Night, my Servant had been out of an Errand, and he came home, and said, he had seen Malden. You Blockhead, says I, you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210014"></xptr> have heard an old Woman's Story: No Master, say, he, I have really seen him, and another said he had seen him. Lord bless me, says I, if so many People have seen him, I will go see him my self. I went to Malden's Wife's Room and there I saw a Man sitting, with three or four Women round about him: and while I was there he put up his Legs, and pulled up, (as I thought) his Trowsers; but it seems they were the sleeves of his striped Jacket. This was in White's Yard, in Rosemary Lane: I cannot say whose House it was; I believe it was the Lodging of one of his Wive's: The Woman they call Malden's Wife, lives in that Room where I saw him. I did not know him, nor should I know him again if I was to see him; but I believe it was he, because I saw the Fetters upon his Legs, and the Rivets of a prodigious Bigness, and the great Links of the Chain, and the great Rivets. I cannot say I saw Shelton the Prisoner there.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alston. You told me this very Day, that she was there.</p>
               <p>Cooper. Well, I believe she was there. I knew the Woman before; I knew her vastly well; I live just by her in White's Yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Women were in the Room when you went in?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I cannot be positive how many.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any of them?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes, this Woman (the Prisoner) was in the Room; she was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Then why do you say, you do not know that she was there?</p>
               <p>Cooper. My Lord, I am cautious of hurting any Body.</p>
               <p>Q. But won't you take care not to hurt your self? now you say she was there.</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes; My Lord, she was there indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. What occasion'd his taking up his Trowsers?</p>
               <p>Cooper. He took them up in a Bravado, and laugh'd. I am sure I should know him again, because I saw two of his Teeth in the upper Part of his Mouth broke out.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be admitted into the House?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Several People told me they had seen him, and thinks I, this is an idle Fellow, I will go see him too. And they omitted ( admitted ) me into the House, and into the very Room where he was Mrs. Humphries, who lives there sometimes, said, I might go in, and see him, she knocked at the Door, and said - here is Mr. Cooper, so they let me in, and he shewed the Irons on his Legs in a Bravado, and laugh'd and said, he had more about him here, (putting his Hands on his Wast) a great many more.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nichols. Please to ask Mr. Cooper, if he has not seen Malden in the Prisoner's Apartment; he has told the same thing to me.</p>
               <p>Cooper. It was the Wife's Room, that I saw him in.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the Prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Cooper. In the same House, I believe; but I won't be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in any Room with the Prisoner Shelton?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Once or twice, I have been in a Room of hers.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her Room in the same House?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alston. My Lord, he owned to me, that he had seen Malden, in the Prisoner's Room.</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes, my Lord, I have been informed, it was Shelton's Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Shelton live?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Next Door to where I saw Malden, the Houses communicate, only there is a little Row of Pales between.</p>
               <p>Germane. On Whitsun-Monday, I was drinking at the Corner of White's Yard, at 12 o'Clock at Night; the prisoner Shelton came and called me out privately. She asked me, if she might put her Life into my Hands? I was shocked, and asked her what she meant? Can I trust you, says she? I do not know, says I; why then, says she, Malden has made his Escape out of Jayl, will you come and take his Fetters off? No, says I, not for an hundred Pounds; I won't wrong my Conscience, my King, nor my Country. She found I would not answer her Ends; and she desired,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210015"></xptr> if I would not do it, I would not betray him. I told her, I would not be concerned with any of them; and away I went home to bed, and came not out again, till next Morning.</p>
               <p>Temperance Germane, confirm'd the above Evidence</p>
               <p>Defence. The 14th of June, at Night, I was a Bed, and a Woman who uses Newgate-Market came up and said there was a sad Up roar; for Malden was got out again. Pshaw says I, 'tis impossible, but a Woman that I give 12 d. a Week to, to look after my Children while I am out, comes and says to me, there's Malden gone up Stairs: with that, says I, if God gives me Leave, I'll go and see him; when I came up, he was eating Pig, and he asked me to eat with him, - No, no, says I, eat it yourself. His Wife said, Oh! Daniel, how did you get out? and he put his Hand to his Pocket, and pulled out a Knife, by means of which he loosened a Stone, and put his Fetters in, to take it up; then he went down the Funnel, and there he said he stuck; but God brought him through it. How will you get your Irons off, says his Wife? I will go, says I, to Germane's and get him to take them off; but he refused, and I went back and told them he would not do it: G - d d - n you all says he, you want me to stay and be taken; with that he went down Stairs, with his Irons on, and I have never seen him since <rs id="t17360721-34-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-34-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
