<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340710-22">
               <interp inst="t17340710-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-22" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-22" type="date" value="17340710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-22-off88-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-defend157 t17340710-22-off88 t17340710-22-verdict92"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-22-off90-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-defend157 t17340710-22-off90 t17340710-22-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>27. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340710-22-defend157" type="defendantName">
                     Catharine
                      Bougle, alias <rs id="t17340710-22-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-defend157 t17340710-22-alias-4"></join>Tracey</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-defend157" type="surname" value="Bougle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-defend157" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-defend157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17340710-22-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               Hig Treason, in Coining 40 false and counterfeit Six-pences
            </rs>, <rs id="t17340710-22-cd89" type="crimeDate">August 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-off88 t17340710-22-cd89"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-off90 t17340710-22-cd89"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17340710-22-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               Coining 12 counterfeit Shillings
            </rs>, <rs id="t17340710-22-cd91" type="crimeDate">August 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-off88 t17340710-22-cd91"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-off90 t17340710-22-cd91"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-22-person158">
                  Ann
                   St. Laurence
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person158" type="surname" value="St. Laurence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person158" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner's Name is Tracey, but she goes by the Names Steward and Bougle.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Tracey was my Maiden Name, but my Husband's Name is Bougle.</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. She Lodg'd at Alice Dearing's, against the George in little Drury-lane, by the new Church in the Strand - In the beginning of August I met by chance my Brother-in-law 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person159">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person159" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person159" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and ask'd him where his Wife (my Sister) was; for since she was got in among these Coiners, I knew not where to find her. My Brother told me, I might meet with her at Alice Dearing's. So about 11 next Morning, I went to Dearing's, where I found only the Prisoner and my Brother, he told her that I was his Wife's Sister, and told me, that the Prisoner was Bett Tracey's Sister. Then he went to Work, and made some Money, which he threw into her Lap, and she cut off the knobs, and filed the Edges. In about an Hour's time Alice Dearing came in,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100009"></xptr> and after her my Sister. I staid till 3 a Clock in the afternoon. This was about the 9th or 10th of August, and about 4 days after I went to 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person160">
                  Christopher 
                  Strong 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person160" type="surname" value="Strong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person160" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Cellar; his Wife was with Child, and my Sister 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person161">
                  Margaret 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person161" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person161" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             introduced me to be the Nurse: there were my Brother and Sister, Mother Haycock, and her Daughter and Sons, the Prisoner and her Sister 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person162">
                  Betty 
                  Stracy 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person162" type="surname" value="Stracy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person162" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They had got 2 Iron Molds, one for Shillings and another for Six-pences, with something white in the middle. They melted Pint and half Pint Pewter Pots in a Fire-shovel over a Charcoal-fire, and then cut the Metal into small Pieces, which they put into a Pipe, and so melted the same again, and then pour'd it into the Molds, and threw Shillings out of one Mold, and Six-pences out of another.</p>
               <p>Council. Who did this?</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. My Brother made Six-pences, and gave them to the Prisoner, who cut off the Lumps, and pared the Money round, and filed the Edges in Imitation of Milling, and rubbed them with Flannel. She put one into my Hand, and said, It is a pity that any Body should be hang'd for their Ingenuity. When he was hot and tired, she took some of the Lumps she had cut off, and squeezing them together with her Teeth, put them into a Pipe, melted them, and pour'd the Metal into the Shilling Mold, and so made Shillings. Mother Haycook and her Daughter, and 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person163">
                  John 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person163" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person163" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             her Son, and 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person164">
                  Betty 
                  Tracey 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person164" type="surname" value="Tracey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person164" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were employ'd in making half Crowns, to carry into the Country - Tracey said, that Six-pences went off best at Publick-houses in Town; and that Tankards were the best Pewter for making Money - Mrs. Strong brought in some Charcoal - I stay'd there about an Hour - The Prisoner and I, and my Brother and Sister afterwards put off the Six-pences in Spittle-Fields; but the Prisoner put off the first in Cheapside, to an old Woman that sold Nuts and Gingerbread. I said it was a Shame to cheat such a poor Woman, and so I went back and gave her a good Six-pence for the bad one. Tracey went presently into the Country to make off the half Crowns, for the Country People were not so sharp as those in London; and I saw no more of her till October, the Night before my Brother and Sister were try'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Put her to the Virtue of her Oath, why she did not discover me sooner.</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. Because my Brother was concern'd with her. But after he was try'd, I heard that she was taken at Hammersmith, and committed to the Gatehouse; and then I inform'd Mr. North where she was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When my Sister was upon her Trial, did not you give Two-pence to get me into Court?</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And why did you not take me then?</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. Because your Sister hurry'd you away, and you got out of Court as soon as the Trial was over; and I saw you no more, 'till Alice Dearing told me you were in the Gatehouse for putting off bad Money at Hammersmith.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was taken the 4th of December, and kept 'till the 27th of April, which was near 5 Months, and you did not give your Information 'till the 4th of March.</p>
               <p>St. Laurence. I inform'd 6 Months ago, upon the Virtue of my Oath - You were sent from the Gatehouse to Hicks's-Hall, where you were try'd and acquitted.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That was for putting off bad Money; but why was I not try'd for Coining?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-22-person165">
                  Alice 
                  Dearing 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person165" type="surname" value="Dearing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person165" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person166">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person166" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person166" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was convicted of Coining when she first came from Ireland, which was about two Years ago; but I did not then know what Business she follow'd. She went back again, and came over a second Time, in August last, with the Prisoner. Before I had seen Wright, the Prisoner came to my Room, and told me Wright was come again, but that they had quarrel'd - How so? says I. Why, says the Prisoner, I made off 6 l. and she allow'd me but half a Guinea, tho' I ought to have had the best Part, for the Moulds were mine, and I made most of the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Put her to the Virtue of her Oath upon that.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100010"></xptr>Dearing. I am upon my Oath. And she said, she had but that half Guinea in the World, and therefore desir'd I would let her lie with my Children, 'till she could get another Lodging. I consented, and on the third Day she desir'd I would give her leave to work. What work? says I. You shall see, says she; and so she took the Moulds out of her Pocket, melted some Pewter in a Fire-Shovel, and then threw it on the Hearth, and cut it into small Pieces. Then she sent my Boy for a Pipe, put some Metal into it, and when it was hot, she held the Mould on her Knee thus - and pour'd the Metal in, and knock'd it thus - to settle. When it was cold she threw out a King William's Six-pence, plainer on the Cross side than the Head. After she had done, she knock'd the white Stuff out of the Moulds, ty'd them in one Cloth, and the Stuff in another - I was curious to see the Moulds, before she broke them; but she would not let me, for she said, she had sworn to let no Body see them, but those that had seen them before - She clipp'd the Edges of the Six-pences with her Scissars, and then scraped them with a Knife, and went to a Brasier's, the Corner of Catherine-Street, and bought a warded File, with which she filed them, and then rubb'd them, and boil'd them in the Soap and a yellow Stuff that Dyers use.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. St. Laurence said it was Cochineal.</p>
               <p>Dearing. You had several Colours - I went out with her that Night to a Brandy-shop, where she put off one, and then she went to look for Mrs. Strong, to go out with her. About two Weeks after this (having left her to look after my Children while I went out to work) I went home, and found the Prisoner and John Brown, and St. Laurence with her; the Prisoner open'd the Door with something in her Lap. I said, What have you been doing? She answer'd, You know - St. Laurence shook her Head at me; and Brown being no great Acquaintance, went out. Then the Prisoner open'd her Apron, and shew'd me near 100 King William's Six-pences, and said, that she and Brown made them. I told her she should do no more there, for if my Husband should know of it he'd sacrifice me. She promis'd she would not; but she would find out 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person167">
                  Moll 
                  Haycock 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person167" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person167" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was her Scholar. But yet about Bartholomew-Tide, I caught her at it again with John Brown. I thought I had warn'd you of this before, says I. Well, says she, the Metal is just melted, and when I have made this out, I'll make no more in your Room; and then she made 20 Six-pences and some Shillings. The last pour'd was a half Six-pence, for there was not Metal enough for a whole one - As she was going down Stairs, she met her Sister Betty Tracey, who told her she had found out Moll. Haycock.</p>
               <p>After this the Prisoner bought some Necklaces, and other Pedlars Wares, and went into the Country, thro' Oxford to Bybury, 70 Miles from London, and I went with her. She had some Money of her own making, some of her Sister's, and some of Brown's, and we put off 6l. in that Journey.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. North and she are both in one Injunction - What Conversation had you with Wright at her second coming over?</p>
               <p>Dearing. She desir'd me to go out with her, and gave me a Six pence to put off in Lombard-Street, and I was taken up for it, and try'd at Guild-Hall, and acquitted.</p>
               <p>Court. Why did you let the Prisoner continue so long in your House, if you were so fearful your Husband should know it?</p>
               <p>Dearing. The Truth is, I was willing to learn to Coin myself, but could not, for they would never let me into the Secret.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in Jail when 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person168">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person168" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person168" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was try'd, and why did you not inform against me then?</p>
               <p>Dearing. I did not think it was you, because you were committed by the Name of Bougle, and I never knew you by any other Name than Tracey and Stuart.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was committed by the Name of Tracey - But you had need talk of Names, when you go by three Names your self - Dearing, Crouder, and Bunting.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-22-person169">
                  Winifred 
                  Swinney 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person169" type="surname" value="Swinney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person169" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I secur'd the Prisoner.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100011"></xptr> My Acquaintance begun by means of a Nephew, who was acquainted with Brown, who left him in the Lurch in the Gate-house - In last August, I went to Strong's Cellar, to get some Subsistence for my Nephew, and there was Brown and the Prisoner. She took some melted Metal out of an Iron ladle with a Pipe, and pour'd it into a little round Thing like Iron, and she open'd it, and Six-pences or Shillings came out. They would not let me have the iron Thing in my Hand, for fear of letting me into the Secret - I saw her Coin but three times, one Day she made Shillings, and two Days Six-pences. After they were cast, she clipp'd and filed them, and put 'em into her Handkerchief, and bent them in her Mouth Then she got a Ha'porth of Hemlock and a Quarter of a Pound of Soap, and put them into a Pot with Water and the Money; and Strong's Wife blow'd the Charcoal fire to make it boil - I thought it had been spoil'd, and they were going to melt it over-again - After this I met the Prisoner in Holborn. We went into a Gin-shop, and she gave a Six-pence to change I had her Apron to wash, there were several Holes in it, and I ask'd her how they came? She said she had burnt them with the Metal.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. Some time about December last, the Prisoner, and Mary and 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person170">
                  Ann 
                  Haycock 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person170" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person170" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person170" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were sent to the Gatehouse for putting off bad Money at Hammersmith. They were try'd at Hicks's-Hall, and acquitted. But on the 14th of February, which was before the Trial, St. Laurence inform'd me that she had seen them and others Coin in Dearing's Lodgings.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And why did not you indict us then for Coining?</p>
               <p>Mr. North. Because I was willing to keep the Information secret as long as I could, there being others in it who were not then taken. But when the Prisoner and the Haycocks were acquitted, I was oblig'd to discover my Information in order to detain them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Then why did not you find a Bill in April Sessions?</p>
               <p>Mr. North. St. Laurence was then gone out of the Way, and I knew not where to find her, and so they were discharged; but were taken again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person171">
                  Jack 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person171" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person171" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had her in his Company - Don't deny it, Jack.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. I met with St. Laurence afterwards, and she said she had been to see her Sister 
               <persName id="t17340710-22-person172">
                  Margaret 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17340710-22-person172" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person172" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to Gravesend</p>
               <p>The Jury found her <rs id="t17340710-22-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17340710-22-punish93" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-punish93" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-22-punish93" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="burning"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-22-defend157 t17340710-22-punish93"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
