<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350522-27">
               <interp inst="t17350522-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-27" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-27" type="date" value="17350522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350522-27-off151-c203" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-defend270 t17350522-27-off151 t17350522-27-verdict154"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350522-27-off151-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-defend272 t17350522-27-off151 t17350522-27-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>36, 37. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-defend270" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Pinchbeck 
                  <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend270" type="surname" value="Pinchbeck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend270" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend270" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , the <rs id="t17350522-27-deflabel150" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-defend270 t17350522-27-deflabel150"></join> of John Pinchbeck, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-defend272" type="defendantName">
                     Joice 
                     Hunt 
                  <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend272" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend272" type="given" value="Joice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-defend272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350522-27-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350522-27-victim274" type="victimName">
                           Susan 
                           Wright 
                        <interp inst="t17350522-27-victim274" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-27-victim274" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-27-victim274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-off151 t17350522-27-victim274"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of the said 
                     <persName id="t17350522-27-person275">
                        John 
                        Pinchbeck 
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person275" type="surname" value="Pinchbeck"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-27-person275" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-27-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , putting her in fear, and taking from her thirteen Shillings
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350522-27-cd152" type="crimeDate">March 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-off151 t17350522-27-cd152"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-person276">
                  Susan 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17350522-27-person276" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person276" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I ow'd the Prisoner Mrs. Pinchbeck some Money, and went to her House in <placeName id="t17350522-27-crimeloc153">Field Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-27-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="Field Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-27-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-27-off151 t17350522-27-crimeloc153"></join> to pay her eight Shillings in Part. But she did not approve it, and threw the Money about the Floor. Her Maid Joice Hunt, (the other Prisoner) pick'd it up and gave it me again, and I put it to five Shillings more which I had in my Pocket. Then Pinchbeck bid her Maid shut the Door, and said, she'd see what the Old Bitch had got in her Pocket. With that she took me by the Throat, put her Hand in my Pocket, and took out thirteen Shillings and two Thimbles. Then she said, I'll see what the Old bitch has got in her Bosom. And not content with hunting in my Bosom as low as my Wake, she punch'd me, and Bruised me, and beat with in an Inch of my Life - I was shut up in the Parlor above an Hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-person277">
                  Rebecca 
                  Bristol 
               <interp inst="t17350522-27-person277" type="surname" value="Bristol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person277" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Mother was missing above an Hour. When she came home, I said, Mother, where have you been? She burst out a crying, and said, she had been at Mrs. Pinchbecks, who had picked her Pocket of all her Money - I thought she would have died that Night; and for my part, I was six Months gone, and miscarried upon it.</p>
               <p>Pinchbeck. I have subsisted this Woman these fourteen Years, because she was a poor Widow, and I was willing to relieve the Widow and the Fatherless; I have lent at times twenty or thirty Pounds and never took a Farthing Interest.</p>
               <p>S. Wright. But you sold Wine and -</p>
               <p>Pinchbeck. I lent her thirty Shillings when she put her Boy 'Prentice to a Weaver in Bridewell, and when he came out of his Time, I lent her seven Pound to buy him a Loom. She was seven Years in paying me four Pound nine Shillings - I lent her thirty Shillings but last Christmas, and she beg'd me to make it up four Pound. And when she should have paid me, she was arrested by a Tally Man: Upon which her Son came and intruded on my Goodness for twenty Shillings more to help her out.</p>
               <p>After this, she offer'd me twenty seven Shillings towards the five Pound, and promis'd to pay me the rest Weekly, and accordingly, she was to have brought me nineteen Shillings on the Day she says I robb'd her. But she brought no more than thirteen Shillings which she put into my Hand; and as I was telling it, she said, Hold! I have given you too much, and so she catch'd it all out of my Hand again, and desired me to let her have a Crown of it. How can you say there's too much? Says I, when I ought to have eighteen Shillings. God D - ye, for a Bitch, says she, and catches up a Quart Pot, I'll split your Scull. But my Maid stepping between. I got no Mischief. This was on the eighth of March, and on the sixteenth, I arrested her, upon which, Lawyer Theobald put it into her Head<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173505220016"></xptr> to prosecute me, and so on the nineteenth she got a Warrant against me.</p>
               <p>S. Wright. When she lent me Money, she made me spend good part of it at her House in Brandy and Wine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-person278">
                  Daniel 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17350522-27-person278" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person278" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She keeps a Linnen Draper's Shop.</p>
               <p>S. Wright. She's a Tally Woman.</p>
               <p>Mr. Just. Robe. On the twenty first of March, she was brought before me, by vertue of a Warrant from Ald. Brocas for violently assaulting and beating 
               <persName id="t17350522-27-person279">
                  Susan 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17350522-27-person279" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person279" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and taking thirteen Shillings out of her Pocket; I kept her above an Hour, but neither Wright nor any body else appearing against her, I took good Bail, and returned the Recognizance to Hick's Hall - Theobald afterwards came to me and threatned me for taking Bail in such a Case</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-27-person280">
                  William 
                  Dakin 
               <interp inst="t17350522-27-person280" type="surname" value="Dakin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person280" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her thirteen Years, her Circumstances are such, that she has no occasion to act in such a manner; and her Principles are such, that, I believe she would not.</p>
               <p>Dr. - She lives just by me in Field Lane, and has as honest a Character as any Woman in England - She has been my Patient these twenty Years.</p>
               <p>Mr. Roundtree. She has large Dealings, and a very honest Character.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17350522-27-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-27-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> them, and the Court granted a Copy of their Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
