<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350416-20">
               <interp inst="t17350416-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350416-20" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350416-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350416-20" type="date" value="17350416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350416-20-off84-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350416-20-defend120 t17350416-20-off84 t17350416-20-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>20. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350416-20-defend120" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Durant 
                  <interp inst="t17350416-20-defend120" type="surname" value="Durant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-defend120" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-defend120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350416-20-off84" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-off84" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-off84" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Guinea and a half
            </rs>, the Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17350416-20-victim122" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Walmsley 
                  <interp inst="t17350416-20-victim122" type="surname" value="Walmsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-victim122" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-victim122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350416-20-off84 t17350416-20-victim122"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17350416-20-cd85" type="crimeDate">March 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350416-20-off84 t17350416-20-cd85"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350416-20-person123">
                  James 
                  Walmsley 
               <interp inst="t17350416-20-person123" type="surname" value="Walmsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person123" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between eight and nine at night as I was going home, my Heels were tripp'd up near Temple Bar by a Man who pretended to help me up again; he picked my Pocket of my Watch, and said, he would carry me to an honest House where I might clean my self. He took me to one Mrs. Warwick's in <placeName id="t17350416-20-crimeloc86">Sheer Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350416-20-crimeloc86" type="placeName" value="Sheer Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350416-20-crimeloc86" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350416-20-off84 t17350416-20-crimeloc86"></join>, where I found the Landlady Warwick and the Prisoner who was her <rs id="t17350416-20-deflabel87" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350416-20-defend120 t17350416-20-deflabel87"></join>, and another Woman. The Man call'd for a Pint of Wine, and I said to the Women, This Man has robbed me of my Watch; upon which he ran out. Then the Woman scraped the Dirt off my Cloaths, after which I gave Warwick half a Guinea to change for the Wine. But when I asked her for my Change. She told me she must have that for cleaning my Cloaths; and she promised to help me to my Watch again. Then they shut the Door upon me, and the other Woman held my Hands while Warwick took half a Guinea out of my Pocket, and she said she'd keep it to get my Watch. We sat down for half an Hour, and then they got a Guinea more from me in the same manner, but I got that again by main force, though it was not long before Warwick got it from me a second time. As for the Prisoner she did nothing to me all the while, but stood by, only she went twice to the Door, and held it that I should not get out. I staid there three Hours, and was as sober then as I am now, but the Door being shut I knew not how to help my self, and was forced to bear with this usage for fear they should do me a mischief. There is a private Door that goes out of this House into another as bad (where one Bishop keeps a Gin Shop) and, as I have been informed, when a Man is robbed in one of these Houses, the Thieves whip through this Door into the other House, and so escape. And so I was served at last, for Warwick, and the other Woman got off this way, and left me and the Prisoner together. I asked her where they were gone, and she said she would go and find them - I went home and came again next Day to take them up, but could meet with none but the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Man came to our House with two Women, 
               <persName id="t17350416-20-person124">
                  Moll 
                  Nutton 
               <interp inst="t17350416-20-person124" type="surname" value="Nutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person124" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17350416-20-person125">
                  Beck 
                  Bean 
               <interp inst="t17350416-20-person125" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person125" type="given" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and called for a Pint of Wine, which I carried in, and then left them together.</p>
               <p>Walmsley. There was no Person went into the House with me but the Man who picked my Pocket, nor did I know what a House it was. The Jury <rs id="t17350416-20-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350416-20-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
