<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-42">
               <interp inst="t17370420-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-42" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-42" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-42-off228-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-42-defend369 t17370420-42-off228 t17370420-42-verdict231"></join>
         
               <p>52. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-42-defend369" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Moreton 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-42-defend369" type="surname" value="Moreton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-defend369" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-defend369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-42-off228" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-off228" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-off228" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 3 l a Silver Seal, value 10 s. and a Brass ditto, value 2 d. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-42-victim371" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Vaus 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-42-victim371" type="surname" value="Vaus"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-42-victim371" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-42-victim371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-42-off228 t17370420-42-victim371"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17370420-42-cd229" type="crimeDate">March 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-42-off228 t17370420-42-cd229"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Vaus. On the 17th of March, about 7 or 8 in the Evening, I was going to my Habitation, and over-against <placeName id="t17370420-42-crimeloc230">St. Magnus's Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-42-crimeloc230" type="placeName" value="St. Magnus's Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-42-crimeloc230" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-42-off228 t17370420-42-crimeloc230"></join> upon the Bridge, I was assaulted by the Prisoner; whether he run his Head against my Breast, or whether he gave me a Blow with his Fist, I cannot tell, but he took the Watch out of my Pocket directly. I miss'd it directly upon the Assault.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel it as it was drawing out?</p>
               <p>Vaus. Yes, I did, and I pursu'd him immediately, and took him: I found nothing upon him, 'tis true, but I saw him throw it away. This is the Watch, the Name is Jackson, and the Number 2020, and here's the two Knives that were taken out of his Pocket when we searched him. After he had robb'd me, I pursu'd him, and he threw me down, and kneel'd on my private Parts in such a Manner, that I had like to have been ruin'd; but this Porter here came to my Assistance, so we carried him to the Constable, and he denied the Fact, and said, I follow'd another Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you follow another Person, and take hold of him, before you seiz'd me?</p>
               <p>Vaus. No, I follow'd him, and took hold of him only.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he was not much in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Vaus. I had not drank so much as a Pint of Beer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was so much in Liquor, that the Man at the Ale-house, where he carried me, would not let him have any Thing, but told him, he had had too much already.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200027"></xptr>Vaus. The Man of the House did say, he did not desire our Company on such an Occasion.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not offer to make it up for 10 s.</p>
               <p>Vaus. I never made any such Offer at all: I told him he was a Rogue and a Villain, and I would bring him to Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-42-person372">
                  Daniel 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17370420-42-person372" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-person372" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That's my Name: I was going Home to my Family that same Night, and just at the Leather sellers Shop, by Magnus Corner, I saw a Tumult, there was a Parcel of People, and this Gentleman in the middle of them I went to see what was the Matter, and he turn'd to me and said he had lost his Watch, and away he ran, crying - stop Thief. I am willing to take any Body's Part that's injur'd, and to serve my Country, so, (tho' I never saw the Gentleman before in my Life) I ran with him, he caught hold of the Prisoner, but he was soon upon the Ground, - the Prisoner was too hard for him, he laid him upon his Back in the Street; but I took him off, and held him by the Collar: Presently up came 2 or 3 Men, who I suppose were the Prisoner's Companions, but seeing I was a rough sturdy sort of a Fellow, they did not care to have any Thing to say to me. I told the Gentleman 'twas a weighty Concern, and asked him if he was positive to the Man; he said, this is the Man, I'm sure 'twas he, -</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark at that Time?</p>
               <p>Cross. Yes, but there were Lamps all around us. The Gentleman desired me to get a Constable; I said I could get a Constable presently, for I was known thereabouts - I carry Coals at Coal-Harbour - so I had them to Mr. Tricket's at the 3 Tunns in Thames street, and we had not been long there, but in comes this young Man with the Watch in his Hand; - here, Sir, says he, I heard you have lost a Watch, and I make bold to bring it you, I kick'd it before me in the Street; but the Gentleman did not believe him, so he charg'd the Constable with him and the Prisoner too.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you charge the Constable with the Lad, that brought you the Watch? (to Vaus.)</p>
               <p>Vaus. Because I thought he was concern'd with the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prosecutor appear to be positive to the Prisoner, before the Lad came in?</p>
               <p>Cross. Yes; he was positive to him; I took him off from the Gentleman upon the Ground, and would have tripp'd up my Heels too, and would have got away, but I was too many for him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if I struggled with him?</p>
               <p>Cross. Yes; and I had 2 or 3 about me like your self; they seemed to be much as honest Men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-42-person373">
                  James 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17370420-42-person373" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-person373" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I was coming over the Bridge, and I happen'd to pick this Watch up, about half an Hour after 7 o'clock at Night; T'was some Time in March, but I can't justly tell the Day. I place'd it up right against St. Magnus Church, and carried it, the Case in one Hand, and the Watch in the other, to the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether the Watch and Case was together or seperate?</p>
               <p>Price. I found the Case first, and the Watch afterwards; I trod upon it, and my Shoes happening to be bad at that Time, it hurt my Foot, so I stoop'd down to see what it was, and 2 Lads seeing me pick it up, told me a Gentleman had just lost a Watch, so I carried it to him directly.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not the Prosecutor offer to make it up, as I was going to the Counter?</p>
               <p>Price. No; I can't say any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. It appears it was dark or duskish; by what Light did you distinguish the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Vaus. I distinguish'd him directly; I follow'd and pursu'd him by the Light of the Day (I might say) for 'twas not shut in, though the Lamps were li't; I saw him by the Lamps too, and am sure of the Person.</p>
               <p>Defence. I had been over the Bridge that Night, and coming along, I saw the Gentleman push a Man away from him, and heard him say he had lost his Watch. I went into the Crowd and asked him what was the Matter; he immediately turn'd about and ran after a Man, and caught hold of him, but the Fellow got away from him, and then, because he would be sure of somebody he laid hold of me. He was very much in Liquor, so he tumbled down, and pull'd me down with him, then this Porter came up and laid hold of me. 'Tis a very plausible Thing indeed, that the Watch should be thrown away, and the Glass should not be broke. <rs id="t17370420-42-verdict231" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-verdict231" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17370420-42-punish232" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-42-punish232" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-42-defend369 t17370420-42-punish232"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
