<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370114-9">
               <interp inst="t17370114-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-9" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-9" type="date" value="17370114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-9-off39-c55" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-9-defend74 t17370114-9-off39 t17370114-9-verdict41"></join>
         
               <p>10. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-9-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Friend 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-9-defend74" type="surname" value="Friend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-defend74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-defend74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370114-9-defloc38">Ickenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-9-defloc38" type="placeName" value="Ickenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-9-defloc38" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-9-defend74 t17370114-9-defloc38"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370114-9-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370114-9-victim76" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Haydon 
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim76" type="surname" value="Haydon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim76" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain open Field near the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him two Linnen Bags, value 6 d. four Pounds of Beef, value 8 d. one Quart of Peas, value 2 d and 6 d. in Money, the Property of the said Haydon, and a Wooden Bottle of spirituous Liquors, value 2 s. 6 d. the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370114-9-victim78" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Owen 
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim78" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim78" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-9-victim78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>Haydon. On Saturday Night last, I was met by the Prisoner coming from <placeName id="t17370114-9-crimeloc40">Uxbridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-9-crimeloc40" type="placeName" value="Uxbridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-9-crimeloc40" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-9-off39 t17370114-9-crimeloc40"></join>, in the first Road near the Cart Road, at a Stile. 'Twas between 6 and 7 at Night. I cry'd who's there, and knowing the Prisoner, I call'd him by his Name; but he darted his Stick at me, cut a great Gash in my Throat, and knock'd me backwards: Then he came over the Stile, and was making another Blow at me; but I slipp'd on one Side, and avoided it. He took from me all the Goods mention'd in the Indictment; so I went Home and got two Men to search after him, but they could not find him. I told my Wife how I was robb'd, and there was a great Congregation of People, who went again to his House; I tax'd him with it at his House; he was in a very great Sweat, and said (as how ) he knew nothing of it. He lives but a Mile and a half from me, and is lame of one Hand; he's the Man and no body else. I have gone in Danger of my Life on his Account before now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any of your Goods again?</p>
               <p>Haydon. Yes, in a Dog-house of the Duke of Bolton's, about 10 or 20 Pole from the Place where I was robb'd. My Lord, he has acted very Ugly by me before now.</p>
               <p>Q. So you think he robb'd you for robbing's sake, and out of Malice!</p>
               <p>Haydon. I don't know what he did it for, not I.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-9-person79">
                  William 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17370114-9-person79" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-person79" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Neighbour between the two Men: When Haydon came Home, I heard he had been robb'd by the Prisoner, so I went to him (the Prisoner) and I found him in a great Heat; I asked him how he came to be in such a sweat: He said, he always sweat very much when he walk'd. The Prosecutor, my Lord, has a very good Character, and the Prisoner a very indifferent one. 'Tis true, he is lame, but he has often made use of his lame Hand: for some Time ago he got his Bread by his Labour, but now he's kept by the Parish, because he is lame of his Hand and his Leg; he is very lame indeed, at some Times, and at others, he walks better.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know any Thing dishonest by me?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, I don't, but John, you have a very indifferent Character.</p>
               <p>Another. All the Parish will give Haydon a good Character; the other, they will not.</p>
               <p>Another. The Prisoner is a Man of a very ill Principle, and I believe he was guilty, because we never catch'd the Prosecutor in any ill demeanour. The Prisoner is often out o'Nights pretty late, and I think it looks as if he was guilty.</p>
               <p>Defence. 'Tis easy to see, that I am a lame Man: My right Hand is lame, and my right Leg and Thigh is not bigger than my Wrist: I am past my Labour and cannot work for my Bread, so I have Assistance from the Parish, and therefore they have done this out of Spite. <rs id="t17370114-9-verdict41" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-9-verdict41" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
