<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-75">
               <interp inst="t17390502-75" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-75" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-75" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-75" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-75-off334-c319" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-75-defend490 t17390502-75-off334 t17390502-75-verdict337"></join>
         
               <p>320. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-75-defend490" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Harris 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-75-defend490" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-defend490" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-defend490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-75-off334" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-off334" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-off334" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-75-victim492" type="victimName">
                           Euphemer 
                           Sadler 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-75-victim492" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-75-victim492" type="given" value="Euphemer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-75-victim492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-75-off334 t17390502-75-victim492"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Alley and open Place, near the King's Highway, called Catherine Wheel Alley, putting her in Fear, and taking from her five Linnen Aprons, val. 24 s. two Linnen Shifts, val. 10 s. three Cambrick Handker chiefs, val. 7 s. 6 d. two Linnen Caps, val. 10 s. two Cotton Handkerchiefs, val. 2 s. three Silk Handkerchiefs, val. 6 s two checqu'd Aprons, val. 8 s. a Pair of Scissars, val. 2 s. 6 d. a Brass Thimble, val. 1 d. a Silk Hood, val. 4 s. 6 d. and 5 s. 6 d. in Money
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Sadler. On the <rs id="t17390502-75-cd335" type="crimeDate">7th of April</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-75-off334 t17390502-75-cd335"></join> I was coming from my Place, and going to my Lodging with my Cloaths, about Eleven o'Clock at Night. In <placeName id="t17390502-75-crimeloc336">Catherine Wheel Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-75-crimeloc336" type="placeName" value="Catherine Wheel Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-75-crimeloc336" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-75-off334 t17390502-75-crimeloc336"></join>, the Prisoner and three Men met me as I was going under the Gate-way; the Prisoner took hold of my Throat with his right Hand, the others held me by the Nape of the Neck; the Prisoner said, - d - mn you, if you call out, or speak a Word, I'll dash your Brains out, or cut your Throat: Then they all hustled me down to a narrow Place, and one of the other Men said, d - mn you, why don't you knock her down, Harris. Upon that, the Prisoner caught me under the Chin, beat me down backwards, and took my Bundle from under my Arm; then he tore my Apron from my Sides, and search'd my Pockets; he took 5 s. 6 d. some Halfpence, a Pair of Scissars, and a Brass Thimble, out of my right Hand Pocket, and a Silk Handkerchief out of the other. I cry'd out, - Fire! - Murder! upon which the Prisoner turn'd back, and said, - You Bitch. - there's no Fire, - 'tis only your Impudence: The three Fellows ran away, and he went into an Alehouse, the Cock and Magpye; I went in after him, and took hold of him, begging the Assistance of the People in the House, and telling them, This Man has robb'd me! Upon which he was seiz'd, and carry'd before Justice Heusch, in Spittlefields, but before the Constable carry'd him there, he and one of his Watchmen desired me to make it up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How came you to know my Face from the rest of those who were about you?</p>
               <p>Sadler. The Prisoner took hold of my Throat, and I put up my Hands to save myself, and felt a Finger wanting upon his right Hand; I observ'd his Want of it immediately on my going into the Alehouse, and upon that I took him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not I charge the Constable with you?</p>
               <p>Sadler. Yes; and he said, if he went to the Watch-house, I should go too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-75-person493">
                  Thomas 
                  Osborn 
               <interp inst="t17390502-75-person493" type="surname" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-person493" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Prisoner a good Character, and said his Business was to sell Fish, Fruit, &amp;c. about the Streets, and to drive a Barrow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-75-person494">
                  John 
                  Bowers 
               <interp inst="t17390502-75-person494" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-person494" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore, he officiated for the Land-lord at the Cock and Magpye; and that the Prosecutrix came in between Ten and Eleven, with a Man in a Sea-faring Dress, who seem'd to be her Husband; that she complain'd of being wet with the Rain, and had her Gown thrown over her Head; and upon her observing him to look earnestly on them, they drank up a Pint of Beer, and went away: That the Prisoner came in about an Hour after she was gone, to shelter himself from the Rain; and as the Watchman went 12, the Woman came in, and asked for the four Sailors that came in there, for they had robb'd her, (she said) by G - d, between that Door and the Passage, tho' she had cry'd out, Fire! That upon the Prisoner's laughing at her, she charg'd him with being one of the Persons, and he staid till the Officer was call'd, and then she said, she had nothing to charge him with, and would have gone off, had not he detain'd her; upon which she swore she would charge him with the Robbery, whether he had robb'd her or not.</p>
               <p>Several Persons appeared to the Prisoner's Character, and the Jury <rs id="t17390502-75-verdict337" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-75-verdict337" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
