<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-4">
               <interp inst="t17390906-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-4" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-4" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-4-off16-c38" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-4-defend47 t17390906-4-off16 t17390906-4-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>432. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-4-defend47" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Albin 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-4-defend47" type="surname" value="Albin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-defend47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-defend47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390906-4-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-4-victim49" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim49" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim49" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim49" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-4-victim51" type="victimName">
                           Hannah 
                           Prior 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim51" type="surname" value="Prior"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim51" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Field, and open Place near the King's Highway, putting them in fear, and taking a Gold Ring, val. 18 s. and 17 s. in Money, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-4-victim53" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim53" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , from the Person of Ann his <rs id="t17390906-4-viclabel17" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-4-victim49 t17390906-4-viclabel17"></join>; and a brass Ring. val. an Halfpenny, and 2 s. 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-4-victim55" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Prior 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim55" type="surname" value="Prior"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim55" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , from the Person of Hannah his Wife, <rs id="t17390906-4-cd18" type="crimeDate">May 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-4-off16 t17390906-4-cd18"></join>.</p>
               <p>Ann Price. On the 21st of May last, Mrs. Prior and I were coming from Kilburn towards London, between Three and Four o'Clock in the Afternoon, and the Prisoner met us about two or three Fields from <placeName id="t17390906-4-crimeloc19">Mary-bone</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-4-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="Mary-bone"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-4-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-4-off16 t17390906-4-crimeloc19"></join>: He came in at one End of the Field, and we come in at the other. The Minute I saw him, I had a Dread upon me that he would rob us; for he came on with a sauntering Pace, and had a Stick in his Hand:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060004"></xptr> I said to Mrs. Prior, - we shall certainly be robb'd! No, said she, I hope not, - pray take Courage. When the Prisoner came up to us, I call'd out, - Tom Prior, Tom Prior (which is Mrs. Prior's Husband's Name) - you sha'n't go abroad with us any more, if you must stay behind to look Birds-nests. Mr Prior was not with us, but I said this, that the Prisoner might imagine he was not far off; and upon this he pass'd by us, and went about twenty or thirty Yards beyond us; then he turn'd about and follow'd us, and when he overtook us, he said, - Aye, God damn you, Madam, I'll give you something besides Birds-nests, and immediately he put his right Hand into his left Side-pocket, and pulled out a Pistol of a very uncommon Size, and clapp'd it to my left Breast, crying damn you, Madam, your Money and Rings. I had none but my Wedding ring, which I pull'd off, and told him, I had no other, except that, which was my Wedding-ring, and he should have it; when he had got it, he still kept his Pistol to my Breast, and stamping with his Foot on the Ground, he cry'd, - d-mn you, your Money; then I put my Hand into my Pocket, and pull'd out about seven Shillings, some Half-pence, and a Cork-screw, which he threw at me again. After this, he stamp'd again, and said to Mrs. Prior, - And D-mn you, Madam, your Money: I saw her give him some Money, but how much I cannot tell. All the while he was demanding Mrs. Prior's Money, and taking it from her, he kept the Pistol to my Breast; and when he had got what he could, he said, - Now, damn you, go on, and you'll meet two more presently; this struck such a Terror into us, than we ran out of the Path way, a-cross the Fields, and over two or three Ditches, to a Farm-house, kept by one Mr. Francis, and when we got there, we were ready to die. I never saw the Prisoner before that Time, but I am positive he is the Man. He was taken up for another Robbery, and I went to see him in Newgate, and knew him immediately: He has got a Wig on now, but he had none when he robb'd us; his Hat was flapp'd, and he had a Bough which he play'd about in his Mouth. When I saw him in Newgate, he abus'd me, and call'd me several Bitches, when he found I knew him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-4-person56">
                  Thomas 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17390906-4-person56" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-person56" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Constable of Pancras. I had a Warrant brought me from Mr. Deveil, against the Prisoner, by Mr. Griffin, on Suspicion of breaking open his Shop, and stealing a Parcel of Books. I took him (I think) on the 9th of August, in his Father's Hay-loft, at Tottenham-Court, pretty near the Turnpike, where I found him hid behind the Hay. I did not know any thing of this Robbery then, nor have I had any Discourse with him concerning it since. He made no Confession of any Kind to me; but he seem'd to be under a great Surprize when I took him, and made but little Resistance.</p>
               <p>This Witness inform'd the Court, that Hannah Prior was taken with an Apoplectick Fit the Day before this Trial came on; and that he call'd at her House, as he came to the Court, and found her but just alive.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have no Witnesses to call. I never did any such thing in my Life; and 'tis hard to take away my Life for nothing at all. I never was guilty of such a thing, as God's my Saviour, and you my Judge. <rs id="t17390906-4-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390906-4-punish21" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-4-punish21" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-4-defend47 t17390906-4-punish21"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
