<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-48">
               <interp inst="t17350116-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-48" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-48" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-48-off205-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-48-defend307 t17350116-48-off205 t17350116-48-verdict208"></join>
         
               <p>51. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-48-defend307" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17350116-48-defend307" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-defend307" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-defend307" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350116-48-off205" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-off205" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-off205" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350116-48-victim309" type="victimName">
                           Margaret 
                           Todd 
                        <interp inst="t17350116-48-victim309" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-48-victim309" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-48-victim309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-48-off205 t17350116-48-victim309"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Place called <placeName id="t17350116-48-crimeloc206">Dumb's Alley, near the Highway, in the Parish of St George Bloomsbury</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-crimeloc206" type="placeName" value="Dumb's Alley, near the Highway, in the Parish of St George Bloomsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-crimeloc206" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-48-off205 t17350116-48-crimeloc206"></join>. putting her in fear, and taking from her a Sattin Gown, five Shifts, six Aprons, a Handkerchief, a Silk Hood, eight Caps, a Petticoat, a Pair of Gloves, a Fan, a Silk Knot. two Combs, and a Cambrick Head
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350116-48-cd207" type="crimeDate">November 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-48-off205 t17350116-48-cd207"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-48-person310">
                  Margaret 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person310" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person310" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person310" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the thirtieth of November I came away from my Service in the Meuse, and between seven and eight at Night I was going to my Lodging in St. Giles's with my Cloaths pack'd up in a Bundle. I saw the Prisoner first in Holborn. She followed me a little way, and then I thought I had got quit of her; but as I was turning out of Holborn into Dumb's Alley, she came and took hold of my Bundle and offer'd to carry it for me. I told her there was no occasion, and so I went forward. She followed me, pushed me down three times, and when I was upon my Knees, she took away my Bundle The last time that she pushed me down I broke my Face against the Wall - Dumb's Alley is pretty long and very narrow, and I saw no Houses that had Doors opening into it. I cryed out, and two Men coming up to me, I told them how I had been robb'd; they run into Holborn, and stopt a wrong Woman. But afterwards they met with a Carman, by whose means we found the Prisoner a bed in a two Penny Lodging in Fletcher's Court, in Church-Street. She had then got my Handkerchief about her Neck though she afterwards made it away. But these other Things, the Sattin Gown, three Shifts, two Aprons. Cambrick Head Cloths, and three Caps were found in her Landlady 
               <persName id="t17350116-48-person311">
                  Rebecca 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person311" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person311" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person311" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Possession. The Prisoner had pawn'd them, and Butler had redeem'd them and bought them outright. The risoner made a Confession before Justice Mitford in Wild Court, and it was taken in Writing, but she would not sign it - I am<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160014"></xptr> positive that she is the Woman that robbed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-48-person312">
                  Rebecca 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person312" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person312" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner ow'd me a little Money, and told me she had pawn'd such and such Goods at the Golden-Ball in King-Street by the Seven-Dials. She went with me to the Pawn-brokers, and I fetch'd out these Goods on the Tuesday, and on Wednesday she was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-48-person313">
                  John 
                  Sample 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person313" type="surname" value="Sample"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person313" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I and 
               <persName id="t17350116-48-person314">
                  James 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person314" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person314" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were going to my Masters, which is four Doors beyond Dumb's Alley, we saw the Prosecutor with a Bundle, and the Prisoner having hold of her Arm, and they went up the Alley. At the end next Holborn, a Woman past us with a Bundle under her Arm, and when we came towards the other end, we saw the Prosecutor under an Arch that leads into High-Street, Bloomsbury. Lord Master! says she to me, the Woman has robbed me. We went afterwards to a Pawn-brokers, and from thence to Bishop's Brandy Shop, and there we met with a Carman, who by the Description we gave of the Prisoner, said he believed he knew her. He directed us for farther Information to a Woman who carried us to the Prisoner's Lodging.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-48-person315">
                  Ann 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17350116-48-person315" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person315" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Sister to the Prosecutrix. That Night as my Sister left her Service, she came home to me about eight at Night with her Face cut and very bloody, she told me she had been robb'd, and I know these Goods to be hers.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I found these Goods at the upper End of Dumb's Alley, and there was no Soul in the Alley but my self when I pick'd them up.</p>
               <p>The Jury found her <rs id="t17350116-48-verdict208" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-verdict208" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350116-48-punish209" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-48-punish209" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-48-defend307 t17350116-48-punish209"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
