<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341016-5">
               <interp inst="t17341016-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-5" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-5" type="date" value="17341016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341016-5-off23-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-defend59 t17341016-5-off23 t17341016-5-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>5. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-defend59" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Butler 
                  <interp inst="t17341016-5-defend59" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-defend59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-defend59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of Clerkenwell, was <rs id="t17341016-5-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               indicted for breaking and entring the House of Frederic Lucan, and stealing a Gold Chain and Hook, value 10 l. 10 s. three Cornelian Seals set in Silver, value 15 s. 1 Stone Seal set in silver, value 10 s. I Horn-handl'ed Hanger set in Silver, value 6 l. a Horn-handled Knife and Fork studded with Silver, value 3 s. three Yards of Gold Lace, value 10 s. a Silver Snuff-Box, value 30 s. a Gold Watch and Shagreen Case, value 12 l 12 s. and a Shagreen Watch Case, value 10 s. the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17341016-5-victim60" type="victimName">
                        Frederic 
                        Lucan 
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-victim60" type="surname" value="Lucan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-5-victim60" type="given" value="Frederic"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-5-victim60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-off23 t17341016-5-victim60"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17341016-5-cd24" type="crimeDate">September 25</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-off23 t17341016-5-cd24"></join>. about the Hour of Eight at Night
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lucan. The Prisoner had been my <rs id="t17341016-5-deflabel25" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-defend59 t17341016-5-deflabel25"></join> about three Weeks, but some Things being missing I suspected him, and turn'd him away on the 8th of September. He came to me on the 24th of September for a Character; I told him I would give him none. He went away, and threaten'd to be revenged on me. Between eight and nine the next Evening, I being at the Castle Tavern in Lombard-street, word was brought me that my House in <placeName id="t17341016-5-crimeloc26">Red-lion Street in Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-5-crimeloc26" type="placeName" value="Red-lion Street in Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-5-crimeloc26" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-off23 t17341016-5-crimeloc26"></join> was broke open. I took Coach directly, and when I came home I found my 'Scritore had been forced open, and the Goods taken away. I went into my Garden, and close to the Back door I saw the Mark of two Feet, which look'd as if some Man had dropt from the Garden Wall. Near the Stable Door I found other Footsteps, and there lay a green Purse with some Gold in it, which I suppose had been dropt in the hurry. The Bar of the Stable Window was forced out, and the Glass was broke, by which I supposed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160005"></xptr> the Rogue made his way out; and one thing that made me suspect the Prisoner, was, that I found his Cane in the Stable Window. The Cane was remarkable, because it had an Iron Thimble upon it instead of a Ferril. I went back by the same Coach to my Friends at the Castle Tavern, to consult with them what Method I had best to take for discovering the Thief, and they advised me to put an Advertisement in the Daily Post. But about Two a Clock in the Morning I was knocked up, and told that the Prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person61">
                  Isabel 
                  Hornby 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person61" type="surname" value="Hornby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person61" type="given" value="Isabel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person61" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prosecutor's Servant. About seven in the Evening I went out on an Errand, and there being Nobody else in the House, I left a Candle on the Stairs to light myself in. The Back Door was on the Latch, and I locked the Street Door and took the Key with me. I was gone about a quarter of an Hour, and then Thomas Brooks, a Foot-boy (but he was not my Master's Servant) came home with me. When I opened the Door all was dark, and I could not find my Candle. Lord, says I to Brooks, Call your Nanny, for our John has been here - I suspected him, because he had done some ugly Tricks while he lived in my Master's Service. I mist a Gold Watch out of my Master's Chamber, and a Draught on the Bank for 137 l. besides what was lost out of the 'Scritoire. I saw Marks of Feet under the Garden Wall, the Key of the Stable Door was taken away, and the Window was propt up with the Prisoner's Cane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person62">
                  Thomas 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person62" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went home with the Maid. She mist the Candle, and felt for it on the Stairs, but could not find it. We went down Stairs into the Kitchen, and found the Back-door open. I called my Fellow-Servant, and he called the Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person63">
                  Robert 
                  Shorter 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person63" type="surname" value="Shorter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person63" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. On the 25th of September, between Ten and Eleven at Night, one came and told me there was a Jobb in the Watch-house, for a Man was taken up for drawing a Hanger upon a Woman in Gray's-Inn-Lane. I went, and found the Prisoner in the Watch house. I saw several Things taken from him, as 3 Cornelian Seals set in silver, some Gold Lace, a Shagreen Case, a Brass Shoe-Snuff-Box, a little pair of Steel Tweezers, and a Tin Box of Gunpowder. - Other Things had been taken from him before I came, by the Order of my Beadle Tim. Micklewright.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person64">
                  Timothy 
                  Micklewright 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person64" type="surname" value="Micklewright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person64" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was brought into our Watch-house at Holborn-Bars, between ten and eleven at Night. One of the Watchmen said, that the Prisoner offered to stick him, and was very troublesome; upon which I ordered him to be Hand-cuffed and searched - He had this Hanger in his Hand; there is a Knife and Fork in the Handle of it - And in his Pockets were found a Gold Watch and Case, a Gold Chain and Hook, four Seals and a silver Snuff-Box with a Stone in the top - the Haft of a Knife with a Nail fastened in it, and turned up crooked, which. I suppose, was to pick Locks with; a Pistol and a Tin Box. I asked him what was in that Tin Box; and he said it was Havanna Snuff, but it proved to be Gunpowder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person65">
                  Robert 
                  Ingleton 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person65" type="surname" value="Ingleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person65" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One that keeps a Snuff Shop in Gray's-Inn-Lane came to the Watch-house, and desired Assistance, for he said a Man had drawn a Dagger upon his Wife, who was big with Child. I told him he had got help at home, for one of our Watchmen lodged in his House - But however, 
               <persName id="t17341016-5-person66">
                  Bob 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person66" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person66" type="given" value="Bob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , another Watchman, went to help 'em, and so they brought the Prisoner to the Watch-house, and there we searched him, and found these What d'ye call 'em's - your Trinkle-me-trankles - your Thingumee's for Ladies, [the Hook and Chain] and a Gold Watch and four Seals. I asked him how he came by such things, and he said he dealt in 'em. Then there was a Tin Box, he said it was full of - some sort of Snuff - I can't think of the Name of it - but I said, I'll swear Devil, that's no Snuff, but Gun-powder.</p>
               <p>- Marsh. The Man at the Snuff-shop came to the Watch-house for a Constable, telling us, that a Man had frightened his Wife. The Constable was not yet come to the Watch-house, and so I went for him; and when we came back the Prisoner was in the Watch-house, and was so unruly that they were forced to Hand-cuff him. Those<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160006"></xptr> Things were found upon him as the other Witnesses have sworn; and about two in the Morning word was sent to the Prosecutor, that the Prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person67">
                  Humphry 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person67" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person67" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman. I lodge at Mr. Forsithe's, the Snuff Shop in Gray's-Inn-Lane; I was called up about Ten a Clock to go to my Watch, and my Landlord charged me with the Prisoner - As we were carrying him along to the Watch-house, he pulled out a Knife, and went to cut my Hand; but I being aware of it, he only scratch'd me with it, and then dropt it; upon which I gave him a knock over the Shins, and stooping down I took up the Knife. When we got him into the Watch-house we searched him, and found the Goods upon him, and a Box of Gunpowder, which he said was Devally Snuff.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person68">
                  William 
                  Seymore 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person68" type="surname" value="Seymore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person68" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About Nine at Night as I was going by Mr. Forsithe's Shop, an Acquaintance of mine (James Francis) called me in, and said there was a Man that had got a great many Valuables, which he believed he did not come honestly by. I went in and found the Prisoner, and happened to know him; for about five Weeks before, I saw him at a Publick House, and then he said he was out of Place, and had but Three half-pence in the World; and by what I saw now, I thought the Times were much mended with him, for he shewed me a Hanger mounted with silver, which he flourished o'er his Head, and then put it up again, and went backwards and called for a Quartern of Gin. Then he shewed us a Gold Watch and Seals, which he said were his own, and that he dealt for such Things to France and Spain. We begun to question him a little, upon which he appeared very much ruffled, asked us what Business we had with his Way of Dealing, and if we had a mind to have a slice of his Hanger? We told him, no. But however he offered to draw in earnest, upon which we seized him. Then he endeavoured to pull out a Pistol. Mr. Francis told me there was no danger, for he had seen the Pistol a little before, and it was not charged. Now, says I to my Gentleman, you shall give an account how you came by these Things before we part with you. The Man of the House was sent for home. As soon as he came in he struck the Prisoner, and told him he had surprized his Wife. There was one Watchman in the House, and Mr. Forsithe went for another, then we carried the Prisoner to the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-5-person69">
                  James 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17341016-5-person69" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person69" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was smoaking a Pipe in Mr. Forsithe's Shop; the Prisoner came in, and said to Mrs. Forsithe, Madam, Will you please to give me a Pinch of Snuff? She said, Yes. Now, Madam, says he, what return shall I make you for this Favour? She told him, she desired none. Then, says he, will you give me leave to walk into your Back Room, and drink a Dram. She said he was welcome, and so he went in and had a half-penny Dram. There he pulled out this Hanger, and some of these other Things. I had some suspicion of him because he did not make an Appearance to be the Owner of such Goods. He took out a Pistol, and was going to charge it, for he said he had 500 l. value about him, and was to go to Bloomsbury, and from thence to Kensington that Night, and therefore must provide for his own safety; but I told him he had better load his Pistol somewhere else for fear of frightening the Woman of the Shop, and so he desisted. Mr. Seymour coming to the Door, I called him aside, and told him what I suspected; upon which he came in, and said, he had some Knowledge of the Fellow. The Prisoner shewed us all his Things, and would treat us with a Quartern. Seymour asked him who he deals with for those Goods. He answered, that he dealt Abroad with foreign Gentlemen. Why says I, those are English Goods. Upon this and some other Words he grew angry, and offered to draw his Hanger, asking us if we would have a slice of it. But we prevented him, and threw him into a Chain.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I met a Man whom I had known beyond Sea, and he gave me these Things, and bid me go into the Snuff-shop, and stay till he came to me.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17341016-5-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17341016-5-punish28" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-5-punish28" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-5-defend59 t17341016-5-punish28"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
