<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-4">
               <interp inst="t17370706-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-4" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-4" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-4-off14-c38" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-defend47 t17370706-4-off14 t17370706-4-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-defend47" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Bullock 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-defend47" type="surname" value="Bullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-defend47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-defend47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-4-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Mare of a Black Colour, value 5 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-victim49" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Shortland 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-victim49" type="surname" value="Shortland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-victim49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-victim49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-off14 t17370706-4-victim49"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , in the Parish of <placeName id="t17370706-4-defloc15">Hornsey</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-defloc15" type="placeName" value="Hornsey"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-defloc15" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-defend47 t17370706-4-defloc15"></join>, <rs id="t17370706-4-cd16" type="crimeDate">June 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-off14 t17370706-4-cd16"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-person50">
                  John 
                  Shortland 
               <interp inst="t17370706-4-person50" type="surname" value="Shortland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I missed my Mare out of <placeName id="t17370706-4-crimeloc17">Flower Field in Northamptonshire</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-crimeloc17" type="placeName" value="Flower Field in Northamptonshire"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-4-crimeloc17" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-off14 t17370706-4-crimeloc17"></join>, about 4 o'Clock in the Morning, June 10. I sought about for her, and was informed that she was gone up the Road, so I pursu'd, and enquired at the Turnpikes, and of the People I met in the Road, if they had seen such a Mare, and I heard of her all the Way I went. At Highgate I overtook the Prisoner, and he had the Mare with him; the People inform'd me that he was on Horseback, and that my Mare was ty'd to his Horse; but when I took him he was on Foot, and was leading them both along the Road. I knew my Mare, - she was a young<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060003"></xptr> black Mare, with a long Tail, and a Star in her Forehead, - so I stopp'd the Prisoner, and examin'd him how he came by her, and I told him she was my Property; he told me I must prove that; but Company coming about us, I sent for a Constable, and took him before a Justice, there he said he had bought the Mare, and that she cost him 4l. The Justice advised him to send for the Man he bought it off, but he said he did not know his Name, nor any Thing about him. He was asked where he parted with this Man, and he said he left him at the Bell on Finchley-Common, but he would not let any one go there to enquire for him.</p>
               <p>Councel. Pris. Did not the Prisoner tell you that he bought this Mare upon the Road, of a Man that rode on a Bay Horse with a Star in his Forehead?</p>
               <p>Shortland. He said the Man rode a brown Horse with a Blaze on his Forehead.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pris. Did any Body go to Finchley to enquire for this Man?</p>
               <p>Shortland. No: No Body went as I know of. The Justice would have had him to have sent there, but he refused to send.</p>
               <p>Counc Pris. On enquiring after your Mare upon the Road, did any one tell you they saw a Man with a brown Horse, and a Blaze in his Forehead, leading such a Mare?</p>
               <p>Shortland. No, they described this Man all the Way upon the Road; I took my Mare from him, and 'tis now in the Constable's Hands at Highgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-person51">
                  Thomas 
                  Wills 
               <interp inst="t17370706-4-person51" type="surname" value="Wills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Mare is my Neighbour Shortland's.</p>
               <p>A Witness. The Prisoner came to my House, which is in the Road, and is call'd the Dirt-House, about a Mile and a half from Flower-Field, (from whence the Mare was stolen) and he told me, he was going to Litchfield. My House is in the main Road from Chester to London.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this? When was the Prisoner at your House?</p>
               <p>Witness. 'Twas the 9th of June in the Evening, the same Night that the Mare was taken away.</p>
               <p>Shortland. And I missed her the next Morning, and I took the Prisoner the same Day. I hir'd fresh Horses upon the Road and pursu'd him, and took him that same Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Highgate from your House, - in the Way to Litchfield? Is Highgate in the Way to Litchfield from your House?</p>

               <p>Witness. He was at my House the 9th of June. He came in about 6 o'Clock in the Evening, he baited, and staid 2 Hours; he told me he was going to Litchfield, and he went beyond my House into a Field, where (I believe) there was 60 Horses, and from whence (I suppose) he took this Mare, and he came back - he went past my House again. He went about 2 Mile beyond my House, as if he was going to Litchfield, but he came back again, and went past my House, the Way to Highgate.</p>
               <p>Defence. I bought this Mare coming along the Road, of a Man on a brown Horse with a bald Face. I desired them to go and find this Man at the Bell at Finchley.</p>
               <p>Shortland. I would have had the Prisoner to have sent to Finchley, but he would not, he never desired me to go there at all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I told them I bought the Mare upon the Road, of a middle aged Man, who rode on 2 brown Horse with a bald Face, and I told them I left him at the Bell at Finchley-Common. I desired them to go there and see if the Man was there or not.</p>
               <p>Shortland. He never desired me to send or go.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. While I was bargaining for the Mare there were 5 Men riding by, I knew them, and here are their Names.</p>
               <p>Shortland. He said before the Justice that no Body was by when the Bargain was made, - nor was any Person present when the Money was paid, and he never saw the Man he bought her off before that Time, nor did he know any Thing at all of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-person52">
                  William 
                  Raiment 
               <interp inst="t17370706-4-person52" type="surname" value="Raiment"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Barking in Essex. I am a Brewer there. The Prisoner <rs id="t17370706-4-deflabel18" type="occupation">kept a Publick House</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-defend47 t17370706-4-deflabel18"></join> at Haveley in Essex, and during the Time he liv'd there, he was a careful honest Fellow. I know nothing of his general Character, but his Behaviour with Regard to me was honest He is a silly innocent sort of a Fellow, and while he liv'd there, the Management of the Business lay altogether upon the Wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-4-person53">
                  William 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17370706-4-person53" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person53" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nothing to say in Behalf of this Indictment, the Prisoner is my Tenant, and he lives in a Publick House belonging to me. I have known him 2 Years, and he bore the Character of an honest, harmless Fellow: he paid me 7 l. 10 s. a Year and several Times has paid me Money and took no Receipts. <rs id="t17370706-4-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370706-4-punish20" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-4-punish20" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-4-defend47 t17370706-4-punish20"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
