<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-65">
               <interp inst="t17390502-65" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-65" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-65" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-65" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-65-off290-c287" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-65-defend435 t17390502-65-off290 t17390502-65-verdict294"></join>
         
               <p>310. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-65-defend435" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Constable 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-65-defend435" type="surname" value="Constable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-defend435" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-defend435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-65-off290" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-off290" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-off290" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-65-victim437" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Read 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-65-victim437" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-65-victim437" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-65-victim437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-65-off290 t17390502-65-victim437"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of Seven at Night, and stealing eighteen Guineas in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-65-cd291" type="crimeDate">Octob. 7. 1730</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-65-off290 t17390502-65-cd291"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Read. On the 7th of October, 1730, I went from my House at <placeName id="t17390502-65-crimeloc292">Hockley-in the Hole</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-65-crimeloc292" type="placeName" value="Hockley-in the Hole"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-65-crimeloc292" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-65-off290 t17390502-65-crimeloc292"></join>, about Six in the Evening, to Mr. Wainwright's at Cow-Cross: I perceived two Men sitting at some Distance from the Door, but it was duskish. About Seven o'Clock a Messenger came to Mr. Wain-wright's, to tell me I was robbed: I went home, and found several Neighbours in my House, and my Housekeeper, (Mary-Holford) unable to speak: her Head was as wet as if a Pail of Water had been thrown on it. Upon going up Stairs into the Garret, which I call my Chamber, I found a Chest broke open, a Deal Box broke all to Pieces, and my Money, which was in it, (18 Guineas) was gone. Holford describ'd one of the Men that was concerned in the Fact, and her Description made me suspect the Prisoner, whom I had then known about Five Years. On the 21st of the same Month I carried her to a Pay-Table, where he received his Wages, that she might have a Sight of him; but as soon as he saw me, he went off, and she did not see his Face. I enquired of the Landlord, where the Prisoner lived? He could not tell. Then I asked him, where he drank? He directed me to another House, and I went there, with Holford, and the Man of the House told me he was above Stairs, and he would call him down. When he came down, I asked him how he did, and shook Hands with him, and desired him to sit down; but that Instant he ran up Stairs again, and two of his Brother <rs id="t17390502-65-deflabel293" type="occupation">Bricklayer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-65-defend435 t17390502-65-deflabel293"></join>s stopp'd me, and told me he was gone over the Tops of the House, and prevented my following him; and I never could take him before. About a Year ago he pass'd by my Door, in the Day-Time, with one 
               <persName id="t17390502-65-person438">
                  Ralph 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17390502-65-person438" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person438" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but no body appeared at Hand, and if I had started him, I should have done myself no Good. I have enquired every Year after him among the Brick-layers, and never could hear where he was, till I found him at the Horse and Groom by St. James's Street, on the 10th of March last. When he was taken, he gave us ill Words, and struggled to get away from the Constable. The Money I lost was all I had in the World, except 30 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-65-person439">
                  Mary 
                  Holford 
               <interp inst="t17390502-65-person439" type="surname" value="Holford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person439" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person439" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account, that when Mr. Read was gone out, somebody knock'd at the Door, and she, being alone in the House, asked, who was there? And, upon being told that a Customer wanted a couple of Whips, she open'd the Door, and two Men rush'd in, one of whom she knew was the Prisoner; for she had often seen him come to an ill House in the Neighbourhood. She said the other Man immediately ran her up against the Boards, and clapp'd one Hand on her Mouth, and the other to her Throat, while the Prisoner took up a Leather Thong, and put it round her Neck; that he gave the other Man the two Ends of the Thong to hold, and then lighted a Piece of Candle, which he took out of his Bosom, or Pocket, and went up Stairs; that the Man who was left with her in the Shop, dragg'd her by the Thong (keeping one Hand on her Mouth) into the Back part of the House, to a Sink in which stood a Pail, full of Water, into which he forced her Head; that she once cry'd out, upon which he kick'd her, and endeavour'd to stab her with a Pair of Scissars which hung at her Side, and did thrust them through all her Cloaths, to her Shift; that the Prisoner made a low Whistle when he came down Stairs, upon which the Man who held her plung'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020021"></xptr> her Head again into the Water, and then went away with the Prisoner; leaving her so spent, that it was some time before she could get to the Door, to call the Neighbours, who, since the Fact, are some dead, and some removed; that she sent for Mr. Read, who came home, and found his Boxes broke, and his money gone. She gave much the same Account as the former Witness had given of the Attempts to take the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner asked her, whether he did not come by her Door about three Years ago, and did not enquire of her if she knew him? In answer to this, she said, About two Years ago he pass'd the Door on a Sunday, and, upon her turning to look after him, he said - How do you do, old Woman, - you don't know me? The Witness reply'd she did, that his Name was Constable, and that it was he who had robb'd the House; upon which he d - d her, and told her it was no more Sin to kill her, than to kill a Cat; She said she saw him then go into a House three or four Doors off (the Sign of the Fox) and that she got a Constable, and went after him into the House, but he had made his Escape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-65-person440">
                  Charles 
                  Wainwright 
               <interp inst="t17390502-65-person440" type="surname" value="Wainwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person440" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the Account that Read gave of his being sent for, and finding Holford in a bad Condition, and his Boxes broke.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-65-person441">
                  John 
                  Plympton 
               <interp inst="t17390502-65-person441" type="surname" value="Plympton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person441" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Constable, gave an Account that he had a Warrant to seize the Prisoner about a Year ago, and had got Assistance in order thereto, but that they could not light of him.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner, in his Defence, said he always work'd hard at the Bricklayer's Business for his Living, and that his Character had never been stain'd before; that he generally work'd in the Country during the Summer, and returned to Town in the Winter; and a great Number of Persons giving him an extraordinary good Character, several of whom he had work'd for, and had known him from his Apprenticeship, the Jury <rs id="t17390502-65-verdict294" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-65-verdict294" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> him</p>
            </div1>
