<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-23">
               <interp inst="t17390906-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-23" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-23" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-23-off104-c109" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-defend164 t17390906-23-off104 t17390906-23-verdict108"></join>
         
               <p>452. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-defend164" type="defendantName">
                     Priscilia 
                     Trillcourt 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-23-defend164" type="surname" value="Trillcourt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-defend164" type="given" value="Priscilia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-defend164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17390906-23-defloc103">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-23-defloc103" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-23-defloc103" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-defend164 t17390906-23-defloc103"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17390906-23-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, and Silver Seal, val. 3 l. and a Piece of Copper, val. 1 d. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-23-victim166" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Selwin 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-23-victim166" type="surname" value="Selwin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-23-victim166" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-23-victim166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-off104 t17390906-23-victim166"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17390906-23-cd105" type="crimeDate">Aug. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-off104 t17390906-23-cd105"></join>.</p>
               <p>Selwin. I lost my Watch and Seal, worth 3 l. with a King's Road Ticket ( which hung to the Watch) o he 19th of August last. The Watch was in my Fob, and I lost it in <placeName id="t17390906-23-crimeloc106">Oxendon-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-23-crimeloc106" type="placeName" value="Oxendon-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-23-crimeloc106" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-off104 t17390906-23-crimeloc106"></join>, about Twelve o'Clock at Night: I was in a private House there with the Prisoner; she carry'd me there about Twelve o'Clock, and there was another Woman in Company, but she was not near me. I did not stay long in the House, - 'twas not above ten Minutes, or a Quarter of an Hour, and indeed I did not miss my Watch till next Morning. How I came to go to this private House with them, at that Time o'Night, - I can't tell. - They asked me to give them a Dram; and I was in Liquor. I miss'd my Watch next Morning; and hearing the Prisoner had it, I got a Warrant, and took her up: While we were carrying her along, she desired I would go back with her, and accordingly I did, and she return'd me the Watch, the Seal, and the King's Road Ticket; but she said it was not she who took it from me, she told me the other Woman took it, and gave it to her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Pray did not the other Woman - sit upon your Knee?</p>
               <p>Selwin. No, she did not; but the Prisoner did. I had both Gold and Silver in my Pocket at the same Time, to the Amount of 3 or 4 l. but they did not meddle with that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When he and I went into this House, we went up Stairs together; and the other Woman was jealous, because he took more Notice of me, than he did of her, and so she went to him, and sat upon his Knee.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person167">
                  Ann 
                  Wilford 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person167" type="surname" value="Wilford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person167" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about a Year and a half, or two Years. Her Character! - as to that, - I can't talk about that: But the Man did come in with the Women, and the Prisoner was one of them; I serv'd them with Liquor; they had five Half-pints of Wine, and after the last Half-pint was serv'd them, my Maid came down, and asked me, if I would take the Gentleman's Watch in Pawn for a Guinea? Money was short with me, and I told her I would not. The Maid that serv'd them with Liquor, was not the other Person - who sat upon his Knee, and that's all I know of the Matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person168">
                  Esther 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person168" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person168" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, I was the Servant in the House, - at that Time. They had five Half-pints of Wine, and when the Reckoning came to be paid, the Gentleman gave me - but half a Crown, and a Piece of Paper, and told me he had no more Money; then he pull'd out his Watch, and desired me to go down to my Mistress and get a Guinea upon it: My Mistress would not lend the Money, so I carried it up to him again, and I saw him give it to the other Woman who was then with him - not to the Prisoner. Indeed he was very much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person169">
                  Ann 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person169" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person169" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor lost his Watch on Sunday Night; and on Monday Night as I was out - looking for my Husband, the Prosecutor laid hold of me in Oxendon-street; I told him I did not know him really; come, come (says he) is signifies nothing for you to deny it, - You have got my Watch, and if you won't go with me, I will swear a Robbery against you; I ask'd him where he lost it? He told me, - at such a House. I went with him thither, and the People knew nothing of me. Upon this he treated me with a Pot of Beet, asked my Pardon, - and so we parted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person170">
                  James 
                  Burnet 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person170" type="surname" value="Burnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person170" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday Night, after the Man had lost his Watch, I was drinking at the Butchers Arms, the Corner of Lombard-Court, and there I saw the Prisoner in Custody of a Constable. In a little time they went out, and came in again in half an Hour; and then the Gentleman told the Constable, he must discharge the Prisoner, for he had nothing to say against her: The Constable said, he could not do it, without carrying her before a Justice; no Justice was to be found, so the Constable would have carry'd her to the Round-house; but the Landlord said, the Prisoner was a Gentlewoman of - such Honour, - that she would to be sure come again in the Morning; so the Constable took her Word, and she accordingly came.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person171">
                  Ellen 
                  Dod 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person171" type="surname" value="Dod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person171" type="given" value="Ellen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17390906-23-deflabel107" type="occupation">Mantua-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-23-defend164 t17390906-23-deflabel107"></join>; she work'd for me and my Mistress two Years: I know her to be a very hard-working Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person172">
                  Martha 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person172" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person172" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She worked a Year and a half with me, and behaved well.</p>
               <p>s
               <persName id="t17390906-23-person173">
                  Thomas 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person173" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person173" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her five or six Years. She has worked for my Wife these two Years, and behaved true and honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-23-person174">
                  Ellen 
                  Dillon 
               <interp inst="t17390906-23-person174" type="surname" value="Dillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person174" type="given" value="Ellen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-person174" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her four Year Her Husband and Mine are now at Sea together. She always behaved well. <rs id="t17390906-23-verdict108" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-23-verdict108" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
