<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391017-35">
               <interp inst="t17391017-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-35" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-35" type="date" value="17391017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391017-35-off138-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-35-defend248 t17391017-35-off138 t17391017-35-verdict141"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391017-35-off138-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-35-defend250 t17391017-35-off138 t17391017-35-verdict142"></join>
         
               <p>526, 527. 
               
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-defend248" type="defendantName">
                     Cuthbert 
                     Wharton 
                  <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend248" type="surname" value="Wharton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend248" type="given" value="Cuthbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-defend250" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Deacon 
                  <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend250" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-defend250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17391017-35-off138" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-off138" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-off138" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391017-35-victim252" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Carrington 
                        <interp inst="t17391017-35-victim252" type="surname" value="Carrington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-35-victim252" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-35-victim252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-35-off138 t17391017-35-victim252"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about Eleven in the Forenoon, (no one being in the said House) and stealing a Silver Porringer, val. 30 s. &amp;c. &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17391017-35-cd139" type="crimeDate">Sept. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-35-off138 t17391017-35-cd139"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carrington. On the 26th of September I lost all the Goods mentioned in the Indictment, out of my House in <placeName id="t17391017-35-crimeloc140">Charles-Square, Hoxton</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-35-crimeloc140" type="placeName" value="Charles-Square, Hoxton"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-35-crimeloc140" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-35-off138 t17391017-35-crimeloc140"></join>; but I don't know who stole them. When the Prisoners were carry'd before Mr. Justice Farmer, they neither deny'd nor confess'd the Fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-person253">
                  James 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17391017-35-person253" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person253" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of September, as I was going thro' Mill Yard into Rag-Fair, about Ten o'Clock in the Morning, I met the Prisoners. Wharton asked me to go with him and Deacon to Mr. Carrington's House at Hoxton: I went with them, and we watch'd till the Maid went out; then Wharton lifted me over the Pales before the Door, and I dug up the Threshold of the Door with a Butcher's Knife, and made a Hole under the Door, thro' which I endeavour'd to get into the House; but I stuck in the Hole, and could hardly get out again. When Wharton found I could not pass thro' the Hole, he wrench'd the Door off the Hinges with the Threshold which we had dug up; then we went in, and took a Silver Porringer, seven Silver Tea-Spoons, and a great Spoon out of the Kitchen; a Hat out of the Hall; a Wig, a Shirt and a Handkerchief, out of a Room above Stairs, and a Bottle of Brandy out of the Maid's Room. When we had taken these Things we came down Stairs, and went out of the House, thro' the Door that goes into the Garden, and carry'd the Goods to Wharton's Lodging in Rag-Fair: But upon offering them to Sale in the Back-Lane, I was stopp'd, and afterward Wharton was taken likewise.</p>
               <p>Deacon. Was I in the House with you?</p>
               <p>Steward. No: Deacon stood behind the Pales to tip Tommy, that is - to tell us if any body came.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-person254">
                  Sarah 
                  Ibbott 
               <interp inst="t17391017-35-person254" type="surname" value="Ibbott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person254" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday the 26th of September, about Nine o'Clock in the Morning, I went after my Master to London, and left the House safe. When I came home, I found the Doors open, between Eleven and Twelve, and the Garden-Door was dug under, and the Threshold taken up. The first Thing I miss'd was a large Silver Spoon, and afterward we found all the Goods had been taken away which are mention'd in the Indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-person255">
                  Shadrach 
                  Hamman 
               <interp inst="t17391017-35-person255" type="surname" value="Hamman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person255" type="given" value="Shadrach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A Man (who is now in Court) brought the two Prisoners and these Goods to me, to take Charge of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carrington. I seal'd them up myself: This Porringer, this Wig, and these Shoes are mine. The Hat and the Shirt are not here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-person256">
                  Thomas 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17391017-35-person256" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of last Month, as I was going along Rag Fair, a Woman call'd to me, and told me, that Cuddy Wharton, and two other Lads, had brought her these Things to buy, and that they were to come again presently to know if she thought proper to have them. In<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173910170015"></xptr> Half an Hour, Deacon and the Evidence came to see after the Goods they had left with the Woman, and I seiz'd them. Steward confess'd he had committed this Robbery with Cuddy Wharton and Deacon, and by his Directions I went to Mr. Carrington, with what Goods he had taken, and he own'd them. I found the Threshold of the Door dug up, and every Thing in the Condition Steward had mention'd. When I came back from Mr. Carrington, he (Steward) gave me some broken Spoons out of his Pocket, and told me Deacon had more in his Pocket: Accordingly we search'd Deacon, and I saw these Tea-Spoons taken out of his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carrington. These are mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-35-person257">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17391017-35-person257" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person257" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are what I took from Deacon: There's a Spoon, and Part of another. He own'd the Fact, and beg'd I would do him what Service I could.</p>
               <p>Wharton. When the Thief takers took me, they asked me to make myself an Evidence, but I told them I was innocent, and told them where I work'd; so they bid me go home about my Business; but next Day, about Eleven o'Clock, Harris came and took me from my Work.</p>
               <p>Harris. Steward did not make himself an Evidence till the next Day; so we did not know till then that Wharton was concern'd in the Fact. I don't remember my asking Wharton to make himself an Evidence: He did tell me he work'd upon the Keys before he was secured, and the next Morning Sullivan took him there.</p>
               <p>Deacon. 'Tis pity this Man (Wharton) should suffer wrongfully: I never saw him till these Men brought him to me. Steward got into the House, and toss'd the Things out to me. Wharton <rs id="t17391017-35-verdict141" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-verdict141" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>; Deacon <rs id="t17391017-35-verdict142" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-verdict142" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-35-verdict142" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty, 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
