<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-25">
               <interp inst="t17370420-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-25" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-25" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-25-off135-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-25-defend200 t17370420-25-off135 t17370420-25-verdict138"></join>
         
               <p>29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-defend200" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-25-defend200" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-defend200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-defend200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370420-25-defloc134">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-25-defloc134" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-25-defloc134" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-25-defend200 t17370420-25-defloc134"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-25-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="damage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="arson"></interp>
               feloniously and maliciously setting Fire to the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-25-victim202" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Rawlinson 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-25-victim202" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-25-victim202" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-25-victim202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-25-off135 t17370420-25-victim202"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of Two in the Night
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370420-25-cd136" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-25-off135 t17370420-25-cd136"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person203">
                  Harry 
                  House 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person203" type="surname" value="House"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person203" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the Time mentioned in the Indictment, we were call'd up by an Alarm of Fire. Mr. Rawlinson was in the Country, and I lay in the House. When I came down to the Door, I found a large Quantity of Straw, but the Fire was put out. I went out with some Watchmen, and we found the Prisoner loitering about the House between 1 and 2; we asked him what Business he had there, he told us he only sat out of the Rain; (for it rain'd very hard). We then desired him to go about his Business, and he swore at the Watchman for turning him away. At Charing-Cross we found him again upon a Bulk; we turn'd him away from thence, and we went to search the Night Cellars for suspicious Persons: when we returned Home, we found him again before our House, so I charged the Watchman with him, and he was carry'd to the Watch-house for that Night, and next Morning he was brought before Mr. De Veil, there he confessed the Fact, and the Justice took his Examination.</p>
               <p>Mr. De Veil. When the Prisoner was brought before me, I did not find any Proof of the Fact charged upon him, but he was pleased to acknowledge it himself. He told me he had been in a melancholy Way, and that he did this, in Order to be Hang'd. He behav'd Modestly, but he seem'd to be in a very heavy dull Condition, and said, he wanted to get out of this Life, and in order thereto, he committed this Fact. As he confes'd the Fact, I thought it my Duty to Commit him, that it might appear whether he was compos Mentis or not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person204">
                  George 
                  Bannister 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person204" type="surname" value="Bannister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person204" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was leaning out of my Box, between One and Two in the Night, and saw a smother at Mr. Rawlinson's Door; I went out and found this Basket and a great deal of Straw against the Door, and a lighted Candle was put into it, and the Candle was cover'd likewise with Straw. I did not see any Body put it there, but when I took it away, I heard some body curse me, and swear the House should be down before Morning. He<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200015"></xptr> confessed that he put a Piece of Wax-candle into the Straw first; but that not doing, he bought a Tallow one for this Purpose.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person205">
                  David 
                  Wetherhead 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person205" type="surname" value="Wetherhead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person205" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About five or six Weeks ago, I was a Bed with him, and he told me the House was on Fire below Stairs, and would not be easy till I went down to put it out. I told him there was no Fire; however, to satisfy him I went down, and found every thing safe. He always look'd very melancholly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person206">
                  James 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person206" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person206" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One Lord's Day Morning I was in Company with him, and he told me he was damned to all Eternity. I have known him three Months, and take him to be disorder'd in his Mind.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person207">
                  Thomas 
                  Atkin 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person207" type="surname" value="Atkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person207" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Company with him another Sabbath-Day Morning, and I heard him say before a great Society, that he was damned to all Eternity. He has been very melancholly three Months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person208">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person208" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person208" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above a Year: I took him for a very sober Lad, but I have heard of his falling in strange Phrenzies and Disorders of Mind. I went to see him in Prison, and asked him what he mean'd by this strange Act of his? I ask'd him if he had any Design to plunder, or had any Resentment against the Man of the House. No, he had no View he said, but only to the ending his Days. I think him distemper'd in his Mind, and that he is of a very melancholly Disposition.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-25-person209">
                  Thomas 
                  Rowel 
               <interp inst="t17370420-25-person209" type="surname" value="Rowel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person209" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner a Twelve-month; he's a very sober Fellow, and a <rs id="t17370420-25-deflabel137" type="occupation">Shoe-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-25-defend200 t17370420-25-deflabel137"></join> by Trade: He is not addicted to Liquor, but lives in all Sobriety. I have heard some People say, they were afraid he would hang or drown himself. <rs id="t17370420-25-verdict138" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-25-verdict138" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
