<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-23">
               <interp inst="t17360610-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-23" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-23" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-23-off92-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-23-defend166 t17360610-23-off92 t17360610-23-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>26. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-23-defend166" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-23-defend166" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-defend166" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-defend166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-23-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Linnen Gown, a quilted Petticoat, a Dimitty Petticoat, a suit of lac'd Head-Cloaths, a Cambrick Apron, a large silver Spoon, with other Things, and one Guinea, a half Guinea, and 3 s. in Silver
            </rs>, the Goods and Moneys of 
               <persName id="t17360610-23-victim167" type="victimName">
                  Edward 
                  Row 
               <interp inst="t17360610-23-victim167" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-victim167" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-victim167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-23-off92 t17360610-23-victim167"></join>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>Mary Row. The Prisoner, poor Creature, came to my House, and I gave her Lodging and Victuals for nothing; she had not been with us more than 7 or 8 Days, before she came down one Morning about four o'Clock, and took my Pocket and my Keys from under my Head, and I took my Keys upon her; she could not be content with robbing me, but she must go up Stairs to my Lodgers Room, and was bundling up their Things; they drew the Curtains and saw her, and wak'd me. A silver Spoon and two Pewter Spoons I took out of her Bosom; a Suit of laced Head-cloaths and my Stockings too. This Bundle I took behind the Street-Door: Here are two Shifts, a pair of Stays, a Gown and two Petticoats.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-23-person168">
                  Benj 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17360610-23-person168" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-person168" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was lying in my Bed, about four o'Clock in the Morning, the Prisoner opened my Door; I saw her take my Wife's Head-cloaths, and put them on. I looked through the Curtains, and by a Looking-Glass which was in the Room, I saw her bundle up my Wife's Shoes, Stockings, Gown, and Petticoat; when she was ready to go off, I opened the Curtains, and asked her what Business she had in my Room, so soon? Only to try on your Wife's Head (says she) and down Stairs she run: I jumped out of Bed, and run after her; then she dropt my Landlady's Apron, and untied her Pockets, and flung them down Stairs. I called my Landlady, and we found my Wife's Things: a large silver Spoon, two Pewter ones, a pair of Stockings, and my Landlady's Garters, and her Shoes with silver Lace, we found upon her, and a great Bundle at the Street-Door ready to carry off. <rs id="t17360610-23-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-23-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
