<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391205-26">
               <interp inst="t17391205-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-26" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-26" type="date" value="17391205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-26-off117-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-26-defend162 t17391205-26-off117 t17391205-26-verdict121"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-26-off117-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-26-defend163 t17391205-26-off117 t17391205-26-verdict121"></join>
         
               <p>26, 27. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17391205-26-defend162" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Markartney 
                  <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend162" type="surname" value="Markartney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend162" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and the 
               <persName id="t17391205-26-defend163" type="defendantName">
                  Ann 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend163" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend163" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-defend163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
              were indicted for <rs id="t17391205-26-off117" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-off117" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-off117" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17391205-26-victim164" type="victimName">
                        Martha, the <rs id="t17391205-26-viclabel118" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-26-victim164 t17391205-26-viclabel118"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17391205-26-person165" type="victimName">
                              
                                 <persName id="t17391205-26-victim166" type="victimName">
                                    John 
                                    Hopkins 
                                 <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim166" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim166" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           </persName>
                               
                           <interp inst="t17391205-26-person165" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17391205-26-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17391205-26-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim164" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim164" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-26-victim164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17391205-26-person167">
                        Henry 
                        Gaffney 
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person167" type="surname" value="Gaffney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-26-person167" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-26-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking two Guineas, three Half-Guineas, and nine Shillings
            </rs>, the Money of John Hopkins, from the Person of Martha, <rs id="t17391205-26-cd119" type="crimeDate">Nov. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-26-off117 t17391205-26-cd119"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-26-person168">
                  Martha 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-person168" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person168" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of November, at Night, I happened to be out late; and about half an Hour after Twelve I went into Gaffney's House, seeing the Door open. - He lives in <placeName id="t17391205-26-crimeloc120">Goldsmith's Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-26-crimeloc120" type="placeName" value="Goldsmith's Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-26-crimeloc120" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-26-off117 t17391205-26-crimeloc120"></join>, in the Coal-Yard, the Back-side of Holborn, and sells Liquor. I never was there in my Life before, but I staid there till Five o'Clock in the Morning: And between Four and Five the Prisoners robbed me of two Guineas, three Half-guineas, and nine Shillings in Silver; The Woman (Johnson) held me, while Mackartney took the Money out of my Bosom. I resisted as much as I could, but Mackartney spirted a Mouthful of Gin in my Face, and abused me very grosly. Gaffney stood by me all the time, but he did not touch me, and I was afraid to speak for Fear of my Life. As soon as they had got all my Money, they all three went to an Ale-house, and left me alone in the House.</p>
               <p>Jury . How came you to be out so late that Night?</p>
               <p>Hopkins. One 
               <persName id="t17391205-26-person169">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-person169" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person169" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to see me at my Lodging at Mrs. Furlong's , in Longditch, Westminster , and I had been to see her Home; she is Servant in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields . I did not know the right Way back again, so I enquired of a Watchman, and he bid me keep strait along. It was then very cold, and I had had an Ague and Fever upon me, and began to grow very ill, so I asked the Watchman, where I might have a Glass of Liquor, so he directed me to this House, and the Door being open, I went in - into the lower Room, - a publick Room, and drank a little. Gin there. I intended to have gone home that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050012"></xptr> Night, but I was seized with a violent cold shaking, soon after I got into the House. When I first went in, there were a great many People drinking Gin, but they all went away; they said they were going to Billingsgate. I did not know I was got into such a Den of Thieves. The other People sat with me round the Fire, and drank with me: But they were gone when the Prisoners robbed me. Mackartney told me (when he took my Money) that I had best be easy, else he would knock my Brains out. I heard a Watchman coming by, at the same Time, and I made all the Noise I could, but they made a greater, to drown mine, and so he did not come in. I staid two Hours alone in the House, after I was robbed; then I went (crying) out of the House, and saw two Soldiers (about Six in the Morning) I told them I had been robbed, but they went on. I enquired where I might find a Constable, and a Stranger coming by, directed me to Mr. Hull, and I told him the Truth. I am a marry'd Woman: My Husband is on Board the Graston Man of War, at Spithead . The Reason of my having so much Money about me, was because I had no Place else to put it in, and I thought 'twas safest in my Bosom. The Maid with whom I went home that Night, is gone to Bath. I went no further with her, than the Corner of the Alley, where they sell Shoes, ( Turnstile )</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-26-person170">
                  Henry 
                  Gaffney 
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-person170" type="surname" value="Gaffney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person170" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . This Woman came into my House, in Goldsmiths-Alley, about Twelve O'Clock at Night, tho 5th of November, and asked what we sold? Mackartney told her, she might have a Glass of good Gin; and so she sat down by the Fire, and called for a Dram. Then she put her Hand in her Pocket, and drew out her Purse, and gave me half a Guinea to change. I sent Mackartney out to get Change; he came in again, and gave her nine Shillings, the rest she had spent. Between Four and Five, Mackartney fill'd his Mouth with Gin, and spirted it in her Eyes; then Johnson held her, while Mackartney took the Purse out of her Bosom - 'twas a yellow and white Purse. He empty'd it into his Pocket-Apron, and threw the Purse in her Face, after he had put a few Half-pence into it, instead of what he took out. She complained immediately of being robbed; but he asked her where she should get so much Money to be robbed of, and turned her out of Doors. She got in again, and we all went to Harry Green's Beer-house, in Cross-Lane , St. Giles's , where he shewed me two Guineas, three Half- Guineas , and nine Shillings. One Guinea he changed, and gave Johnson fifteen Shillings, and I had fifteen Shillings myself. He gave me a Guinea, and I gave him a Crown out of it, to make up the Change for Johnson. She had half a Guinea, and the rest in Silver. When he was before Colonel 
               <persName id="t17391205-26-person171">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-person171" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person171" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Constable searched him, and found the Change in his Pocket-Apron, in my Presence. Before we had divided the Money equally at Green's, Mr. Hall came in and took us, so I got no more than fifteen Shillings.</p>
               <p>Johnson. Ask Gaffney, Whether the Woman did not come in without Stockings, and whether he did not lend her a Pair, to keep her Legs warm? And whether she did not give him half a Guinea to serch a Gallon of strong Beer, and if he did not come in again and say, 'twas a bad Half-Guinea? Gaffney would have put it off, at another Alehouse, but the Woman, to prevent Disputes, gave him another to fetch the Beer.</p>
               <p>Gaffney I never saw the Woman before that Night, with my Eyes: Nor do I know whether she had Stockings on, or not. She gave me half a Guinea, but it was a good one; I gave it to Mackartney , and he having a bad one before, swore 'twas the same the Woman gave me.</p>
               <p>Hopkins. I had Stockings on when I went in; and borrowed none.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-26-person172">
                  John 
                  Hull 
               <interp inst="t17391205-26-person172" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Constable. The Woman (Hopkins) came to my House, in Bow-street, Bloomsbury , on the 6th of November, between Six and Seven in the Morning, crying: She said, she had been robb'd, and believ'd she could find the People who had her Money. I went with her to the Coal-Yard , and from thence to Harry Green's, where I found Gaffney and the two Prisoners very much in Liquor. I told them, a Robbery had been committed among them, but-O they knew nothing of it, - not they, - and they all swore to it. Hopkins charg'd me with Mackartney and Nan Johnson , so I took them before Mr.De Veil, and left Gaffney behind, but Mr. De Veil ordered him likewise to be brought, so I went back and took him. Mackartney told me, he had borrow'd two Guineas of Green, and I asked Green before his Face if it was true? Green said, no, he had not loat him a Parthing. We searched him, and found 17 s. and some Halfpence, in his Pocket Apron, this is the Money. Upon Nan Johnson we only found some few Half-pence, but as we were carrying the Prisoners to Newgate, Green's Son brought her five or six Shillings. Gaffney was made an Evidence, but what he said to Colonel De Veil I know<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050013"></xptr> not, for he was taken backward when he made his Confession.</p>
               <p>Mackartney , This Money was my Creditors, 'twas none of mine.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hull . He told us, he owed one Mr. Collier, a Distiller, for Liquor; and Mr. Collier said it was true; but he did not say this was his Money. He gave him a bad Character, and said he should be glad to have what he owed him.</p>
               <p>Johnson. When I went to Gaffney's , this Woman was secting by the Fire, smoaking her Pipe, without Stockings; she called for half a Pint of Gin; then for another, and made six or seven People drink who were in the House. It snow'd, and was very cold, so Gaffney said, - my dear, you'll catch cold; how come you out without Stockings? Why my Landlady and I have quarrelled, said she, and I never can lie a-bed when I am in a Fret. Then Gaffney bid her pay the Reckoning, (it came to 10 d.) and he told her he would not trust. Do you think, said she, that I have no Money! I'll have a Gallon of Beer, and out she pulled half a Guinea from her Purse, and Gaffney gave it to Jemmy Mackartney , to fetch the Beer. Jemmy came back, and said it was bad Money, and the Woman gave him another. Then Gaffney lent her a Pair of Stockings, which affronted her, and she said she'd sit without. Gaffney swore before the Justice, that I picked Seven-pence Half-penny out of her Pocket, and she laid no more than this to my Charge.</p>
               <p>Hopkins. I charged her before the Justice, with taking Four-pence Half-penny from me. I would be within Compass. She picked my Pocket of Four-pence Half-penny, just before Mackartney took my Purse.</p>
               <p>Mackartney . There was one Carolins , and Nan Beaver, and several others in the House beside us; and the Woman was asleep by the Fire-side, when I went out for the Beer. When I came back again, she had lost her Money. As to Gaffney, - He'll swear a Cat's a Cucumber ; he wants Bread, and would steal a Morsel from a Cat.</p>
               <p>Gaffney . I took this Mackartney in, as a Partner with me in selling Liquors. The House is mine: I took it about three Months ago of Mr. Hilliard, and am to answer to him for the Rent; but on his coming in Partner with me, he was to pay half the Charges.</p>
               <p>Hopkins. I am sure 'twas all the Money I had in the World. I came up about a Fortnight before, from Bath, and had worked hard for it, at Chairing and Ironing. My Husband left me , and went a-board a Man of Wat , because he and I had a few Words. Both <rs id="t17391205-26-verdict121" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-26-verdict121" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
