<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-82">
               <interp inst="t17361208-82" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-82" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-82" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-82" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-82-off409-c401" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-82-defend601 t17361208-82-off409 t17361208-82-verdict412"></join>
         
               <p>106. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-82-defend601" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Sommers 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-82-defend601" type="surname" value="Sommers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-defend601" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-defend601" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, <rs id="t17361208-82-off409" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-off409" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-off409" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               for that she, on the 14th of February, in the Second Year of his Majesty's Reign, at the Parish of St. Brides, took to Husband 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-82-victim603" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Sommers 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-82-victim603" type="surname" value="Sommers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-82-victim603" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-82-victim603" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; and that afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17361208-82-cd410" type="crimeDate">27th of April, in the Second Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-82-off409 t17361208-82-cd410"></join>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17361208-82-crimeloc411">St. Bennet, Paul's-Wharf</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-crimeloc411" type="placeName" value="St. Bennet, Paul's-Wharf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-crimeloc411" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-82-off409 t17361208-82-crimeloc411"></join>, she took to Husband 
                     <persName id="t17361208-82-victim604" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17361208-82-victim604" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-82-off409 t17361208-82-victim604"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , her former Husband being then living
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution open'd the Charge, and the Nature of the Evidence. And,</p>
               <p>The Council for the Defendant observed, that tho' in the Preamble to the Statute, it is said to be an equal Offence, whether a Man marry two Wives, or a Woman two Husbands, yet the enacting Part makes it only an Offence to marry, having a Wife still living. And whenever a new Felony is made by Act of Parliament, the Act is never construed to extend farther than the Letter.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution reply'd, that the Intention of the Statute was to punish Women, as well as Men; that this was evident from the Title of the Statute, and even from the Enacting Part itself, which says, If any Person or Persons, being marry'd, or which hereafter shall marry, do, at any Time (after the End of this Sessions of Parliament) marry any other Person or Persons, the former Wife being alive, &amp;c. That no one with Reason could say, that because former Husband, is not express'd in this Part of the Statute, 'tis no Crime for a Woman to marry a second, her former Husband being alive. That the same Construction has always been put upon the Statute, which they now contended for; Women as well as Men having been indicted upon it. That in the Recital of the Act, the Intention was plain; the Words being, - if any Person or Persons, within his Majesty's Dominions of England and Wales, being marry'd, do at any Time or Times marry another, the former Husband or Wife being alive, it shall be Felony.</p>
               <p>The Court deffer'd giving their Opinion on the Objection made to the Statute by the Prisoner's Council, and order'd the Evidence to be call'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-82-person605">
                  Dr 
                  Gainham 
               <interp inst="t17361208-82-person605" type="surname" value="Gainham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person605" type="given" value="Dr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person605" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Minister of the Church of England; I was a School-master and Curate at Bow by Stratford, about 20 Years ago. I was in the Fleet when I marry'd them; 'twas on the 14th of Feb on the turn of the Year. This is the Book I take the Names of the People I marry in. I marry'd 
               <persName id="t17361208-82-person606">
                  John 
                  Sommers 
               <interp inst="t17361208-82-person606" type="surname" value="Sommers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person606" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person606" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Hannam, Gloucestershire, Gent. and 
               <persName id="t17361208-82-person607">
                  Mary 
                  Wallen 
               <interp inst="t17361208-82-person607" type="surname" value="Wallen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person607" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person607" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Spinster, at the Kings Arms Tavern; I have some Idea of her, but cannot swear positively to her. I think she is the same Person. The Wedding was kept at Mr. White's at the Kings Arms Tavern, and I drank Tea with them the next Morning, They Lay there that Night. Mrs. White and the Gentlewoman that was marry'd sung; they said it was 
               <persName id="t17361208-82-person608">
                  Polly 
                  Peachum 
               <interp inst="t17361208-82-person608" type="surname" value="Peachum"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person608" type="given" value="Polly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person608" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember a great Dispute arose between her and me at it, for she was printed in the Bills Miss Warren, and when I came to put down her Name in my Book, says I, pray tell me your right Name, and she told me it was Wallen, and not Warren. This is a Pocket Book, in which I put Names down, and then I enter them into this Book</p>
               <p>Councel. Was this Entry made at the Time of their Marriage:</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes; and no Alteration has been made in it since.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present, beside your self?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17361208-82-person609">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodyere 
               <interp inst="t17361208-82-person609" type="surname" value="Woodyere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person609" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-person609" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and an elderly Woman, who call'd her self King</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. White, the Master of the House sup with you?</p>
               <p>Gainham. He came up; but did not stay to sup.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Reason to say you marry'd these People, but by the Entry in this Book?</p>
               <p>Gainham. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you tell me whether all this is right? John Sommers of Hannam, Gloucestershire, Gent. To Mary Wallen, Spinster, Kings-Arms, Private: Pray what's the Meaning of Private?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080039"></xptr>Gainham. The Gentleman desired it might not be known.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray was it all wrote at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you put on your best Spectacles? Was it wrote all at one House?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And with the same Ink?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes, upon my Word it was: and I never alter'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you look upon it again?</p>
               <p>Gainham. May be I might call for a better Pen.</p>
               <p>Q. But if you call'd for a better Pen, you wrote with the same Ink: here's a Word blotted out King's-Head, and the Words under are King's-Arms. You have struck out King's-Head, and with blacker Ink, and a different Pen, you have wrote King's-Arms.</p>


               <p>Gainham. My Lord; - 'tis Eight Years ago.</p>
               <p>Councel Well, Doctor, when was this Entry made?</p>
               <p>Gainham. On the Day of Marriage, and here I enter all my Marriages; this Entry was made on the Day of Marriage.</p>
               <p>Counc Def. You cannot read this in Evidence.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pros. I have know them read at a Trial at Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What is this 14 for?</p>
               <p>Gainham. That's the Day of the Month.</p>
               <p>Q. Why here are a great many People ruin'd in a Month. - Pray are there any Entries made here of People marry'd by any other beside yourself?</p>
               <p>Gainham. No.</p>
               <p>Councel. Look to the first Day of the Month.</p>
               <p>C. I am going to it; but I must turn over a great many Leaves before I come to it.</p>
               <p>Q. You don't make these Alterations, but when you have Occasion for them.</p>
               <p>Councel. What Money, Doctor, had you for this Alteration?</p>
               <p>Gainham Not a Farthing, as I hope to be sav'd:</p>
               <p>Q. Do you keep any other Book? for I have seen some of your People who have kept two, one with close Lines, and the other with open Lines.</p>
               <p>Gainham. I have Three Register Books, and I have a Ledger, in which I enter them; and I can easily find out any. My Books are paged and number'd. I never made a false Entry in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you enter into these Books from the little Book?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes, and the Entries into these Books are always according to the Entries in the little Book.</p>
               <p>Q. Read the Entry of this Marriage in the little Book, and compare it with the great Book.</p>
               <p>Councel. 14. Feb. John Sommers, of Hannam, Gloucestershire, Gent. To Mary Wallen of Clements Dane, Spinster, King's-Arms, Private. Compare them, and see if they are not both the same Ink, as to all but the King's-Arms. The Alteration seems to be made long since the Entry. The King's Head it was first.</p>
               <p>Gainham. That was a Mistake.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was there any such Tavern as the King's Head in 1728.</p>
               <p>Gainham. No; none but the King's-Arms.</p>
               <p>Councel The Ledger goes according to the amended Entry, and wrote with the same Ink.</p>
               <p>Councel. The Entries here, are very regular.</p>
               <p>C. The Entry in the Ledger is the same Ink as that in the Day Book, the Alteration in the little Book seems to be done with a different Ink.</p>
               <p>C. K.. 'Tis a Misfortune that Marriages of this kind are so frequent; but the Ledger is fair, and the Entry is fair. You said something just now of some Songs, which were sung by her.</p>
               <p>Gainham. There were some Songs sung by Mrs. White and she.</p>
               <p>C. K. Do you remember what she was call'd?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Some body told me, she was Polly Peachum.</p>
               <p>C. K. When was this?</p>
               <p>Gainham. In the Year 28, or 29.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the second Polly Peachum since that Time?</p>
               <p>Mr. White In the Year 1728, I kept the King's-Arms Tavern on Ludgate-Hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any such Tavern as the King's Head there?</p>
               <p>White. No, there was but two, the King's-Arms and the Crown.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you remember John Sommers and the Prisoner being at your House?</p>
               <p>White. I can't say I know Sommers, but I remember something of the Prisoner's Face, though I can't say positively that is she; I remember I ask'd who was above Stairs, and my People said, one who went by the Name of Wallen or Polly Peachum, and that Mr. Gainham was above with them, and had married them; he was with them all Day, and I believe they dined at my House, and they asked me to dine, but I don't know whether I did or not; I drank a Glass of Wine with them. I cannot swear to the Woman.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did they sup at your House?</p>
               <p>White. I cannot be positive; there was some Company there singing, and I believe my Wife went up and sung too: I heard several Songs, and I think she is the Person, but I can't swear it.</p>
               <p>Mrs Coker. I know Mrs. Wallen: In February 1728 she lived at my Brother's House, I lived there too at that Time, 'twas in Cary-Street; she lodged there Part of the Year 1728, but I won't be positive that she lived to the End of that Year<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080040"></xptr> there; I believe she was there in March. I remember Mr. Sommers, one who went by that Name, but I did not hear when they were going to be married.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Wallen's going away in February?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. Yes, she went away with the Gentleman who said his Name was John Sommers; I remember my Sister lay-in, and he stood Godfather to the Child. They went away the 14th of Feb. in a Coach from our House, with an old Gentlewoman, one Mrs. King.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they return to your House that Night?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. No, Mrs. King did. Neither Mr. Sommers nor Mrs. Wallen returned 'till next Day.</p>
               <p>Q. When they returned the next Day, did they live at your House any Time afterwards?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. Yes, about a Fortnight, and in that Time both Sommers and she owned they were married, but I don't remember whether they mentioned the Place where they were marry'd or not. I heard them say they were marry'd, the next Day; they liv'd and lay together as Man and Wife.</p>
               <p>Coun. There is a remarkable Day in February, Madam, a coupling Day; all the young Women remember Valentine's Day.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. Yes; 'twas Valentine's Day.</p>
               <p>Q. After Mr. Sommers went away, when did you see him again?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. About a Year afterwards he came into the House where I liv'd to ask for her, I don't know whether he asked for her by the Name of Sommers, but he asked me where she liv'd, for she did not lodge there a great while after she was married, but I saw him about a Twelvemonth afterwards - the Beginning of the next March was Twelvemonths, but I am not positively sure.</p>
               <p>Coun. Can you be sure it was 10 Months? Can you be sure it was eight Months?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. Yes; tho' I don't remember the particular Time, yet I can take upon me to swear that I saw him alive eight Months after.</p>
               <p>Coun. Def. I take an Exception to the Establishment of the Marriage: 'Tis not sufficient, in Cases of this Nature, to prove a Cohabitation: They must give Evidence of an actual Marriage; all the Proof they can give, is this Fleet-Register, which ought to have no Weight at all. I submit it, whether they have established the first Marriage.</p>
               <p>C. Criminal Marriages must be positively proved  for Men and Women in this wicked Town, who live together, to say they are marry'd, is not sufficient Evidence.</p>
               <p>Councel. Here is the Man of the House remembers something of the Woman, and remembers likewise the Doctor present, at the same Time.</p>
               <p>C. This is Evidence to create a Suspicion; if a Person is accused of a Crime, it must not be Suspicion, but positive Evidence that must be brought against him.</p>
               <p>Councel. The Evidence of Gainham, perhaps may be thought not sufficient, but the Parties themselves have acknowledged it. Pray how long did they live together as Man and Wife? (To Mrs. Coker.)</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. About a Fortnight, and then he went away; after he had been gone two or three Days, she told me he was gone into the Country.</p>
               <p>A Juryman. I desire to know whether she went by the Name of Polly Peachum, when she was marry'd?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coker. She acted the Part; and there was no other at that Time, and she then belonged to the Play-house. I have heard her sing my self. <rs id="t17361208-82-verdict412" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-82-verdict412" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
