<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-58">
               <interp inst="t17341204-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-58" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-58" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-58-off285-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend396 t17341204-58-off285 t17341204-58-verdict290"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-58-off285-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend398 t17341204-58-off285 t17341204-58-verdict290"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-58-off285-c276" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend400 t17341204-58-off285 t17341204-58-verdict290"></join>
         
               <p>57. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-defend396" type="defendantName">
                     Isaac 
                     Berridge 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend396" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend396" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-defend398" type="defendantName">
                     Roger 
                     Arnold 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend398" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend398" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-defend400" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Pembroke 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend400" type="surname" value="Pembroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend400" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-defend400" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , (with Joseph D'eniere, not yet taken) of <placeName id="t17341204-58-defloc284">St. George's Hanover Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-58-defloc284" type="placeName" value="St. George's Hanover Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-58-defloc284" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend396 t17341204-58-defloc284"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend398 t17341204-58-defloc284"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend400 t17341204-58-defloc284"></join>, were indicted for the <rs id="t17341204-58-off285" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-off285" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-off285" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-58-victim402" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Cantillon 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-58-victim402" type="surname" value="Cantillon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-58-victim402" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-58-victim402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-off285 t17341204-58-victim402"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17341204-58-viclabel286" type="occupation">Esq.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-victim402 t17341204-58-viclabel286"></join> Berridge, by assaulting, and with both his Hands and Feet on the Breast, Belly, Groin, and Privy-Parts, kicking, striking, and beating him, and giving him several mortal Wounds and Bruises on the <rs id="t17341204-58-cd287" type="crimeDate">14th of May 1734</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-off285 t17341204-58-cd287"></join>. of which mortal Wounds and Bruises he instant; died; and Arnold and Pembroke, together with Joseph D'eniere, by being present, aiding, abetting, comforting and maintaining the said Berridge in committing the said Murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They were a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>The Council for his Majesty having opened the Indictment and Evidence against the Prisoners, proceeded to examine the Witnesses - They were examined a-part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person403">
                  Thomas 
                  Goosetrey 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person403" type="surname" value="Goosetrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person403" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Council. Were not you a Servant in the Family of the deceas'd Mr. Cantillen?</p>
               <p>Goosetry. I was Coachman, but I did not lye in the House.</p>
               <p>Council. Do ye remember where he was on the 13th of May last?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. I can't tell the Day of the Month; but the Day before his House was burnt down, I was out with him at the Temple and other Places all Day and particularly at a House in Queen-Square, Westminster where he supp'd, and set him down at his own Door at ten at Night. He ordered me to come again at 10 o'Clock next Morning, for he said he believed he should go out of Town. But I was call'd out of Bed at four the next Morning, and was told that the House was on Fire. I went thither, and then the House was burnt down.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see any of the Prisoners there at that Time?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. No; I saw none of them then.</p>
               <p>Council. When and where did you first see them after this Misfortune?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040025"></xptr>Goosetrey. I saw them at 8 a-Clock the same Morning at the Red horse in Bond Street, my Master's Horses stood at the Red-horse, and so I suppose they went thither for Shelter.</p>
               <p>Council. What Conversation had you with them there?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. I asked them if my Master was burn'd, and they said they believed so, but they could not tell.</p>
               <p>Council. Did they say they could not tell whether he was burn'd or not?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. I asked them whether it was so or no, and they said it was so, he was burnt; but they could not tell how or which Way.</p>
               <p>Council. How long did you stay with them?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. About a Quarter of an Hour, and then I went away and don't know what came to them afterwards.</p>
               <p>Council. How many Servants had Mr. Cantillon in his Family?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. We had 3 Maids and 2 Men.</p>
               <p>Council. Were the Prisoners at home when you set your Master down at the Door?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. I believe so - One of them let him in - I can't say which.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see the Prisoners when they were in Custody?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you any Discourse with them about this Misfortune?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. Nothing in particular that I remember.</p>
               <p>Council. On what account did you go to them?</p>
               <p>Goosetrey. I went on my own Charity to carry them Provisions in Prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person404">
                  Christopher 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person404" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person404" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sworn.</p>
               <p>Council. Where did you live in May last?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. At Mr. Percivals in Albemarle-street.</p>
               <p>Council. Was that near Mr. Cantillons?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Yes it was next Doot; his House joined to my Master's on one side, and to my Lord St. John's on t'other.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you remember when the Fire happen'd?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Yes, It was the 14th of May.</p>
               <p>Council. What time did it begin to the best of your Knowledge?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Between 3 and 4 in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Council. Go on, and inform the Court of what you did observe on that Occasion.</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. I went to Mr. Cantillon's Door and knock'd very loud, the <rs id="t17341204-58-deflabel288" type="occupation">Maid</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend400 t17341204-58-deflabel288"></join> Eliz. Pembroke came to the Window up two Pair of Stairs - The House is two Pair of Stairs high besides the Garret - I told her the House was on Fire: She said she knew nothing of it, and that they were all a-bed. That Answer not being very agreeable as I thought, I damn'd her and bid her get up: Then I went to my Lord St. John's Door and called his Porter, who got up immediately; I return'd in a Minute and found Mr. Cantillon's Door open. How it came open I can't tell, for I saw no body below in the House nor in the Street; but going thro' the Hall into the Back Yard and looking up, I saw 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person405">
                  Isaac 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person405" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person405" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the Lids on the Top of the House, I told him the House was on Fire: He said By-God he saw no Fire. Presently I saw it come out under the Roof and shewed it him, and then he said, Aye by God, so it is.</p>
               <p>Council. When the Maid look'd out of the Window, did you observe whether she was dress'd or not?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. She was dress'd, I think, as far as I could see of her.</p>
               <p>Council. How long did you stay in the back Yard?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Not above a Minute, and then I went Home, and my Master sent me for the Firemen: and just as I was going, I saw the 3 Maids come to the Door, crying and saying, that their Master was murdered.</p>
               <p>Council. Was 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person406">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pembroke 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person406" type="surname" value="Pembroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person406" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person406" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one of those three Maids?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly, Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Was she drest at that Time?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. They all seemed to be drest as they used to be in a Morning, when they were about their Business.</p>
               <p>Council. How long was they after she spoke to you out at Window?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. About 10 or 11 Minutes. - Then<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040026"></xptr> I went to see for the Fire-men, and at last I found them at St. George's Church, and knock'd them up; and when I came back again the House was burnt down.</p>
               <p>Council. Did Isaac seem surprized when you told him the House was on fire?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. No; he said at first that he saw none. I stood half a Minute and shewed it him, and then I went away before he went in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person407">
                  Isaac 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person407" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person407" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Were my Stockings tied up?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Pembroke. Was I drest?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. I can't say as to that, but you had something about you.</p>
               <p>Juryman. You said the 3 Maids were drest as usual.</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. That was not when she looked out of Window, but afterwards, when they cry'd and said their Master was murdered.</p>
               <p>I. Berridge. Were not my Stockings the wrong Side outward?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. I could not observe at that Distance.</p>
               <p>Council. On which Side of the House did the Fire begin?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Backwards: for I saw none in the Front at first.</p>
               <p>Council. How came you at first to have notice of the Fire?</p>
               <p>C. Kelly. Our House-keeper, Mrs. Shuttleworth was coming down Stairs about 3 a Clock. I asked who was there. She answer'd, There's a Fire. Then I smelt it, and got up; and she and I went down, and search'd the lower Part of the House, but found nothing there. We went up again, and then we found it was ready to break into our House.</p>
               <p>Malachi Kelly, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person408">
                  Malachi 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person408" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person408" type="given" value="Malachi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr. Percival. At half an Hour past 3, hearing the other Servants going up and down, I suspected Fire and got up. We apprehended that it was in Mr. Cantillon's House, because our House-keeper discovered it first in her Chamber, which was next to his House. My Master and I went into the Garden, and the Smoke seemed to come out towards the Top of Mr. Cantillon's House, by the Party-Wall. Then I went into the Street, and Mr. Cantillon's Door being open - I can't tell who opened it, for it was open before I came - I went into the Hall, where I found one of his Men - I can't say which of them it was, but I told him there was a Fire. He went with me into their Garden, and looking up, I saw the other Man-Servant upon the House, and perceived the Smoke coming out of the Crevises of the Window up one Pair of Stairs backward. Upon which, I asked him that was with me, if his Master was in Town. He said yes. Is that his Bed-Chamber, says I, where the Smoke came out? He said yes. And is he a-bed? says I again. I believe so, says he. Then, why the Devil, says I, - or - Damn ye! - I don't know which of the two it was - Why don't you call him up? And upon this we went up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Council. Which of you went first?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. He went foremost, but I went with him - I believe I might have him by the Hand.</p>
               <p>Council. When you came up Stairs did you see any Smoke or Fire?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. No, not in the least, till we came to the Bed-Chamber-Door.</p>
               <p>Council. Now look at the Prisoners, and see if you can tell which of them it was you went up Stairs with?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. I am not sure it was either of them, but it was one of the two Men.</p>
               <p>Council. Was it he that you saw upon the House?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. No, it was he that I was with in the Garden.</p>
               <p>Council. What was done when you came to the Chamber-Door?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. He turned the Bolt and opened it, and out came the Smoke: upon which he turned back to the Wainscot, and kick'd against it, and said, Master! Master! Fire! Fire! I bid him go and pull him out. So he went in and took him by the Legs, and brought him to the Door, but no Part of the Body without the Door. He held him Knee high by the Legs, and I saw that he was dead, tho' I thought before, that he had been alive. The Deceas'd seem'd to be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040027"></xptr> quite naked to the Navel. There was a vast many red Spots on his Belly. Knees and Legs, and down his Thighs - he was all over large Spots.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you observe any Part about him, that appeared to be scorched or sindged?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. No, I saw no Scorching or Sindging.</p>
               <p>Conncil. How near were you to him?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. I was then about 6 Feet from the Chamber-Door.</p>
               <p>Council. You say that he was naked to the Navel: do ye know if any Part of him was cover'd? Had he a Shirt or a Night-Cap on?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. I can't say as to that, for I did not see his Head nor his Arms, I saw nothing but the lower Part of his Body, as the Servant had hold of his Legs.</p>
               <p>Council. Then he might have had a Shirt on the Rest of his Body, and a Night-Cap on his Head, tho' you did not see them?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. Yes, he might.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see any Fire in the Room?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. No, There was Smoke in the Room - a vast Deal of Smoke, but I saw no Fire.</p>
               <p>Court. What, was no Part of the Furniture on Fire?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. Not that I could see, for the Door was not quite open, and I saw nothing in the Room but that Part of the Body.</p>
               <p>Council. By what Light did you see the Body?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. It was Day-Light, as it is now: and the Light that I had, was from the Street-Window.</p>
               <p>Council. Did those red Spots upon the Body appear to be Blood?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. I can't say they were Blood, but I thought he was murder'd.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see Elizabeth Pembroke there?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. No; When I came to the House I saw one of the Maids in the Entry, but I believe it was the Cook.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you observe the Smoke come out of any Room but that where the Deceas'd lay?</p>
               <p>Kelly. I can't say that I did, but I thought it time to save him.</p>
               <p>Council. Was that <rs id="t17341204-58-deflabel289" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend396 t17341204-58-deflabel289"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-58-defend398 t17341204-58-deflabel289"></join> who went up with you, drest?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. He was in a Cap and Frock, and so I think was he upon the House.</p>
               <p>Council. In what manner did he that was with you, go up Stairs?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. He ran up in a Hurry before me, and immediately after he had knock'd at the Wainscot, he went into the Room and pull'd the Deceas'd out by the Legs; and as soon as ever I saw him, I said to the Servant your Master is murder'd.</p>
               <p>Court. How far did he bring the Deceas'd?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. Almost to the Chamber Door, and then I left him.</p>
               <p>Court. Was he holding the Deceas'd when you went away?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. He had him by the Legs; but I believe he might not be holding still; but might be drawing the Body out, when I ran away; for I ran away as soon as I saw it. Then I ran to call the Engines; but I went no further than the Corner of Conduit-street, where I gave the Word, and so it was carried to the Church, and I ran back in five Minutes. Mr. Cantillon 's House was then in a Blaze backwards; Our House was on Fire too, and I went to save our own Things.</p>
               <p>Ann Shuttleworth, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person409">
                  Ann 
                  Shuttleworth 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person409" type="surname" value="Shuttleworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person409" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person409" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Percival's House-keeper. The first thing that I perceived was a great Smoke which waked me; I got up, and awaken'd the Family. I went to Mr. Cautillon's Door; Malachi Kelly was then in the House, and I was going in when I heard the Shriek of Woman's Voices, crying three or four times that their Master was murder'd. They were then up two Pair of Stairs, and came down screaming the same -</p>
               <p>Council. Was Elizabeth Pembroke one of them?</p>
               <p>A. Shuttleworth. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Was she drest?</p>
               <p>A. Shuttleworth. She was drest as Servants generally are in a Morning - The Fire was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040028"></xptr> not then broke out; nor did I see any Smoke in Mr. Cantilion's Hall.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you go in?</p>
               <p>A. Shuttleworth. No; I only stood at the Hall Door; for as I was stepping to go in, I heard the shriek of Murder, and the Maids, immediately came down and out at the Door, and stood upon the Flags. I said, I wonder'd they did not go in and try to put the Fire out; and then I went directly into our House, and up Stairs; by which time the Fire was breaking into my Bed Chamber, which was opposite to Mr. Cantillon's Two-pair of Stairs Room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person410">
                  William 
                  Marson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person410" type="surname" value="Marson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person410" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sworn.</p>
               <p>W. Marson. I was Servant to my Lady 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person411">
                  Mary 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person411" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lived almost over against Mr. Cantillon's House. At half an Hour past three, I heard a knocking at the Doors in the Street; and thinking there was a Fire, I got up, went down Stairs and open'd the Door. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person412">
                  Mary 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person412" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person412" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person412" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had lived with Mr. Cantillon three Weeks, had been our House Maid. She was standing at his Door, and called me over. I went; I saw there was a great Smoke, but no Fire. I ran up one Pair of Stairs, and saw the Corps of the Deceas'd lying at length upon the Landing Place - I saw by his Face that it was the Deceas'd - He was naked to the Stomach.</p>
               <p>Council. Was his Body entire?</p>
               <p>W. Marson, Yes; I saw him at full length; no Part of his Body was off.</p>
               <p>Council. Did his Body appear to be scorched?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you observe any Red Spots upon him?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Or any Blood?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Had he any Linnen upon him?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. Yes; His Shirt was above his Breast, and he had a Night Cap on, and I think it was tied with a Red Ribbon.</p>
               <p>Council. Did his Shirt or his Cap appear to be burnt?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Was his Chamber Door open?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see any Fire there?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. Yes; There was a violent Fire in the Room, and it made 2 great Ratling - Miss Dollin beg'd me to carry her over: I took her in my Arms, but I was in such a Fright, I scarce knew how I got down Stairs - In a few Minutes afterwards, the House was all in a Fire - I did not see that the Servants were drest; they had their Cloths on slackly. The Men were in their Frocks; but I am not sure they were button'd.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you any Discourse with either of the Prisoners after this?</p>
               <p>W. Marson. Yes; When most of the Hurry was over, I saw one or both of the Men standing in the Street; I spoke to one of them; he was talking to some of the People; and he said, he pulled his Master out of Bed - And I think he said, his Master was burnt - I saw them standing there a Week or 10 Days afterwards, when the Ashes were sifting; but I had no particular Discourse with 'em then.</p>
               <p>Oliver Price, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person413">
                  Oliver 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person413" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person413" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd at my Lord St John's when the Fire happen'd at Mr. Cantillon's, which was next Door; I went up one Pair of Stairs; I saw the lower Part of the Deceas'd's Body; the Lappet of his Shirt was turned over his Stomach. There was Redness about his Thighs, and Privy Members and Belly; but whether they were burnt, or bloody I can't tell - I could not distinguish - The Man Isaac had him by the Legs, one Legs, in each Hand.</p>
               <p>Council. Was the Body in the Room?</p>
               <p>O. Price. No; it was out upon the Stairs - the Stairs turned short, and the Body lay at the Corner of the Turning.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see any Fire in the Bed-Chamber?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I did not look into the Bed Chamber; and I don't remember that I saw any Fire, or any Smoke, or smelt any.</p>
               <p>Council. Was the Chamber Door open?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I don't know that I saw it open.</p>
               <p>Council. How far were you from the Chamber?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I can't tell - but there might be a Fire there and I not see it.</p>
               <p>Council. Was Isaac drest?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040029"></xptr>O. Price. I don't know whether he was drest or undrest.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you any Discourse with him?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I don't remember if I said any thing or not - but I left him holding the Deceas'd.</p>
               <p>Council. Was he drawing the Body along?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I think not.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see Malachi Kelly?</p>
               <p>O. Price. I don't know that I did.</p>
               <p>Charles Woolmer sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person414">
                  Charles 
                  Woolmer 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person414" type="surname" value="Woolmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person414" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday the 14th of May last, as I was going by Vine-street to a Brew-house with a Cask in my Hand; there was a Man on the Top of a House cry'd Fire; I ran round to Albemarle-street, and saw Mr. Cantillon's three Maids at his Door. They said, their Master was dead. I ran up Stairs, and saw no Fire then; but the Deceas'd was lying at full length with his Head against his own Door, and his Feet to the Parlor. He had a White Cap on, and his Shirt was turned up to his Navel; his Privities appear'd bruised and blackish; his Linnen was not at all sindged. I stept to the Chamber Door, looked in, and saw the Bed standing, and the Cloths turned up against the side of the Wall. I ran down. The Servants were all in the Entry, crying, and wringing their Hands.</p>
               <p>Council. Did the Men cry?</p>
               <p>C. Woolmer. I did not perceive that they cry'd; but the Maids did - Why, says I, Don't you take care to bring him down?</p>
               <p>Council. Which of them did you speak to to take care of the Body?</p>
               <p>C. Woolmer I think it was to Isaac, but they were all together - I ran up again, but then a Flame burst out of the Chamber Door, and then I said it was too late.</p>
               <p>Council. How long was that after the first time you went up?</p>
               <p>C. Woolmer. It was presently after; for I ran up and down the first and second time as fast as I could; and at the second going up, the Fire burst out and caught hold of the Wainscot, and the Banisters of the Stairs, and crack, crack, crack, they went in a Moment.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Joakin, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person415">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Joakin 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person415" type="surname" value="Joakin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person415" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person415" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at my Lord Craven's, a pretty way from Mr. Cantillon's House; but I was going by there with 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person416">
                  Mary 
                  Mersit 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person416" type="surname" value="Mersit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person416" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about 4 o'Clock in the Morning. At first, I only stood over the way against the Back-side of the House, and saw the smoke come out at the top, but no Fire. In a Quarter of an Hour we went round, and stood over against the Foreside of the House, and then I saw the Flare of the Fire; it seemed to be up one Pair of Stairs. The Street Door was open, and the Servants were coming out; I saw two Maids come out first, one of them was the Kitchen-Maid, and the other was Elizabeth Pembroke: I asked them if they belong'd to the Family; they said, Yes; I asked them if all their Family was out; they answered, No, their Master was burnt, and they saw him dead, and bloody - Then Isaac Berridge, and the other Maid came out. And Mary Mersit asked them several times why they did not bring their Master out. The Man answered, That he brought him to the Top of the Stairs, but having no help, could get him no farther: That he left him at Night reading abed; and that he knew he had 500 l. in the House.</p>
               <p>Council. Did he say in what Room it was?</p>
               <p>E. Joakin. He said it was in the Fire.</p>
               <p>Council. Were the Servants drest?</p>
               <p>E. Joakin. They all seemed to have their Cloths loosely on - two of the Maids had Aprons. I was not in the House at all. After this, while we staid there, they all went to a little House at the upper end of the Street.</p>
               <p>Mary Mersit, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person417">
                  Mary 
                  Mersit 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person417" type="surname" value="Mersit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person417" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived at my Lord Cravens in Brook street. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person418">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Joakin 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person418" type="surname" value="Joakin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person418" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person418" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I were going by Mr. Cantillon's just as the Fire began. When we came round into Albemarle-street, two Maids and one Man stood upon the Steps: We asked if all the Family were out of the House; and the Maids answered (for the Man was not there then) that their Master was burnt to death; and that one of their Men went in when the Room was in Fire, and dragg'd him by the Legs, and his Head dropt off, and so he left him there.</p>
               <p>Council. What the Witness heard a strange Maid say, is no Evidence.</p>
               <p>M. Mersit. But then I saw Isaac; and he himself said, that he went in and dragg'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040030"></xptr> him by the Legs, and his Head dropped off; that there was a great deal of Fire in the Room, and so left him on the Stair's Head, and then went to another Room where he thought his Master had got 500 l. and forced the Door open; but the Flames bursting out, he could not save any thing - We were in Bond-street when we first heard of the Fire, and so we came round - The Door was open before we came, and we saw the Fire was on the Stair Case; but no Fire without side the House at that time - The Maids had their Cloths on loosely, and one of them had her Stays in her Lap. The Man had a Napkin Cap, and his Stockings were not tied up - I don't know any of the Maids, but they cry'd prodigiously; and the Man seem'd to be very much concern'd.</p>
               <p>Francis Brooks, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person419">
                  Francis 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person419" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person419" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen Elizabeth Pembroke, tho' I don't know that she was Mr. Cantillon's Servant. She came to my Shop about seven o'Clock that Morning as the Fire happened - The other Maid and 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person420">
                  Isaac 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person420" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person420" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came with her.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you any Discourse?</p>
               <p>F. Brookes. Mr. Parry penn'd down what it was, which I can't remember, only there was some talk how the House came on Fire, and one of the Maids, I think it was the Prisoner, said, When I came down and saw my Master bloody, I was frighted out of my Wits. Bloody? says I, How came he to be bloody? and Berridge made answer. In pulling him down seven Stairs his Bowels came out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person421">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pembroke 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person421" type="surname" value="Pembroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person421" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person421" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Had I my Cloths all on when I came to your House?</p>
               <p>F. Brookes. No; she brought her Stays under her Arm, and laced them on in my Shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person422">
                  Sarah 
                  Leneve 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person422" type="surname" value="Leneve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person422" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person422" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sworn.</p>
               <p>Council. What Discourse pass'd betwixt you and the Prisoners after the Fire?</p>
               <p>S. Leneve. Next Day I and my Fellow-Servant 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person423">
                  Elizabeth 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person423" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person423" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (who was Mr. Percival's Cook, went to the Red Horse in Bond Street. The two Men, Berridge and Arnold were standing at the Door, and the three Maids were drinking Tea within. We sat down with them, and asked them how the Fire happened. Elizabeth Pembroke answered, My Master is very much given to Reading in his Bed, and he did it himself. What time did he come home? Says I. Between 10 and 11. Says she. Was he in Drink? Says I, No, She said he was sober, she put him to Bed herself, drew the Curtains, and shut the Windows. Then he took his Book, and she said to him, Sir, do ye want any thing else? He answer'd No. I may read these two or three Hours; and as she was going out, he said to her, Bid the Footman take the Key of the Door that I mayn't be disturbed in the Morning, and tell him to take a Side-Box in the Play house; and so she said the Footman took the Key and carry'd it down and laid it upon the Table; and, as luck would have it, they had the Key, or they should all have been burnt - I asked her why they did not bring their Master down Stairs; and she said the Man was bringing him down, but the Fire catch'd hold of his (the Man's) Cap, and he fell down over his Master on the Stairs, and some body came and fetch'd him ( the Man) away, or he had been burnt too.</p>
               <p>Council. Were the Men present when she said this?</p>
               <p>S. L.. I cannot tell that.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth James, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person424">
                  Elizabeth 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person424" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person424" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person424" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person425">
                  Sarah 
                  Leneve 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person425" type="surname" value="Leneve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person425" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person425" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the RedHorse in Bond street the next Morning after the Fire. All the Servants were there - I can't say the Men were there; but the three Maids were. - Leneve said, How came this Fire? And Elizabeth Pembroke said that her Master did it, fot his way was to read a-bed every Night. - That he came home between 10 and 11, and went up to bed - Then she warm'd the Bed, and shut the Windows, and asked him if he wanted any thing else: That he answer'd, No Child, go all to Bed, I may read this three Hours. That she shut the Door herself, and he called his Man and bid him take the Key; but did not say what Key. - Leneve asked her why they did not take their Master down: And she made answer, that the Man did go to take him, but swooned upon the Corps, and his Cap was on fire, and he had been burnt if some body had not carried him away.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040031"></xptr>Council. Did she say nothing else of her Master?</p>
               <p>E. J. That the Left-side of his Face and Shoulders, and Belly were burnt.</p>
               <p>Council. Nothing else?</p>
               <p>E. J. Not about her Master; but she said that when the Servant knock'd at the Door, she jump'd out of Bed, and he called Fire: but she did not believe him, and so was going to Bed again; but something pull'd her by the Arm and said, Get up, or you'll be burnt: And presently she heard her Fellow-Servants upon the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Council. Did she tell you nothing at all of any Blood that she saw?</p>
               <p>E. J. No not a Word.</p>
               <p>Council. Nor of her Master's being pull'd down Stairs.</p>
               <p>E. J. No, I heard no such thing.</p>
               <p>Mary Blaston, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person426">
                  Mary 
                  Blaston 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person426" type="surname" value="Blaston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person426" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person426" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About half an Hour past three, that Morning as the Fire happened, as I was going along Albemarle street, to wash at my Lady Trevor's, I saw a Man come out in his Shirt and Breeches, and white Cap, and look'd towards the Top of the House, and then go in again and shut the Door softly.</p>
               <p>Council. Do ye know what House he came out of?</p>
               <p>M. B. No I can't say I do.</p>
               <p>Council. Was it the same House that was burnt?</p>
               <p>M. B. I am not sure of that.</p>
               <p>Edward Martin, sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person427">
                  Edward 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person427" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person427" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Coachman. I had been with my Lady Mrs. Aston (Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person428">
                  Thomas 
                  Aston 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person428" type="surname" value="Aston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person428" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Sister) to - Street; and having set my Lady down, I saw several People about Sir T omas Clarges's Door; and among the rest there was the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person429">
                  Isaac 
                  Barridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person429" type="surname" value="Barridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person429" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He was iron'd and complain'd that his Irons were very troublesome to him, but said he should have a heavier Pair that Night. Somebody asked him, Why so? Because, says he, I shall go to Newgate to Night: Upon which a Woman said, May be more than you may go. I believe not, says he, for they don't deserve it.</p>
               <p>Council. Who did he speak of then?</p>
               <p>E. M. His Fellow-Servants - he said Neither of my Fellow-Servants deserve it.</p>
               <p>Council. Did he say that he himself deserved to go?</p>
               <p>E. M. No; He said his two Fellow-Servants did not deserve to go; but he should go himself.</p>
               <p>Council. This is not material - Mr. Parry, look on those Papers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person430">
                  Isaac 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person430" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person430" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Clerk to Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person431">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person431" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person431" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are the Examinations of the Prisoner before Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person432">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person432" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person432" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - This is the Examination of 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person433">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pembroke 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person433" type="surname" value="Pembroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person433" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person433" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - and this is her second Examination.</p>
               <p>Council. Were they read over to her.</p>
               <p>I. Parry. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. And did she sign them voluntarily.</p>
               <p>I. Parry. Yes - And here are the Examinations of 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person434">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person434" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person434" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person435">
                  Richard 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person435" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person435" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - They are both upon one Sheet - The first is Arnold's, I saw him sign his Name to it freely, after it had been read over to him: The other is Berridge's, and he set his Mark to it voluntarily, after he had heard it read.</p>
               <p>Court. Read the Examinations</p>
               <p>Clerk. Reads the Examinations.</p>
               <p>Middlesex, to wit.</p>
               <p>The Examination of 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person436">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person436" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person436" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , taken before me Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person437">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person437" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person437" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bart. one of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace for the County of Middlesex, the 14th Day of May, 1734.</p>
               <p>' THIS Examinant saith, that he  was a Servant to one Mr. Cantillon,  in Albemarle-street, and has lived  with him about three Weeks. - That  this Morning, between three and four  a-Clock, as he lay a-bed with his Fellow-Servant  
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person438">
                  Isaac 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person438" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person438" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he heard a  knocking at the Street Door, and calling out Fire! That he and his Fellow-Servant got up, and went down  Stairs, and opened the Door: that then he went into the Yard, and saw<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040032"></xptr> Smoak come out of the Wall of his  Master's Bed-Chamber; upon which, he, this Examinant, went up to his Master's Room Door, knocked at it several Times, and called to him, but was not answered by him. That he hearing the Fire snap within the Room, immediately broke the Door open, and the Smoak came out so fast that he was forced to retire. That soon after, he saw his said Fellow-Servant go into the Bed-Chamber, or Room, once or twice, and cried out much, and at last pulled his Master off the Bed, and dragg'd him to the Stair-Case; and observed that he was burnt about the Neck and Face, and Bowels; and did not observe whether he had any Linnen on; and further saith, that he believes his Fellow-Servant found the Key of the Street-Door in the Parlour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person439">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person439" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person439" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Taken and acknowledged before me the Day and Year aforesaid.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person440">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person440" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person440" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Witness. J. Parry.</p>
               <p>Middlesex, co wit.</p>
               <p>The Examination of Isaac Berridge, taken before me the 14th Day of May, 1734</p>
               <p>' THIS Examinant saith, that he was a Servant to one Mr. Cantillon in Albemarle-street, lately deceased; and had lived with him about four Months. That for about three Weeks last past, his said Master had taken the the Key of the Street-Door up into his Bed-Chamber; and believes his Reason for so doing was upon some Distaste he took to a Servant discharg'd three Weeks ago: but that last Night he left the Key, together with his  Watch below in the Parlour, and believes it was on account of this Examinant's being to go early in the Morning to take a Box for him in the Opera; because that he gave him Directions for that purpose. That he let his Master in last Night about Eleven a Clock, who undrest himself in the Parlour as usual; took his Candle and Book, and went up to Bed soon after; and told this Examinant he would read. That as this Examinant was in Bed with his Fellow-Servant, he heard a knocking at the Door between the Hours of three and four o'Clock, and Fire cry'd out, that he immediately got up, put on his Cloaths, and went down Stairs and opened the Street Door: That he afterwards went into the Yard, and saw the Smoke coming out of the Wall of his Master's Bed-Chamber, and immediately ran up Stairs; and coming to his Master's Chamber- Door, found it open, and attempted once or twice, to pull his Master out of Bed, the Room being full of Smoke and Fire: that at last, he got him by the Legs, and pulled him off the Bed to the Stair-Case, and then swooned away, and was carried off. Says, he does not remember he had his Shirt on, and that his Breast, Face and Bowels, were scorched and burnt; and does not remember his having his Night-Cap on. Says, that his said Master usually locked himself up.</p>
               <p>His Mark, Isaac + Berridge.</p>
               <p>Taken and acknowledged the Day and Year aforesaid before me</p>
               <p>Thomas Clarges.</p>
               <p>Witness. J Parry.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040033"></xptr>Middlesex, to wit.</p>
               <p>The Examination of Elizabeth Pembroke, taken before me Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person441">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person441" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person441" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bart. one of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace for the said County, the 19th Day of May, 1734.</p>
               <p>' THIS Examinant saith, that she was Servant to 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person442">
                  Richard 
                  Cantillon 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person442" type="surname" value="Cantillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person442" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; deceased, in Albemarle-street: and that between three and four o'Clock in the Morning, on the 14th Instant, she was awaked by some Person knocking at her Master's Door, that she got up and put her Gown upon one Arm, and looked out of the Window, and was asked to call the Servants, for there was reason to believe the House was on Fire; and that she answered, she believed not, upon which she went to call the rest of the Servants, and saw them coming out of the Room; and further saith, that she did not see her, Master's Body.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Pembroke.</p>
               <p>Taken and acknowledged the Day and Year aforesaid, before me, Thomas Clarges.</p>
               <p>Witness. J. Parry.</p>
               <p>Middlesex, to wit.</p>
               <p>The further Examination of Elizabeth Pembroke, taken before me Sir Thomas Clarges, Bart. one of his Majesty's Justices of the, Peace for the said County, this 28th Day, of May, 1734.</p>
               <p>' THIS Examinant declares and says, that she did not warm the Bed of her Master Richard Cantillon, Esq; deceased, or see him in Bed, for about two Months before the Fire happened; except, that she was once called to take a Blanket off the Bed, about two Sundays before the Fire. And she further saith, that she did not hear her Master, the Night before the Fire, call a Man-Servant into his Room, to take the Key of the Street-Door, to take a Side-Box in the Play-house; but the Man-Servant, Isaac, came down Stairs, and told this Examinant, his Master had left the Key of the Street-Door in the Parlour. This Examinant further faith, that she never had any Conversation with 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person443">
                  Sarah 
                  Leneve 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person443" type="surname" value="Leneve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person443" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person444">
                  Elizabeth 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person444" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person444" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person444" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             since her Master's House was burnt; except once, that the said Sarah Leneves came to the Red-horse, and told this Examinant she was sorry for her Misfortune; which was all that passed between them at that time.'</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Pembroke.</p>
               <p>Taken and acknowledged before me the Day and Year aforesaid. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person445">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarges 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person445" type="surname" value="Clarges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person445" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Witness. J. Parry.</p>
               <p>Council. My Lord, we rest our Evidence here.</p>
               <p>Court. Then the Prisoners may make their Defence - Isaac Berridge, What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Berridge. I have nothing to say to the Fact, but that I am innocent - I have two or three Witnesses to my Character - I lived in Northamptonshire before I came hither; I have been but a little time in London, and have but a small Acquaintance. The first Place I lived in was Mr. Cantillon's</p>
               <p>Mr. Wadeson was call'd and sworn.</p>
               <p>Court. Give the Court an account of what you know of the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wadeson. I have heard Mr. Cantillon several times complain of his Servants in general.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040034"></xptr>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person446">
                  Baron 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person446" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person446" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am not asking you about other Servants. Do you know the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person447">
                  Isaac 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person447" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person447" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Wadeson. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baron Carter. Howlong have you known him, and what do you know of his Character and Behaviour?</p>
               <p>Mr. Wadeson. I cannot tell exactly how many Weeks I have known him; but from about the latter end of January, till the beginning of May, when the Accident happen'd. He is us'd to come with his Master to our House, both in Town and Country, and his Behaviour was modest and sober; and I have heard his Master say, that he believed he was an honest Boy.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gordon. I did work for Mr. Cantillon, for which Isaac paid me: I knew him six Weeks while he lived in that Gentleman's Service; and I believe him to be a very honest young Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person448">
                  John 
                  Bounford 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person448" type="surname" value="Bounford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person448" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red Horse in Bond-street: The Deceas'd's Horses were kept at my House. Isaac often came thither, and always behaved himself very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person449">
                  Robert 
                  Avis 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person449" type="surname" value="Avis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person449" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Elizabeth Pembroke eight Years; she lived with me two Years; she was a very honest, faithful, and just Servant, and always bore a good Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Peters. She lived with me five Months about three Years ago; she behaved very well then, and I have heard a good Character of her since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person450">
                  William 
                  Gouge 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person450" type="surname" value="Gouge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person450" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her from her Infancy; I am Trustee to the School that put her out: She has had all the Encouragement that is allowable to those that are brought up there, and behave well - New Cloaths when they go out, and Thirty Shillings when they have staid a Year in a Place. I have traced her Character since she went away from thence, and have found it very good; which, if I had not, I should have wrong'd my Family in being bound for her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person451">
                  Josiah 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person451" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person451" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew her in the Charity-School, where she bore a very good Character.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person452">
                  Maltis 
                  Ryall 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person452" type="surname" value="Ryall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person452" type="given" value="Maltis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Parish where she was brought up; she had as good a Character as any young Woman in the Parish - I never knew a better Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cunningham. She lived with my Wife as Chamber Maid from January to May; she was trusted alone in our House when we were out of Town, and we never found but she was very honest.</p>
               <p>Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person453">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person453" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person453" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person453" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She lived with - Smith, Esq; at Weild hall in Essex. He would trust her with Keys when he would trust no body else. I know her to be very honest, and I believe there never was an honester Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person454">
                  Arthur 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person454" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person454" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person455">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person455" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person455" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             eight or nine Years when he lived with my Lord Bathurst - he was brought up in my Lord's Family, and bore an honest Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sedgwick. I served my Lord Bathurst; I knew 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person456">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person456" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person456" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             eight Years there, and he always had a good Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. I have known him six or seven Years - All the Family gives him a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person457">
                  Alexander 
                  Lovett 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person457" type="surname" value="Lovett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person457" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived eighteen Years with my Lord Bathurst. 
               <persName id="t17341204-58-person458">
                  Roger 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person458" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person458" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came a Child into that Family; he continued in it about eleven Years, and had Wages six Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-58-person459">
                  Richard 
                  Brewart 
               <interp inst="t17341204-58-person459" type="surname" value="Brewart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person459" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight Years, and never saw him disguis'd in Liquor; and I believe he's as honest a Fellow as lives.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-58-verdict290" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-58-verdict290" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoners</p>
            </div1>
