<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-4">
               <interp inst="t17390502-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-4" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-4" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-4-off15-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-defend50 t17390502-4-off15 t17390502-4-verdict19"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-4-off17-c45" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-defend54 t17390502-4-off17 t17390502-4-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>237. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-4-defend50" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Barnes 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend50" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend50" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-4-off15" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-off15" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-off15" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, and Silver Seal, val. 7 l. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-4-victim52" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Hutchinson 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-4-victim52" type="surname" value="Hutchinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-4-victim52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-4-victim52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-4-cd16" type="crimeDate">Apr. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-off15 t17390502-4-cd16"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-off17 t17390502-4-cd16"></join>. And,</p>
               <p>238. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-4-defend54" type="defendantName">
                     Margery 
                     Akers 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend54" type="surname" value="Akers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend54" type="given" value="Margery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-defend54" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17390502-4-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same; knowing it to be stole
            </rs>, Apr 2.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-4-person55">
                  William 
                  Hutchinson 
               <interp inst="t17390502-4-person55" type="surname" value="Hutchinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person55" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 2d of April I was coming by Spring Gardens, at the Bottom of the Park, pretty much in Liquor, and I met with the Prisoner Barnes, and another Woman not taken; I went with them to the George Tavern in Spring Gardens, and from thence to the <placeName id="t17390502-4-crimeloc18">Cross Keys in St. Martin's Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-4-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Cross Keys in St. Martin's Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-4-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-off15 t17390502-4-crimeloc18"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-4-off17 t17390502-4-crimeloc18"></join>; while we were there, Barnes came and sat in my Lap, and took my Watch:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020004"></xptr> I felt it in my Pocket just before, but I miss'd it presently after she had sat in my Lap, and I told the Prisoner I had lost it; upon which she went to the other Woman, and that other Woman ran away; so I laid hold of the Prisoner; and afterwards, upon making Enquiry after my Watch, this Evidence [Watkins] brought it to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-4-person56">
                  James 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17390502-4-person56" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person56" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner Akers lives in Lumley Court in the Strand; I happen'd to be with a Friend next Door to Akers's, and she (Akers) came in, and enquired for 
               <persName id="t17390502-4-person57">
                  George 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17390502-4-person57" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person57" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said, she wanted to get this Watch pawn'd. Groves happen'd not to be at Home, so she gave it me, and went with me to the Rose in Long Acre; we both went in, and she asked three Guineas upon it, the Pawnbroker would lend but two; then she said, he must let her have Two Guineas and a half. He refused, and we were at the Door coming away; but at last she turned about and took the two Guineas. The next Morning I informed the Prosecutor that his Watch was pawn'd; he gave me Money to redeem it, and I returned it to him. This is the Watch.</p>
               <p>Hutchinson. This is the Watch I lost:</p>
               <p>Watkins. I had heard that Mr. Hutchinson had lost his Watch, and by going sometimes to Akers's House, I saw it; she shewed it me, and said, that was the Watch. She had been talking to me several Times before about it, though I don't know how she came to do it, for I had no Concern in it, - no, none at all. I heard her say, Mr. Hutchinson had been robbed of his Watch, and that this was the Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Akers. Ask him whether he did not come to my House and call for a Pint of Wine, and not having Money to pay for it, whether he did not pull out the Watch himself, and desire me to go with him to pawn it, that he might pay me a Shilling for the Wine, and another Shilling for lying in my House all Night?</p>
               <p>Watkins. She shewed me the Watch, and went with me to pawn it, for Fear the Pawnbroker should refuse to take it in from me. She herself asked the Pawnbroker to lend her the Money upon it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fraser. This Woman (Akers) keeps a most notorious House, in the Parish of St. Martin's in the Fields; a Harbour for Thieves. She was brought before me, she made no Manner of Defence.</p>
               <p>Hutchinson. She owned before the Justice, that she received the Money for the Watch, and was very sorry for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-4-person58">
                  James 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17390502-4-person58" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person58" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Akers's House about a Month ago, and the Evidence [Watkins] came in, and told her, he wanted a Trifle of Money; and if she would lend him a little Matter upon a Watch, he said, he would pay her the Rent which was due to her, from a Friend of his who lodged in a House which she rented at next Door. She refused to lend him Money upon it, (I believe she had none to lend,) but she agreed to go with him to a Pawnbroker's, and I staid in the House till she and the Prisoner came back; and then I heard her say, the young Fellow has pawned the Watch for two Guineas in Long-Acre. He did not stay 3 Minutes in the House before they both went out, in order to pawn it. Akers keeps a private House, but I have often drank Punch there, and the Evidence drank something when he came back, I did not see him drink any thing before.</p>
               <p>Akers. He had two Pints of Wine before we went out with the Watch; I had nine Shillings out of the Money he received at the Pawnbroker's, which was due to me from 
               <persName id="t17390502-4-person59">
                  George 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17390502-4-person59" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person59" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Footman, who is an Acquaintance of Watkins.</p>
               <p>Watkins. I never saw this Man (Chapman) in the House, nor have I ever drank with him: Both <rs id="t17390502-4-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-4-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
