<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-23">
               <interp inst="t17381206-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-23" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-23" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-23-off103-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-23-defend158 t17381206-23-off103 t17381206-23-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>26. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-defend158" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Andrews 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-23-defend158" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-defend158" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-defend158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17381206-23-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately and secretly stealing 55 Guineas, the Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-23-victim160" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Tanner 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-23-victim160" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-23-victim160" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-23-victim160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-23-off103 t17381206-23-victim160"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , from his Person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17381206-23-cd104" type="crimeDate">Nov. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-23-off103 t17381206-23-cd104"></join>, in the Parish of St. Mary, Aldermanbury.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tanner. On Wednesday was Fortnight, half an Hour after Nine at Night, I and six or seven more Countrymen I went from The Three Nuns in Aldermanbury to see a Funeral. I stood (to see it go along) about twenty Yards from the Church-Door. While I was standing there, two Men came up against me, and one of them, with the Point of his (bent) Elbow kept my Arm thus, - (i.e. confined his Arm by keeping his bent Elbow between it and the Prosecutr's Body) and had it not been for the Crowd, he pressed me so hard with his Elbow, that I should have been drawn down by it. At the same Time I felt something grabbling in my Breeches Pocket. As soon as I could, I endeavoured to bring my Hand to my Pocket, but before I could do that, Kew (the next Witness) said to me, '' Sir, your Watch is '' picked out of your Pocket.'' No, no, says I, 'tis not my Watch, - 'tis my Money, - 'tis fifty five Guineas in a Purse, which was in my Left-hand Pocket, buttoned up; and the Purse lay at the Bottom of my Pocket. This is the Fellow to the Purse I lost; - I have been a hundred Miles in the Country for it. - I perceived it going, and that another was picking my Pocket, while my Arm was held up, by the other Person's Elbow; which was done with so much Force, that I could not stir my Arm, to secure my Pocket, and my Side is still sore, with (the Pressure of) the Point of his Elbow. I put my Hand into my Pocket, and cry'd - '' My '' Money is gone''! Kew said, - Then that's the Man, and immediately caught hold of him, and said, he would swear it. Then I took hold of him, and we carry'd him to the Three Nuns in Aldermanbury, and from thence he was carry'd to the Compter. I apprehend it was not the Prisoner, but another, who pinned me up with his Elbow, - but the Prisoner was pressing against me at the same time as close as he possibly could, and bit his Lips in this Manner, [Here Mr. Tanner bit his Lips and contracted the Muscles of his Face] and staring me full in the Face, while he was grabling in my Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person161">
                  James 
                  Kew 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person161" type="surname" value="Kew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person161" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of November I carried a Light at the Funeral in <placeName id="t17381206-23-crimeloc105">Aldermanbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-23-crimeloc105" type="placeName" value="Aldermanbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-23-crimeloc105" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-23-off103 t17381206-23-crimeloc105"></join>. When I came near the Church Gate, the Crowd press'd prodigiously. I stood with my Light, and the Countryman, (Tanner) stood by me: I knew him before. Presently I saw a Man come up, that goes by the Name of BLACK SAM; a Man of a base Character, and who gets his Bread this way. This rais'd my Suspicion, and seeing him, I imagin'd Mischief was going forward: I look'd at the Countryman, and believed 'twas intended toward him. Presently I saw Black Sam shove the Countryman, and the Prisoner (whom I never saw before) was behind Black Sam and the Countryman, but his Situation was a little on one Side of the Countryman. I thought the Prisoner's Hand was in his Pocket, and that he was the man; but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060010"></xptr> he look'd genteely dress'd, and I was so afraid to accuse him, that my Knees totter'd under me: But I observ'd what I could, and saw a Hand come out, just where the Countryman stood. I look'd at the Countryman, and thought they were picking his Pocket. As soon as the Hand was drawn from the Countryman, I saw Black Sam put out his Hand, and take something from the other. Something hung down, which I thought was the Chain of a Watch. Upon this I immediately said to the Countryman, - '' Sir, '' You have lost your Watch.'' Black Sam turned about to me that Instant, and said, - How d'ye, Master? How d'ye, Master? - and slipp'd by me. The Countryman, the same Minute said, 'twas not his Watch, but his Money, that was gone. Then, says I, this is the Man that took it, and caught hold of the Prisoner by the Collar: The Countryman seiz'd him likewise, and another Man coming up to our Assistance, he was carried to the Three Nuns, and I follow'd them soon after.</p>
               <p>Q. What Cloaths had the Person on that the Hand belong'd to which you saw drawn from the Countryman?</p>
               <p>Kew. He was in Blue-Grey, and I saw what he was about. Black Sam kept shoving him, and the Prisoner was behind the Countryman.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body between him and the Countryman?</p>
               <p>Kew. I don't apprehend there could be any one between them; for Black Sam kept shoving the Countryman, and the other was behind him: I believe there was no body between the Prisoner and the Countryman. There might be six People round them, but I don't apprehend that any body was between them.</p>
               <p>Q. When you charg'd him, as the Person that took the Money, what did he say?</p>
               <p>Kew. He said, - I take the Money! - Yes, says I, you took the Money, for I saw Black Sam with you. Why did not you secure Black Sam, says he? I said I was not sure of the thing, till the Countryman spake, and then he was just slipp'd by me. While the thing was doing, I don't apprehend that any one was between Sam and the Countryman, or between the Countryman and the Prisoner: For I was so near them, that I saw them both; and if I had had Spirit enough, I could have put out my Hand, and could have received it (the Hand with the Purse), for Black Sam put his Hand behind him, and the other Man all into his Hand but the Strings; then it was that I spoke, Black Sam turn'd to me - How d'ye, Master? and slipp'd away in the Crowd; an then I said to the Prisoner, Let it be what it will (that is lost) you're the Man, - because I said at first he had lost his Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you speak to the Prisoner in particular, above all the rest of the People?</p>
               <p>Kew. Because I thought he must be the Man that took it, and because before I spoke I thought he was about it; and because I thought no one was capable of doing it but Him; and my Thoughts were so strong, that I laid hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any one else so near, or so situate, as to be able to take the Purse, and put it into Black Sam's Hand, but the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Kew. It was my Opinion there was not. Black Sam only confin'd the Countryman, and I charg'd the Prisoner, because I thought no body else could do it; and, before I spoke, I thought he was about it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you, or Tanner, lay hold of me first?</p>
               <p>Tanner. Mr. Kew touch'd him by the Shoulder, and said, - You are the Man that pick'd his Pocket. He then took hold of him, and said he would swear it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not a Countrywoman as near Tanner, as I was?</p>
               <p>Tanner. No; there was not While I had got the Prisoner by the Collar, I look'd about for somebody to assist me, and I saw Mrs. Billings, who quarter'd in the Inn, and I call'd to her, and said, - Mrs. Billings, this Man has pick'd my Pocket of 44 Guineas, for God's sake take hold of him! Upon this, she and some others assisted me, and we got him to the Three Nuns</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr. Kew if I had not both my Gloves on, and my Cane in my Hand, at that Time?</p>
               <p>Tanner. He had his Cane in his Hand, - but he had no Gloves on. I look'd at his Hands the same time he was seiz'd.</p>
               <p>Kew. I did not look at his Hands at all; but caught him by the Collar, at the Instant I suspected him to have done the thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the Hand that deliver'd the Purse to Black Sam's a Glove on? (to Kew)</p>
               <p>Kew. No; none at all.</p>
               <p> Abraham Woodhoster. I paid Mr. Tanner 57l. 6 s. for some Cloth I bought of him, on the 21st of November, by a Draught on the Bank .</p>
               <p>Tanner. I had 16 Shillings from another Person, which I was to carry down and pay in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060011"></xptr> the Country. The Draught upon the Bank I received between Twelve and One the Day before; so I made up 65 Guineas, and put them in a Purse.</p>
               <p>Mr. Woohoster. I take Mr. Tanner to be a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr. Tanner, it he has not been encouraged to prosecute me in hopes of the Forty Pounds Reward?</p>
               <p>C. There's no Reward at all in this Case.</p>
               <p>Tanner. I have neither been applying to get my Money made up, nor to make up the Matter. After I had been robb'd, I went away directly into the Country, and travell'd Night and Day to get home. My Pocket was pick'd on Wednesday Evening, and I got to Froome in Somersetshire on Sunday, for fear the Gang should do me a Mischief after the Prisoner was sent to Newgate. I had brought up some Goods to sell; and as I was in Necessity for Money against Christmas, I sold these Goods at Five Pounds Loss. I had been absent three Weeks from Home; and though I went home directly, yet several of my Neighbours met me, and lamented my Misfortune, which they had heard of by the News-Papers, before I got home, and by a private Letter which somebody had sent into the Country. On Tuesday after I got home, one Gully came into the Crown Inn at Froome, and said he had been in Gloucestershire, Bristol, and other Places, buying Goods; he pull'd out a Sheet of Paper, wrote on both Sides, and told the People he was come to Froome to buy 100 Pieces of Cloth. On Wednesday Morning this Man sent for me; I was afraid to go, lest it should be to arrest me, as I had met with this Misfortune; so I sent a Friend to drink a Pint of Beer there, and learn who it was that wanted me. He returned, and told me 'twas a Gentleman that came from London; so I went to him, and he ask'd me what I would please to drink, and told me he heard I had the Misfortune to have 55 Guineas pick'd out of my Pocket lately at London; I told him 'twas true, and the worse Luck was mine. Says he, I have been considering on my Pillow, by what Means you might have your Money again. I said was a great Loss to me - Ay, says he, 'tis a great Loss to a poor Tradesman, - I beg your Pardon for calling you so - I am so, indeed, said I. Well, reply'd he, if you'll be rul'd by me, I'll find Means that you shall have your Money again, though the Man that took it is a Stranger to me, and I have been ten Days from London; yet I have Acquaintance who will make up this Matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that this Man came from the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tanner. He insisted upon it, that I should go to London with him, and though he said he came to buy many Pieces of Cloth, yet he would buy none, and at last the Gentlemen of the Place suspected he was a Confederate. About six or seven in the Evening he told me, he would lay me five Shillings, that sixty five Guineas should be made up to me if I would be directed by him, and that the Money should be found in some unknown Person's Pocket, and I should not sign any Writing at all. I told him, it was impossible to make up a Felony, and that the Lord-Mayor had commited him, and had ordered me not to make it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you make it out, that this Man came from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Tanner. He said, he came from London directly; and the Gentleman in the Town having some Suspicion of the Man, I was sent for to the George, and he was taken up, and put into Ilchester Gaol. When I got home, two Lawyers were sent to assure me, that this Man would give it me under his Hand, that if I would do as he would have me, I should have fifty-five Guineas, and ten for my Trouble. The Justice hearing this, was very angry the Gentlemen should suffer such a Person to be in the Town, - one who had offered to make up the Matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Still I ask you, whether you can prove this Man came from the Prisoner, or was employ'd by him?</p>
               <p>Tanner. I can't prove that - but there are several Names to the Papers (he had upon him) of Persons, that did employ him. My Lord With Submission, he was talking of forty Pounds which I expected to make of him, - I never had a Thought about, nor was any Money offer'd me, till this Man came to me to make it up.</p>
               <p>Defence. This Countryman is a Man of an ill Character, his Country people give him a bad Word. He can neither write nor read, and since he has lost his Money, he has heard I have three of four hundred Pounds, and he said he would swear any Thing to get two hundred Pounds of it. He is a litigious Man, - I thought the Court would have indulged me, - I have feed Council, -</p>
               <p>C. But here is no Point of Law; and you know Matters of Fact as well as your Council.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Night this thing happened, I was going from Gutter Lane Moorfields, and the singing Boys being at the Funeral, I stood between<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060012"></xptr> the Church-Gate and the Conduit, to see them. As I stoed there, a Man came and asked me, Whose Burying that was? I told him, I could not tell. Then a young Woman, who had washed for me, stopped, I asked how she did, and took her by the Hand, with my Gloves on; but before she had spoke a Word out of her Mouth, this Man came and took me by the Collar, and said I had got Mr. Tanner's Watch, tho' I knew nothing of the Matter; and a Woman that belonged to Tanner came and clapped hold of my Collar too. I was carry'd to the Three Nuns, and there I pulled off my Gloves, and turned out my Pockets, and I had - no more than an Eighteen-shilling Piece and some Silver - about me, - that was all I had, - in my Pockets. Call Henry Emps, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person162">
                  Henry 
                  Emps 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person162" type="surname" value="Emps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person162" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Chick Lane, and sell Cloaths, I was going that Night to the Axe Inn, and the Funeral coming by, I asked the Prisoner, Whose Funeral it was? I never saw him, - nor knew him before, - but he was in grey Cloaths, with a Glove (or Gloves) on, leaning on his Cane. He told me, he did not know; so I walked away, and was not farther from him, than I am now, when a Woman came up and spoke to him, and presently, I heard a Noise, that a Person was laid hold of, for picking Pockets: I crowded up, and saw it was the Person I had just been speaking to.</p>
               <p>Q. What Distance of Time might there be, between your speaking to the Prisoner, and your hearing this Noise?</p>
               <p>Emps. Not a great while: Five, six or seven Minutes. - It might be seven or eight, for aught I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the Axe Inn that Night?</p>
               <p>Emps. Yes; to enquire for a Man that came from Birmingham, but they did not know him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person163">
                  Susan 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person163" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person163" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going up Aldermanbury at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business are you of?</p>
               <p>Phillips. I follow the Wash-Tub, and was going to put off a Day's Scowering at the George and Gate, in Gracechurch-Street, but seeing the Funeral, I stopped, as others did, and seeing the Prisoner, for whom I used to wash, I asked him for his Washing, &amp;c. I said it was a fine Burying; - Yes, says he, and took me by the Hand, and says he, - pray excuse me, - my Gloves are on. - And not a Minute afterward, - no, - not Half a Minute afterwards, - the Mob seized him, and cary'd him away; I can safely swear to a Minute, and I was just by him when this happened.</p>
               <p>Kew. I don't remember this Woman's Face.</p>
               <p>Phillips. No; I was in a Deshabille then, and had my Leathern Apron under my Arm, - I had just done Washing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I <rs id="t17381206-23-deflabel106" type="occupation">deal in Hollands and Cambricks</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-23-defend158 t17381206-23-deflabel106"></join>, - but I deal with People at the Scotch-Wharf for ready Money, - with Captains of Ships, so I have my Goods the cheaper, - they are not Run Goods; and I have a Correspondent at Bristol who sends me Irish Cloth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person164">
                  Thomas 
                  Hawkes 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person164" type="surname" value="Hawkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person164" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Ayliffe Street, - Little Ayliffe Street. I have known the Gentleman at the Bar these ten Years, I have worked for him, and he has lodged in my House. I never heard any Thing ill of him in my Life; - I believe he would rather give a Shilling, - than wrong any one of a Farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he lodged in your House?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. He lodged in my House when he was taken, and he used to carry Bundles in and out, - he always dealt fairly with me, so I never asked him about his Business, but he used to talk - about Hollands and Cambricks, and he used to buy Stockings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person165">
                  Mary 
                  Packenham 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person165" type="surname" value="Packenham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person165" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Gentleman that stands at the Bar, lodged with me, - at Times, upwards of seven Years. He has been gone from me two Years and a Half. When he lived with me, he dealt in Irish Cloth and Scotch Cloth, and I, being a Mantua maker, have disposed of some Poundsworth for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person166">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Houseman 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person166" type="surname" value="Houseman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person166" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him fifteen Years, and have bought Cloth and Stockings of him. He used to come to my House, because - he knew it very well, - I live in a Lodging, and have about fifty Pounds a Year Income. I knew his Wife, she lived about three Years with him, and was an Acquaintance of mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person167">
                  Amelia 
                  Harrup 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person167" type="surname" value="Harrup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person167" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten Years, and have dealt with him for Cloth, Handkerchiefs, and Stockings. I buy them of him, and sell them again to my Acquaintance, I always believed him to be a very honest, just Gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person168">
                  James 
                  Aris 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person168" type="surname" value="Aris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person168" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Back-maker to Brewers and Distillers, in Old street, and 
               <persName id="t17381206-23-person169">
                  John 
                  Catterns 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person169" type="surname" value="Catterns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person169" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had known him a great while, one eight, the other twenty Years, and said he bore an honest, handsome Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person170">
                  Ralph 
                  Crawford 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person170" type="surname" value="Crawford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person170" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Scotch Wharf, near the Hermitage, said he knew him to be frequently with Men belonging to Ships; that he bought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060013"></xptr> Goods, and paid them and him for what he had of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person171">
                  Thomas 
                  Grainger 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person171" type="surname" value="Grainger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person171" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew him fourteen Years; his Wife and Sister bought Cloth and Stockings of him, and he never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person172">
                  Catherine 
                  Mattocks 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person172" type="surname" value="Mattocks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person172" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew him ten Years, and deposed to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person173">
                  William 
                  Hopper 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person173" type="surname" value="Hopper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person173" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew nothing of his Dealing, but he used to clean his Cloaths for him, and he paid him for so doing.</p>
               <p>The following Witnesses were called to Mr. Tanner's Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person174">
                  Henry 
                  Kingman 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person174" type="surname" value="Kingman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person174" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Froome, and have known Tanner 10 Years. He always behaved like a very honest Man. Some Years ago, he was charged with a Thing for which he took his Trial, but he was acquitted. The Case I don't know at present.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person175">
                  Thomas 
                  Grainger 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person175" type="surname" value="Grainger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person175" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Son of the Woman that keeps the Three Nuns. I know Mr. Tanner to be a very honest Man, and one who would not wrong any one of a Farthing. He never gets drunk, nor raves and swears as some others do. As to the Charge that the former Witness mentioned, I have heard it mentioned by his Countrymen, that he bought some Wool, which proved to be stole, but he was honourably acquitted, and every body thought him innocent, and that it was a malicious Prosecution.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person176">
                  Isaac 
                  Percival 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person176" type="surname" value="Percival"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person176" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Neighbourhood, his general Character is, that he is a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-23-person177">
                  Edward 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person177" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person177" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by when this Fact was committed, and I heard him say, This Man had robbed him of almost sixty Pounds, so I assisted him to the Three Nuns, and made the Prisoner go up Stairs. I asked him, what Friends he had to send for? He had none, and scrupled very much to tell his Name. I insisted upon his being searched, and he took a Piece of Gold and some Silver out of his Pockets, but they were not turned inside out. I think he was playing with his Gloves in (not on) his Hands when he was brought into the House.</p>
               <p>Mr. Percival. I saw no Gloves at all.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marsh. They were not upon his Hands when he was in the House. I heard Kew then say, - '' Lord now must I take this '' Man's Life away! I saw him hand something '' to Black Sam! Must I swear this''</p>
               <p>Mr. Tanner called an Officer in Court to give an Account of the Prisoner, who deposed that he had been known as a Pickpocket about the Town, for a long Time; that he had known him three or four Years, and believed him to be a Pickpocket; and that he had carry'd him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17381206-23-person178">
                  Richard 
                  Brocas 
               <interp inst="t17381206-23-person178" type="surname" value="Brocas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person178" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about a Lottery Ticket, lost in Exchange-Alley.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17381206-23-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-23-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
