<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360505-89">
               <interp inst="t17360505-89" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-89" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-89" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360505"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-89" type="date" value="17360505"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360505-89-off421-c443" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-89-defend633 t17360505-89-off421 t17360505-89-verdict423"></join>
         
               <p>104. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-defend633" type="defendantName">
                     Jacob 
                     Dell 
                  <interp inst="t17360505-89-defend633" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-defend633" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-defend633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17360505-89-defloc420">St. Botolph Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360505-89-defloc420" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360505-89-defloc420" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-89-defend633 t17360505-89-defloc420"></join>, <rs id="t17360505-89-off421" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-off421" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-off421" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               was indicted that he on the <rs id="t17360505-89-cd422" type="crimeDate">21 of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-89-off421 t17360505-89-cd422"></join>, with Force and Arms, 14 Dozen Pounds of the Candles, Parcel of the 20 Dozen, feloniously stolen, did receive, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person634">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Grigson 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person634" type="surname" value="Grigson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person634" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person634" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17360505-89-person635">
                  Richard 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person635" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person635" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person635" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger, convicted for stealing the Candles, lived in my House; I sold the Candles for him, and paid him the Money. Mr. Dell had 14 Dozen of them. I sold them to him for 4 s. a Dozen.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you never sell any for less than 4 d. a Pound?</p>
               <p>Grigson. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you never sell any for a half Penny a Candle?</p>
               <p>Grigson. No *; I sold them for three Farthings a Candle, and to Dell for 4 s. a Dozen. The Man lodged in my House, and owed me Money, and said he would pay me if I sold the Candles, and I thought Dell a proper Person to buy them. I keep a Chandler's Shop and sold Candles in the Shop.</p>
               <p>* See 
               <persName id="t17360505-89-person636">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holden 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person636" type="surname" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person636" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person636" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Evidence on Yates's Trial; Sessions Paper, No. 3.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to sell such Quantities as 14 Dozen at a Time?</p>
               <p>Grigson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Dell ever your Customer, but for Candles?</p>
               <p>Grigson. No, and he had these all at one Price.</p>
               <p>Pris. What Quantities of them were broke?</p>
               <p>Grigson. Near half of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apply to Dell, or did Dell apply to you?</p>
               <p>Grigson. I went to him, and asked him if he wanted any Candles; he asked what Candles they were I told him there were 17 or 18 to the 3 Pounds; he asked me whence they came; I said, they were Perquisites of the King's Servants.</p>
               <p>Council. Perquisite Candles! have all you sold been li't or broken?</p>
               <p>Grigson. I can bring some People who have had Candles neither li't nor broke.</p>
               <p>Q. And don't you think they are such Perquisites as Peop'e are try'd here for.</p>
               <p>Juryman. What induced you to apply to Mr. Dell?</p>
               <p>Grigson. I dealt with him for Butter, Cheese and Bacon.</p>
               <p>Council. Other Candles you sold for 5 d. a Pound, how came you to sell these for 4 d. when they were thicker and larger?</p>
               <p>Grigson. They were indeed thicker and larger, but I believe there was almost one half of them broke, and Dell said he did not think them any great Penny-worth on that account.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you tell me they were Dutch Candels?</p>
               <p>Q. If she told you they were Dutch Candles, how came you to imagine they were the King's Candles?</p>
               <p>Grigson. I thought they were Perquisite Candles, come from Holland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person637">
                  Henry 
                  Willonghby 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person637" type="surname" value="Willonghby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person637" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person637" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of January, I was sent for and told, that the Excise-Officers had seized a large Quantity of Candles, supposing them not to have paid the Duty: Upon Enquiry I found them to be my Mother in Law's Candles, They were seized about<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173605050038"></xptr> Two o'Clock, and about Eight I was sent for, and then Dell came to me and said, I have got some of Mrs. Greswell's Candles that were stole; this was after the Discovery. I am surpriz'd, says I, that you should encourage any Thing of this Kind, I have 10 or 11 Dozen, says he, I bought them for Perquisite Candles: They must be broke or lit then, said I. No, he told me, that there was not one broke, nor one that had been lighted. I asked him what could tempt him to buy such Quantities, they were more than could be Perquisite Candles fairly, the King should not be here any more than a private Person; but now the Thieves are tied, you make the Discovery. However, I would have thought as well of Mr. Dell. as I could, and hoped he would have assisted me in the Prosecution of the Persons concerned, but he told me he would not come. I had put this Woman into the Indictment with the two Yates's, but I knew I could not convict the Prisoners without him: He came at last, and was in the Court when the Bill was drawn, but went away, and I was forced to have another Bill drawn, and to admit the Woman an Evidence in this, who was a Principal in the other, else I could not have made any thing out.</p>
               <p>Council Are you sure Dell told you, that none of the Candles were broke, nor lit?</p>
               <p>Willoughby. On my Conscience and Oath, he told me they were not; and that he bought them as Perquisite Candles from St. James's. After the Trial was over, I asked him what he designed to do with the Candles: he said he would keep them. What, says I, after you have heard the Property prov'd? Do you act like an honest Man?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I freely own I bought the Candles, and told you the Price?</p>
               <p>Willoughby. He did, and threatned me if I did so and so, if I went on with the Prosecution, what he would do.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you apprehend this Indictment was Felony?</p>
               <p>Willoughby. I did not know what it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you say you was shock'd at it?</p>
               <p>Willoughby. I said I was sorry, and was, perhaps, more uneasy, than he was himself</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I bring this Letter to you, which Grigson sent to me, by which means the Thief was taken?</p>
               <p>Willoughby. I believe I might see this Letter, but, I believe it was a Day or two afterward. Clerk reads the Letter.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Dell, These, Signed Eliz Grigson.</p>
               <p>Sir. 'I am in the Concern in Life to ' hear of the Trouble you are like to have on my ' Account, but depend on my appearing to ' you. I am innocent of their being stole, as ' you are. He told me, they were Perquisites ' of the King's Servants: I took them as such, ' and, he says, they came from Holland: I ' have heard he is in Farthing Fields. There ' are 4 or 5 near Houses, and he is at the 3d ' and the Persons Name is Malt, and I should ' be glad if Mr Bray and you could take him ' to clear us. Sir, be satisfied, I will appear ' whenever you have necessity for me, or I ' should think myself the worst of Creatures; ' or if it was that which would hang me, I ' will appear and own I sold them for Perquisite ' Candles, and he brought them to me open, ' and I unhappily brought them to you unknown ' to him: When I see you, I will give ' you a more particular Account, which shall be ' whenever you fix the Time.'</p>
               <p>Q What do Candles sell for in the common Way of Trade?</p>
               <p>Willoughby I gave my Mother five Shillings a Dozen: I had twelve Dozen, for which I paid 3 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person638">
                  John 
                  Speller 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person638" type="surname" value="Speller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person638" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person638" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Dell call'd me in one Day, before the Thing was found out, and shewed me a Candle; ( I was Mrs Greswell's Apprentice) and he said he had those Candles out of the Country at four Shillings a Dozen. I said I would give him four Shillings and six Pence for an Hundred Dozen. It was a whole Candle; he bid me break it, and I did, and I am sure they could not be made nor sold under five Shillings to get any Thing by them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person639">
                  Allen 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person639" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person639" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person639" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After the Thing was known, Mr. Dell shewed me about five Papers, a Dozen in a Paper: The Chief Part was whole, and there might be here and there a broken one, but very few, and all with whole Cottons: I believe there might be half a Dozen Pounds broke in the five Papers: He told me, he gave four Shillings a Dozen for them: I believe I made part of them myself, and they stood us in more, who were the Makers.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I not tell you my self, that I had bought Candles, and ask your Opinion?</p>
               <p>A. Parsons. After the Thing was found out, you came to me and said, you believed you had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173605050039"></xptr> some of our Candles, and that you had them of Grigson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person640">
                  William 
                  Cogan 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person640" type="surname" value="Cogan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person640" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person640" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After the Affair was known, I saw about five Dozen of Candles; and in the whole I believe there might be half a Dozen Pounds broken. I know they could not be sold under 5 s. a Dozen.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. The Charge against me is of a heinous Nature; no less than Felony; the Proof therefore ought to be strong, and bear a Proportion to the Charge, especially if it be against a Person of Reputation, as I shall prove my self to be. It may be the Misfortune of the honestest Man to buy Things in thus Manner; and if he is to answer for a second or third Hand, what Tradesman can be safe?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person641">
                  Thomas 
                  Weedward 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person641" type="surname" value="Weedward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person641" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person641" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Master asked Speller his Opinion of the Candles, he had then no more than one Dozen in the House, which he had by way of trial, I did not hear my Master say from whence they came: They were brought in openly, and when we had Customers in the Shop Our Porter told my Master. Mrs. Greswell had lost Candles, and her Journeyman came over with my Master to look at those.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person642">
                  Joseph 
                  Delafield 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person642" type="surname" value="Delafield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person642" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person642" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Dell freely shewed me the Candles, and told me and others what he gave for them; I cannot remember the particular time, but it was before the Discovery that they were stolen, and there were some of them broke; he said they were Perquisite Candles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person643">
                  John 
                  Hattersley 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person643" type="surname" value="Hattersley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person643" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person643" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed to the same Effect, adding that Grigson was a good Customer to him; that if she had come to him he should have taken them of her; that the Commissioners of the Navy at that time gave but 4 s. 2 d. a Dozen, and at that time Candles were sold at different Prices by different People.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person644">
                  Richard 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person644" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person644" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person644" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sold good condition'd Candles at that time for 4 s. 4 d. if these Candles were in the condition they have been sworn, I would not have given 3 s. 6 d. The Victualling Office a little before, gave 3 s. 11 d. I offered them at 3 s. 11 pence half penny per Dozen.</p>
               <p>- Bracebridge. Mr. Willoughby told me this Prosecution was owing to Dell's Obstinacy; if he had not been obstinate he had never gone so far.</p>
               <p>Justice Richards. I heard Willoughby say he expected Dell shou'd have return'd the Candles; that he was concerned at what was done, and had not had a Wink of Sleep all Night; but Mr. Dell he said, had not used him well, for he had told him, he had paid for the Candles  and would keep them, had he returned them, Mr. Willoughby said he should not have prosecuted him, and if the thing was to do again, he would not do it for the World.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person645">
                  Samuel 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person645" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person645" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person645" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have bought Perquisite Candles, some of which had been lit, and some only prepared for lighting, at three, four, or half a Dozen Pounds at a time, at three Shillings and eight Pence, or three Shillings and ten Pence, I cannot say, but I should have been cautious of buying them had the Cottons never been cut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-89-person646">
                  Charles 
                  Bray 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person646" type="surname" value="Bray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person646" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person646" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17360505-89-person647">
                  Allen 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17360505-89-person647" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person647" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-person647" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in my hearing own'd that his fellow Servant told him, Mr. Dell had shewn him the Candles, and asked him, if his Mistress would sell such Candles, so cheap; that he told him, there was a great deal of Stuff in them, to put him out of conceit with them, but that they were indeed as good Candles as ever he saw in his Life. Mr. Willoughby I believe might say at the Sessions House Gate that if Mr. Dell would not deliver the Candles he would proceed in another manner.</p>
               <p>Q. You had no Colour to think the Property of the Candles was alter'd; why did not you deliver the Candles?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I told him I would deliver them in a proper manner.</p>
               <p>John Hattersley, Mr Burroughs, Mr. Delafield, Justice Rickets, Mr. Overall, Mr. White, and Mr. Wright, gave the Prisoner a very good Character; and informed the Court, that he was a Man of Credit and Reputation; and one of too much Honour and Conscience to be capable of committing a mean or base Action. <rs id="t17360505-89-verdict423" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360505-89-verdict423" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>After the Trial was over, the Prisoner moved by his Council for a Copy of his Indictment, but the Court would not grant it.</p>
            </div1>
