<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-31">
               <interp inst="t17360610-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-31" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-31" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-31-off133-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-31-defend223 t17360610-31-off133 t17360610-31-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>37. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-defend223" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Raitt 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-31-defend223" type="surname" value="Raitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-defend223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-defend223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-31-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing (with 
                     <persName id="t17360610-31-person224">
                        Alexander 
                        Raitt 
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person224" type="surname" value="Raitt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-31-person224" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-31-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken) two silk Aprons, three silk Hoods, one Yard of Padesoy, one Burdett Gown and Petticoat, one Flaxen Sheet, two Napkins, one Table Cloath, a Muslin Handkerchief, six Cambrick ditto, two Muslin Aprons, five Suits of Cambrick Headcloaths, one pair of Cambrick Rufflels, with sundry other Goods, a Portugal piece of Gold value 36 s. and 5 Guineas
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-victim226" type="victimName">
                     Patrick 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-31-victim226" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-victim226" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-victim226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-31-off133 t17360610-31-victim226"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17360610-31-cd134" type="crimeDate">May 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-31-off133 t17360610-31-cd134"></join>
               </p>
               <p>Patrick Smith. Sunday May 16, about half an Hour after three in the Afternoon, my Wife and I took a Walk to Pancras, leaving all fast; the Street Door we left single Lock'd, because Mrs. Raitt the Prisoner's Mother, who lodg'd up Stairs should let herself in and out. About 10 we came home and found the Street-Door open: My Wife went up Stairs to undress her, and found her Drawers broke open and the Goods and Money ominated in the Indictment gone. Mrs. Raitt and the Prisoner came Home about 10. I enquir'd among the Neighbours, and they told me they had seen a young Woman come out with a Bundle, and Mrs. Raitt's two Sons walking about the Door to and fro. I took up Mrs. Raitt (her other Son liv'd in my House) but she was bail'd and he got off. The Woman who was concern'd in this Robbery has made herself an Evidence, and by her Directions we found these Goods at Laurana Ward's in Crown-Court in Chick-Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person227">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person227" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person227" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account, adding, that she had no suspicion of the Prisoner and his Brother, 'till she was informed by the Neighbours of his going up Stairs: That there were no other Lodgers in the House, and that a Neighbour told her Mrs. Cole who lived with Mrs. Raitt had carry'd out a Bundle, while her two Sons walked about the Door, and one of them had two bright Keys in his Hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person228">
                  Mary 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person228" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person228" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner about the Door, (I live over the way) looking as if he wanted somebody; he stood still; then walked backwards and forwards before the Door; this was about four o'Clock to the best of my Memory; I can't say I saw him either go in or come out: but Alexander the youngest, I saw come out with the Key of the Door in his Hand. He look'd both ways, and went in again; I thought he spoke to somebody behind the Door, and immediately this Mrs. Cole put her Head from behind the Door, and look'd me full in the Face; she seemed to be shy, so I turned my Head aside; then I look'd at them again, and saw her come cross the Kennel by herself, with a Bundle in her Hand: I never spake to her in my Life, and know her only by her living with Raitt.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100011"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person229">
                  Eliz 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person229" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person229" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived with Mrs. Raitt the Prisoner's Mother. On Sunday the Day the Robbery was committed between two and three o'Clock I went out to Sir John Oldcastle's, and returning in about an Hour, I met the younger Brother at the Door; he desired me to make haste up, for his Mother was ill. I went in, and seeing Smith's Door fast, I said, Mr. Smith is gone out I see. Yes, says he, and laughed. I went up Stairs, and saw their Chamber Door open, Lord bless me, said I, how came their Door open? What's that to you, Fool, says he, laughing: I stept into the Room, and saw the Lid of a Chest broke open, I saw the Whiteness of the Wood where it had been broke or cut. What have you been doing, says I? They bid me not trouble my Head, but go up Stairs, for both the Brothers were with me in the Prosecutor's Room, and went up with me; I went up Stairs, and saw a Bundle lie upon their Mother's Couch-bed, which they desired me to take out, for fear they should be discovered; I carried it out, and did not see what was in it till the Monday following. I asked them what they had been doing, and they said, they had been doing for themselves. I carried the Bundle to my Acquaintance, 
               <persName id="t17360610-31-person230">
                  Laurence 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person230" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person230" type="given" value="Laurence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Chick-Lane. On Sunday Night, (the same Night) the two Prisoners and I, went to an Ale-house, and we drank two Pints of Beer, and told them I would never go home any more; and on Monday I went to Ward's, and look'd over the Bundle, and took an Account of the Things, tho' I never went for them, till after I was taken up. There was in the Bundle a Gown and Coat, two or three Napkins, a Diaper Table-Cloath, three black Hoods, two Muslin Hoods, a piece of black Padusoy, two or three open Stocks; I can't say any Thing as to the Money, I saw none. I remember that Sheet now it is produced. I was taken up on Tuesday or Wednesday following, and carried before Justice Midford, and as soon as I had sent for a Friend, I made the Discovery.</p>
               <p>Justice Midford. When she was first brought into the House, the Constable told me she was charged with a Robbery, and that she was enclined to make herself an Evidence: I asked her if she would? but she would say nothing, till she had sent for a Friend. I asked her what she wanted a Friend for? She said the House was full of Strangers, and she wanted a Friend to advise with; and as soon as the Person came she sent for, she said that was the Man she could trust: I can trust him to take up the Fellows now says she, I will make the Discovery; then she gave me the same Account that she has done now, almost Verbatim, and signed it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person231">
                  Laurena 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person231" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person231" type="given" value="Laurena"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person231" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Cole desired me to let her leave the Bundle on Sunday, and I did (whereof) she came not again till Monday. I told her my Place was little, and she must put them into an empty Trunk, (whereof) she did so. She told me they were her Mother's Things. From Sunday between four and five, till six or seven on the Tuesday they were in my House; then the Gentleman came and asked me if I knew such a Woman, and I said I could not be positive where to find her; she brought a Gown and some other Things at another Time, and I delivered them all the Things.</p>
               <p>Cole. Those were my own Things. I had not all my Cloaths at Raitt's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Raitt. I live with Mr. Leach a Peruke-maker, in Freeman's Court, in Cornhill; that Sunday I went to see my Father in the Fleet, and from thence to my Mother's, to see her and my Brother and Sister. I staid with this Woman and my Brother about half an Hour, and about three o'Clock my Sister and I came down and left them two at Dinner. I parted with my Sister, and went into St. James's Park, and Lincoln's-Inn Fields, to see the new Rails; then I went into St. James's Park again, and from thence to my Mother's; I found the Street-Door open, and nobody at Home; so I went to Hatton-Garden, and from thence to my Father's, and staid till half an Hour after nine with him; then I went Home with my Mother, and the People of the House charged me with the Robbery.</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. I went out to get a Constable that Night, and when I returned, his Mother said, what do you stop my Son? I told her I suspected him; the other Brother was sent away before I returned with the Constable. The Prisoner staid there till Morning, then his Master came and fetched him away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Smith told me at twelve o'Clock at Night, I might go home.</p>
               <p>Smith. I did say, if he was not guilty he might stay here all Night, and I would go home with him to his Master in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Cole. We all dined together that Day, and he sent for half a Pint of Gin after Dinner.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100012"></xptr>Q. And can there be no Mischief done without a Dram of Gin at the beginning or ending of it? What Hour was it that you came home and saw the Box broke?</p>
               <p>Cole. Between three and four in the Afternoon, and I carried it away in a Quarter of an Hour afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person232">
                  Joseph 
                  Roper 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person232" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person232" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the Prisoner entering into Russet-street, between four and five; we only said your Servant, and pass'd on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person233">
                  John 
                  Merchant 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person233" type="surname" value="Merchant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw him in St. James's Park about five.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person234">
                  Eliz 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person234" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person234" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met him in Hatton-Garden a Quarter after six.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-31-person235">
                  William 
                  Mitchen 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person235" type="surname" value="Mitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-31-person236">
                  Archibald 
                  Leach 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person236" type="surname" value="Leach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person236" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-31-person237">
                  John 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person237" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person237" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360610-31-person238">
                  Andrew 
                  Ailsbury 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person238" type="surname" value="Ailsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person238" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17360610-31-person239">
                  James 
                  Cambden 
               <interp inst="t17360610-31-person239" type="surname" value="Cambden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person239" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, that in general the Prisoner had behaved well, and had a good Character. <rs id="t17360610-31-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-31-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
