<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-54">
               <interp inst="t17360610-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-54" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-54" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-54-off230-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-defend380 t17360610-54-off230 t17360610-54-verdict234"></join>
         
               <p>63, 64, 65. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-defend380" type="defendantName">
                     George
                      Watson  otherwise 
                     <rs id="t17360610-54-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-defend380 t17360610-54-alias-7"></join>Yorkshire George</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-defend380" type="surname" value="Watson otherwise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-defend380" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-defend380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person381">
                  William 
                  Hemming 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person381" type="surname" value="Hemming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person381" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person382">
                  Robert 
                  Heming 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person382" type="surname" value="Heming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person382" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken) for <rs id="t17360610-54-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-54-victim384" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Alexander 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-54-victim384" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-54-victim384" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-54-victim384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-off230 t17360610-54-victim384"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and giving him with a Whip, value 6 d. one mortal Wound on the upper Part of the Left Side of the Head, of the Length and Depth of one inch, of which Wound (in the Parish of <placeName id="t17360610-54-crimeloc231">St. Luke Middlesex</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-crimeloc231" type="placeName" value="St. Luke Middlesex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-crimeloc231" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-off230 t17360610-54-crimeloc231"></join>) he died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360610-54-cd232" type="crimeDate">May 17. in the 6th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-off230 t17360610-54-cd232"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person385">
                  George 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person385" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person385" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner at the Bar these four Years: The first Time I rid with him was last March four Years. May 16. three Years ago about seven in the Evening we set out from William Farrow's at Red-hill, Between Cobham and Ripley; we rid cross the Country to Highgate; we were in Company 15 or 16 Men, and 20 Horses, at Highgate we separated; some came to London, and the rest went back to Mussel hill: We came through Islington seven or eight of us; at Goswell-street we separated again: 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person386">
                  Tom 
                  Brick 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person386" type="surname" value="Brick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person386" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Blue Dick, went towards Wood's-Close to a Grocer there; (we had three Hundred and a Quarter of Tea: I had one Hundred and a Quarter with me) we came down Old-street as far as the Dog-house Bar; and in the Stone-Yard over-against the Dog-House, the Prisoner waited with his Hundred Weight of Tea, for People who were to fetch it from thence. 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person387">
                  Robert 
                  Heming 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person387" type="surname" value="Heming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person387" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I went into Bunhill Row with our Quantity; when we got almost to Chiswell-street, Heming went before to put off his Tea; but being surprized by the Watch, he came back, and said he could not do it there. While we were coming back, a Watchman came by; Bob, says I, give him a Shilling; the Watchman asked who's there? Friends, says I, and we gave him a Shilling to drink. Coming back, (in the middle of Feather-stone-street ) we met Tom the Shoemaker, and Bess the Carrier, who were to take Watson's Tea: D - ye (says Robert Heming, what makes you so late? I ordered you at two o'Clock, and you make it three. Watson waited for them in the Stone-Yard; and we were consulting where to go. While we were considering, Tom the Shoemaker came to us; for God's Sake, says he; come back, the Watch has taken our Tea from us: Watson's Tea was gone, and Jack Heming had unstrapp'd his Horse, and threw his Load off: Watson rode a Grey Horse, with a long Tail; Robert Heming a Chesnut Sorrel; Jack Heming a Milk-white, and I rode a Coal black one. When Jack Heming went away he bid us come immediately after him; but I did not think sit to leave my Load there, so I cross'd the Road and laid it on a Dunghill (or Laystall) in Old-street, and then I rid after them, and came to a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100017"></xptr> Porch, where I saw Jack Heming and his white Horse; his Horse's Head was within the Porch, and he had his Whip in one Hand, and a Pistol in the other, and he cry'd, D - you you old Rogue, I will shoot you. This was in Mr. Everet's Porch, in <placeName id="t17360610-54-crimeloc233">Brown-street by Bun-hill-Row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-54-crimeloc233" type="placeName" value="Brown-street by Bun-hill-Row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-54-crimeloc233" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-off230 t17360610-54-crimeloc233"></join>: The Porch is four Feet and a half before the House. I came up and asked, what's here to do! says he, here's the Rogue who took the Tea: No Pistol-work, for God's sake, says I, don't beat him any more; and a Man look'd out of the Window, and asked what was the Matter; and immediately Bob Heming and the Prisoner came out of an Alley, and came up to us; we turned from the Porch and met them; we went to the Stone-Yard, and Watson and I rode side by side. I said, George, 'tis strange you could not re-take the Tea! No, D - 'em, says he, they are gone through the dark Alleys, but D - 'em, I have noynted one of 'em handsomely, and shewed me his Whip, which was broke at the But-end.</p>
               <p>Council Prisoner. You say it was John Heming who was beating the Man in the Porch?</p>
               <p>Walker. Yes, Watson and Robert Heming rode before me to the Porch two or three Minutes. Robert Heming and Watson came to us up Coleman Alley about fifty Yards from the Porch, and Watson shew'd us his Whip: it was a very heavy one, and the But-end broke; Watson and Robert Heming rode after the Watch-men about a Minute and a half before John Heming and all of them about three Minutes before me. I had my Tea to unstrap and throw off before I could follow them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You have kept Company with me ever since; why did you not take me up before?</p>
               <p>Walker. I have rid with him many a Time since; but I had no Inclination to do it before. I made my Information before Mr. 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person388">
                  Baron 
                  Commyns 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person388" type="surname" value="Commyns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person388" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in November last; and there was no Opportunity to take you before; besides, I went a Smuggling with him, and was in the same way. A Smuggler is not to be taken at any Time, we are here and there and every where; I may be shot for what I have done now, and I did not care to expose myself to the Danger then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Why do you discover now?</p>
               <p>Walker. Truly, George, because you know we are always in Jeopardy, and I am weary of the Trade; and as to the Reward, I declare as I am a living Man, I did not know there was any Reward till a Fortnight after I had made the Discovery. I don't say I saw you strike the Man; not one Word of mine ( George ) shall hurt you, more than is Truth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person389">
                  Edward 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person389" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person389" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live over-against the Porch. May 17. about three in the Morning, I heard a great Noise, and got up and went to the Window, and I saw a Woman have hold of the Deceased, crying out, Thieves! Murder! then I saw some Horsemen galloping down; and when they came up, the Woman quitted her hold, and he crept as far into the Porch, as he could: One of the Men was upon a Gray, and the other upon a Brown or a Sorrel Horse. I am positive to the Gray Horse; the Man rode his Fore-feet into the Porch, and with the Handle of the Whip, gave the Deceased a great many Blows; he cry'd out, Oh! Oh! and at last, Oh Lord! you have kill'd me! Then he drew his Horse out of the Porch, and the Man on the Brown Horse would have got his Horse in, but he had a long Stick in his Hand, and he struck him with it four or five Times. I threw up the Sash, and cry'd out, You Villains, have you a Mind to murder the Man; they went off, and I dress'd myself, and went to the Window again, but the Deceased was gone, and in the Afternoon I heard he was dead. It was just Twilight, and in a narrow Street: I am not mistaken, if it was not a perfect white Horse; I wrote down the Colour the same Day, while it was fresh in my Memory: here it is set down, a light Gray Horse.</p>
               <p>Walker. Watson's Horse was a dark Gray, 15 Hands high, with a long Tail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person390">
                  Jonathan 
                  Everet 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person390" type="surname" value="Everet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person390" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the House where the Porch is. I heard a great Noise of Horses, and got up to see what was the Matter; I heard grievous Blows given, and saw two Men on Horseback: One was on a light Gray Horse, and he got into the Porch as far as he could; the other was on a Sorrel Horse and he was Startlish, and the Man could not get him in. I heard them say, you Old Rogue, go to rob a Woman! I'll knock you o th' Head. When I came down Stairs, the Porch was sprinkled with Blood, and the Deceased was gone. He dyed the same Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person391">
                  Mary 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person391" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person391" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Corner of Featherstonm-Street. On the 17th of May about 3 Years ago, I heard a Noise of Thieves and Murder, and presently I heard Horses come<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100018"></xptr> Galloping down the Street, I look'd out and saw one Horse with his Fore-feet in the Porch; I was so frighted I did not observe the Colour of the Horses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person392">
                  John 
                  Willson 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person392" type="surname" value="Willson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person392" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Brother Watchman with Alexander that Time. We were going our Rounds, and we met a Man and a Woman with Baskets; the Constable asked what they had got, they said they were going to Market: The Constable said, it looks like Linnen, take it down: When we had taken down the Baskets, the Man ran away, and the Woman ran after him, and cry'd they have robb'd us Dicky. We lay'd hold of her, and she threw herself down and clung to some Pallisades, crying Dicky, Dicky, Dicky, why don't you come away. While we were struggling with her, two Horsemen came Galloping from the Dog House Bar, so we left the Woman and made off; he got into the Porch, and I made down Coleman's-Alley: The Man on the Gray Horse push'd by me; he was going towards the Porch, and I got over a Wall and escap'd. He dy'd about 12 the same Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person393">
                  Richard 
                  Hachlin 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person393" type="surname" value="Hachlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person393" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I watch in Lombard-Street, and was coming home to Coleman Alley about 3 o'Clock in the Morning, and saw one Man following a Horse. and another Horseman in the middle of Bunhill-Row; they asked me, if I was the Man that was to call up their Folks; I was afraid of them and said Yes, and they gave me something to drink.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person394">
                  Thomas 
                  Godman 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person394" type="surname" value="Godman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person394" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Servant attended the Deceas'd that Night, and he told me, he was dying. About 10 o'Clock the same Morning I found him convuls'd. He had a large contused Wound on the left side of his Head, which was the Occasion of his Death. I open'd him two Days afterwards, and took out two pieces of his Scull that were beat in. I believe the Wound was given with a heavy blunt Weapon.</p>
               <p>Defence. On the 17th of May, 3 Years ago, I was upon a Gray Horse, but not there. I came from Highgate to Aldersgate Street; at the Coach and Horses I met with John Heming and 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person395">
                  George 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person395" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person395" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I asked them what they had done with their Hundred of Tea, and they told me the Watch had taken it away in Bunhill-Fields; but that they had met with one of them, and had beat him sufficiently, and they were afraid he would not recover.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person396">
                  Robert 
                  Dimmock 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person396" type="surname" value="Dimmock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person396" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard this Tray (we call him so, his right Name is Walker) talking with Towzer in the next Yard to mine on Mussel hill, and telling him they had beat a Watchman, and were afraid he wou'd die. I can't say I heard him tell who did it.</p>
               <p>Walker. This is the Man that takes our Goods in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person397">
                  Henry 
                  Press 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person397" type="surname" value="Press"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person397" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Hostler at the Cock-Inn in Aldersgate-Street, and I believe, it was the Morning the Man was kill'd, that I took in Tray and Towzer's Horses; and they told me a Watchman was kill'd in Bunhill-Fields. One rode a Gray Horse, and the other a Sorrel, and they came in about 4 in the Morning: I saw nothing of Watson.</p>
               <p>Walker. After the Murder was committed, we went to Spittle-Fields to deliver some Goods there, and I believe Watson might be half an Hour before us, for I had Goods to deliver in the back Shed of the George, near Shoreditch-Church; I did indeed come to the Cock with another Horse, but Towzer was not with me.</p>
               <p>Q. You know them all by their Nick-names, how many Smugglers us'd your House?</p>
               <p>Press. I had eleven or twelve Horses at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person398">
                  Mary 
                  Pultney 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person398" type="surname" value="Pultney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person398" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the Evidence Lawrence tell Watson in Newgate, that Tray came to him half an Hour after the Accident happen'd, and asked him where he was when the Mischief was done: and Lawrence told him he was at the Burying-Ground. Lawrence deny'd this.</p>
               <p>Walker. This Woman is one of our Dealers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person399">
                  Samuel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person399" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person399" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Weaver, and was in Company with Walker, somewhere about the Custom-House, and he told me he should do George no harm, but he must act for the Safety of his Family.</p>
               <p>Walker. This Samuel Jones is a Smuggler and an Informer.</p>
               <p>Q. How come the honest Weaver to talk so freely with a Smuggler about another notorious Smuggler.</p>
               <p>Samuel Jones. I own I was a Smuggler.</p>
               <p>Q. Then why do you come here as an honest Weaver?</p>
               <p>- Pullen. I am a Waiter and a Searcher. I informed the Commissioners of the Customs, I had found out George Watson. I got a Capiat for 450 l. and a Writ of Assistance; I got a Soldier, and told him he must fight for the King and at Coppet's Farm we got another Man. Then we went to the House. I went in first,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100019"></xptr> and he did not behave like a Murderer; for he had three Pistols and a Blunderbus, which he might have made use of. Then my Assistants came up, and I said, here take this Pistol, and this, and this, and this Blunderbus; then I told him he must go with us, and George, says I, your's are foolish Arms to mine, and out I pull'd my Brace of Horse Pistols. I asked him about the Murder, and he said he would not tell me the Truth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-54-person400">
                  James 
                  Capstick 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person400" type="surname" value="Capstick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person400" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17360610-54-person401">
                  Sarah 
                  Capstick 
               <interp inst="t17360610-54-person401" type="surname" value="Capstick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person401" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-person401" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We never knew but that the Prisoner was an honest Man; he has used our House three Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear he was a Smuggler?</p>
               <p>Capstick. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you take a Smuggler for an honest Man? <rs id="t17360610-54-verdict234" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-verdict234" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment. <rs id="t17360610-54-punish235" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-54-punish235" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-54-defend380 t17360610-54-punish235"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
