<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-14">
               <interp inst="t17361013-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-14" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-14" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-14-off74-c121" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-14-defend157 t17361013-14-off74 t17361013-14-verdict77"></join>
         
               <p>21. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-14-defend157" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Crafts 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-14-defend157" type="surname" value="Crafts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-defend157" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-defend157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-14-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver Watch value 3 l.
            </rs> from the Person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-14-victim159" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Chapman 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-14-victim159" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-victim159" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-14-off74 t17361013-14-victim159"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17361013-14-cd75" type="crimeDate">September 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-14-off74 t17361013-14-cd75"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Chapman, September 27, about 11 at Night I stood up to make Water in Well-close Square. The Prisoner called out for some body, and I said, Hollo. I struck into the Road, she followed me, and we walked together to Shadwell Church, there she asked me for a Pint of Beer. We went into a House and had a Pint of Beer; then we went to <placeName id="t17361013-14-crimeloc76">Shadwell Mar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-14-crimeloc76" type="placeName" value="Shadwell Mar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-14-crimeloc76" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-14-off74 t17361013-14-crimeloc76"></join>ket, and there having occasion to ease my self, I put my Watch into my Coat Pocket; then we went into the Fields, but she wanted me to go to Ratcliff Cross; I went cross the Market with her, and had the Watch then in my Hand, but I lost it, and I said, Hussey you have got my Watch. She made a Noise, and up came 2 Men, and then she scolded and called me Names; I collar'd one, but he got from me, and they both ran away. Then I carried her up Market Hill, and at the White Lyon Tavern Back Door, she said she wanted to tie her Garter, and there I suppose she dropped my Watch, for there it was found the next Morning.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him on his Oath, if he did not mislest (molest) me first, and tell me he and I must be better humour'd? Nay, ask him if he did not mislest me in the Ale-house? And ask him if he did not haul me cross the Kennel; and on the Sun Tavern Steps, at the Back Door that is stopped up, if he did not - and mislest me there again?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-14-person160">
                  Stephen 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17361013-14-person160" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person160" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . September 29, I was going to work about six in the Morning, and at the Back Door of the White Lyon, on a Heap of Ashes I found this Watch. The Prosecutor had the Creature before the Justice, and charged her with taking his Watch; my Master hearing this, and knowing I had found one, he went and told the Justice.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He had me before the Justice; no, I went voluntary my self, - O ye vile Rogue! I met him in Well-close Square, where are you going, says he? What's that to you, says I, don't be so sulky, says he. I told him if he went on, he'd meet somebody to his Mind: but going along we came to an Alehouse, where there were Curtains to the Windows, so he made me drink part of a Pint there. When we came out, he haul'd me down Sun Tavern Fields, I asked him what he was going to do; and being a'lone Woman he haul'd me cross the Kennel, and got me down on the Steps, and said, d - n ye, if you squal I'll give you a good Knock: After<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130013"></xptr> this we went to Shadwell Market, and there he wanted to have me again upon the Stalls; he did pull up my Petticoats quite over my Head, but 2 Men coming up, God bless you, says I to them, for coming, and then he charged me with taking his Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-14-person161">
                  Esther 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17361013-14-person161" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person161" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Dealer in old Cloaths, and 
               <persName id="t17361013-14-person162">
                  John 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17361013-14-person162" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person162" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Hackney Coach man, never heard any Harm of the Prisoner. <rs id="t17361013-14-verdict77" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-14-verdict77" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
