<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-16">
               <interp inst="t17351210-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-16" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-16" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-16-off67-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-16-defend115 t17351210-16-off67 t17351210-16-verdict70"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-16-off67-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-16-defend117 t17351210-16-off67 t17351210-16-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>20, 21. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-16-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend115" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend115" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-16-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend117" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend117" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-defend117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17351210-16-off67" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-off67" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-off67" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing one Moidore, and five Guineas, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351210-16-victim119" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Lee 
                        <interp inst="t17351210-16-victim119" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-16-victim119" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-16-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-16-off67 t17351210-16-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17351210-16-cd68" type="crimeDate">October 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-16-off67 t17351210-16-cd68"></join>.</p>
               <p>Henry Lee. I being a Country-man. and a Stranger in this Town, was going to my Quarters between eight and nine at Night, and meaning no harm. I happened upon these two Women in Long Acre, and they asked me to go to their Lodging in <placeName id="t17351210-16-crimeloc69">Earl's Court, in Drury lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-16-crimeloc69" type="placeName" value="Earl's Court, in Drury lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-16-crimeloc69" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-16-off67 t17351210-16-crimeloc69"></join>; I was unwilling to go, but they said it was a very civil House. So they took me up one pair of Stairs, and ordered a Bowl of Punch, and a Fire to be made. I grew uneasy, and was for coming away. for I did not much like them; but they shut the Door, and kept me with them an Hour longer than I would have been if I could have helped it. I had no disorderly Dealings with them, though they did what they could to bring me to it, for they took up their Coverings, and shewed me what Ware they had, and then they would needs examine mine - When the Punch was out, they called for Drams, we drank three Quarterns of Brandy, and then I paid the Reckoning. I had Silver in my Pocket, and Gold in my Fob. As I was going down Stairs, they knocked out the Candle, and the Landlady went out with me pretending to shew me the way to my Quarters. We had not gone one hundred Yards before I mist five Guineas, and a Moidore out of my Fob. Landlady, says I, what sort of People do you keep in your House? I have lost my Money; sure you have not, says she, but if it is so I will go back and see you righted. But instead of going back, she took me down a contrary way to lose me, when a Man hearing me complain<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100006"></xptr> of losing my Money, said, why do not you lay hold of her Countryman? And with that she run away, but tumbled down, near her own House, and so we took her. Upon which the two Prisoners came out and swore and called us all to Naught. We went to call the Watch, and so the three Women all run away. When we had got the Watch, we went to the House again, and took the Maid and another disorderly Creature, who said she was a Whore, but no Thief, and she would go with us to find them. We found 
               <persName id="t17351210-16-person120">
                  Ann 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17351210-16-person120" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-person120" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asleep on the Stairs at the Hamburgh Coffee house in Drury-lane, and carried her to the Round-house, she own'd that 
               <persName id="t17351210-16-person121">
                  Ann 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17351210-16-person121" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-person121" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had gave her two Shillings of the Money to pay her Lodging, and that they were to share the rest in the Morning, and told us that Allen was gone home again. We went back to the House between One and Two in the Morning. It seems Allen was then a Bed up one pair of Stairs with a Gentleman, but hearing us come in, she left her Bed-fellow, and run up into the Garret, and got to Bed with two other Creatures, we brought her down into the Room she went from, and Searching about, we found Four Guineas, a Moidore, and fifteen Shillings, hid between a Board and the Wall.</p>
               <p>Some of these particulats were sworn to by other Witnesses</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351210-16-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-16-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoners.</p>
            </div1>
