<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-63">
               <interp inst="t17360908-63" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-63" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-63" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-63" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-63-off250-c241" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-63-defend382 t17360908-63-off250 t17360908-63-verdict253"></join>
         
               <p>75. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-63-defend382" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Latour 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-63-defend382" type="surname" value="Latour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-defend382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-defend382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360908-63-off250" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-off250" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-off250" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver Cross set with Diamonds, value 80 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-63-victim384" type="victimName">
                     John
                      Guider de Miranda
                  <interp inst="t17360908-63-victim384" type="surname" value="Guider de Miranda"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-victim384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-victim384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-63-off250 t17360908-63-victim384"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17360908-63-viclabel251" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-63-victim384 t17360908-63-viclabel251"></join>: commonly called Sir 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person385">
                  John
                   Guider de Miranda
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person385" type="surname" value="Guider de Miranda"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person385" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Portugal, Knt. <rs id="t17360908-63-cd252" type="crimeDate">August the 25th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-63-off250 t17360908-63-cd252"></join>. The Prisoner demanding a Party Jury, the following Persons were sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-63-person386">
                  Thomas 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person386" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person386" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person387">
                  Anto 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person387" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person387" type="given" value="Anto"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person388">
                  Val 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person388" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person388" type="given" value="Val"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person388" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person389">
                  William 
                  Clarkson 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person389" type="surname" value="Clarkson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person389" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person390">
                  Tho 
                  Abbot 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person390" type="surname" value="Abbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person390" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person391">
                  Wm 
                  Street 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person391" type="surname" value="Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person391" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , English, 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person392">
                  Paul 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person392" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person392" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person393">
                  Paul
                   La'marie
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person393" type="surname" value="La'marie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person393" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person394">
                  Peter 
                  Amiot 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person394" type="surname" value="Amiot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person394" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person395">
                  Samuel 
                  Aveline 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person395" type="surname" value="Aveline"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person395" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person396">
                  Paul 
                  Crispin 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person396" type="surname" value="Crispin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person396" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person397">
                  Tho 
                  Collard 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person397" type="surname" value="Collard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person397" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Foreign. (Interpreters were sworn for the Prisoner and Prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>The Rev. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person398">
                  Charles 
                  Brockwell 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person398" type="surname" value="Brockwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person398" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The unhappy Gentleman at the Barr, was recommended to me, on his first coming to England to learn English. I live at Chigwell in Essex. On Saturday the 28th of August, he was in London, and a Person came down to me, with a Letter without a Name, as from the Prisoner, for some Papers; he told me he had got the Key of his Room; but as there were Things of value in the Room, and no Name was to the Letter, I sent for a Neighbour, one Cotton, who keeps the Stage Coach, and we all went up; the Messenger found the Paper, so we locked the Door and gave the Key to the Messenger; this was Saturday Night; and on Sunday Morning about 6 o'Clock, Major General Franks and 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person399">
                  Stephen 
                  Moreau 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person399" type="surname" value="Moreau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person399" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came down to search his Room for a Diamond Cross; he broke open the Door, and they felt in the Pockets of the Cloths which lay in his Bed. I told them, there could be nothing there, for I had searched there last Night for some Papers, but (I told them) there were more Cloaths in the Press; we open'd it and searched a pair of Black Velvet Breeches, with Gold Buttons, and out of one of the Side Pockets, the Jewel was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the Prisoner go to London from your House?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. The Monday before; he had been about a Week in London.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you searched those Breeches (in which the Cross was found) the Night before for the Papers?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I looked no farther than into the trunk, for the Messenger found the Paper he wanted taking within some Tape, the inside of the Lid.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Directions in the Letter, where the Papers were to be found?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Letter, the Prisoner's own Hand writing?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I cannot tell. (The Prisoner own'd it .)</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I sent this Letter, in order to have a Bill of Exchange delivered me out of the Trunk, but the Paper the Messenger took, was only an Order for Post Horses. (Clerk reads the Letter.) At Chigwell, Essex, For Mr. Brockwell. I desire you to go into my Room, and give the Bearer the present Paper.</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I did not know what Paper it was, nor the Man neither; but this being the first Paper I li't of, I read it to him, and he said, this is the Paper; and away he went. He told me the Gentleman was under Misfortunes, and in the Gatehouse, and that Paper was to let the World know, who he was. He told me the Prisoner desired me to come up next Morning to bail him; so I did not give the Man the Paper, but thought to carry it up my self: next Morning General Franks and Mr. Moreau finding the Jewel in his Breeches, prevented the Delivery of the Paper.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he wear those Breeches?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I don't know; he had such a variety of Cloath, that I cannot remember.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Has Mr. Brockwell ever observed any thing blameable in my Behaviour or Conduct?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. No, never; he always behav'd like a Gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-63-person400">
                  Stephen 
                  Moreau 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person400" type="surname" value="Moreau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person400" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and Sir 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person401">
                  John 
                  de Miranda 
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person401" type="surname" value="de Miranda"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person401" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , both lodge in my House; I hear in the Morning at Eight o'Clock the 26th of August, his Excellence complain he lose his Cross; he speak very low to his Servant, but I hear: and I went to him, in his own Chamber, and I ask, when he saw it: he say the very Morning before: he tell me he saw it: just the Day before, the 25th, when I went to the Races at Barnet: I ask him, who was in the Chamber? He say, none but Monsieur Latour. I ask, have you Suspicion, he took the Cross? He say. I open my Bureau, he ask for a Paper there. I leave de Bureau open, and go into mine Chamber to dress. When I came back, he ask me to walk in the Park; Sir John tell me, between the Time he was gone to dress, Monsieur Latour take the Cross. So he go to General Frank, and tell this General Frank come at 10 o'Clock at Night, the 26th, and persuade his Excellence to take Warrant immediately: the General and his Excellence go to Justice Cotton, he grant a Warrant; this was Friday Morning. The Prisoner went to Chigwell that Night, came home again on Saturday Morning. I ask him if he have been at Chigwell? He tell me No. I find he changed Stockings, Breeches, Wastcoat and Wig. I ask him if he have Cloaths in the City, and he tell me, yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What Cloaths had he on when he went to Chigwell?</p>
               <p>Moreau. Green Coat, Flannel Wastcoat, Velvet Breeches, and gold Buttons: this he had on when he go from my House the Friday Night, 5 o'Clock, and he come home in plain Breeches, no gold Buttons.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080019"></xptr>Q. To Mr. Brockwell. Did he come to your House at Chigwell on Friday Night?</p>
               <p>Brockwell, I was not at home, but I heard he had been there.</p>
               <p>Q. To Moreau. Did you see him on Saturday Morning with plain Breeches?</p>
               <p>Moreau. Yes; before I go to the Races, he come home, between 9 and 10 in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take such particular notice of his Breeches?</p>
               <p>Moreau. He come home, with the same Coat, not the same Wastcoat, and different: Breeches; I ask him whether he have been at Chigwell? He tell me no; but then he take me into the Yard, and say to me, I have been at Chigwell, you not say any Thing of it; and he give me 3 l. 12 s. to change; I sent to change it, and he pay me some Money, he owe in the House. I am ver' sure they were plain Breeches, and they was tore between the Legs. the Breeches he had on before was not tore. I say nothing to him, because General Frank and his Excellence was gone to the Councellor, to take him up. At Night my Wife tell me, he was took up, in the Gatehouse; I go to him, and come home, and tell the General; he go to Chigwell, but he say, Moreau, you say nothing of that; so General Frank have a search Warrant to search his Cloaths at Chigwell; (before the Justice, he deny he was there,) and his Excellence being weak, not go himself, but desire me to go with the General; we had search Warrant back'd by Justice Gold, and we come to this Gentleman's House, at 6 Sunday Morning; he tell us the Messenger was gone, and not take the Paper, and he shew us the Paper, and it was only about Post-Horses from Calais, and his Name not in the Paper. We desire Mr. Brockwell when he come at 6 o'Clock Sunday Morning, to let his Room be search; so he broke open the Door with a Hammer, and when we come in, he say, all these Cloaths I search yesterday for the Paper; and by and by we come to the Press, the Parson take the Breeches from the Press, and he throw'd them on the Bed; these are the Breeches, I say, and I feel about, in this manner, and put my Hand so, - and I feel something, and I say here is something, and I put my Hand in the Pocket, and take out the Cross - just so - a few Days after he was in the Gatehouse, he sent an Attorney, to ask for one Bill of Exchange that was in his Pocket; I say, the Gentleman is mistake; the Gentleman, the Attorney, he say, it was in the Breeches, so we look in the Breeches, and we find this Paper, a Bill for 70 l.</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I know nothing of this; they took the Breeches, and the Cross away with them.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17360908-63-person402">
                  John
                   Guider de Miranda
               <interp inst="t17360908-63-person402" type="surname" value="Guider de Miranda"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person402" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to shift my self (I cannot name the Day) and left the Prisoner in the Room. I remember I took a Paper out of the Bureau, and left the Key in it; the next Day I missed the Cross; I went with General Franks to an Attorney, got a Warrant, and found it in the Prisoner's Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not Moreau, and his Servants frequently came in your Chamber?</p>
               <p>Sir John. No. I apprehend no one could go into this Room but the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long was it left open?</p>
               <p>Sir John. Only while I went into another Room to shift me.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. I was in the Country the Night Latour came down; he came on Horseback, without Boots; about 7 or 8 o'clock, he sat down to Supper, but seemed very pensive, and did not eat; he said he came for a Bill of Exchange, and next Morning he rid to London. I took no notice of his Breeches but he came down in whitish Stockings, and next Morning went up in dark Gray. I was present when the Cross was took out of his Pocket; and the Account that has been given, is exactly true.</p>
               <p>Q. (To Brockwell) Did you, or this last Witness lay Hands on the Breeches, and feel them before Moreau?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. No; no one felt them but he.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Eye fixed on them from the Time you handed them to the Bed, 'till Moreau took the Cross out?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I think it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was not possible for any thing to be put into the Breeches?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I cannot answer that; I have seen many things done by Legerdemain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Gentleman want Money then?</p>
               <p>Brockwell. I believe he did; for he had been 3 Months at my House; and when I asked him for Money, he had none.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner gave a long Account of his first coming to England, and that his Acquaintance with Sir John began in Moreau's House, where they both lodged; that the Morning the Cross was lost, there was a Master of Languages in the Room with them; and when he opened his Cabinet to take out the Paper, he said he would leave nothing in it, because Moreau was a Rogue, and had a false Key.</p>
               <p>Sir John denied this; and being asked if he had any suspicion of Moreau, he said, no.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Sir John has said so, in the Presence of a Man that lodges at Moreau's, and who came with him this Morning to this Place.</p>
               <p>Moreau. I do not know the Man's Name, nor where he is.</p>
               <p>Several Persons appeared to Moreau's Character, as an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not left in the Room, but went with Sir John into his Dressing Room. Sir John dedenied this.</p>
               <p>The Reason the Prisoner gave for his Journey to Chigwell on Friday Night, was to satisfy Mr. Brockwell about Money due to him; and he informed the Court, that he could not make a proper<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080020"></xptr> Defence, because he was brought unexpectedly to the Barr; he having the Night before given 5 Guineas, a Gold Watch, 3 or 4 Embroidered Wastcoats to the Persons concerned in the Prosecution; and a Bond with a Penalty of 300 l. to Sir John, to make up the Affair (which Bond was produced and read in Court.) He said, they told him, he need not provide any Counsel or any Attorney; and farther informed the Court, that his Attorney had engaged Counsel in his Cause, but the Prosecutor sent notice to him last Night, that the Matter was compromis'd, and that this was the Reason he had no body to appear for him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Compton. My Clerk told me, such notice was sent; and I was much surprized when I found Mr. Latour was called to his Trial; if I had known it, I should have feed Serj Haywood. I had Instructions to call a Person, who was to speak to Moreau's having a false Key, if I had been prepared.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this Prisoner committed?</p>
               <p>Keeper of the Gatehouse. The Commitment is dated August the 27th, which was on a Friday; he came into my case the Night of the same Day, about 10 or 11 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Moreau swore he was at Chigwell that Night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. 'Tis a little odd, that they should not search my Boxes in Town, before they went down to Chigwell.</p>
               <p>Moreau. They were searched, as I have been informed; I was not at home.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They demanded 200 Guineas of me; then they fell to 100, then to 50, and there the Matter stuck. <rs id="t17360908-63-verdict253" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-63-verdict253" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
