<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-3">
               <interp inst="t17390607-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-3" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-3" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-3-off16-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-3-defend38 t17390607-3-off16 t17390607-3-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>329. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-defend38" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hill 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-3-defend38" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-defend38" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390607-3-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing an Iron Grey Mare, val. 15 l.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-victim40" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Warren 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-3-victim40" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-victim40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-3-off16 t17390607-3-victim40"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17390607-3-cd17" type="crimeDate">May 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-3-off16 t17390607-3-cd17"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Warren. In August last my Mare was at Grass, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17390607-3-crimeloc18">Stapleton , about four Miles beyond Bristol</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-3-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Stapleton , about four Miles beyond Bristol"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-3-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-3-off16 t17390607-3-crimeloc18"></join>: She was a genteel Mare, between a Nutmeg and an Iron Grey. The Farmer under whose Care she had been for about a Month before, sent me Word that she was missing the 2d of August, upon which I advertised her, but had no Information of her in several Months: But at last one Mr. Jakes, who lives at Leeds in Yorkshire, (and who had formerly been the Owner of her) wrote me Word that he had seen my Mare at Mr. Stokes's, at the Flying-Horse without Bishopsgate; upon which I came up to London, and went to Mr. Stokes, who told me he had bought such a Mare of an Old Man he knew but very little of, and that she was then at Grass. I then sent one 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person41">
                  Robert 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person41" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person41" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to see the Mare: He inform'd me she was mine, and she was brought to Mr. Stokes's: I knew her, and demanded her, and got a Warrant to take up Stokes; but he produced the Prisoner, and said, he was the Man who sold him the Mare. I know nothing at all of the Prisoner</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-person42">
                  Geo 
                  Stokes 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person42" type="surname" value="Stokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person42" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Flying Horse without Bishopsgate, and keep Livery Stables there. About the Middle of September last I was at Wandsworth; and there I saw the Prisoner, who told me he had a pretty Mare to sell. I went into a Stable, and when I had seen her, I ask'd him what she was worth? He ask'd me 11 l. and I bid him 7 l. or seven Guineas, but he not being inclinable to take my Money, I came home. In about a Week's Time he brought her to my Stables, and set her at Livery, desiring me to help him to a Customer for her if I could, and telling me she was his Property: But one Morning when he came to see her, I told him, I would buy her myself, if we could agree upon Price, and in Talking I bid him 8 l. and at last eight Guineas, which he took for her; this was about the 29th of September last. The Mare for which I paid this Money to the Prisoner, is the same that Mr. Warren afterwards own'd. I did not ask the Prisoner how he came by her, for when I saw him at Wandsworth, I found he was an Acquaintance of my Brother-in-Law's there, and upon that Account I had no Suspicion of him. I had had her about a Fortnight, before Mr. Warren came to enquire after her, and had put her to Grass at Plastow, for she was very poor when I bought her. I believe I told Mr. Warren at first, who I bought her of, and about two Days after he had claim'd her, the Prisoner come into my Yard, and I took him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-person43">
                  Robert 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person43" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person43" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Mr. Warren's Servant, and came to live with him last Christmas was Twelve-Months. I know my Master had this Mare one Quarter of a Year in the Time I liv'd with him. I found her in a Field at Plastow, at Grass: Mr. Stokes came to me at Plastow, and I told him the Mare was Mr. Warren's: Upon which we both return'd to his Stables, and the Mare was deliver'd to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was going along Thames Street one Day in August, and met one 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person44">
                  John 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person44" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lives in Southwark; I had been acquainted with the Man this seven or eight Years at Times, and he ask'd me to buy this Mare, which he was then leading in the Street; I told him, she was very poor, and I did not know what to do with her. He said he had work'd her very hard, and as he was going over to Holland, and wanted Money, I should have her for eight Guineas: I told him 'twas too much Money for her, for she was very poor, and a little lame; but at last we went to the Black Bull Alehouse, and there he agreed I should have her for six Guineas. I paid him the Money in the Alehouse, and took a Receipt for it before two or three People, and spent a Shilling in the House. I drive a Cart at Queen-Hithe, and have work'd there twenty Years. At that Time I wanted a Horse for my own Use; for I buy and sell Corn, and serve a great many Gentlemen's Servants with Corn. When I sold Mr. Stokes this Mare, I told him I bought her of a Man who deals to Holland, and when she was claim'd, I surrender'd myself to him, without any Warrant, and sent to enquire after the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070004"></xptr> Man I bought her of as soon as I could, but he is not to be found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-person45">
                  Hugh 
                  Catterel 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person45" type="surname" value="Catterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person45" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About August last I and 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person46">
                  John 
                  Stubbs 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person46" type="surname" value="Stubbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were drinking at the Black Bull, and the Prisoner came in with one whom he called Pritchard, the Mare was left at the Door, and they desired me to go out and look at her, which I did, and saw she was an Iron-grey Mare, very poor in Flesh: The Bargain was made before they came in, but I saw the Prisoner pay the other Man 6 l. 7 s. one Shilling of which was spent, and we witness'd the Receipt which the Prisoner took for the Money. I never saw either of the Men before that Time in my Life, but I was desired to go and look at the Mare, and to witness the Receipt. This is the Receipt, and this is my Name, - 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person47">
                  Hugh 
                  Catterel 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person47" type="surname" value="Catterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person47" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Receipt was read.</p>
               <p>August 29. 1738. Received of Thomas Hill, the Sum of Six Pounds Seven Shillings, in full for a Mare, and all Demands,</p>
               <p>Witness. Hugh Catterel. per 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person48">
                  John 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person48" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person48" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-person49">
                  John 
                  Stubbs 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person49" type="surname" value="Stubbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Catterel. I never had seen the Prisoner before, nor been in his Company; nor have I ever seen him since, till he sent for me upon this Affair. I told him, when I witness'd the Receipt, that I liv'd at the Golden Lion in Russel street, Covent-Garden.</p>
               <p>John Stubbs confirm'd Catterel's Testimony.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-3-person50">
                  Hen.
                   Froom
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person50" type="surname" value="Froom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person50" type="given" value="Hen."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person51">
                  John 
                  Leman 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person51" type="surname" value="Leman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person51" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person52">
                  William 
                  Froom 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person52" type="surname" value="Froom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person53">
                  John 
                  Millet 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person53" type="surname" value="Millet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390607-3-person54">
                  William 
                  Folbigg 
               <interp inst="t17390607-3-person54" type="surname" value="Folbigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person54" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest Man. <rs id="t17390607-3-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-3-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
