<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-18">
               <interp inst="t17390607-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-18" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-18" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-18-off90-c122" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-18-defend160 t17390607-18-off90 t17390607-18-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>349. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-18-defend160" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Patridge 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-18-defend160" type="surname" value="Patridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-defend160" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-defend160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17390607-18-person161">
                  James 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17390607-18-person161" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-person161" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken) for <rs id="t17390607-18-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390607-18-victim163" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Vannie 
                        <interp inst="t17390607-18-victim163" type="surname" value="Vannie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-18-victim163" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-18-victim163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-18-off90 t17390607-18-victim163"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of Twelve at Night, and stealing a Sirloin of Beef, val. 6 s. two Springs of Pork, val. 5 s. a 14 lb. Leaden Weight, val. 14 d. an Iron 7 lb. Weight, val. 7 d. and a 4 lb. Leaden Weight, val. 4 d. in his Dwelling-house,
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17390607-18-cd91" type="crimeDate">Dec. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-18-off90 t17390607-18-cd91"></join>.</p>
               <p>Vannie. They broke my Shop, and I lost all my Meat; two Springs of Pork, a Sirloin and a veiny Piece of Beef, a Loin of Pork, and some Pieces more; - they took my Tray, - and all. And I lost all my Weights; - there was a 14 lb. Weight, a 7 lb. and two 4 lb. Weights; - they took all. They broke my Shop, though I lye in my Bed next to my Shop. I lost them a little before Christmas, and miss'd them the next Day, about Eleven or Twelve o'Clock at Noon, - but I am not certain neither.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When did you see them last, before you miss'd them?</p>
               <p>Vannie. Oh! - next Morning. I went to Bed, between Nine and Ten, - for my Wife was dead at that Time, and my House was safe, - all the Doors and Windows fast, when I went to Bed. - Yes, yes, - I am sure of that, and my Beef and Pork were there then. I got up next Morning between Five and Six o'Clock, and I found my House very well, - all, but my Shop broke, and my Meat gone. The Shutter was broke, I found it broke before Day-light, - before Five o'Clock, when I get up. I found all my Things gone by Candle-light next Morning. - I never had a Bit of my Things at all, and I made no Complaint about them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And did you lose your Weights the same Time you lost your Meat?</p>
               <p>Vannie. I can't be sure of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-18-person164">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17390607-18-person164" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-person164" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner, Styles, and I went into <placeName id="t17390607-18-crimeloc92">Hog-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-18-crimeloc92" type="placeName" value="Hog-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-18-crimeloc92" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-18-off90 t17390607-18-crimeloc92"></join>, and broke open this Frenchman's Shop; and we stole a Sirloin of Beef, a Foreloin of Pork, and a Veiny-Piece of Beef: This was on a Saturday Night, between Twelve and One o'Clock, about five or six Months ago. We broke the Shutter in half, and had it not been<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070014"></xptr> for his two Dogs, we should have gone into his Back-room. We broke the Shutter, but none of us went in, the Dogs prevented us, so we only put our Arms in, and took the Meat, some of which we sold, the rest we kept for our own Eating; what we sold, - we sold to one Mrs. Watts, and the Money was divided among us. <rs id="t17390607-18-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-18-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
