<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390117-1">
               <interp inst="t17390117-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-1" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-1" type="date" value="17390117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-1-off2-c26" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend27 t17390117-1-off2 t17390117-1-verdict6"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-1-off2-c27" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend29 t17390117-1-off2 t17390117-1-verdict6"></join>
         
               <p>68, 69 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-1-defend27" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Reynolds 
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend27" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend27" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend27" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     Martha 
                     London 
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend29" type="surname" value="London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend29" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-defend29" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17390117-1-defloc1">St. Bennet Fink</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Bennet Fink"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend27 t17390117-1-defloc1"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend29 t17390117-1-defloc1"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17390117-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-1-victim31" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Hornby 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-1-victim31" type="surname" value="Hornby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-1-victim31" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-1-victim31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-off2 t17390117-1-victim31"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Foot passage near the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from her a Camblet-Gown, value 2 s. a Cloth-Cloak, value 6 d. a Checqu'd-Apron, value 1 d. a black quilted Coat, value 18d. and a Pair of Stays, value 4 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17390117-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">January 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-off2 t17390117-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>Anne Hornby. I had been on an Errand last Wednesday Night, to the other Side of the Bridge, and as I was coming back about seven o'Clock of Night, I met a well-dressed young Woman, whom I afterwards heard was named Sarah, She asked me where I was going? I told her I was going Home. She next enquired where I lived? I said, I lived by the Old Spaw, near Clerkenwell Bridewell. Then she told me, she lived that Way too, and would go with me, but I must first go a little Way with her towards Gracechurch-street. I went with her 'till I came to a Pump, and there the two Prisoners at the Bar met us. She stepped a little on one Side with them, and then came up to me, and asked me if I wanted a Place? I told them yes, if I could get into a civil Family. Upon this they took me up into a Court, but there being a Light there, they took me into the next, and then one of them said to the others, I believe my Mistress will like this young Woman, because she is so fresh coloured; but (says she to me) you must pull off your Cloaths to see if they are clean. I said, I would not pull my Cloaths off; Won't she, says one of them, - then d - mn the Bitch, give her a Drive on the Wind-pipe; and immediately they put something soft into my Mouth, and took off this Gown, a checqu'd Apron, a Pair of Stays, and my Quilted-Petticoat; all which, the Prisoner London put into her Apron, and carry'd away. The Woman that met me first went away with her, and the Prisoner Reynolds was to stay with me, 'till they came back with my Cloaths. I waited some time with Reynolds; then I told her, I hoped they were not gone away with my Things. No, no, says Reynolds, they are only gone to see if your Cloaths are clean, - I'll go and call them. So away she went, and I called after her (as far as I could) by the Name of Pat, which I had heard the other two call her by. I can't say which of them stripped me, but they were all about me, and held me up against the Wall, while they were doing it. When they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170003"></xptr> had all left me, I went back the same Way I came crying and roaring; and the People asked me if I should know the Persons again that had robbed me? I said I should, and described them as well as I could. One of them, I said, had a black Gown on, and a Cast with her Eyes, and the other had a Scar in her Face. Somebody then said, such Persons lived in an Alley in Bishopsgate-street, and there the two Prisoners being found, I knew them immediately, and went with them to the Watch-house, where I was examined by the Constable, and because I had nobody to be bound for my Appearance the next Day, I was sent with them to the Counter, and Orders were sent, that I should be taken Care of; but we being all put together, the Prisoners threatened me, and said, when I came before my Lord, I must say, I was very much in Liquor, and pulled off my Cloaths, and gave 'em away myself. The next Morning, a Man came into the Counter, and asked which was the Prosecutor? I said I was. D - mn you, you B - ch, says he, What are you doing? They wanted me to set my Hand to a Paper, and I told them I would, if I might have my Things again. Upon which, Martha London pulled off the checqu'd Apron from her Sides, and sent for my Gown out of Pawn. The Petticoat, she said, was hung out of the Window when the Search was made after her, for fear it should be seen in the Room, and the Stays were hid under a Basket of Oranges. I was to have sign'd the Paper they drew up, but as I had not all my Things again I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-1-person32">
                  William 
                  Elliot 
               <interp inst="t17390117-1-person32" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-person32" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. Last Wednesday Night I was on my Watch at Bishopsgate, and going my Rounds, I met three Watchmen, with the two Prisoners, and this Hornby. They told me, the two Girls, (the Prisoners) had committed a Street Robbery. Hornby was naked, all but her Shift and a coat, and a simple thing which she had wrapped round her Shoulders. I took them all to the Watch-house, and the Prisoners confessed that the Gown, and (I think) the Cloak were pawned at the Corner of Skinner-street. The least of the Prisoners desired to be made an Evidence, and told me, That the third Person who was concerned with them was gone over the Water.</p>
               <p>Prisoner London. I <rs id="t17390117-1-deflabel4" type="occupation">sell Oranges and Lemons</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend27 t17390117-1-deflabel4"></join>, and was waiting at the Top of a Court for this Reynolds to come to me. About seven o'Clock she and the Prosecutrix, and 
               <persName id="t17390117-1-person33">
                  Sarah 
                  Creech 
               <interp inst="t17390117-1-person33" type="surname" value="Creech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-person33" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-person33" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me. Creech told the Prosecutrix, she would help her to a Place, but she must see whether her Cloaths were clean or not; and so she took off her Cloaths and put them into my Apron, then Creech and I went away and left Reynolds with the Prosecutrix. I pawned her Gown and Cloak for Six-pence at a Place where my Mother used to pawn her Things before she dy'd After this, I went home to Mrs Thornton's and bought a Two-penny Loaf; and had not been at Home but a very little Time before the Prosecutrix came in She bid me herself pawn them, and buy some Victuals.</p>
               <p>Pris. Reynolds. I was going up to <placeName id="t17390117-1-crimeloc5">Cornhill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-crimeloc5" type="placeName" value="Cornhill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-1-crimeloc5" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-off2 t17390117-1-crimeloc5"></join>, and met the Prosecutrix and Sal Creech. 'Twas they persuaded the Girl to pull her Cloaths off They carried them away, and I staid a great while with her. At last she fell a-crying, and I called out, Pat London; but not hearing her answer, I went home. London hung the Girl's Petticoat out of the Window when the Watchman came, that it might not be seen, and the Stays we hid under a Basket of Oranges. Both <rs id="t17390117-1-verdict6" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-verdict6" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-1-verdict6" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty. <rs id="t17390117-1-punish7" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17390117-1-punish7" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend27 t17390117-1-punish7"></join>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-1-defend29 t17390117-1-punish7"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>. The Jury recommended them to the Mercy of his Majesty.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
