<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350911-99">
               <interp inst="t17350911-99" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-99" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-99" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-99" type="date" value="17350911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350911-99-off424-c464" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-defend685 t17350911-99-off424 t17350911-99-verdict429"></join>
         
               <p>124. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-defend685" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Hutchins 
                  <interp inst="t17350911-99-defend685" type="surname" value="Hutchins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-defend685" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-defend685" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173509110039"></xptr> the <rs id="t17350911-99-off424" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-off424" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-off424" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17350911-99-victim686" type="victimName">
                        Manwaring 
                        Low 
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-victim686" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-99-victim686" type="given" value="Manwaring"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-99-victim686" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-off424 t17350911-99-victim686"></join>
                     </persName>
                    by giving him with an Earthen Pipkin one mortal Bruise on the upper part of his Nose, <rs id="t17350911-99-cd425" type="crimeDate">May 9</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-off424 t17350911-99-cd425"></join> of which he languished till the seventh of June, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for Man slaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person687">
                  Diana 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person687" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person687" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person687" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Husband <rs id="t17350911-99-viclabel426" type="occupation">kept a Distillers Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-victim686 t17350911-99-viclabel426"></join>. The Prisoner was his <rs id="t17350911-99-deflabel427" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-defend685 t17350911-99-deflabel427"></join>, and lived next Door. On the twenty ninth of May, in the Evening, as my Husband was drawing a Dram for Mr. Morley, and I was sitting at the end of the Counter, looking through the Window. The Prisoner's Wife run by, and he followed her. My Dear says I, There is Sam running after his Wife, to beat her: I wish you would speak to him. So my Husband went out and desired him not to beat his Wife. The Prisoner (as my Husband afterwards told me) said, G - D - your Blood, though you are a Constable, you have got no Warrant for me. The Deceased answered, No Sam, and if I had I would sooner let you know of it, than serve it upon ye. The Prisoner D - 'd his Blood again and having a Pipkin in his Hand, with Eggs in it, he upped with this Pipkin, and knocked the Deceased down in the Kennel: I helped to take him up. The Wound was at the Corner of his Eye, and the Grissle of his Nose was broke, he bled near three Hours. I sent for Mr. Meadows a Surgeon, who, after trying several things to stop it, was forced to bleed him in the Arm, and that turned the Blood. The Prisoner came into the Shop, my Husband said to him Sam, I did not think that you of all Men would have served me The Prisoner d - 'd his Blood, and said, If I had killed my Wife I had not cared, for I could but have been hanged for her. This was done on Thursday and my Husband died on the Saturday sennight following - And he said two or three times the Day before he died that the Wound was the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person688">
                  John 
                  Morley 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person688" type="surname" value="Morley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person688" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person688" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Going up <placeName id="t17350911-99-crimeloc428">Old Gravel Lane </placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-99-crimeloc428" type="placeName" value="Old Gravel Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-99-crimeloc428" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-off424 t17350911-99-crimeloc428"></join>about ten o'Clock. I found my self ill, and called at the Deceased's Shop for a Glass of Anniseed. He drew it, and I sat down. The Prisoner and his Wife quarrelled. He wanted her to dress his Supper, which she refused, and would not go home with him. Ye Son of a B - , says she, Because you have brought home so much Money you want a hot Supper and be d - 'd to you. He begun to pull her violently to make her come home, and she struggled hard not to go upon which the Deceased stept between them in a friendly manner, and said, Sam don't beat your Wife. The Prisoner returned. If you are a Constable, you have no Warrant against me. No says the Deceas'd, And if I had I'd sooner let you know it than serve it upon you. And then I think he took hold of the Prisoner's right Arm. but in a gentle friendly manner. D - ye, say, the Prisoner, You have no business between me and my Wife; and then having a Pint Pipkin with two or three Eggs in it, in his Hand he lifted his Hand up, and with the Pipkin he struck the Deceased a Blow just by the left Eye; but whether he threw the Pipkin, or held it in his Hand when the Blow was given, I cannot say, but the Pipkin was broke and the Deceased fell in the Kennel. I stepped from the Door where I then stood to help him up. But he being a heavy Man, I called his Wife to assist me. I called three times before she came, for she was then in a little Room backward, and saw nothing of the Affair. We brought him into the Shop, and she sent me for a Surgeon; after which the Prisoner came in and said, If you had kept in your Shop this had not happened - It is done and I cannot help it - I am sorry for it, but if I had killed my Wife I had not cared, for I could but have been hanged for her</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person689">
                  Alice 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person689" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person689" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person689" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased's Servant. My Master was carried up Stairs for dead. I sat up with him, and towards the Morning he came to himself. He got up in the Morning for two or three Hours, but was forced to go to bed again. He afterwards languished about the House, but was not capable of doing any Business. He declared on his Death Bed, that if he died, it would be by the Wound Sam Hutchins had given him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person690">
                  Peter 
                  Ken 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person690" type="surname" value="Ken"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person690" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person690" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to visit the Deceas'd in his Illness. He was in a Dose, and his Wife said to him, Low! Low! Do you think that Hutchins has been the Cause of your Death. He answered, Yes, but spoke as if the Words were pulled out of his Mouth - He used to be troubled with Fits, so that once he bit his Tongue almost in two.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person691">
                  Thomas 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person691" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person691" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person691" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day before he died, he said, he was afraid he should never do well in this World for the Blow that Hutchins had given him would be his Death. I told him I hoped not. He replied that he was satisfied it would be his end, and there was no possibility of the contrary. I was with him when the Surgeon bled him, and then I and the Surgeon's Man carried him up in a Chair like a dead Man. I saw him in his Shop three Days after,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173509110040"></xptr> I asked him how he did. He told me Hutchins was just gone by, and says he, I ask'd him how he could serve me so ill, and he answered, D - ye, if I had killed ye, I should have been glad of it, for you had no business to meddle with me at that time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Wife and I had some Words, and she run out. I followed her with a Pipkin in my Hand to bring her back; upon which the Deceased came and took hold of my Shoulder, and it being dark. I tost the Pipkin out of my Hand, but did not strike him with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person692">
                  Alice 
                  Richmond 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person692" type="surname" value="Richmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person692" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person692" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About a Month before the Blow, I saw the Prisoner in his Shop, and he said he that he was very ill, and he believed he and I strove who should die first, for he had something on his Heart that he could not remove.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person693">
                  Hains 
                  Brasier 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person693" type="surname" value="Brasier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person693" type="given" value="Hains"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person693" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw him five Weeks before the Blow, and he said he was not well, nor he believed never should; and then he shewed me his Tongue which he had bit through in several places when he was in Fits; but says he, I was never subject to these Fits before I was cast in this Law suit. I have lain it to heart, and I believe it will be my Death</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person694">
                  John 
                  Brick 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person694" type="surname" value="Brick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person694" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person694" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner twenty Years, he was an honest industrious Man, and not given to quarrelling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-99-person695">
                  William 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17350911-99-person695" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person695" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-person695" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. Four Days after the Deceased's death, I viewed his Body, he had a Wound on the left side of his Nose, there was no Fracture of the Bone, but the Cartlage or Grissel of the Nose was separated from the Bone by the Violence of the Stroke. I opened the Head, I found no Fracture in the Cranium, nor any extravasated Blood, nor visible Cause of his Death from that Wound. Indeed I have heard he lost a vast Quantity of Blood. The violent Contusion made by the Blow might cause that extraordinary Effusion of Blood at the Nose, and this might cause the subsequent Convulsion Fit, to be more violent, which might carry him off.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17350911-99-verdict429" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-verdict429" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-verdict429" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17350911-99-punish430" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-punish430" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-99-punish430" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-99-defend685 t17350911-99-punish430"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
