<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-3">
               <interp inst="t17361208-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-3" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-3" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-3-off14-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-defend55 t17361208-3-off14 t17361208-3-verdict18"></join>
         
               <p>3. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-3-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Winston 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-defend55" type="surname" value="Winston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-defend55" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17361208-3-defloc13">St. Giles's, Cripplegate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-defloc13" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's, Cripplegate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-defloc13" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-defend55 t17361208-3-defloc13"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17361208-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 600 Pound Weight of unwrought Copper, value 12 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-3-victim57" type="victimName">
                     Daniel 
                     Marcon 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-victim57" type="surname" value="Marcon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-victim57" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-victim57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-off14 t17361208-3-victim57"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17361208-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">July 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-off14 t17361208-3-cd15"></join>.</p>
               <p>Daniel Marcon. About the Middle of July last, the <placeName id="t17361208-3-crimeloc16">Ship Nancy</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-crimeloc16" type="placeName" value="Ship Nancy"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-3-crimeloc16" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-off14 t17361208-3-crimeloc16"></join> (of which I am in Part Owner) arriv'd from Barbary, of which there was a large Quantity of Copper, the Property of myself and two or three Merchants. In order to land this Copper it was put into Lighters, my Quantity was about 9 Tun Weight, 386 double Heads; when my Part was landed at Galley-Key, I miss'd nine double Heads; I enquir'd then, whether the other Proprietors had their Complement; one miss'd seven double Heads, another miss'd a double Head and a half; a double Head weighs about half a Hundred, some more, some less, they are in round Cakes, two of them join'd together. I next enquir'd, whether the Copper was all come from the Ship, and I found my whole Quantity had been put on board the Lighter; I sold what was brought ashore upon the Keys, and told the Person who bought it, that I had not so much as I expected I enquired still after what I had lost, and about three Weeks afterwards, Mr. Briggs came and told me, he believ'd he had discover'd my Copper. I went with him to one Mr Gardiner's in Barbican; Mr. Gardiner was not at Home, but I saw the Copper, and took Notice of the Marks D, and D L P, on two Heads; there was six or seven in a Heap. Mr. Briggs said, Mr. Gardiner was a Man of Honour, I might trust him; and that he was sure he would give an Account how he came by them. Next Day I saw Mr Gardiner, and he told me that he bought the Copper of the Prisoner, and that Mr. Hone had bought another Parcel of him. I was obliged to take out a Search Warrant, but knowing the Prisoner's Character, I did not make use of it. Mr. Hone shew'd me the Copper he bought of the Prisoner, and I saw the Mark D on one of the Heads. We then sent for the Prisoner to a Publick House, and Word was brought us, that he was out of Town; but about the latter End of Aug. Mr. Briggs, Mr. Gardiner, Mr. Hone, and myself, met at the White-Lyon Tavern in Aldersgate-Street, and the Prisoner came to us, with a Friend who was to advise him; he own'd he sold Mr. Gardiner and Mr. Hone the Copper, but he did not know the Person he himself bought it of. We allow'd him two or three Days to find this Man out, but he could not, so I took the Prisoner before Sir Richard Brocas, who committed him; he offer'd Bail, I accepted it, and was in Hopes he would have found (by this Time) the Person that he bought it of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. I have known the Prisoner about five Years, I have dealt with him in his little Way of Trade, he is a <rs id="t17361208-3-deflabel17" type="occupation">Founder</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-3-defend55 t17361208-3-deflabel17"></join> as well as I. In July last he brought a Piece in his Hand to my Shop, and asked me if I wanted any Barbary Copper; he asked 4 l per Hundred for it; I said he must leave it for me to try, for some of this Barbary Copper proves very bad: He left me two Heads and they prov'd indifferent, so I-gave him 4 l. per Hundred, and took a Receipt for the Money: I think there was about 300 l. weight, and I did not observe any Marks upon it, nor did Mr. Briggs, or Mr. Marcon shew me any; but the Copper which Mr. Marcon claim'd, was the same I bought of the Prisoner. The Discovery was made by my telling Mr. Briggs and Sir 
               <persName id="t17361208-3-person58">
                  Thomas 
                  Mackworth 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person58" type="surname" value="Mackworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person58" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the White Lyon Tavern in Aldersgate-street,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080005"></xptr> that I had lately bought a little Parcel of Barbary Copper for 4 l. per Hundred. Sir Thomas said, if you have bought but a small Quantity, it is very likely it was stolen. I said, I had bought about three Hundred Weight, that it lay open in my Shop, and I knew who I bought it of.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, whether Winston used to deal in Copper, and in such Quantities?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. A Man in Trade may take Copper for Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he deal in casting Things of great Weight.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. No, small Things; he is a Candlestick-Founder. I was one Day at Mr. Hone's, and I saw he had got some Barbary Copper, and, says I, what, have you bought Barbary too? What did you give for it? Why, says he, the same Price that you did; I bought it of the same Man, but I thought he had no more.</p>
               <p>Councel. Then he did not care to let you know what Quantity he had got.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. I did ask him how much he had got, and he told me he had about three Hundred Weight; I thought I had bought all he had. When he met us at the White-Lyon Tavern, he told us, he had it of a Man that bought Candlesticks of him to the Value of 7 l. and who was a perfect Stranger to him. I said, that is stranger still, that you should buy so much Metal, and sell so many Candlesticks to a Man you knew nothing of. I asked him how the Man brought it, he said the Man came himself with Porters (or a Cart, I cannot remember which) and took the Goods he bought away with him. He was asked, whether there was any Bills of Parcels or Receipts given, and he said no, there were none at all; he said he would endeavour to find out the Man, and had his Liberty for three Weeks or a Month to do it, but at last he said he could not do it, and he believed he should hear no more of him.</p>
               <p>Councel. Is it usual for People to hawk such a Weight of Copper about with Porters, or in a Cart?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. No.</p>
               <p>Councel Pris. Is it not usual for Founders to buy unwrought Copper for the Purposes of their Trade?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. And of Persons that come about with it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. I can't say so, but it is usual to take it in Truck for Goods.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I ask Mr. Gardiner, whether, when my Servants carried the Copper to his House, he did not bid them go and bring him more?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gardiner. No, I did not; his Servant's brought me the Copper and he was with them, and took the Money for it; and I have his Receipt for it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hone. The 27th of July last, the Prisoner brought me a Piece of Barbary Copper, and asked me to buy it. I said it was generally bad but if he would leave it for me to try it, if it proved good, I told him I would give 4 l 8 s. per Hundred for it. He left a single Head with me, about a Quarter of a Hundred, and I sent to Mr Gardiner to know the Price of Copper, for I did not know myself; he sent me Word the Price was about 4 l per Hundred; so when the Prisoner came, I said I had over-bid myself, and that I would not give more than 4 l. a Hundred. He took 4 l. and I bought 3 hundred and a half. He told me he had sold Goods to the value of 7 l 4 s. and took this in Payment for them. I had us'd a good deal of it, before Mr. Marcon apply'd to me for it, but he shew'd me the Marks upon what was left, tho' I should not have seen the Mark D upon it, if I had not call'd for a Brush and clean'd it. I have known the Prisoner these five Years, and I know 'tis usual for him to take Brass and Copper from the Brasiers in Truck for his Work, and we thought him a fair dealer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you, he had sold some of this Copper to Gardiner?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hone. Not at first; he did afterwards. At the White-Lyon the Prisoner said, the Man he bought it of, was a Stranger to him, and that he waited at his Shop, while he received the Money of me to pay him for it.</p>

               <p>Councel. I would ask you, if it is usual to buy Copper in this manner?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hone. We all of us have sometimes Metal which we can't use our selves. We have it commonly brought to our Shops. I never heard but that the Prisoner was an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Briggs. I never heard any thing to the contrary before. Mr. Marcon having lost Copper, and Mr. Gardiner telling me he had bought some, I carried Mr. Marcon to Mr. Gardiner's to see it. He told us Mr. Hone's, had bought some of the same. So we went to Mr. Hone's, and sent for the Prisoner, 2 or 3 Nights together, but he was not at Home: At last he came with one Renshaw, who said he knew the Porters to be all Rogues, for he had been among them, and that it might be stole by them. Mr. Marcon allow'd him Time to search after the Man he bought it of; but at last he said he could make no Discovery, and bid us Defiance. Such parcels of Copper are not usually sold to Founders, in the Manner this was Sold, but by Merchants and Factors.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080006"></xptr>Defence. A Man coming by while my two Boys were filing Candlesticks, he asked them if they made those Things; they told him, Yes, and he asked for me. When I came to him, he told me he had some Barbary Copper to dispose of, and if I would buy it, he would take some of my Goods. I did not understand the Worth of it, so I went to Mr. Hone's, and Mr. Gardiner's, to know what they would give for it. I left a Piece with Mr. Gardiner to be try'd, and he sent me Word in the Afternoon, that he would give but 4 l. per Hundred. I gave the Man I had it of 3 L. 18 s. and sold it for 4 l. The Man had three dozen Pairs of Candlesticks, and gave me 4 s. a Pair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-3-person59">
                  Samuel 
                  Parkin 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person59" type="surname" value="Parkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person59" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been the Prisoner's Servant almost 7 Years: It was in July last my Master bought this Copper. I was at Work in the Window, and the Man asked me if we made such Things. I told him we did; he came into our Shop (we live in Beech-lane) and I call'd my Master to him: He said he wanted some Candlesticks, and had some Copper to dispose of, and if my Master would agree, he would traffick with him. He bespoke three dozen Pairs of Candlesticks, at 4 s. a Pair; after this he brought the Copper, and my Master told him, if he would call again, he would let him know what he could give him for it: Then he carry'd it to Mr. Hone's, and the Man that brought the Copper was to have some Money, and some of our Goods for it. Three Days after he had agreed for the Candlesticks, he sent this Copper (at twice) to our Shop by two Porters; each of them went twice back: My Master and the Man weigh'd it, and my Master set down the Weigh: in a Paper, but I did not weigh it, nor see the Weight. He was a Sea-faring Man in brownish Cloaths, and Buttons of the same Colour, middle siz'd, and had on a bob Wig. He brought it in about Two o'Clock in July last, but I can't remember the Day.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did your Master carry to Mr. Hone's for trial?</p>
               <p>Parkin. One whole Piece; that is, two Pieces join'd together.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the Copper paid for?</p>
               <p>Parkin. Not 'till the Delivery of all the Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your Master to give?</p>
               <p>Parkin. Three Pounds 18 s. per Hundred.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not your Master keep a Book?</p>
               <p>Parkin. We did not set these down.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they carried away?</p>
               <p>Parkin. They were not packed up; he took them away with him put up in Papers, in a Basket.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your Master keep a Book?</p>
               <p>Parkin. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he enter what he buys and sells?</p>
               <p>Parkin. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What does he keep the Book for?</p>
               <p>Parking. He may enter Things in the Book, and I know nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. When your Master went to Mr. Hone's to know the value of the Copper, did the Man stay in the Shop 'till he came back?</p>
               <p>Parkin. No; he went away and came back in about five Hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-3-person60">
                  Richard 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person60" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person60" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Work when the Man bespoke the Candlesticks, and told my Master that he had Copper to dispose of; he was a pretty lusty Man, middle-siz'd for Height, in brown Cloaths and a bob Wig: He had it not with him then; but he brought it about Two or Three o'Clock in the Afternoon, by two Porters at twice coming. My Master and I, and my fellow 'Prentice, weigh'd it at several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Parkin (your fellow 'Prentice) by, when it was weigh'd?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes; and when the Weight was set down. The Gentleman asked my Master what he could give; he said he must ask what it was worth, so he carry'd some of it to Mr. Hone. I know nothing of the Paper in which the Weight was set down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Man that sold it, stay 'till your Master came back?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes; he staid a great while! but when my Master came back, they agreed about the Price. Mr. Hone said it was worth 4 l. and my Master gave the Man 3 l. 18 s.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the Candlesticks pack'd up?</p>
               <p>Jones. In Papers, and then put into a Bag.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure they were put into a Bag?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, and the Bag (I believe) was put into a Basket.</p>
               <p>Q. Who carry'd them away?</p>
               <p>Jones. A Porter that stood at the Door.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your Master often buy Metal unrefin'd?</p>
               <p>Jones. No.</p>
               <p>Mr. Green. I have known the Prisoner ten or twelve Years; he is a House-keeper, and as to his Character, I never knew him guilty of any thing like this. I would have been bound for him for a thousand Pounds. That Gentleman now has ask'd so many Questions! - Why, when he brings his Goods to me; here's a Piece of Chalk, and there's a Piece of Chalk, and we cast up the one and the other.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080007"></xptr>Q. And do you keep a chalk Account?</p>
               <p>Mr. Green. Why these are my Work-folks, and when they bring in their Work, there's the Chalk, and we cast up what it comes to, and pay them. This Man works for the Shops, and he's able to buy a thousand times the Quantity; not that he's able to pay for it, - but he brings it to us, and we bid him buy it, if there's any thing to be got. - There is some of this Barbary Copper now to be sold at a Broker's in Drury-Lane. I have had it brought to my Shop by Jews, and Fellows unknown, but I would never trouble my self for 2 s. a Hundred Profit. I have sold Candlesticks that have come to 10 Guineas, and never book'd them: And I have had 20 Pounds worth of Irish Half-pence, I have weigh'd them: And where do you live, says I? Why, if you'll buy them you may, and if you won't, we'll take them away. Barbary Copper, - 'tis hawk'd about, I have bought some To-day, I know nothing how 'tis come by.</p>
               <p>Councel. Then you may buy stolen Goods, and subject your self to a Prosecution.</p>
               <p>Mr. Green. In our open Shops 'tis thus; - here's new Goods for your old.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-3-person61">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person61" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person61" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - Nash, 
               <persName id="t17361208-3-person62">
                  William 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person62" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17361208-3-person63">
                  Francis 
                  Kelborn 
               <interp inst="t17361208-3-person63" type="surname" value="Kelborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person63" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of a very honest, industrious Man, and all of them never heard any ill of him in their Lives. <rs id="t17361208-3-verdict18" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-3-verdict18" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
