<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-35">
               <interp inst="t17380628-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-35" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-35" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-35-off172-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-35-defend290 t17380628-35-off172 t17380628-35-verdict174"></join>
         
               <p>40. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-35-defend290" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Marks 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-35-defend290" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-defend290" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-defend290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380628-35-defloc171">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-35-defloc171" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-35-defloc171" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-35-defend290 t17380628-35-defloc171"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380628-35-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-35-victim292" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Pomeroy 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-35-victim292" type="surname" value="Pomeroy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-35-victim292" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-35-victim292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-35-off172 t17380628-35-victim292"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him, a silver Watch, value 4 l. a Silver Chain. value 5 s. a Brass Seal, value 1 d. a Hat, value 4 s. a Peruke, value 15 s. and a Cane with a Brass Head, value 3 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17380628-35-cd173" type="crimeDate">Nov. 9.</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-35-off172 t17380628-35-cd173"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-35-person293">
                  Joseph 
                  Pomeroy 
               <interp inst="t17380628-35-person293" type="surname" value="Pomeroy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-person293" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know the Prisoner, for I was very much in Liquor that Night. I had been at the Jerusalem Tavern, with some Friends that Night, and parted with them I don't know where; - but a little above the Watch-house, somebody shov'd me down, or I fell down, I don't know which; so I went to the Watch-house, and told them I had lost my Hat and Cane and Whig; and putting my Hand to my Pocket, I miss'd my Watch. - Z - nds! says I, (I did say Z - nds) I have lost my Watch too. I did not mind the Loss of any Thing but my Peruke, - for I was afraid of catching Cold, and getting deaf; therefore I desired to come into the Watch-house; the Watchmen opposed me, - Bl - d! says I, I will come in, with that they sent me to - the Round house; and because I would not pay the Watchmen a Shilling a-piece, they bound me over. The Watch was advertised, and I got it again; and the Constable got the Cane. As to the Prisoner I know nothing of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-35-person294">
                  Richard 
                  Smitherman 
               <interp inst="t17380628-35-person294" type="surname" value="Smitherman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-person294" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Pawnbroker. I believe it was the 17th of November, the Prisoner brought the Watch to my House, to pawn, about 9 o'Clock<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280020"></xptr> in the Morning. He asked 3 Guineas upon it, I knew him to be a poor Fellow, and wonder'd how he came by it; therefore I asked him how he came by it? He said he bought it at Mr. Hulet's in Eagle Street; I step'd to Mr. Hulet's, and he told me the Prisoner had bought no Watch of him. The Prisoner followed me to Mr. Hulet's, and gave me ill Language, and would have had the Watch by Force from me. I told him before Mr. Hulet, if he could give any Account where he had it I would return it. Then he said he won it by Gaming at Temple-Bar, and would have it from me, and struggled with me for it, till we both fell down together; then I offered a Shilling to any one that would fetch a Constable, upon which he went away, and got clear off; but the Watch being advertised, the Prosecutor had it again. Some time afterward, the Prisoner was seen by Mr. Cross in the Street, he gave me Intelligence of him, I went up and took him, and sent for the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Pomeroy. When the Prisoner was before the Justice, he said I had a Woman with me in Holborn, and that I staid with her about a Minute; then I made up (he said) towards the Watch-house, and there she pull'd at my Watch, - and I pull'd, and so it fell down: After which, he went to the Place and trod upon my Cane, stooping down for that (he said) he found the Watch. As for my Hat and Wig, he knew nothing of them. Now I can take an Oath that I had no Woman with me that Night.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Margets The Prisoner was brought before me, and behav'd as impudently as ever I saw any one in my Life. He told me the Prosecutor had got a Whore, and fell down in a Sirreverence, and that after he had pick'd himself up, and the Woman was gone, he went to the Place where he fell, and treading upon his Cane, he found that and the Watch. He cursed and swore very much, and a more impudent Fellow I never saw in my Life.</p>
               <p>Defence. I was going Home that Night about 12 o'Clock, and in Newport Street, I had Occasion to ease myself, and the Gentleman came down with a Woman, and d - mn'd her for a B - ch, he wanted to ease himself, and bending down, he fell backwards. She helped him up, and I saw her pulling at something all the Time. I was almost blind then, and I am quite blind now; so when they were gone, I went over to the Place, and groping about, I trod upon the Cane, and stooping down, I found the Watch and the Cane link'd together. Next Morning I went to this Pawnbroker's to get some Money upon the Watch, and he stopp'd it.</p>
               <p>Jury. He says he was almost blind, how could he see the Prosecutor on the other Side of the Way? He says, he went over the Way, and feeling for the Cane, found the Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not quite blind then. <rs id="t17380628-35-verdict174" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-35-verdict174" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
