<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390718-10">
               <interp inst="t17390718-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-10" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-10" type="date" value="17390718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-10-off46-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-defend89 t17390718-10-off46 t17390718-10-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>397. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-defend89" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Trumble 
                  <interp inst="t17390718-10-defend89" type="surname" value="Trumble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-defend89" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-defend89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390718-10-off46" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-off46" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-off46" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390718-10-victim91" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17390718-10-victim91" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-10-victim91" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-10-victim91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-off46 t17390718-10-victim91"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, in the Parish of St. John, Hackney, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Silver Watch, val. 30 s. an Iron Chain, val. 2 d. and a Brass Seal, val 1 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17390718-10-cd47" type="crimeDate">June 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-off46 t17390718-10-cd47"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180006"></xptr>Mr. Brown. On the 18th of June I was walking in the Field towards <placeName id="t17390718-10-crimeloc48">Hackney Downs</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-10-crimeloc48" type="placeName" value="Hackney Downs"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-10-crimeloc48" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-off46 t17390718-10-crimeloc48"></join>; Brook-House Clock had just struck Six, when the Prisoner came past me, and looking me full in the Face, he went on his Way. But when I was got into the next Field, I saw him coming after me, in a Path between some Corn; seeing him coming towards me, I made towards the Hedge-Side; when he came up to me, he made a full Stop, and asked me the Way to Newington? I directed him thither, and turned my Back on him; but I had not gone many Steps, before I heard somebody coming behind me; I turned about, and saw a Man with a Mask upon his Face, and a Pistol in his Hand; he called to me, and said, - Sir, I must have your Money. Money, says I! - I don't know whether I have any Silver or no. However, he came up to me with his Pistol in his Hand, and I put my Hand in my Pocket for my Money; I had a pretty many Half-Pence, about 8 or 9 Penn'orth, and while I was feeling for them, he saw my Watch Chain: Sir, says he, I must have your Watch. I desired him not to take my Watch, but he said he must have it immediately, and he took hold of the Chain, and drew it out himself; then he went away, and did not stay to search me any farther. When he was got some Distance from me, I saw him run; then I call'd out - Stop Thief! Stop Highwayman! Upon the Alarm he was follow'd and taken. I saw him when the People started after him, but not when he ran out of the Ditch, for that was near Three quarters of an Hour afterwards. I remember the Prisoner's Face perfectly well; and though when he robb'd me he had a Masque on, yet by his Voice and Cloaths, I have Reason to believe he is the Man; and no one else could come into the Field in that Space of Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person92">
                  Edward 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person92" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person92" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor lodged at my House, and at the Time he was robb'd I was drinking with a Friend at the Door of a Publick House in the Neighbourhood. While I was there, a Man came up and told me the Gentleman had been robb'd; so two or three of us went after the Thief; - One went one Way, and others another. By the Account I had of the Robbery, I thought the Man could not be far off, and that he could not easily escape. I and two others searched for him in the Field next the Downs, and there we found a Track in the Field, which we follow'd till we came to a Ditch, and under the Bushes I thought-I saw something, and it proved to be the Prisoner. One of the Lads that was with me said, he was sure it was either a Man, or a Sack of Peas that was hid there; I said 'twas a Man; upon which the Prisoner raised himself upright in the Ditch, from under the Bushes, and put on his Hat and Wig, which before were off, and he had no sooner done that, but he held up a Pistol through the Bushes at me. I drew back, and cautioned those that were with me to do so too; at the same Time bidding the Prisoner come out; he accordingly came out, presenting a Pistol in each Hand. We had two or three Dogs with us, and we set them at him, but they would not seize him; so he ran away, with a Pistol in each Hand, and we pursue'd him over the Downs, and towards a Wooden Bridge at the Bottom of the Downs, which goes over a Brook. He ran over the Bridge, and we called to a Man, who was then coming over it, to stop him, but he did not. When he had got a few yards over the Bridge, I saw him shift his Pistols into one Hand, and dropp'd the Watch with the other. I bid one of the Lads take it up, and carry it to Mr. Brown, while we pursued the Prisoner, who ran up a dirty Lane, where some Men were digging Ballast, and we alarmed them likewise. We pursued him out of this Lane, cross Kingsland Road, and through an Orchard, into a large Field of Beans and Peas; and here the People coming thick upon him, he got into a Corner of the Field, and stood with a Pistol in each Hand, and every one being afraid to go near him for fear of his Pistols, a Man called out for a Gun; I said, I would go and get one, upon which the Prisoner called to me, and said he would surrender himself to me; We did not understand him at first; and a Man asked him, whether he would surrender to him? No, says the Prisoner - I will surrender to that Man in his own Hair, (meaning me.) Then I went nearer him, and desired him to drop his Pistols; he told me I might come safely, for he would do me no Hurt; I insisted on his throwing down his Pistols, and while we were arguing, some People got hold of his Arms, and secur'd him. When he was taken we carry'd him to a Publick House, (where he behaved well) and from thence we took him before Justice Norris, and there he said but very little; he told the Justice, - he did not chose to say either one Thing or another. This Pair of Pistols was found upon him, and two or three Balls, and a Pair of Bullet-moulds; one of the Pistols was loaded, but I think it was not prim'd; I don't know whether the other had any Thing more than<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180007"></xptr> a Ball and a Bit of Paper in it. I was never above twenty or thirty Yards from him, from the Time of his being started out of the Ditch, to his being taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person93">
                  Samuel 
                  Bamblin 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person93" type="surname" value="Bamblin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person93" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Mr. Dixon's Evidence in every particular; adding that he deliver'd the same Watch which the Prisoner dropp'd into the Prosecutor's Hands, and it being produced in Court, he swore it was the Watch which was then taken from him, and which was afterwards deliver'd to him by Bamblin.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person94">
                  Henry 
                  Harrill 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person94" type="surname" value="Harrill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person94" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Constable, produced the Bullet-moulds, the Pistols and the Watch, which were seal'd up in a Bundle before Mr. Norris and Mr. Tyssen: His Evidence, with regard to the Condition the Pistols were found in, and the Prisoner's Behaviour when taken, agreed with the former Witnesses. In Answer to a Question relating to the Temper of Mind the Prisoner was in at the Time of his being apprehended, he said, the Prisoner then appear'd - very solitary, and a Sort of a Wildness appear'd in his Eyes; and when any Question was ask'd him, he turn'd about, and look'd wistfully. This Witness likewise depos'd, that the Prisoner told the Justices, - he chose to say nothing, nor to answer any Questions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person95">
                  Thomas 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person95" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person95" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at Work in the Gravel-pits by Shacklewell, and when the Prisoner came by, he join'd with the Rest of the Pursuers, and confirm'd the former Accounts of the Prisoner's being taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person96">
                  Edward 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person96" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person96" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             depos'd, That he was the Person who came behind the Prisoner and seiz'd him, while he was parleying with Dixon, the 2d Witness.</p>
               <p>Job Griffin, 
               <persName id="t17390718-10-person97">
                  William 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person97" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person97" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17390718-10-person98">
                  John 
                  Chelton 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person98" type="surname" value="Chelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were likewise present when the Prisoner was taken in the Manner already related.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person99">
                  Thomas 
                  Steed 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person99" type="surname" value="Steed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person99" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner from a Child: I knew his Parents; they lived next Door to me, in St. Clement's Parish, in Ipswich. His Mother was many Times beside herself; she made many Attempts to destroy her Life, and at last she hang'd herself; I was upon the Coroner's Inquest, and she was brought in Lunatick, for she had been reputed as such. The Prisoner lived at Ipswich till he was twelve Years old, and behav'd well; then he was put out Apprentice at Colchester, and during his Apprenticeship, I only saw him when he came to visit his Friends. His Father was several Times out of Order: - Once I remember he came to our House, and my Wife perswading him to eat something with us, he said, he could not, for if he did he should be choak'd, and should die at the next high Water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person100">
                  Eleanor 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person100" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person100" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known the Prisoner seven Years. She depos'd, that the Prisoner (in her Opinion) had been disorder'd in her Senses ever since the Death of his Father, who was Master of a Ship, and was drown'd: That he appear'd as a Man disturb'd, and to have had his Mind full of Trouble, for six or seven Weeks before he committed this Fact: That he often appear'd melancholy, and would immediately be in a Flurry, and look wild: That seven or eight Weeks after he had heard of his Father's being drowned, he took a House by Hicks's-Hall, and before he came to live in it, he shut himself up in it, and she going there to see him, was obliged to knock half an Hour at the Door, before he open'd it to her; that at that Time there were only his Shop Goods in the House, and this she said, was about three Days before the Fact; she never heard any thing amiss of him before, and observed that he work'd industriously at his Business of a <rs id="t17390718-10-deflabel49" type="occupation">Cabinet-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-defend89 t17390718-10-deflabel49"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person101">
                  Francis 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person101" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person101" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             depos'd, that the Prisoner had been melancholy for six or seven Weeks before the Commission of this Fact: That when he was spoke to, he never cared to speak again: This Witness took him to be a Man disturbed in his Senses, but could not say he ever saw him so much disorder'd, as not to be capable of distinguishing Good and Evil. He never heard any Ill of him, and took him to be very sober and very industrious.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person102">
                  John 
                  Sawyer 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person102" type="surname" value="Sawyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person102" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known him twelve Years, and saw him two or three Days before this Fact. He said, the Prisoner then appear'd very melancholy, and to be much disorder'd, which he imputed to the Uneasiness created in his Mind by the Death of his Father. He added, that the Prisoner, (before he parted with him) appear'd to have strange Notions of having a great deal of Business upon his Hands, - so much - that he could not stay to talk with the Witness; that he started from one Thing to another, and appear'd disorder'd in his Understanding, but he could not say he knew no Difference between Good and Evil.</p>
               <p>Wilford Head had observed him to have been melancholy and dejected, since the Death of his Father, but he took him to be in his Senses, and, as far as he could apprehend, he took him to be capable of discerning Good and Evil.</p>
               <p>The three following Prisoners were brought from Newgate, to give an account of his Behaviour since his Confinement.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person103">
                  Thomas 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person103" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person103" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             declar'd, that he was confin'd with him on the Common Side, and that once he took a Knife out of his Pocket, and was going to cut his own Throat. That another Night he had put the Bell-rope round his Neck; and had hang'd himself, had not the Witness seen him struggling for Life, and hoisted him up till he had disengag'd him from the Rope, otherwise (the Witness said) he had certainly jamm'd himself. 'Twas added farther, that the Prisoner, during his Confinement with them, could never give a regular Answer, that they durst not trust him by himself, and that this had been his Condition very near a Month.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person104">
                  John 
                  Garment 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person104" type="surname" value="Garment"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person104" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account; and said farther, that they were obliged to keep a Rush Candle burning every Night, for Fear he should make away with himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-10-person105">
                  William 
                  Skingler 
               <interp inst="t17390718-10-person105" type="surname" value="Skingler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person105" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same Effect; and likewise, that the Prisoner disturb'd them o'Nights, sometimes by his walking about with melancholy Thoughts, and sometimes by his raveing, and talking of Things without any Sense. <rs id="t17390718-10-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390718-10-punish51" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-10-punish51" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-10-defend89 t17390718-10-punish51"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
