<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-12">
               <interp inst="t17360610-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-12" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-12" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-12-off52-c84" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-12-defend112 t17360610-12-off52 t17360610-12-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>14. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-12-defend112" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Holburt 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-12-defend112" type="surname" value="Holburt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-defend112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-defend112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-12-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-12-victim114" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Macneal 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-12-victim114" type="surname" value="Macneal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-12-victim114" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-12-victim114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-12-off52 t17360610-12-victim114"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Hat, Peruke, a Cloth Coat, Wastcoat, Shirt, Silk Stockings, silver Stock-buckle, Shoes and Base-metal Buckles, and 5 s. and 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360610-12-cd53" type="crimeDate">April 20. 1735</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-12-off52 t17360610-12-cd53"></join>.</p>
               <p>Macneal. Last April was twelve Month, I had been drinking at the Ship by Well-close Square: Holburt and 
               <persName id="t17360610-12-person115">
                  Daniel 
                  Malden 
               <interp inst="t17360610-12-person115" type="surname" value="Malden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-person115" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and two Women were drinking in the next Box: Crossing <placeName id="t17360610-12-crimeloc54">Salt-petre Bank</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-12-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="Salt-petre Bank"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360610-12-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-12-off52 t17360610-12-crimeloc54"></join> in my way Home, they follow'd me, and Holburt came behind me and knock'd me down, and they stripp'd me as naked as ever I was born: I did not know that the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100007"></xptr> Prisoner knocked me down 'till Daniel Malden had put him into an Information.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-12-person116">
                  Joseph 
                  Dallison 
               <interp inst="t17360610-12-person116" type="surname" value="Dallison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-person116" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In April last was twelve Month, about 7 in the Morning, I open'd my Window, and saw the Evidence stand quaking and in a miserable Condition; for Christ's sake, says he, good Christians take me in! I took him in, and my Wife got a Blanket and put about him, and a Cap upon his Head. I did not see any Wounds about him. He lay down on a Couch 'till twelve a Clock; we sent to his Wife for some Cloaths, and then he went his way Home. I asked him who had robb'd him, and he said there was two Women with them that did it.</p>
               <p>Dallison's Wife. I remember the Time; for I took my Blanket and Rug and cover'd him: He said two Men and two Women who had been drinking at the Ship had dogg'd him and knock'd him down and stripp'd him. It was near twelve o'Clock before he could express himself well; then he sent me to his Wife for Cloaths; she sent them by me, and he put them on, and went away.</p>
               <p>(Macneal's Coat, which be then lost was produced.)</p>
               <p>Another Witness. Jack Holburt's Wife brought this Coat to me, and I lent her 3 s. upon it, I think.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. Malden having made his Information before Justice Farmer, we searched the former Witness's House; she deny'd the Goods, but upon searching we found the Coat. She would not tell us then how she came by them, but it seems she has since recollected her Memory. Macneal upon the first fight of the Prisoner in Jayl, knew him and tax'd him with the Fact; upon which he cry'd out, This is the Man who is to tuck me up.</p>
               <p>- Harris. I know the Prisoner is a Man of very ill Fame: He has been in three Informations. <rs id="t17360610-12-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-12-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
