<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360115-25">
               <interp inst="t17360115-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-25" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-25" type="date" value="17360115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360115-25-off149-c151" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-defend213 t17360115-25-off149 t17360115-25-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-defend213" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Davison 
                  <interp inst="t17360115-25-defend213" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-defend213" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-defend213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17360115-25-defloc148">St. Martin in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-25-defloc148" type="placeName" value="St. Martin in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-25-defloc148" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-defend213 t17360115-25-defloc148"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360115-25-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360115-25-victim215" type="victimName">
                           Talmash Duke 
                           Ford 
                        <interp inst="t17360115-25-victim215" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-25-victim215" type="given" value="Talmash Duke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-25-victim215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-off149 t17360115-25-victim215"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , and violently throwing, &amp;c. him from a Step-Ladder, in the back Yard of 
                     <persName id="t17360115-25-person216">
                        Robert 
                        Keaton 
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person216" type="surname" value="Keaton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-25-person216" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-25-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   in <placeName id="t17360115-25-crimeloc150">Long-Acre</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-crimeloc150" type="placeName" value="Long-Acre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-crimeloc150" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-off149 t17360115-25-crimeloc150"></join>; by Reason of which throwing, &amp;c. the said Talmash Duke Ford received one mortal Wound on the Back part of his Head, of which Wound he languished from the <rs id="t17360115-25-cd151" type="crimeDate">3d to the 14th of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-off149 t17360115-25-cd151"></join>, and then died.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>Justice De Veil. On the 23d of December, the Prisoner was brought before me for throwing the Deceased from a Ladder: Mr. Matthews informed me there was no Possibility of removing the Deceased; therefore I went to the House and took the Deceased's Information under his own Hand; he was then perfectly in his Senses, but as I thought, had but a few Hours to live. I presented the Prisoner at the Bar to him; asked him if he knew him, and he said it was 
               <persName id="t17360115-25-person217">
                  James 
                  Davison 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person217" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person217" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I asked him if he wilfully threw him from the Ladder? He said he did, and next Day he died.</p>
               <p>Read the Information.</p>
               <p>The Information of Tallmash Duke Ford taken the 23d of December 1735. Who being on Oath, deposeth, that James Davison threw him off a Ladder, whereby his Skull was so fractured, that there is no Hopes of Life; and that it was done by him, and no other Person, wilfully and maliciously.</p>
               <p>Taken before me T. De Veil, the Day and Year aforesaid.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person218">
                  William 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person218" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person218" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased died at my House, and always declared the Prisoner wilfully and maliciously threw him from the Ladder, and that he had injured him once before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person219">
                  Sarah 
                  Bowcher 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person219" type="surname" value="Bowcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person219" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I looked after the Deceased, and heard him say the same; he lay three Weeks ill of this Wound.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coldham. About the 3d or 4th of December, I was sent for to this Man, he had received a Wound in the back part of his Head. Upon Examination, I found the Skull fractured, and tho' all possible Care was taken of him, yet in about three Weeks he died; the Fracture being the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The last time you dressed him in Mr. Keaton's House, Mr. Cooley was with you, and bled him; I held him in my Arms, while you drest him: did you hear him make any such Declaration then?</p>
               <p>Coldham. I don't remember that I ever did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person220">
                  James 
                  Glanfield 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person220" type="surname" value="Glanfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person220" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Garret when the Accident happened, and Word was brought me that the Deceased's Brains were knocked out: I went down to see him, and next Morning he told me he believed it was Davison threw him off the Ladder. The Morning before he got the Hurt, he was very much in Liquor; I cannot tell how he was in the Afternoon, but I know they were sociable, and quiet, and drank Beer together that very Afternoon: I saw them together, and they behaved as well as two Fellow-servants could do: The Prisoner had lent the Deceased a Crown, and he would have pawned his waistcoat, to have paid the Prisoner, and he would not let him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was he not frequently in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Glandfield. Yes</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person221">
                  James 
                  Macmullan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person221" type="surname" value="Macmullan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person221" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Work in the Shed, erected for priming Cloath for Painters. We go up and down by a Ladder with Bevill-Steps, 14 Foot high. I heard the Prisoner and the Deceased, about two Minutes before the Accident happened, talking in a very Friendly Manner, about a Pot of Beer. The Deceased's Business was in the Shop, not in the Yard, but he was coming to speak with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Ladder stand?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. It bore against the Bracimer of the Building, and stood aslant.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not the Deceased speak to you without going up the Ladder?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. Yes, unless he had private Business.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it necessary to go up that Ladder, if he would be on a Level with you?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. Yes he could not say any Thing in private, without coming up the Ladder.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the Accident happened?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. Yes he fell before the Ladder fell.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Occasion of the Ladder's falling?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. The Prisoner's coming to assist the Deceased, I take to be the Occasion of the Ladder's falling. - The Saturday before the Accident, I know he lent the Deceased a Crown, and the Day the Misfortune happened the Deceased<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173601150013"></xptr> would have pawned his Waistcoat to have paid him; but the Prisoner would not suffer him to do it. I am sensible they were very good Friends. When the Deceased had lost his Business, the Prisoner got my Master to employ him, and sent me to his House to fetch him to my Master Keaton. I visited him several times in his illness, and I never heard him charge the Prisoner, till that Night Mr. Deveil was there.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say then?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. What has been read from Mr. Deveil. When the Ladder fell, I called for a round Ladder to come down, and found the Deceased on the Ground, with his Head between the Prisoner's Hands: O! says he, I believe my poor Boy has killed himself, and desired me to go immediately for Mr. Coldham. I have known them both 14 Years; the Deceased was about 24 or 26 Years old.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Prisoner behave when Mr. Coldham came?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. He held him in his Arms, and assisted at the first and third Dressing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would ask him, whether the Ladder was standing, or whether it had not slip'd away from its Footing.</p>
               <p>Macmullan. As I am on my Oath, I am sensible it slip'd from its Footing: it bore on a White Lead Barrel 3 Foot high, after it fell; one Part was on the Ground, and one Part on the Barrel.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was there not a large Grinding-stone on the Barrel-head; and did not the Ladder fall upon that?</p>
               <p>Macmullan. Yes; and we all apprehended the Deceased fell on that Stone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person222">
                  James 
                  Duffrey 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person222" type="surname" value="Duffrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person222" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sat up with the Deceased two Nights before he died; and he told me James Davison threw him off of the Ladder; he was going up to Macmullan; and disputing about a Pot of Beer, they had but few Words before he was flung off; but whether it was done designedly or not, he could not tell.</p>
               <p>Wm. Williams. The Ladder from whence the Deceased fell, was a large Ladder, every Step about 6 Inches and half wide: I heard the Deceased say, the Prisoner did it willfully.</p>
               <p>Q. They have not all declared so.</p>
               <p>Williams. I heard him declare so to Mr. Deveil.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This, Gentleman, was the Constable's Assistant and when they took me, he said, I should be carried from thence to New-gate, and from Newgate to Tyburn, if my Master did not pay the Charges upon Duke Ford's Account.</p>
               <p>Williams. I did tell him, I would not quit him till I had got him to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Sutherland Ford (the Deceased's Brother.) I have nothing to say, but only when I called to see my Brother, and asked him about Davison, he would rap out an Oath, and say, Don't talk to me about him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person223">
                  Ann 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person223" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person223" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never heard him say any thing of the Matter.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. The Prisoner gave the same Account before me, that he never owed the Deceased any Ill-will, and he behaved very well; and the Deceased was so ill, that I could not ask him half the Questions I would have done.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person224">
                  Mary 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person224" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person224" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Keaton's Servant. I saw them at Breakfast together, in very good Friends.</p>
               <p>Mr. R. Keaton. The Prisoner has lived with me 9 Years; he is a sober diligent Man, not given to quarrel: I never heard of any between him and the Deceased.</p>
               <p>Mrs. - Keaton. I have known him two Years: He is a quiet, sober, careful Fellow, and as good a <rs id="t17360115-25-viclabel152" type="occupation">
                     <rs id="t17360115-25-deflabel153" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-defend213 t17360115-25-deflabel153"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-25-victim215 t17360115-25-viclabel152"></join> as any we have. I have often requested Mr. Keaton never to let the Deceased come into the House any more, on Account of his Drinking and Quarrelling.</p>
               <p>And several others gave him a good Character</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If the Apothecary is in Court, I de sire he may be called.</p>


               <p>Mr. Beaumont. I attended Duke Ford; and when I saw him, I thought him not in a Condition to make any Information; he seemed delirious; and I thought him then Incurable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-25-person225">
                  Thomas 
                  Gomond 
               <interp inst="t17360115-25-person225" type="surname" value="Gomond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person225" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took him to be delirious; when I attended him, he was not sensible.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17360115-25-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-25-verdict154" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               not guilty of the Indictment, and on the Coroner's Inquest, that Tallmarsh Duke Ford's Death was Accidental
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
