<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-41">
               <interp inst="t17390502-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-41" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-41" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-41-off192-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-41-defend301 t17390502-41-off192 t17390502-41-verdict195"></join>
         
               <p>282. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-defend301" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-41-defend301" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-defend301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-defend301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-41-off192" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-off192" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-off192" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Tankard, value 6 l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-41-victim303" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Plummer 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-41-victim303" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-41-victim303" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-41-victim303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-41-off192 t17390502-41-victim303"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-41-cd193" type="crimeDate">April 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-41-off192 t17390502-41-cd193"></join>.</p>
               <p>Edward Plummer. The Prisoner came to my Lodgings in <placeName id="t17390502-41-crimeloc194">Strand Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-41-crimeloc194" type="placeName" value="Strand Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-41-crimeloc194" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-41-off192 t17390502-41-crimeloc194"></join>, under Pretence of looking at them, and treating about them. I saw him there about Five Days before the Tankard was taken away. I can only say, the Tankard is mine, and is was lost the 10 th. of April.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-person304">
                  Jane 
                  Plummer 
               <interp inst="t17390502-41-person304" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person304" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner had been three or four Times in the Room to look at the Lodgings, before I missed the Tankard. He came on the 10th of April, to meet my Husband, and be informed from him, whether he designed to quit them, or no. The Tankard stood on a turn-up Bed in the Room, and was worth six Pounds, and more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-person305">
                  Sarah 
                  Manning 
               <interp inst="t17390502-41-person305" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person305" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While the Prisoner waited in the Room, he gave me a Shilling to fetch a Pot of Beer, and I went to the Ale-house to fetch it. While the Beer was drawing for me, my Mother-in Law (Jane Plummer) came to me, and asked if the Man came in there, I told her no; why says she, he has got the Tankard and is gone away. Upon this we went to look after him, and found him walking with another Man, in the King's-Bench Walks, in the Temple. I ran to this Gentleman, (the next Witness) and told him, he had got my Father's Tankard, so the Gentleman cry'd, Stop Thief, and we got the Tankard again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-person306">
                  Francis 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17390502-41-person306" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person306" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of April, about Seven in the Evening, I met the Prisoner in Serjeant's Inn, in Fleet street, and saw his Hand under his Apron, with either a Silver Mug, or a Tankard in it, for Part of the Silver was cover'd with his Apron, and Part was uncovered. This Girl (Manning) coming up, and telling me, that Man had got her Father's Tankard, I pursued him and got up to him, upon which he threw the Tankard with such Violence from him, that it rebounded two Yards, and had I not got out of the Way, I believe he would have broke my Legs with it. Mr. Evans (the next Witness) took it up, and I pursued him to the Steps in Red-Lyon Court, in Fleet street, and there he was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-person307">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17390502-41-person307" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of April this Girl [Manning] came to me under the Piazza's in the Temple, and took me by the Sleeves, and said, - That Man (pointing to the Prisoner) has got my Father's Tankard under his green Apron; upon that I cry'd Stop Thief, and pursu'd him cross Tanfield Court into the King's Bench Walks, and through the Maidenhead Alehouse into Serjeants Inn, and there he threw the Tankard out of his Hand, I took it up, and carry'd it to the Prosecutor, and he own'd it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Plummer. It was my Tankard.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was drinking at the Maidenhead Ale-house, and hearing a Noise, I went out to see what was the Matter, so they pursued me, and took me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-41-person308">
                  William 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17390502-41-person308" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person308" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner many Years, I believe he is just in his Character. I keep a House in Cross street, in Hatton Garden. He loged with me for some time, and paid me justly and honestly. I don't know that he wronged me.</p>
               <p>Another Witness had known the Prisoner a Year and a half; and another ten or twelve Years; both of them had never heard any Thing ill of him, nor that he had been guilty of any Dishonesty. <rs id="t17390502-41-verdict195" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-verdict195" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-41-punish196" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-41-punish196" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-41-defend301 t17390502-41-punish196"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
