<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-39">
               <interp inst="t17380222-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-39" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-39" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-39-off170-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-39-defend262 t17380222-39-off170 t17380222-39-verdict172"></join>
         
               <p>43. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-39-defend262" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Russell 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-39-defend262" type="surname" value="Russell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-39-defend262" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-39-defend262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of London, <rs id="t17380222-39-deflabel168" type="occupation">Gent</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-39-defend262 t17380222-39-deflabel168"></join>. was indicted, for that he on the <rs id="t17380222-39-cd169" type="crimeDate">30th of Nov</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-39-off170 t17380222-39-cd169"></join> in the Parish of St. Dunstan's in the West, <rs id="t17380222-39-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-39-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-39-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously made and forged an Acquittance and Receipt for Money, under a certain Account; which Account and forged Acquittance is in the Words and Figures following, viz. Guiren against Bancillion. Bill, 23 l. 4 s. 1 d. - 12 l. 10 s. 5 d. - 10 l. 13 s. 8 d. - half Profit, 5 l. 6 s., 10 d. - Costs out of Purse, 12 l. 10 s. 5 d. - my Dividend, 5 l 6 s. 10 d. - 17 l. 17 s. 3 d. - Receiv'd 4 l. 4 s. - Due to me 13 l. 13 s. 3 d. Receiv'd the above Contents. R. Gately.
With Intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-39-victim264" type="victimName">
                           Roger 
                           Gately 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-39-victim264" type="surname" value="Gately"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-39-victim264" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-39-victim264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-39-off170 t17380222-39-victim264"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , one of the <rs id="t17380222-39-viclabel171" type="occupation">Solicitor</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-39-victim264 t17380222-39-viclabel171"></join>s of the High Court of Chancery. And for uttering and publishing the same, knowing it to be forged and counterfeit.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution having open'd the Charge, the Court observ'd that the Indictment was not laid within the Words of the Statute, made in the 2d Year of his present Majesty, Chap. 25. and which was made perpetual in the 9th Year of the King.</p>
               <p>It was farther observ'd, that the Paper produced, appear'd rather a Bill of Costs. That if it was a Receipt, it was not express'd, who received. That as it was worded, the Receipt could not with any Propriety of Construction be apply'd to the Word Costs; and that the Paper appearing but a Memorandum, it was not applicable to the Case, as the Councel had open'd it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Russel. I humbly hope these Objections may be wav'd; and that the Court will be pleas'd to enter into the Merits of the Case.</p>
               <p>Councel Defendant. I beg leave to give the Gentlemen on the other Side this Hint. - That neither Mr. Gately's Testimony, nor his Affidavits, can be admitted in Evidence. The Case between the King and Whiting, is a Case in Point; and 'tis laid down by the Lord Chief Justice Holt, that where a Person is concerned in Interest, he cannot be a Witness.</p>
               <p>Councel Plaintiff. I presume Mr. Gately is an Evidence in Law; for supposing we convict the Defendant on this statute, the Benefit of the Clergy is taken from him, and every Thing he has, will be forfeited to the Crown; by his Conviction therefore Mr. Gately loses all Prospect of Satisfaction, - 'twill be out of the Defendant's Power to make him any, if he is convicted. The Objection against a Man's being a Witness, arises from his being concern'd in Point of Witness, and from it's being to his Advantage that he should be a Witness. But when 'tis to his own disadvantage that a Man appears as a Witness, he has always been allow'd a legal Evidence; as a Man may give a Testimony to charge himself. Now in this Case, if by Mr. Gately's, Evidence the Defendant should be convicted, Gately will be depriv'd of ever having any Satisfaction. What is he doing? Why he is prosecuting a Man, to convict him of an Offence, which Conviction takes away all Prospect of his having any Recompence.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner was <rs id="t17380222-39-verdict172" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-39-verdict172" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, and the Court granted him a Copy of his Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
