<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340424-37">
               <interp inst="t17340424-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-37" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340424-37" type="date" value="17340424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340424-37-off158-c191" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-37-defend266 t17340424-37-off158 t17340424-37-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>40. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340424-37-defend266" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Cotterell , alias <rs id="t17340424-37-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-37-defend266 t17340424-37-alias-8"></join>Tilbury</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-defend266" type="surname" value="Cotterell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-defend266" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-defend266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17340424-37-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a silver Watch and Chain, Value 5 l. 15 s. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340424-37-victim268" type="victimName">
                           Anthony 
                           Malione 
                        <interp inst="t17340424-37-victim268" type="surname" value="Malione"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340424-37-victim268" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340424-37-victim268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-37-off158 t17340424-37-victim268"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17340424-37-cd159" type="crimeDate">April 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-37-off158 t17340424-37-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173404240016"></xptr>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-37-person269">
                  Anthony 
                  Malione 
               <interp inst="t17340424-37-person269" type="surname" value="Malione"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-person269" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I vas coming home from de Post Office, vare I had been to cury some Letter, and I meet vid dat Voman, and she ask a me vare I vas going, and I sav Home. Home? She say, vare you live ? So I tell her vare I live. Vell, she say, she was going dat vay too, and she will go vid me. So ve come to a sort of a Lane - I tink da call it de <placeName id="t17340424-37-crimeloc160">Birt-in-Hand-Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340424-37-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Birt-in-Hand-Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340424-37-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340424-37-off158 t17340424-37-crimeloc160"></join>, and I tell her, dat is not my vay home. Den she make a stop, and begin to tell me her Nonsence, and ask a me for some Money. I tell her, I ave no Money, but some ha' Pence. Vell, she say, give a me dat for good luck. So I feel for mine Vash vonce and twice, and it vas in mine Pockate; den I feel again, and it vas gone. Vat you do vid mine Vash? I say. Vy, she said, she ave got no Vash, and she know noting of it.</p>
               <p>Den she fall down, and I begin to feel about her, and she cry Murder; and I call de Vash, but no Vash come. So I pull her into de Street, and 2 Vashmans come and carry her to the Vash-house, and I tell de Coonstauble to do me Shustice, for I vas a Stranzyer: But de Coonstauble vood no sarsh her, but he send her to de Coontaur, and de next Morning she was carry before Sir Rishard Brocass.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say to the Fellow, I never saw him before - But I had been to the Post-house with a Letter to my Husband, and going back, he catch'd hold of my Apron, and said, I was the Woman. What do you mean Fellow? says I. Go about your Master's Business. Where's the Watch? The Watch? Says he. I thought he had call'd the Watch; but I could not think for what. And 2 Watchmen came, and carried me to the Watch house, where I was search'd all over.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340424-37-person270">
                  David 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17340424-37-person270" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-person270" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Watchman of Cheap-side, and all as I know is, that I know nothing of the Man, for I never saw him till after he was brought to the Watch-house; and I did not see the Woman at all, for she was sent to the Compter, before I came to the Watch-house. But I am possible she was never search'd at the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>Court. How can you be sure of that, when you did not see her?</p>
               <p>Jones. I am very sure of it, for my Brother Watchman told me so.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17340424-37-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340424-37-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
