<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-19">
               <interp inst="t17380222-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-19" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-19" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-19-off87-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-19-defend152 t17380222-19-off87 t17380222-19-verdict89"></join>
         
               <p>20. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-defend152" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Thomas 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-19-defend152" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-defend152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-defend152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-19-off87" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-off87" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-off87" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling House of 
                     <persName id="t17380222-19-victim153" type="victimName">
                        Dorothy 
                        Elliot 
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim153" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim153" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , about 11 in the Forenoon, (no one being in the said House) and stealing a Cocoa cup tipp'd with silver, value 2 s. a silver Ring, value 18 d. six Guineas, and 10 s. 6 d. in Money, the Goods of the said Elliot, and a Silver Tankard value 40 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-19-victim155" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Chalk 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim155" type="surname" value="Chalk"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim155" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-19-victim155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-19-cd88" type="crimeDate">Jan 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-19-off87 t17380222-19-cd88"></join>.</p>
               <p>Dor. Elliot. Last Sunday was se'nnight, I work out about 8 o'Clock in the Morning to Church; and when I came Home, People met me and told me I had been robb'd. I came Home as fast as I could, and found the street Door lock'd. I open'd it, and ran up into my Chamber; there I found the Lock upon a Box where I keep my little Substance, quite broke off. I had six Guineas, ten Shillings and Six-pence in Silver, a silver Tankard, a Cocoa shell-Cup, with a silver Foot, and a silver Ring, in this Box, when I went to Church; but when I came Home, - they were all gone; the Prisoner was taken before I got Home, and the Things were found upon him. When he was before the Justice, he own'd he did the Fact, and that he had taken the Tankard, the Cup and the Ring; and as to the Money, he said he had but 1 Guinea and 10 s. 6 d. but he said he knew where the other five Guineas were. I knew nothing of the Prisoner before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-person156">
                  David 
                  Dobey 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person156" type="surname" value="Dobey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person156" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Constable, and was sent for the 5th of this Month, about 11 o'Clock to take Charge of the Prisoner. The Things mention'd in the Indictment, I found upon him, except the 6 Guineas. These are the Things.</p>
               <p>Elliot. And they are all of them mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-person157">
                  Mary 
                  Chalk 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person157" type="surname" value="Chalk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person157" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Tankard is mine; I gave it my Sister Elliot to take Care of it for me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dobey. I carry'd the Prisoner before Mr. Justice Phillips; he own'd taking of the Plate, the Ring, and the half Guinea in Silver; but he had some Partners (he said) concerned with him who took the Gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-person158">
                  James 
                  Drummer 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person158" type="surname" value="Drummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Feb. 5th in the Fore-noon, I was sitting in my House, next Door to Dame Elliot's, and saw the Prisoner cross the Way toward her Door. He had a dirty Canvas er his Arm. I heard him lift up the Latch of her Door, so I sent my Brother (a Boy, about 10 Years old) to tell him, there was no Body at Home; the Boy came back and said, there was no one at her Door, nor in the Street; while I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220010"></xptr> was making a Noise at the Boy, my Sister who was up Stairs, making the Bed, call'd to me, and said somebody was in Dame Elliot's Room; I bid her make hast and come down; she did so, and saw him. This was between 10 and 11 o'Clock; I am sure he's the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-person159">
                  Mary 
                  Drummer 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person159" type="surname" value="Drummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person159" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was above Stairs making the Bed, and hearing the Noise in Dame Elliot's House, I call'd down to my Brother, and asked him if she was at Home? He told me no, and bid me come down Stairs. As I came down, I heard the Prisoner lock the Door, and saw him go into the Alley. One of his Pockets was stuff'd out, and he had a Bundle under his Arm. After he came out of the Alley, he ran down the Lane, as hard as he could. I told my Brother, - there he ran. About three quarters of an Hour after, I saw him again, and said hold of him I took him; and asked him how he could be so base, to rob the old Woman? He told me, he had met her in Stepney Fields, and she had given him the Key, to carry up a Bag of Iron Nails; she deals in Iron. However, I took him by the Shoulder, and carried him to my own Door; he begg'd Leave to go into the House, because the Mob rose upon him. When I had got him into the House Mr. Jackson got a Constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-19-person160">
                  James 
                  Ridley 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person160" type="surname" value="Ridley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person160" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This 
               <persName id="t17380222-19-person161">
                  Mary 
                  Drummer 
               <interp inst="t17380222-19-person161" type="surname" value="Drummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person161" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came into our Yard, to wash some Leeks, and told me that Dame Elliot was robb'd. What at Noon Day says I! Yes, said she, and describ'd the Man to me, and told me what sort of a Coat he had on. While we were talking, the Prisoner went by, and we ran after him. We ask'd him what Business he had to rob Neighbour Ellot's House? He said he said he met her in Stepney Fields, and she gave him the Key of her Door to carry in a Bag of Nails. I told him she did not use to buy Iron on Sundays, - so we carry'd him to Drummer's House. <rs id="t17380222-19-verdict89" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-verdict89" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-verdict89" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty, Felony only
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17380222-19-punish90" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-19-punish90" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-19-defend152 t17380222-19-punish90"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
