<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380906-12">
               <interp inst="t17380906-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380906-12" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380906-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380906-12" type="date" value="17380906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380906-12-off65-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-defend102 t17380906-12-off65 t17380906-12-verdict68"></join>
         
               <p>13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380906-12-defend102" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Woodcock 
                  <interp inst="t17380906-12-defend102" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-defend102" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-defend102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380906-12-defloc64">St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380906-12-defloc64" type="placeName" value="St. Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380906-12-defloc64" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-defend102 t17380906-12-defloc64"></join>, was indicted, (with 
               <persName id="t17380906-12-person103">
                  Joseph 
                  Blison 
               <interp inst="t17380906-12-person103" type="surname" value="Blison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person103" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17380906-12-person104">
                  Joseph 
                  Meadows 
               <interp inst="t17380906-12-person104" type="surname" value="Meadows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person104" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken) for <rs id="t17380906-12-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380906-12-victim106" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Pulpin 
                        <interp inst="t17380906-12-victim106" type="surname" value="Pulpin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380906-12-victim106" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380906-12-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-off65 t17380906-12-victim106"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain Alley, near the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 4 l. a Portugal Piece of Gold, value 36 s. two Guineas, and 9 Shillings in Silver
            </rs>. <rs id="t17380906-12-cd66" type="crimeDate">Aug. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-off65 t17380906-12-cd66"></join>
               </p>
               <p>Thomas Pulpin . About 11 at Night, Aug . 22. as I was going home, I met the Prisoner and two Men in an Alley that goes into the <placeName id="t17380906-12-crimeloc67">Cole-Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380906-12-crimeloc67" type="placeName" value="Cole-Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380906-12-crimeloc67" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-off65 t17380906-12-crimeloc67"></join>, she came up to me, and said I had got Money, and she must have it; and if I spoke a Word, there were two Men would knock my Brains out. I was afraid of my Life, so I let her take it easily. I felt her Hands in my Pocket; and when she had done, the two Men call'd out, - Fiend of Hell, come along. While she was robbing me, they stood about 4 or 5 Yards off. She took from me a Watch, a 36 Shilling Piece of Gold, 2 Guineas, and 9 Shillings in Silver; (the Money was in a Purse) and then she and the two Men ran away together. I was afraid of following them, for Fear of being murder'd, therefore I went to the first House I found, and told the Man I had been robb'd. He ask'd me if I knew the Persons? I told him, No, I did not; but I had hear'd the Woman call'd Fiend of Hell, by the two Men that were with her. O! (says he) if it was Fiend of Hell that robb'd you, I can find her out in the Morning; and in the Morning she was found out, and I am positive she is the Person that robb'd me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380906-12-person107">
                  George 
                  Lines 
               <interp inst="t17380906-12-person107" type="surname" value="Lines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person107" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Pulpin came to my House the 22d of August between 12 and 1 at Night, and said he had been robb'd. I asked him if he knew who robb'd him, he said the Woman was call'd Fiend of Hell. O! says I, I know that Gentlewoman, sit down till Morning, and I will go and see if I can find her. Next Morning I went to a House in Drury-Lane, and called for a Pot of Beer, while I was drinking the Prisoner came in, so I took her, and the Prosecutor said, she was the Woman that had robbed him. She was very drunk when I took her, so I carry'd her to the Round-house 'till she was sober; then I had her before Justice Poulson, and he committed her. I heard her own the Robbery before the Justice, but I can't tell whether it was reduced into Writing or not.</p>
               <p>Jury. We desire Pulpin may be asked what Time of Night he was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Pulpin To the best of my Remembrance 'twas about 12 o'Clock. I was looking for a Friend that had been in a Quarrel when this happened.</p>
               <p>Jury. By what Light did you observe her Face?</p>
               <p>Pulpin. It was not so dark but I could see her Face very well, I swear she is the Woman that robb'd me. I can't say the Moon shone, but it was very Star-light.</p>
               <p>Jury. Were there any Lamps near you?</p>
               <p>Pulpin. No, but I saw her plainly, and am positive to her.</p>
               <p>- Lyon. I went with Mr. Lines the next Morning to see for the Prisoner at a House where she lodged in Drury-Lane. While we were there she came in with 
               <persName id="t17380906-12-person108">
                  Betty 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17380906-12-person108" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person108" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Betty had got a short Cloak, a Shirt, and a check'd Apron, which she said she had been to buy for the Prisoner. Upon this we sent for Pulpin, and he charg'd a Constable with her for robbing him. She was searched directly, and 31 s. and 6 d. were taken from her; and as she was fuddled, she was sent to the Round-house till she was sober, then she was carry'd before Mr. Poulson, and as we were coming from thence, she desired the Constable to let her have half a Crown, and said Pulpin might have the rest, for it was his Money, and she begg'd he would be favourable to her.</p>
               <p>Defence. I met Mr. Pulpin, and he enquired of me if I could tell him where 
               <persName id="t17380906-12-person109">
                  Moll 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17380906-12-person109" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person109" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             might be found, she was one that he kept Company with, and he promised to make me drink if I could find her; so I went to 2 or 3 Places, and at last he carry'd me to Lines's House, and he sells Spirituous Liquors -</p>
               <p>Lines. Mr. Pulpin never brought the Prisoner to my House in his Life as I know of. I never saw her there with him. <rs id="t17380906-12-verdict68" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-verdict68" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380906-12-punish69" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-punish69" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380906-12-punish69" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380906-12-defend102 t17380906-12-punish69"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
