<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-4">
               <interp inst="t17381206-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-4" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-4" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-4-off18-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-4-defend50 t17381206-4-off18 t17381206-4-verdict21"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-4-off18-c44" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-4-defend52 t17381206-4-off18 t17381206-4-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>4. 5. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-defend50" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Bates 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend50" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend50" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-defend52" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Gordon 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend52" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend52" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-defend52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17381206-4-off18" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-off18" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-off18" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Guinea and a Thirty six Shilling Piece of Gold, from the Person of 
                     <persName id="t17381206-4-person53">
                        John 
                        Seymonr 
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person53" type="surname" value="Seymonr"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-4-person53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-4-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17381206-4-cd19" type="crimeDate">Nov. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-4-off18 t17381206-4-cd19"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-victim55" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Seymour 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-4-victim55" type="surname" value="Seymour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-victim55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-4-off18 t17381206-4-victim55"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . On Friday the 10th of last Month, about a Quarter before Nine at Night, I was going along Cheapside, and Gordon took hold of my Arm, and ask'd me if I wanted a Whore? I walk'd on towards Bow-Lane, and she and Bates follow'd me. When I came to <placeName id="t17381206-4-crimeloc20">Bow Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-4-crimeloc20" type="placeName" value="Bow Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-4-crimeloc20" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-4-off18 t17381206-4-crimeloc20"></join>, I stopp'd about five Minutes, to hear what they had to say: We talked together, and they wanted me to go to a Tavern. While we were talking, I am sure I felt one of their Hands in my Breeches Pocket, and I believe it was Garden's Hand, because she was nearest me: Bates was not near enough me to do it. I said nothing about it then, but clapp'd my Hand to my Pocket, to know if they had been there; upon which they immediately walk'd off, and I miss'd a Guinea and a Portugal Piece, of 36 Shillings. I had the Money, I am sure, an Hour before, when I came from my Master's House in Bow-Lane, and I had been in no Company. Upon missing my Money, I follow'd 
               <persName id="t17381206-4-person56">
                  Jane 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17381206-4-person56" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person56" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into a Publick-House, within ten Yards of the Place where we had been talking, and asked her what was become of the other Woman? She told me I was mistaken; and that she had no other Woman in her Company that Night. Very well, says I, pray how long have you been here? A great while, she said; but the Landlord told me she was but just come in, and had given him a Guinea to change: I saw it, and believed 'twas mine; 'tis now in the Hands of the Landlord, and is very pale and very full-headed. I can swear it was mine, but I could hear nothing of the Portugal Piece: I had taken the Guinea but a little before, of a Servant in our House, and had disputed whether 'twas a good one. I think it was not possible for Bates to have pick'd my Pocket, because Gordon stood before me, and Bates stood on one Side of us. I never saw either of them before, but I am sure they are the Persons.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find Gordon?</p>
               <p>Seymour. Bates's Husband, by his Wife's Instructions, took her last Saturday Night; but we found nothing upon her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060005"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-person57">
                  Richard 
                  Flint 
               <interp inst="t17381206-4-person57" type="surname" value="Flint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person57" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Jane Bates came into my House that Night, and called for a Pint of Beer; then she gave me a Guinea to change: I scrupled it, because I thought 'twas not a good one. I had it in my Hand, and was looking upon it, when the young Man ( Seymour ) came in; he saw it likewise. As to the other Woman, (Gordon) I know nothing of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-person58">
                  William 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17381206-4-person58" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person58" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. The Husband of Bates li't of Gordon in the Street, last Saturday Night, and charg'd a Watchman with her. In bringing her to the Watch-House, she had like to have been rescued. She confess'd nothing, nor was any thing found upon her. Seymour, (the Prosecutor) would have discharg'd her, when he found that his Master would not come to speak for him, nor have any thing to do in the Affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-person59">
                  Tobias 
                  Isaacs 
               <interp inst="t17381206-4-person59" type="surname" value="Isaacs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person59" type="given" value="Tobias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a Jew). On a Friday Evening, about three Weeks ago, (but I can't tell what Month, nor what Day of the Month it was) I was at Bates's House, and she ask'd me to change her a Guinea; 'twas a sort of a pale Guinea; but I did not change it. I have known her 11 Years, and know no Harm of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-4-person60">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17381206-4-person60" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person60" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw her Husband give her a Guinea, and four or five Shillings, last Thursday Morning was three Weeks. She is a Woman that always carries herself sober and honest, and always paid as far as she went. Both <rs id="t17381206-4-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-4-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
