<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-34">
               <interp inst="t17390906-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-34" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-34" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-34-off157-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-defend245 t17390906-34-off157 t17390906-34-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>466. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-defend245" type="defendantName">
                     Jarib 
                     Watts 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-34-defend245" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-defend245" type="given" value="Jarib"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-defend245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17390906-34-defloc155">St. George's Hanover Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-34-defloc155" type="placeName" value="St. George's Hanover Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-34-defloc155" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-defend245 t17390906-34-defloc155"></join>, <rs id="t17390906-34-deflabel156" type="occupation">Schoolmaster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-defend245 t17390906-34-deflabel156"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17390906-34-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17390906-34-victim246" type="victimName">
                        Judith, the <rs id="t17390906-34-viclabel158" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-victim246 t17390906-34-viclabel158"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-person247 t17390906-34-viclabel158"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17390906-34-person247" type="victimName">
                              William 
                              Redman 
                           <interp inst="t17390906-34-person247" type="surname" value="Redman"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17390906-34-person247" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17390906-34-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-off157 t17390906-34-person247"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17390906-34-victim246" type="surname" value="Redman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-34-victim246" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-34-victim246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-off157 t17390906-34-victim246"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , and giving her a mortal Bruise on the Left Side of the Head, by striking, beating, casting her to the Ground, and breaking her Jaw-Bone; of which mortal Bruise, and breaking her Jaw Bone, she instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390906-34-cd159" type="crimeDate">Aug. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-off157 t17390906-34-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person248">
                  William 
                  Pemberton 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person248" type="surname" value="Pemberton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick House, the <placeName id="t17390906-34-crimeloc160">Coach and Horses in Conduit-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-34-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Coach and Horses in Conduit-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-34-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-34-off157 t17390906-34-crimeloc160"></join>. On the 20th of August, about Three o'Clock in the Afternoon, I lay down on a Bed in a Closet behind the Room where the Accident happened. About Six, some Carpenters, who were at Work in the Yard, making a Noise, I 'wak'd, and heard the Word - Bitch, in the little Room. 'Twas a small Drinking-Room on the Ground-Floor, and parted off from the Room where I lay by a Single-deal Partition, pannell'd. I imagin'd somebody was abusing my Wife, so I got up; and as I was coming through this little Room, I saw the Prisoner with his Left Arm round the Deceased's Neck, and his Right Hand somewhere on her Breast. Lord, Sir, said I, what's the Matter! His Answer was, - The Gentlewoman is in a Fit! In a Fit, said I! I am afraid 'tis something worse; how came her Mouth to be so bloody? For the Blood ran from her Mouth down her Stays and her Apron, and she was sitting in a Chair, with her Head lolling back over his Arm: I called three times for Water, and the fourth time it was brought: I sprinkled some in her Face, and endeavoured to make her drink some; but she was gone. While I was doing this, the Prisoner escaped out of the Room, and left some new Linnen behind him, and a little Child of the Deceased followed him, crying. Some small Time after this, another Child of the Deceased came to our House, and said, Lord, Sir! I hear my Mother is killed, pray let me see her. I told him his Mother was better, and asked him where his Mother used to buy Linnen? He told me - at the Corner of Carnaby Market. I took the Child and the Linnen to the Place, and the Man knew it, and said it was bought of him about Four o'Clock that Evening. The Boy then told us the Prisoner's Name was Watts, and that he used to meet his Mother at one Carter's, the Red Cross in May-Fair. We went thither, and Carter said the Prisoner had not been there for three or four Days; he believed we might find him at Kensington, where he was Usher in a School. At Kensington we enquired after him a good while to no Purpose; but at last, one who was with us having some Acquaintance with Carter's Son, (who was Coachman to Madam Jacob at Kensington) he put us upon going to the Stables where the Coachman lay. When we came there, we ask'd if Mr. Watts was not there? and, to prevent Suspicion, I shamm'd drunk, and said, I would drink no more. Carter's Son spoke to us out of a Window, and asked us what we wanted with him? We told him we wanted to speak with him: Upon which he [Carter] came down and open'd the Door: Then we got in, and upon searching the Hay-loft, I observed some Straw to stand up against the Wall; I put it aside with my Stick, and found the Prisoner behind it. We searched him, and found nothing upon him but his Penknife. His Ruffles and his Right Hand were bloody, and he had the same Shirt on when we carry'd him before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was the Door of the Room in which you was asleep lock'd, or unlock'd?</p>
               <p>Pemberton. There is a Lock to it; but whether it was lock'd or no, I can't tell. 'Twas not lock'd when I came out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Is there not a Window in the Room where this happen'd, which looks into the Yard where the Carpenters were at Work?</p>
               <p>Pemberton. Yes; and there is a Glass Door, with a Curtain before it, which looks into the Common Drinking Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I call for Water, and desire Assistance?</p>
               <p>Pemberton. Not, as I remember.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you in Liquor at that Time?</p>
               <p>Pemberton. I was as sober then, as I am now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person249">
                  Lochlan 
                  Maclaughlan 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person249" type="surname" value="Maclaughlan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person249" type="given" value="Lochlan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he was going by the Door about Six that Evening, and hearing a Woman was dying in the House, he went in, and found her siting in a Chair: Mr. Pemberton was washing the Blood from her Mouth. Her Pulse was gone: But she being warm, he open'd a Vein, and she bled about a Spoonful or two. He said there was the Mark of a Blow, or Fall, upon her Left Jaw; that she had bleed much at her Mouth, and that he saw no other Marks of Violence upon her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060016"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person250">
                  William 
                  Graves 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person250" type="surname" value="Graves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person250" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account, that he was sitting that Evening at Pemberton's Door, and the Prisoner came out of the House and asked him to direct him to Mr. Despagnol's House, the Surgeon; which he did; and the Prisoner ran down the Street, towards the House. That immediately afterward, he heard a Woman was dead in the House; upon which he went in, and found her sitting in a Chair, bleeding at the Mouth, and her Head lolling on one Side. That he thought proper to wipe the blood out of her Mouth, and finding her dead, he went to Mr. Despagnol's, to enquire if any body had been to fetch him to a Woman at this House, and was informed, that no one had been there for above an Hour past, upon which he told them, the Woman had not been dead above half an Hour. He added, That he saw the Prisoner the Day after he was taken, and was positive he was the Man that he directed to Mr. Despagnol's. That he had sat at the Door about half an Hour, before the Prisoner came out; that the Place where he sat, was about the Breadth of the Court from the Room in which the Woman died, and that the Prisoner came out at the Back-door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person251">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person251" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That the Prisoner came to him last Monday was a Fortnight, and told him, that he had appointed Mrs. Redman to meet him at The Coach and Horses about buying some Cloth; that he went to her there, and Words arising about the Liquor, and the Price for making the Shirts, she told him she would sooner go a-digging, than work for such a Scrub-dog as he. That he told her he was no more a Dog, than she was a Bitch; upon which she told him, she would split his Brains out, and snatching up an Apple, in throwing it at him, she fell down. That upon lifting her up, she bled at the Mouth, and the Landlord coming in, while he was wiping off the blood, he called for Water, and desired him three Times to get a Surgeon, which the Landlord not doing, he went to Mr. Despagnol's himself; but he not being at home, nor any Surgeon to be found, at two or three other Places where he went for one, he returned to Pemberton's Door, and hearing the Woman was dead, he was struck with such a Terror, that he could not go in, but came directly to this Witness, and gave him this Account, desiring his Advice, what to do. The Witness said, he advised him to keep out of the Way 'till the Sessions began, and then to surrender himself and take his Trial. He gave the Prisoner the Character of a very quiet, peaceable Man, and not at all given to Quarrelling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person252">
                  Thomas 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person252" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person252" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That the Prisoner came to him that Night, about Seven in the Evening, and told him much the same Story; that he advised the Prisoner to surrender, but he being unwilling to do so, because he had no Money to keep him in Goal, the Witness consented to let him stay with him, and 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person253">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person253" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person253" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was to bring him Word next Morning, whether the Woman was dead or not. This Witness confirmed the Account given by Mr. Pemberton, of the Prisoner's being taken behind the Straw in the Hayloft.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person254">
                  Richard 
                  Twist 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person254" type="surname" value="Twist"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person254" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he was a Carpenter, and had some Men at Work in Pemberton's Yard when this Accident happened. That at Six o'Clock that Evening he was drinking with two or three Friends in the publick Room, which is parted from that, in which the Prisoner and the Deceased then were, but by a slight Partition. That he heard no Noise, 'till Pemberton came to the Door and called for Water; and about six Minutes after this, he went into the Room, and found the Deceased and the Prisoner in the Condition and Situation related by the former Witnesses, and Mr. Pemberton was endeavouring to give her some Water. That she had lost all Motion, when he came into the Room, and the Prisoner told him she had fell down against a Chair, and had hurt herself; that upon his saying she was dead, the Prisoner then went for a Surgeon, and did not attempt to go before. This Witness gave an Account of her Child's coming to enquire for his Mother, by which Means they came to the Knowledge of the Prisoner, and he believed if there had been any extraordinary Noise made he should have heard it, - but he heard none.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person255">
                  Peter 
                  Maccullogh 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person255" type="surname" value="Maccullogh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person255" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Surgeon, deposed, That he viewed the Body of the deceased two Days after her Death. That it was then so corrupted, he could not perceive any Marks of Violence upon it, only that the lower Jaw-bone was broke, and upon opening the Head and Breast, he found a great Quantity of extravasated Blood in the Cavities of the Brain and Stomach, which might be occasioned (he thought) by a violent Blow, or a sudden Fall, which shook the Brain, and made the Blood Vessels start.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Examination before Sir 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person256">
                  Edward 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person256" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person256" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was produced, and (being proved) was read. It contain'd the Account the Prisoner gave to Sir Edward, of the Accident, and was agreeable to that given by the Prisoner to the former Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person257">
                  Samuel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person257" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person257" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Chairman, depos'd, That the Prisoner enquired of him in Bond-street for any Surgeon; he directed him to Mr. Ranby, but did not see whether he went to the House or not. And 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person258">
                  William 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person258" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person258" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             his Partner confirm'd his Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-34-person259">
                  James 
                  Gulliford 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person259" type="surname" value="Gulliford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person259" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Carpenter, was at Work in the Yard; and something after Six he came into the House to put up his Tools, and he heard no Noise nor Disturbance while he was in or about the House.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cox, (Wife of the Gentleman at Kensington to whom the Prisoner was Usher) Mr. Wiseman Holt, (a Clergyman) 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person260">
                  John 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person260" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person261">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person261" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390906-34-person262">
                  Edward 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17390906-34-person262" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person262" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest, good-natur'd, grave, peaceable Man. <rs id="t17390906-34-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-34-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
