<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360225-28">
               <interp inst="t17360225-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-28" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-28" type="date" value="17360225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360225-28-off169-c135" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-defend191 t17360225-28-off169 t17360225-28-verdict173"></join>
         
               <p>35. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360225-28-defend191" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17360225-28-defend191" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-defend191" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-defend191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17360225-28-defloc168">St. Botolph Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-28-defloc168" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-28-defloc168" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-defend191 t17360225-28-defloc168"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360225-28-off169" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-off169" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-off169" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               feloniously stealing out of the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360225-28-victim193" type="victimName">
                           Jacob 
                           Busaglo 
                        <interp inst="t17360225-28-victim193" type="surname" value="Busaglo"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-28-victim193" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-28-victim193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-off169 t17360225-28-victim193"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . 21 Guineas, one half Guinea, a Barbery Ducat value 8 s, 6 d. a Barbary silver Ducat, value 2 d, and a green silk Purse. value 6 d,
            </rs> the Goods and Moneys of the said Busaglo, on the <rs id="t17360225-28-cd170" type="crimeDate">17th of January</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-off169 t17360225-28-cd170"></join>.</p>
               <p>Busaglo On Saturday the 17th of February, at Night, my Wife and I were both out: I live in <placeName id="t17360225-28-crimeloc171">Church Row Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-28-crimeloc171" type="placeName" value="Church Row Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-28-crimeloc171" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-off169 t17360225-28-crimeloc171"></join>; there was no one in the House, but the Prisoner, who was my <rs id="t17360225-28-deflabel172" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-defend191 t17360225-28-deflabel172"></join>; a Nurse, and a Boy. I had not been out more than an Hour and half, before the Boy came to me, and said, Sir, pray come Home as soon as possible: Why, says I, what's the Matter? He said there was no body at Home, but the Nurse up two pair of Stairs with the Children, to take care of the House. I asked him as I went Home with him, what was become of the House-Maid? He told me, she had sent him of an Errand as soon as I was gone, and before he came back, she had pack'd up her Cloaths and was gone. I ow'd her 5 Months Wages and wonder'd at her going without her Money: I thought she would come Home again, but seeing nothing of her at 9 o'Clock, I went to see if her Cloaths were left; I found she had taken every Rag, and her Trunk empty. Then I imagin'd she must have taken something, or else she would not have left her Wages. I looked about the Kitchen, but miss'd nothing there; upon searching for the Key of my Desk, I found I had left it in the Lock when I went out; and the Money mentioned in the Indictment, and which was there when I went out, was taken away. I advertis'd her the next Day, and a Butcher, (on Tuesday Morning) in Hungerford Market, came and told me, if I would give him the 3 Guineas I had promis'd as a Reward to the Person who apprehended her, he would tell me where the Money, the Purse and the Maid were to be found. I told him I would give him the Money, and so he carryed her before Justice Frazier, and sent for the Man who had the Money, who returned me the Purse with 18 Guineas and a half, and the Barbary Coin, and I gave a 50 Pound Bond to indemnify him. I went to the Woman who gave me a Character of this Servant, and asked her how she could give me a false Account of her? She said she thought she had been honest, and to show she was so, she assisted in finding her out. She confess'd the Fact before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Justice Frazier. She made a voluntary Confession before me the 20th of January; it was read twice over to her, before she sign'd it.</p>
               <p>Read the Examination. This Examinant voluntarily confesseth, That last Saturday Night, being the 17th of this Instant January, she privately stole out of a writing Desk in the House of her Master, 
               <persName id="t17360225-28-person194">
                  Jacob 
                  Basaglo 
               <interp inst="t17360225-28-person194" type="surname" value="Basaglo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-person194" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one green Purse, in which was 18 or 19 Guineas; and farther this Examinant faith not.</p>
               <p>Another Evidence. I keep a publick House in Hungerford Market; the same Night the Money was lost, the Prisoner came to my Maid, who had not then lived with me above 10 Days, and gave her a Guinea to fetch her Things out of Pawn; she had it, she said, from her Husband, and said, my Maid must go along with her to see him. The Prisoner call d for 18 Pen' worth of Punch; while it was making they went out; but when they came back, they drank it. She staid so late at my House, that she said she was afraid to go home, and desired she might lye with my Maid. I let her lye there that Night, and in the Morning, before my Wife or I were up, they came down stairs. and knocked at my Door; the Prisoner was in a Hurry, and said to my Maid. I thought you had lived in an honest House, and not in a House, where I must lose my Money. I told them, I knew nothing of the Money: They went down Stairs 2 Hours before me, and made a Noise below, and then went away. In the mean time a Butcher, who is a Tenant at the Door, had been out late with his Brother, and they came in, and desired I would let them lye down, for they did not care to go home; I told them, they might lye down on the Maid's Bed if they would; 'twas only a small Table-bed, but they made a shift to pig in any how, and lay 'till 10 o'Clock When they were gone, my Wife, (not expecting her Maid again) turn'd up the Bed, and there she saw the Purse; I call'd in 2 Neighbours to be present; they open'd it, and found 18 Guineas and a half, and a Shilling. and a Ducat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. My Master gave me the Money; when I made my Confession before Justice Frazier, I was in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173602250015"></xptr>Justice Frazier. She was perfectly sober when she made it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Master gave me the Money to lye with me. He was very kind, but I did not care to stay with him. <rs id="t17360225-28-verdict173" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-verdict173" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17360225-28-punish174" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-28-punish174" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-28-defend191 t17360225-28-punish174"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
