<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-39">
               <interp inst="t17390906-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-39" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-39" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-39-off178-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-39-defend286 t17390906-39-off178 t17390906-39-verdict179"></join>
         
               <p>471. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-39-defend286" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Cox 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-39-defend286" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-defend286" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390906-39-off178" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-off178" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-off178" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-39-victim288" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-39-victim288" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-39-victim288" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-39-victim288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-39-off178 t17390906-39-victim288"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17390906-39-person289">
                        George 
                        Thorn 
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-person289" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-39-person289" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-39-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , kicking him down on a boarded Floor, and giving him, with both his Hands and Feet, several mortal Bruises on the Head, Breast, Belly, Back, Sides and Groin, of which he languished from the 20th to the 23d of August, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time charged, by vertue of the Coroner's Inquest, for feloniously slaying the said Price.</p>
               <p>It appear'd from the Evidence, that Thorn kept a Chandler's Shop, and the Deceased meeting with the Prisoner there, the Deceased call'd the Prisoner Black-guard Rogue and Rascal, and told him he was a Bailiff's Follower, and they were worse than Dogs; that the Prisoner call'd him Blockhead, and bid him be quiet, but the Deceased (being a little in Liquor) went up to him, threw his Hat in the Prisoner's Face, and tore his Coat; upon which the Prisoner, as he sat upon a little Table, gave the Deceased a little Kick on the Backside, and bid him be gone; but he (the Deceased) turn'd, and gave the Prisoner a Blow in the Face, and then they laid hold of each other, and fell to the Ground together. The Prisoner got up, and the Deceased told him, - he would do for him. The Witnesses gave no farther Account of Blows, or Kicks, only that the Prisoner complain'd of the Deceased's having pull'd him twice by the Nose, and the Deceased told him it was no more than he deserv'd.</p>
               <p>Other Witness deposed, That the Deceased being in Extremity in Thorn's House after the Fray, they would have had him blooded, but Mrs. Thorn declared, she'd have none of his nasty Blood there; upon which he was carried Home, and declared to his Death, that the Prisoner had murdered him, and that when he lay upon the Ground, Mr. Thorn and one Meredith (a lame Man) and the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060019"></xptr> Prisoner, each of them gave him a Kick. Mr. Wood (A Surgeon) who attended him 'till he died, gave the same Account of the Deceased's Declarations: And having opened his Body after his Death, he found the Guts swelled, a Quart (or more) of Water and Blood in the Cavity of the Belly, an Ounce of Blood in the Cavity of the Stomach, and his Bladder burst at the Bottom, but no outward Marks of Violence.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17390906-39-verdict179" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-verdict179" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-39-verdict179" type="verdictSubcategory" value="selfDefence"></interp>
               Acquitted the Prisoner of the Murder, and found he killed the Deceased in his own Defence
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
