<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-24">
               <interp inst="t17361013-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-24" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-24" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-24-off114-c146" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-24-defend202 t17361013-24-off114 t17361013-24-verdict116"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-24-defend202" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lyon 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-24-defend202" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-defend202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-defend202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17361013-24-off114" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-off114" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-off114" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               whereas 
                     <persName id="t17361013-24-person203">
                        Edward 
                        Bonner 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person203" type="surname" value="Bonner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-24-person203" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-24-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , was convicted of a Robbery on the Highway by him committed <rs id="t17361013-24-cd115" type="crimeDate">July 23</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-24-off114 t17361013-24-cd115"></join>, he the said Lyon did falsely and maliciously depose and swear, that the said Bonner was at the Greyhound Inn in Smithfield from eleven to three of the same Day; whereas in Truth and in Fact, the said Bonner was not there, not at any Place commonly so call'd from eleven to three on that Day
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the King having opened the Charge, and the Record of Bonner's Conviction being read, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hasswell. The 23d of July last, I was going in a Chariot to Southgate, and a little on this side Tottenham, the Coachman turned down the Green Lane. In this Lane 2 Men came up, one on one side, and the other on the other side of the Chariot and robbed me, between 1 and 2 o'Clock. Bonner was convicted here for this Robbery last Sessions. I did not swear positively to the Man: it was proved upon him by other Evidence. 'n behalf of Bonner there appeared at the Trial Abraham and 
               <persName id="t17361013-24-person204">
                  Susannah 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person204" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person204" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Story, who is since dead in Newgate, and 
               <persName id="t17361013-24-person205">
                  John 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person205" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Prisoner at the Bar. He is the Man who swore on that Trial that he met Bonner the 23d of July in Smithfield; that he went with him to the Grey hound Inn, that they were together from eleven to three in the Afternoon; that he wrote a Receipt for Money paid by Wells to one Foiler a Grazier in Essex</p>
               <p>Lyon. I only desire you to take notice he does not swear to Bonner.</p>
               <p>The Constable. Bonner was tried here last Sessions, and he produced the Prisoner Lyon, who was sworn in Court, he deposed that he was with Bonner from 11 to 3, and wrote a Receipt for Money which Wells paid to one Foiler, and was never out of his Company all that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-24-person206">
                  Philip 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person206" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person206" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Master was travelling to Southgate, the 2 d. of July; I turn'd out of the Road on this side the High-Cross. into the Green Lane and saw 2 Men hollow to one another. I turn'd back and saw Bonner and Cocky Wager following the Chariot. I saw them both very plain. before they mask'd themselves: I did not expect a Robbery, 'till I saw one of them mask himself; and I am sure the Man who was try'd here last Sessions, was one of them that robb'd my Master between 1 and 2 o'Clock. The Prisoner Lyon swore on that Trial, that he was in Bonner's Company from 11 to 3 the 23d. of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130014"></xptr> July, at the Greyhound Inn, and that he wrote a Receipt for Money then paid.</p>
               <p>Lyon. Ask the Coachman what he said, when Bonner was carry'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17361013-24-person207">
                  Richard 
                  Brocas 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person207" type="surname" value="Brocas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person207" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Wilson. I said I would inform my self a little more, before I would swear to him, I had a Mind to inform my self a little better, and on that Information I was sure he was the same Person.</p>
               <p>Lyon. He only swore to his Speech, before Sir 
               <persName id="t17361013-24-person208">
                  Richard 
                  Brocas 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person208" type="surname" value="Brocas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person208" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and had he not had an ill Character of Bonner, he would not have swore against him.</p>
               <p>Council. Now we will shew the Assignment of the Perjury; and that he was not at the Greyhound Inn, that Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-24-person209">
                  John 
                  Broughton 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person209" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Greyhound Inn. I did not know Bonner, nor did I see him there that Day. The Prisoner I don't remember I ever saw in my Life 'till last Sessions. I did not go into the several Rooms, for I was at the Book, taking Money for the Grazier's all Day. I go out at Dinner sometimes, but I did not see any of them.</p>
               <p>Council. Is there not a Register kept of the Cows, &amp;c. that are sold in your Market?</p>
               <p>Broughton. Yes, I set them down, and there was no such Beast paid for that Day, nor was Bonner any Customer of mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-24-person210">
                  Theophilus 
                  Joiner 
               <interp inst="t17361013-24-person210" type="surname" value="Joiner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person210" type="given" value="Theophilus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Mr Bonner, and I was all Day July the 23d at the Greyhound Inn, but I cannot recollect that he was there at all. I was at my Books all that Day; for I am concerned for several Persons who sell Goods in the Field, and I take their Money. I was in the Front of the House, on the right Hand, going in at the Door. I never saw the Defendant Lyon in my Life. 'Tis a large Inn, but most of the Rooms were taken up: Bonner might be there, but I did not see him there all that Day.</p>
               <p>Council. We prove by Wilson that he was the Man who robb'd Mr. Hasswell, and we say Foiler is a fictitious Name; if what we say is not true, it lies on him to produce this Foiler. We can go no farther than Negative Proof, if he can produce a Person to make out the Affirmative, we must submit. <rs id="t17361013-24-verdict116" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-verdict116" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-24-punish117" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-punish117" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-punish117" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-24-defend202 t17361013-24-punish117"></join>
               
                     <note>[Pillory. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-24-punish118" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-punish118" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-24-defend202 t17361013-24-punish118"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-24-punish119" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-punish119" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-24-punish119" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-24-defend202 t17361013-24-punish119"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
