<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-28">
               <interp inst="t17341204-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-28" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-28" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-28-off149-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-defend209 t17341204-28-off149 t17341204-28-verdict154"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-28-off149-c2" targOrder="Y" targets="NODEFENDR t17341204-28-off149 t17341204-28-verdict154"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-28-off151-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-defend214 t17341204-28-off151 t17341204-28-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>30. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-defend209" type="defendantName">
                     Martha 
                     Holcomb , alias <rs id="t17341204-28-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-defend209 t17341204-28-alias-4"></join>Nichols</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend209" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend209" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               <persName id="t17341204-28-defend210" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend210" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17341204-28-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Snuff-Box value 20 s. and 9 Guineas
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-victim212" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     King 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-28-victim212" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-victim212" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-victim212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17341204-28-cd150" type="crimeDate">November 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-off149 t17341204-28-cd150"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-off151 t17341204-28-cd150"></join>. And</p>
               <p>28. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-defend214" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Holcomb 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend214" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend214" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-defend214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-28-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the said Snuff-Box, knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person215">
                  Charles 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person215" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person215" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Von Night ven it vas too late to go home, I go with Mrs. Olumb, to de Tree Tun Tavern in Princes-street. - No, she no go vid me dare, but I go vid mine self, and bid de Drawer to fesh me some body dat will help me to a Loshing, and he bring Mrs. Olcomb, and she tell a me dat she will help me to von vary good Loshing at Mrs. M - in de same Street - dat Mrs. M - is de oder Presonar - Vell, den we drink some Vine, and den she call for de Coash and we go togader to Mrs. M - in tree Minute, and Mrs. Olcomb make a me give de Coashman Tree Shillings. Velden ve go up deStair, and den ve all drink togader; and I pay five or six<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040014"></xptr> Shilling for mine Loshing and de Reckoning, and give Mrs. Olcomb Ten Shilling for her Troubel, and den I go to Bed vid mine self and put mine Breeshes in de Shair and mine Snuff-Box, and 9 Guineas was den in mine Pockate, and de Lequor was got in mine Head, and I fall asleep till 5 o' de Clock in de Morning. Vell, den Mrs. Olcomb come into de Room (vor de Door was open all de Night) and she make a great Noise and vake me, and say, Pray you Fellow get up! - Vat you do here in mine Bed? So, I get up and take mine Breeshes, and when I feel in mine Pockate, I no cou'd find my Snuff-Box and Money, it was all gone, and den Mrs. M - come down into de Room; den I dress mine self and go avay but say noting of vat I lose for fear I shall be knock'd on dehead, till de next Night, and den I go to de Shustice and get de Varrant for de Conestauble and take up de two Womans. Mrs. Olcomb confess before de Shustice dat she take 2 Guinea and a half out of mine Pockate, and dat I give her de rest. And Mrs. M - was bail'd. Vell den Sharles Olcomb come to me and say dat if I no prosecute de Vomans, he will give me de Snuff Box, and two Guinea in Gold, and his Note for tree Guinea more; but I tell him I no vill do dat; and so I take him before de Shustice, and de Shustice commit him to de Bridevell.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rawlins. On the 9th of November, 
               <persName id="t17341204-28-person216">
                  Charles 
                  Holcomb 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person216" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person216" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pawn'd this Snuff-Box to me for 10 s. and it was fetch'd away again on the 18th. He is a <rs id="t17341204-28-deflabel152" type="occupation">Chairman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-28-defend214 t17341204-28-deflabel152"></join>, and plyed in the Neighbourhood, Justice Mitford sent for me, to let me know it was stolen.</p>
               <p> 
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person217">
                  Henry 
                  Pike 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person217" type="surname" value="Pike"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person217" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Charles Holcomb own'd in my hearing, that he had the Box, and said, he would deliver it to the Prosecutor, if the Prosecutor, would give the Woman a release. Upon this the Prosecutor got a Warrant, and took him up.</p>
               <p>The Defeuce of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person218">
                  Martha 
                  Holcomb 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person218" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person218" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to my Husband - I call him my Husband, but he's only my Friend - who was at an Ale-house in Princes-street when the Drawer at the Three Tuns met me, and said, an old Acquaintance of mine wanted to speak with me. So I went to the Tavern where I found the Prosecutor, and very drunk he was, and would needs go home with me to my Lodging. So after we had drunk together, a Coach was called, we drove to Catherine-street where we stopt, and then drove to Mrs. M - We went up Stairs, and here I and Mrs. M - drank 3 three Shilling Bowls of Punch and a Bottle of Wine: After which, he made me a present of half a Guinea, and eight Shillings in Silver, and offered me half a Guinea more to lie with him; but I told him I was not very well; and so he gave Mrs. M - the half Guinea to pay my Surgeon; and promised me that when I was cured, he would buy me a new Gown, and keep me. And as for the Snuff-Box he made me a Present of it, and bid me keep it for his sake.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Go ye nasty lying Toad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person219">
                  Martha 
                  Holcomb 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person219" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person219" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to what he says about leaving his Breeches in the Chair, and my frightning him out of Bed in the Morning, there is nothing in it, for he did not go to Bed at all: Indeed he was very angry at it, because I would not oblige him; but when I had told him the reason of it, the Heat of his Passion was soon over, and a vast deal of Civility passed on both sides, and he went away in a very good Humour.</p>
               <p>C - M - The Prosecutor and Mrs. Holcomb came in a Coach to my Door about 2 o'Clock in the Morning: I shew'd 'em up two Pair of Stairs, and they had a Bowl - it was but one Bowl - of Arrack Punch, a Bottle of Wine, and three Jellies. He would have gone to Bed with her, but she said she was out of Order. And indeed I knew she was very ill - so ill, that she could not well go out about her Business. And I had engaged my self for a Guinea to a Doctor. And so she came down and left the Gentleman, and he would not go to Bed by himself. I desired her not to leave him there alone; upon which, she went up again and brought him down. I told him he might have a Bed at the Bear in Bow street. He Swore and Curst, and called me B - but said nothing of any Loss; and so he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040015"></xptr> went away - I had No-body than up in my House but one Gentlewoman, for my Maid, and my Husband were gone to Bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person220">
                  Joseph 
                  Staton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person220" type="surname" value="Staton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person220" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Mrs. Holcomb offer to give two Guineas, and her Note for four, and to return his Box, rather than go to Jail. But as for Mrs. M - I have known her these four Years; she bears a very honest Character; she <rs id="t17341204-28-deflabel153" type="occupation">keeps a Coffee-house</rs>, and a civil House it is - as to Robberies.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cleaver. I keep a Tavern and serve her with Wine; she is a Woman of a good Character, and Civil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person221">
                  Robert 
                  Fish 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person221" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person221" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Drawer at the Three Tuns. The Prosecutor came in alone; he sent our Porter for a Woman. The Porter fetch'd Mrs. Holcomb. They had two Pints of Wine; he order'd a Coach; she called for another Pint, and when that was out they went away together in the Coach. They ordered the Coachman to drive to Cheapside. The Prosecutor being drunk, my Master bid the Porter see which way they went, and he follow'd them till they were in Russel-street, which is beyond Mrs. M - but how much further they went I don't know.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cope. I have known Mrs. M - five or six Years; she is a very honest principle Woman, and would not suffer any wrong to be done in her House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person222">
                  Edmond 
                  Holcomb 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person222" type="surname" value="Holcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person222" type="given" value="Edmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner Charles is my Brother, he is a Chairman, and works hard for his Bread - I know his Wife - but the Prisoner Martha is not his Wife, tho' she may call him Husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-28-person223">
                  Richard 
                  Avison 
               <interp inst="t17341204-28-person223" type="surname" value="Avison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person223" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 15 Years; he lodged a long time in St. Alban's Street, near where I live, and always had a good honest Character.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-28-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-28-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> all the Prisoners.</p>
            </div1>
