<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350702-28">
               <interp inst="t17350702-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-28" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350702-28" type="date" value="17350702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350702-28-off146-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-28-defend219 t17350702-28-off146 t17350702-28-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>35. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-defend219" type="defendantName">
                     Joshua 
                     Dean 
                  <interp inst="t17350702-28-defend219" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-defend219" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-defend219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17350702-28-deflabel145" type="occupation">Callico Printer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-28-defend219 t17350702-28-deflabel145"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17350702-28-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a Stamp, to resemble a certain Stamp, provided to stamp Vellum, Parchment, and Paper, chargeable by certain Statutes with the Duties of six Pence, six Pence, and six Pence
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350702-28-cd147" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-28-off146 t17350702-28-cd147"></join> in the Parish of <placeName id="t17350702-28-crimeloc148">St. Mary le Bow</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350702-28-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le Bow"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350702-28-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350702-28-off146 t17350702-28-crimeloc148"></join>, in London.</p>
               <p>Elihu Bridoak. I have known the Prisoner since 1733 - About the twenty sixth of July, 1734. I by his Direction, purchased two Treble six Penny Stamps, from one of which he made a Counterfeit - He had told me before that he could make a Counterfeit so exact as not to be known from the true Stamp; and if I would assist him I should have half the Profit. He then had a House in New street, Fetter-lane, which I hired by his Orders, with an intent only to Coin Money there - He melted a Composition of Metal in a Crucible, and so cast a counterfeit Stamp; after which he repaired it fit for use, and then stampt near two Ream and a half of Paper. He made three Impressions on some Sheets, and but two on others - In March last, I went again by his Orders for two other Stamps, and these I carried to a Lodging in Paul's Alley in Aldersgate-street, and there he cast another Stamp from one of these new ones and stampt several Papers.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173507020012"></xptr>Council. The Stamps have usually some particular Letter on them - What Letters had those the Prisoner made?</p>
               <p>Bridoak. The first was Y, and the second AA. But he made others. There was one twelve Penny Stamp among them. He had a House at Lambeth-marsh when we had the Lodgings in Paul's Alley, and there was another House in St.George's Fields, which was partly his, and partly Mr. Watts's - When the Prisoner was in the New Goal in Southwark, he bid me go to his House at Lambeth-marsh, and fetch the Key of the House in St.George's Fields, and carry away all his Implements that they might not be produced. But I gave Information to the Stamp Office. Mr Lunnies, the Messenger, came with me to this House in St. George's Fields, where we found two Presses one for Coining, and one for Stamping, and several Dies for half Pence and Guineas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person220">
                  Thomas 
                  Lunnies 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person220" type="surname" value="Lunnies"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person220" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We found two Presses, one was fixt to a Block. On the Block we found two Dies for half Pence, a Head and a Britannia, and two more were in the Window. This Stamp and three more were found in a Tin Box, two for two Shillings and three Pence, one for twelve Pence, and one for six Pence, and several more were found under the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Bridoak. I was present when the Prisoner made this Stamp AA, and saw him stamp Paper with it. I saw him stamp this Paper in my Hand with the Letter Y. He made other Stamps with T and R.</p>
               <p>Thomas Hodson. I took these eight Stamps from between the Wall and the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Bridoak. Here are four six Penny Stamps, and I saw him make three of these; Y, AA, and O, and one Penny Stamp.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rollos. I have engraved for the Stamp Office about thirty three Years. The Stamps now produced are Couterfeit; ours in the Office are all of Steel, but these I believe are a composition of - and - I am sure this Paper was not stampt in the Office; and I verily believe it was done with this counterfeit Stamp Y.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lunnies. This other Press is for stamping; we found it up two pair of Stairs in the same House, it was not fixt to any thing, nor put together as that on the Block is - And this is the Fly of the Stamp Engine; we found it at their Lodging in Paul's Alley.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person221">
                  John 
                  Boddington 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person221" type="surname" value="Boddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Smith. This Screw and Box which belongs to this Press I made by Bridoak's Order. After I had done it, he brought the Prisoner to me; and the Prisoner gave me orders to make the Block that the Iron is fixt on.</p>
               <p>Council. What name did he call it by?</p>
               <p>Boddington. He gave it no name, but he chalked out the Parts of it for my direction, and said it was to make Buckles and Buttons - It was found up two pair of Stairs in the House in St. George's Fields.</p>
               <p>Council. We mention this, only to shew that that House where the Stamps were found, was made use of to hold the Prisoner's Goods.</p>
               <p>Bridoak. Here's the Instrument we used to Label the Parchment with, and these are the Prisoners Punches.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rollos. These Puncheons are to repair the Stamps after they are cast - This is to sink the Leaves of the Roses - These are Letters - This represents the Seed in the Rose of the six Penny Stamp - This by way of ornament round the Hoop of the Crown - This is for the end of a Leaf of the Rose within the Garrer - This, a Flower de Luce in the Imperial Crown - This the end of the inner Leaf of the Roses - And here is another Ornament for the Hoop of the Crown.</p>
               <p>Prisoner to Boddington. You say that I gave you Orders to make that Engine; did I not tell you that it was not for my self?</p>
               <p>J. Boddington. He said it was to go to Lancashire to make Buckles and Buttons.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not an old Man come to examine it?</p>
               <p>J. Boddington. Yes, one Watts.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Here is Mr. Boddington's Brother - Did you make any part of that Screw Press on the Block for Bridoak?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person222">
                  George 
                  Boddington 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person222" type="surname" value="Boddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person222" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know that I made any of this for him, for this is Three Threads, but I made part of one of Two Threads for him.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you often make such things?</p>
               <p>G Boddington. Yes, I have made several.</p>
               <p>Council. For what use?</p>
               <p>G. Boddington. They may put it to what use they please, but they commonly say it is for Buckles and Buttons -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Being told that Bridoak belong'd to the Law, I employed him to get a little Money that was due to me. Thus our Acquantance begun. After this he told me he was going to set up one Watts to make Buckles and Buttons at Warrington in Lancashire, but did not care to trust Watts by himself; and therefore if I would get a Press made, and assist in the management of this Affair, he would make it worth my while. So I employed Bridoak to dispose of my House, and I sent all the things into the Country - And when I was taken, I told Mr. Lunnies what<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173507020013"></xptr> Ship I sent my Goods in for Liverpool, that he might examine into the Truth of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lunnies. Yes you did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. 'Tis natural for a guilty Man when he is discovered, to throw the blame on another. This is what Bridoak has done by me - I shall prove that the Presses belonged to him - Call 
               <persName id="t17350702-28-person223">
                  John 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person223" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17350702-28-person224">
                  George 
                  Wilden 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person224" type="surname" value="Wilden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person224" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>John Roach. Bridoak hired me and Wilden to carry a thing in a Sack - I don't know what it was, but it was very heavy - from a Stationer's in Butcherhall Lane - and these two square Stones from the corner of New-Street, Fetter-lane, to White Fryer's Stairs, where we put them into a Boat, and carryed them over to the Old Barge House, but I do not know what became of them afterwards.</p>
               <p>Wilden deposed to the same effect.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. These were all found in the House that belongs to Watts - Let them prove that it belong'd to me - Call Mrs. Hollings.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hollings. I keep the Hat and Feather on the Broad Wall at Lambeth. The Prisoner and Bridoak and Watts were several times at my House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not Bridoak make a Bargain with one Sharp for my House on the Broad Wall?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hollings. But Wattt came at last, and said, that he and not Sharp was to have your House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is to shew that I employed Bridoak to dispose of my House when I was going into the Country - As for the House where the things were found, I say it belonged to Watts - Let them call the Landlord to prove whether it was Watts's House or mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person225">
                  John 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person225" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was sitting at Mr. Wigly's House at Lambeth marsh (where the Prisoner lived ) I saw Bridoak going by, I called him and told him that in my opinion he would be taken up as well as the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And thereupon to save himself he surrendered and informed against me - Who is there to prove any thing against me but he - And he owns himse'f to be an Accomplice - Had I been concerned I should have got Money as well as he - But I was reduced to such streights, that I was forced to sell my Wig in the last Law-suit he managed for me.</p>
               <p>Council. Prove the Law-suit.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. So I will - Call Giles Bradshaw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person226">
                  Giles 
                  Bradshaw 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person226" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person226" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Bridoak brought an Officer and arrested me at the Prisoner's Suit - but I believe Bridoak was not an Attorney.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not he act as a Solliciter?</p>
               <p>G Bradshaw. I don't know what a Solliciter is - But he received the Money of me and gave me a Receipt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person227">
                  John 
                  Wigly 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person227" type="surname" value="Wigly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the Prisoner's Landlord in Lambeth Parish. At first he rented a House of me at five Pound a Year - Then he quitted it and let it Bridoak, and took a place that goes off the Broad Wall - Its a mighty promiscuous place, its a Hovel, and was a Hog's Sty. Every Door is a Window and every Win- dow is a Door, and there is no looking into the Windows. There is a Garden before it, and a Ditch behind; a mighty promiscuous place indeed. The Prisoner built it himself (for he is a very good Workman, with all these Contrivances - This is not the House in St. George's Fields</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Contrivances, Doors, and Windows? What is there particular in the House?</p>
               <p>J. Wigly. There was a Forge.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rollos. A Furnace, and Crucibles, and Sand.</p>
               <p>J. Wigly. He cut Callico-prints, and made Buckles - I have often heard him pound. pound, pound-something or other; and Bridoak often went backwards and forwards to him with something in a Flag Basket. He was to have had a Lease of this promiscuous; place, but I not liking the Company that came after him (a Woman they called Flora, Bridoak, Watt, and Boulter) I refused. Upon which the Prisoner said he did not want the Lease for himself, but for old Watts - But Bridoak and Boulter threatned to sue me in Chancery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Call 
               <persName id="t17350702-28-person228">
                  Benjamin 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person228" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person228" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - Mr. Dell, is there any thing uncommon in that House?</p>
               <p>B. Dell. I never saw any thing suspicious - Tis a slight House, has two or three little Rooms on the Ground Floor, and the upper part is a Lost - There is a Garden with a Gate before it, and a Field with a Ditch behind it - I have seen Buckles, and such things, and he cut Prints. I have been at his House Day after Day; and I have often seen him at work upon his Prints, but never knew him do any base Action.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hains. I lived next Door to him. He was a civil Neighbour,and bore a very good Character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Could not you at any time come out of your Ground into mine?</p>
               <p>Hains. Yes; There is a Gap on purpose; and the Door is only fastened by a single Bolt, and there is room for a Man to put his Hand in and push t back.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173507020014"></xptr>Prisoner to Mr. Lunnies. Who is the Landlord of the House in St. George's Fields.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lunnies I think his Name is Igby, by St. George's Church.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ask him who was the Tenant?</p>
               <p>Mr. Lunnies Old Watts was the Tenant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Very well; and I would ask Mr. Bridoak, who took the House in New-street, and the Lodgings in Pauls Alley?</p>
               <p>Bridoak. I did.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Petty. Bridoak hired a Room of me in Paul's Alley, a Month before Lady-Day. I understood it was only for himself; but afterwards the Prisoner came to lodge with him, and they cohabited together three or four Months.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lodged there only after I had sent my Goods into Lancshire - Call Mr. Herbert, who was Watts's Landlord - Did not Bridoak come to your House to bid Watts keep out of the way?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person229">
                  Edward 
                  Herbert 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person229" type="surname" value="Herbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person229" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Bridoak came to where I live (at Mr. Williams, a Baker in David-street) to ask if Watts lodged there. I said, Yes. What is your Business. Nothing, says he, but to leave a Direction. So he took this Paper out of his Pocket and left it for Watts - This was about three Weeks ago, and three Days after the Prisoner was taken up.</p>
               <p>Then the Note was read in these Words.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dean does not want to see you till he returns out of the Country.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Don't you apprehend that by my being in the Country he meant my being in Prison?</p>
               <p>E. Herbert. I thought afterwards when I heard the Story, that his Design was to keep Watts out of the way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350702-28-person230">
                  Florance 
                  Cameron 
               <interp inst="t17350702-28-person230" type="surname" value="Cameron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person230" type="given" value="Florance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked Bridoak what he thought would come of this Affair of the Prisoners; he said he could not tell, till the Trial was over. Do you know where old Watts is? says I. No, says he, but sure he is got out of the way by now for I have left a Note for him - And if Dean had done as I bid him, he need not have been in Confinement, and might have had Money in his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Bridoak brought me some Patterns to cut Wooden-prints for Paper; but there being some of them like Post Marks, and some with Crowns upon them, I refused to meddle with them. However there being one for Daffy's Elixir I begun upon that, but shuffled off the finishing of it as long as I could, in hopes that by the time it was done he would make an end of the Law-suit I had employed him in that I might get a little Money that was due to me, and which was all I wanted for, before I went into the Country.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17350702-28-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350702-28-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
