<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-33">
               <interp inst="t17380222-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-33" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-33" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-33-off148-c163" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-33-defend237 t17380222-33-off148 t17380222-33-verdict151"></join>
         
               <p>37. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-33-defend237" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Thomas 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-33-defend237" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-defend237" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-defend237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-33-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-33-victim239" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Felton 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-33-victim239" type="surname" value="Felton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-33-victim239" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-33-victim239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-33-off148 t17380222-33-victim239"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling House of the said Mary, putting him in Fear and Danger of his Life, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 5 l. a Silk Handkerchief, value 12 d. an Iron Tobacco Box, value 12 d. a Silk Purse, value 12 d. ten Guineas and a half, sixteen Shillings in in Silver
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-33-cd149" type="crimeDate">Feb, 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-33-off148 t17380222-33-cd149"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Felton. I was going Home the 21st of this Instant, about eleven o'Clock at Night, and this Woman met me, and got me into her House in <placeName id="t17380222-33-crimeloc150">Bluegate Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-33-crimeloc150" type="placeName" value="Bluegate Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-33-crimeloc150" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-33-off148 t17380222-33-crimeloc150"></join>, - 'twas her own House, and she took me in, - in the Way of Design to murder me, - she forc'd me into her House, and robb'd me; I was a little in Liquor She took me into the House, - she forc'd me, - she l'it of me in the Way, - we have Proof enough of the Affair - here's the Constable. I met her in Ratcliff-Highway, and she did what you may say - pick'd me up; I was found in a House, - but here's the Constable, - he'll give an Account of it I believe. - Why  I do tell you, - but here's the Constable; he can tell you more; - I can't give no (any) farther Account. I was robb'd, - why, I don't know how I came into her House, but by her Instructions, and she carry'd me into the upper Part of it, - the uppermost Room in the House, - yes, - the Garret, - I suppose it may be so call'd - These was no Body else but the Prisoner, and she forc'd me up, and made me stay, - about 2 Hours, - the Constable came; - here's the Constable, - he fetch'd me out. He heard a Gentleman was robb'd - he had an Information. I employ'd my Time while I was in her House, - said I fell asleep. I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220013"></xptr> given you all the Account I can, - but here's the Constable. I lost 10 Guineas and a half, a Silver Watch, a green Silk Purse, and a Tobacco-box; when I was up in the Garret, - she put me in Fear, and said, if I did not deliver the aforesaid Things she would take - and dispatch me - she would cut my Throat. There was no Body there but she and I, but she had got a Knife, and threat'ned me if I made any Noise she would cut my Throat from Ear to Ear. So she took the Money out of my Breeches Pocket, and upon this she got my Money. The Constable was taking a Walk in Bluegate Fields, and heard a Gentleman was robb'd, - so for that Reason he found me. I did cry out, - I begg'd of her to save my Life - she was going to cut my Throat, I can't say but I did go to sleep, but 'twas a very little Time. It was a Terror upon me, and I was really frighted for Fear. I could not tell which Way to get out of the House indeed, I was afraid of coming down for Fear of losing my Life upon the Stairs; so I went to sleep, - a-bed - yes, I was a-bed, but I was alone, and I believe I slept a little. The Constable came and raised me, - only examine the Constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-33-person240">
                  Michael 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17380222-33-person240" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person240" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Headborough. Last Tuesday Night I went out with Watchmen to visit Bluegate Fields, - 'tis a most notorious Place. In the Way thither I met a Woman, who told me, a Man well dressed was fallen into Mall Thomas's Hands, and she believ'd he was stripp'd. I ask'd her where he was? She directed me to the House, and I found the Door open, between 12 and one o'Clock. In the lower Apartment I found no Body, but above Stairs in a Corner of the Room, there were Cloaths spread, and the Gentleman was lying upon them. I found him fast asleep, but I 'waked him, and after he had look'd about him a little, he got up and said, he was robb'd of his Watch and his Money. I wonder'd at his Cloaths being left, and that she had not taken them away; but they were there, and he drest himself, but he could not tell how he came there. When we came into the Street, People told us that Moll Thomas was at Ray's, at the Blue Gate. I went thither and knock'd at the Door, but they would not open the Door. At last one Coleman a Bailiff of Whitechappel Court, heard my Voice, and he let me in. I told the People of the House, I wanted Beer for my Watchmen; no, no, says Coleman, you shan't drink Beer, we have got Wine enough above Stairs. So I went up Stairs, and there I saw the Prisoner sitting upon a Bed in the Room, in a fine ruffled Smock. I told her she was my Prisoner, and asked her for the Gentleman's Watch; she told me 'twas pawn'd for a Guinea, and asked me if I had brought the Money to redeem it? I sent for the Gentleman up Stairs, and he charg'd me with the Prisoner. I desir'd him to let me know how he lost his Money and Watch, but he was so surpriz'd when I first 'wak'd him, that he could hardly speak, but when we were at the Watch-house, he explain'd himself. When I asked her for the Watch, at the Blue-Gate, another Woman gave it to her, and she put it into her Bosom; but on my threa'ning her she deliver'd it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-33-person241">
                  Bartholing 
                  Brinkley 
               <interp inst="t17380222-33-person241" type="surname" value="Brinkley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person241" type="given" value="Bartholing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was that Night at a Place where they sell Gin; and I heard a Gentleman was lost in Moll Thomas's House; Mr. Bell knock'd at the Door, and I open'd the Wicket, thinking Informers were at the Door. I told them they had more need go to Thomas's House, and take Care of a Man that had been robb'd there, than come to trouble us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-33-person242">
                  William 
                  Tumber 
               <interp inst="t17380222-33-person242" type="surname" value="Tumber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Watchman confirm'd Mr. Bell's Evidence, and was very particular in his Description of the House, and the Condition in which the Prosecutor was found. He deposed farther, that in the Account which the Prosecutor gave of the Robbery, he made use of the Word They, - They had threat'ned him, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had been out that Night, and when I came Home, I found the Prosecutor with two Women. He bid me fetch some Beer, and I went for 5 or 6 Pots I believe. Then he asked me to let him lie there all Night; I told him he might if he pleased, but he could not give me less than 6 d. for a good Bed. Why then, which of these Girls must I lie with, said he, I told him, Sir, if I lie with any Man besides my Husband, it shall be with you. He said he had no Money, so he left his Watch with me, I took it, and went to Mr. Ray's at the Blue-Gate, where they found me. I told Mr. Ray, a Gentleman had desir'd to lie at my House that Night, so I was come to trouble them for a Lodging.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Tho' I might make use of the Word. They when I gave an Account of the Robbery, yet there was no Body with me but she, - and she robb'd me. <rs id="t17380222-33-verdict151" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-33-verdict151" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
