<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390221-19">
               <interp inst="t17390221-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-19" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390221"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-19" type="date" value="17390221"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390221-19-off101-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-19-defend162 t17390221-19-off101 t17390221-19-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>166. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-defend162" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Adamson 
                  <interp inst="t17390221-19-defend162" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-defend162" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-defend162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17390221-19-defloc100">St. Mary Whitechappel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-19-defloc100" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Whitechappel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-19-defloc100" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-19-defend162 t17390221-19-defloc100"></join> was indicted, <rs id="t17390221-19-off101" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-off101" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-off101" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               for that at the Sessions of Goal-delivery of Newgate, held at Justice-hall in the Old Baily, on Wednesday the 17th of January last, &amp;c. 
                     <persName id="t17390221-19-person163">
                        William 
                        Rogers 
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person163" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-19-person163" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-19-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   was according to due Form of Law indicted for that he, on the 15th of November, in the Parish of Allhallows Barkin, 13 lb. of Tobacco, val. 7 s. the Goods of Persons unknown, did steal, &amp;c. and on the said Indictment, the said Rogers was according to due Form of Law try'd by a Jury of the Country, empannel'd between our Lord the King and the said Rogers, and was by the said Jury convicted, as by the Record, &amp;c. doth more fully appear. And the Jurors now farther present, that he the said Adamson on the <rs id="t17390221-19-cd102" type="crimeDate">15th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-19-off101 t17390221-19-cd102"></join>, the said 13 lb. of Tobacco, did receive, &amp;c. knowing it to be stole
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Council for the King having open'd the Charge, the Witnesses were call'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person164">
                  William 
                  Keys 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person164" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Rogers, and I know the Prisoner; and I know of some Tobacco which was taken by Rogues, - some from the Tops of the Hogsheads, and some out of the Hogsheads, - where we can light of it. Rogers and I have been concern'd in taking Tobacco; this 13 lb. and a half we took: we stole it, and carry'd it to 
               <persName id="t17390221-19-person165">
                  David 
                  Adamson 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person165" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person165" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner, at his House: He lives two Doors beyond the Bull-head in <placeName id="t17390221-19-crimeloc103">Petticoat Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-19-crimeloc103" type="placeName" value="Petticoat Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-19-crimeloc103" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-19-off101 t17390221-19-crimeloc103"></join>, on the right Hand Side of the Way; I carried it there, and Adamson weigh'd it: He then had not Silver enough in the House to pay for it, but he desired me to go to the Bull-head, and he would come to me, - desiring me not to take any Notice; and accordingly he came there, chang'd a Guinea, and paid us. Rogers was with me at the same time. He paid us for 13 lb. and a half of Tobacco, 5 s. 6 d. and he paid at the same time 3 d. for a full Pot of Beer, which we had Part of.</p>
               <p>Counc. And what Sort of Tobacco might this be?</p>
               <p>Keys. Merchants Tobacco, - good Tobacco. I never enquired into the Worth of it; but sometimes we got Threepence, - sometimes a Groat a Pound: What he gave us was not the Worth of the Tobacco, for he gave us but 5 s. and 6 d. - for 13 lb. and a half. I was taken up on Thursday in Christmas Week, and was committed to Bridewell, where I lay a Fortnight. When I was taken up, I went before a Justice, and declared the whole Truth. We took our Opportunity to take Tobacco, sometimes in a Morning, before People were stirring, and at other times, as we had Opportunity. Rogers help'd to steal this Tobacco as well as I: He own'd before the Lord Mayor that it was stoln; - and he stole more than I did.</p>
               <p>Counc. I ask you, Whether the Prisoner knew it was stole?</p>
               <p>Keys. Yes; I have sold several Quantities of Tobacco to him before this; and I have told him where it came from. He us'd to say, - Why, this is bad Tobacco; and I us'd to say to him, - we can't make it better than it is - 'tis such as we can get.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you tell him this very Tobacco was stolen?</p>
               <p>Keys. Yes; I did; this very 13 lb. and half. - and every Bit of Tobacco we sold him, we told him was stolen; and he knew it was stolen. We have sold him Tobacco very frequently, - and large Quantities.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173902210013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person166">
                  Joseph 
                  Crosier 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person166" type="surname" value="Crosier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person166" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Constable belonging to the Custom-House Key. My Business is, to look out for lurking Fellows, who steal the Merchants Tobacco. I saw a great deal at Adamson's House, when I went there with Mr. Green the Surveyor; Keys told me, when he was taken up, that if I would go to Adamson's, I might see a great many Pilferers upon the Keys. I went; and the first Man, I saw go in was Mr. Hanbury's Watchman, with a great Parcel of Tobacco, which we seiz'd in Adamson's Scales, and we found several Parcels of Tobacco, of different Sorts, in several Parts of his House; some Oroonoko, some Sweet-scented, and all in small Quantities. He keeps a little Snuff-Shop in Petticoat-Lane, and there we found a great Parcel of different Sorts of Tobacco. When he was taken up, he desired Rogers and Keys to be as favourable to him, in their Account before my Lord Mayor, as they could; and he desired me to speak to Rogers and Keys, that they might be favourable to him, for the sake of his Family, and that they might not tell all they knew of him; telling me that if I would go down with him to the Keys, he would shew me a great many People he had bought Tobacco of. He owned he bought this 13 lb. and a half of Rogers and Keys and they told him he knew very well that he had bought a great many other Parcels of them beside this. He would have made an Information against several People, but it was too late.</p>
               <p>Counc. What do you take this Tobacco to be worth?</p>
               <p>Crosier. Some Tobacco is better than other; but I think none can be bought for the Price he gave for this. I take it, the Duty upon it is Five Pence Farthing, or Five Pence Half-penny per lb. I have taken 3000 lb. Weight of stolen Tobacco from other People; and there are forty People now in Bridewell for taking it. When the Prisoner was first taken, I advised him to make himself an Evidence; but then he said, he knew nothing of the Matter; and afterwards, when he desired it, it was too late.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person167">
                  Peter 
                  Lindsey 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person167" type="surname" value="Lindsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person167" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have wrought about a Twelve-month in the Prisoner's Shop: And all I have to say is, That I never saw him deal in this Way. I have sometimes made 40 lb. of Snuff in a Week for him.</p>
               <p>Counc. And how much Tobacco goes to the making 40 lb. of Snuff?</p>
               <p>Lindsay. I can't tell that. 'Tis made of Scuts Roll, and he has bought Roll of Mr. Gregory.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person168">
                  Mary 
                  Campell 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person168" type="surname" value="Campell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person168" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived as a Servant with the Prisoner Nine Months, and have been come away from him about Three. I served often in the Shop, and I never saw any such Persons come there.</p>
               <p>Counc. Might he not buy Tobacco, and you not know it?</p>
               <p>Campbell. He never did - to my Knowledge. He bought some of one Mr. Gates - but I did not use to go with him when he bought it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person169">
                  Alexander 
                  Cootes 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person169" type="surname" value="Cootes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person169" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner used to come to our House, and he'd buy sometimes more, sometimes less; - sometimes he'd buy a Roll of Tobacco, - sometimes a Cask of Snuff. Sometimes he'd pay, and sometimes he'd let it alone till he had another Parcel. I have been acquainted with him Six or Seven Years, full; and he always came down very hard for what he bought, but I took him to be an honest Man. I deal in Roll Tobacco from Scotland.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever sell him any Leaf Tobacco?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cootes. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person170">
                  Thomas 
                  Foresight 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person170" type="surname" value="Foresight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person170" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner from a Child. I have been acquainted with him, and have had Dealings with him, and have lodged in his House, and have work'd for him; and his Character is, - that he is an honest Man, and buys his Goods honourably, and has Bills of Parcels with them. I am a Snuff-Maker.</p>
               <p>Counc. And do you buy your Tobacco in Small Quantities?</p>
               <p>Foresight. No; I never buy less than a hundred Weight now: 'Tis not usual to buy in small Quantities; but when we have not much Money, we must buy what we can. I don't know but I have bought a Shilling's Worth myself, - a Man can go no farther than his Stock will bear.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hamilton. I am Clerk to Mr. Buchanan, a Tobacco-Merchant: The Prisoner has bought small Parcels of Tobacco of us. I never heard any thing amiss of him before this Affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person171">
                  Edward 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person171" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person171" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Tobacconist and Snuff-Maker; I have known the Prisoner Twelve or Fourteen Years, and never heard but that he was a fair Dealer, and bore the Character of an honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person172">
                  John 
                  Oliver 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person172" type="surname" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between two and three Years, in my Neighbourhood, and never heard but that he was very honest. - I am not a Snuff-Man, - I am a Horner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-19-person173">
                  John 
                  Row 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person173" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person173" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , likewise, and 
               <persName id="t17390221-19-person174">
                  William 
                  Catchpole 
               <interp inst="t17390221-19-person174" type="surname" value="Catchpole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person174" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner a good Character. <rs id="t17390221-19-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-19-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
