<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-10">
               <interp inst="t17380628-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-10" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-10" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-10-off50-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-10-defend103 t17380628-10-off50 t17380628-10-verdict51"></join>
         
               <p>12. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-10-defend103" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Green 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-10-defend103" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-defend103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-defend103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , the younger, was indicted for <rs id="t17380628-10-off50" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-off50" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-off50" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing two black Geldings, value 10 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-10-victim105" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hinton 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-10-victim105" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-victim105" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-victim105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-10-off50 t17380628-10-victim105"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-10-person106">
                  William 
                  Hinton 
               <interp inst="t17380628-10-person106" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person106" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 14th Day of this Month, between Twelve and One o'Clock at Night, I lost two black Geldings out of a common Field in Gloucestershire. The Prisoner is my Neighbour: I can't swear I found them upon him, but one of them I found in this Man's (Davis's) Possession: he was selling him in Smithfield. I seiz'd him, and carry'd Davis before my Lord-Mayor. While I was doing this, the Hostler at the Rose-Inn came to me, and asked me, if I had not lost another, I told him yes, I had lost another, with a Star in his Forehead, two white Heels behind, and a white Foot before. Upon this, I went with him to the Rose, and he brought out my other Horse to me. A little while afterwards, as he and I were coming from a Coffee-House, where we had been to see for the Prisoner, we met him in the Street: Neighbour, says I to him, 'tis an odd Thing you should take my Horses away! He had not a Word to say for himself, but was ready to sink when he saw me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-10-person107">
                  David 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17380628-10-person107" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person107" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The Prisoner brought the Horse to my Stables, and ask'd me if he could be put up? I took the Horse in, the 16th of this Month, and baited him; 'twas a Cart black Gelding, with but one Eye. The Same Day I bought the Horse of the Prisoner, in my own Stables, for 4 Guineas and a half; I gave him half a Guinea earnest, and was to pay him the rest in a few Days. He told me he bought this Horse and another in Wiltshire, and I said, 'twas hardly worth his while to go so far, to buy two such Horses; I brought them up with me, says he, only to help to make up my Charges. When we had agreed for the Horse, I carry'd him to Smith-field to sell again; and there Hinton found him out, and claim'd him. I know nothing of the other Horse.</p>
               <p>Benj Taylor. The Prisoner came to my Master Davis's Stables, at the George in Hedge Lane, and asked me to put up his Horse, and give him a Quartern of Oates, a Rack full of Hay, and a Penn'orth of Beans. I went for the Corn, and when I return'd, I found my Master and the Prisoner bargaining for the Horse, - a black Gelding, blind of an Eye. I did not see the Horse in Mr. Hinton's Possession.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hinton. The Horse I found in Davis's Possession, was the same that I lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-10-person108">
                  John 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17380628-10-person108" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person108" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner brought a black Gelding to my Master's, - the Rose Inn, in Smithfield, the 16th of this Month, and order'd me to put him up, and bait him. After some little Time, he order'd him into the Market, to be sold; and he rid about the Market accordingly. I heard that Mr. Hinton had lost two Horses, and had found one of them again; so I went and told him, I believed I could help him to his other Horse, and he went with me to see him, and claim'd him. Upon this, I found out the Prisoner, and took him.</p>
               <p>Defence. I know nothing at all about these Horses.</p>
               <p>Hinton. The Prisoner's Father and Mother are very honest People: I don't desire he should be hang'd. <rs id="t17380628-10-verdict51" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-verdict51" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-10-punish52" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-10-punish52" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-10-defend103 t17380628-10-punish52"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
