<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-2">
               <interp inst="t17380222-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-2" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-2" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-2-off9-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-defend41 t17380222-2-off9 t17380222-2-verdict14"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-2-off12-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-defend41 t17380222-2-off12 t17380222-2-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-2-defend41" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Nevil 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-2-defend41" type="surname" value="Nevil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-defend41" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-defend41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380222-2-defloc8">St. Andrew's Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-2-defloc8" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew's Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-2-defloc8" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-defend41 t17380222-2-defloc8"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-2-off9" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-off9" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-off9" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 14 hundred lb. of Lead, value 12 l. fixed to the Freehold of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-2-victim43" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Hind 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-2-victim43" type="surname" value="Hind"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-2-victim43" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-2-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off9 t17380222-2-victim43"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off12 t17380222-2-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17380222-2-viclabel10" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
               
                  </rs>; <rs id="t17380222-2-cd11" type="crimeDate">March 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off9 t17380222-2-cd11"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off12 t17380222-2-cd11"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d. Time indicted for <rs id="t17380222-2-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of Robert Hind, Esq; about 12 at Night, and stealing 2 pair of leather Breeches, value 40 s. 5 pair of linnen Socks, value 5 s. a Velvet Cap, value 10 s. 6 yards of Fringe, value 2 s. 2 Cushions, value 10 s. a Mattress, value 25 s. 2 Feather beds, value 5 l. and other Things
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-2-cd13" type="crimeDate">Feb. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off9 t17380222-2-cd13"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-off12 t17380222-2-cd13"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hind. I was out of Town when the Facts were committed, but I have seen the Goods I was robb'd of, and can swear they were once in my Possession.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-2-person44">
                  Daniel 
                  Riggs 
               <interp inst="t17380222-2-person44" type="surname" value="Riggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person44" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and I one Night took a quarters of a hundred of Lead from Mr. Hind's House, the next Night we took 5 Hundred, and the next Time about 6 Hundred. We carry'd it to one 
               <persName id="t17380222-2-person45">
                  Daniel 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17380222-2-person45" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person45" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Mutton-Lane, and told him where we had it; he bought it of us, and the Prisoner and I were equally concern'd.</p>
               <p>At another Time, (about the middle of the Night) I went to Mr. Hind's House, the Prisoner with an Iron Crow broke open the Malt Loft Door, and then an inner Door, and so got into the fore Parlour, where we broke open some Drawers, and took out 2 pair of Leather Breeches, a Velvet Cap, and some Velvet Cushions; some Stocking Feet, and some Fringe Then we broke a fine Scrutore, and when we had taken what we thought proper, we roll'd up all the Goods together in a Mattress and a Feather Bed, which we got out of the Hop-lost. We brought all the Goods thus bundled up into the fore Parlour; then we broke open the Compting-house Door, where we took a Chest of Candles, and from thence we got into the Street, and carry'd all the Things to the Prisoner's House. This is the Truth if I was dying this Moment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-2-person46">
                  John 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17380222-2-person46" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner's Wife was my own Sister; she died the 13th of Oct. and not having Money to pay the Undertaken for the Funeral, he desired me to sell some of these Things, which he said were his Wife's, but they prov'd to be the Gentleman's, and I informed him of them, after the Prisoner and Riggs were taken up. These are the Things which were sold to pay the Expence of his Wife's burying.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hind These are my Goods; I lock'd them up with my own Hands in a Chest of Drawers.</p>
               <p>Berry. Some were sold to one in Whitecross-street, and some were pawn'd by my Wife at the Prisoner's Direction. This red Silk I had from him, and was to have got it dy'd a Massareen blue, and to have made him a Waistcoat. The Velvet Cap, and one side of the Mattress I deliver'd to Mr. Gordon for Mr. Hind.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gordon. I can't swear the Prisoner stole the Lead, or broke the House, but the next Morning after it was done, we missed the Goods mention'd, and about a Month or 5 Weeks ago, this Berry came to my House, and told me he had something to say to me about my Apprentice Riggs. Riggs as soon as he saw Berry, ran from his Work to Berry's House, to ask his Wife what Business he had with me. I got a Warrant and took up Riggs, (my Apprentice) and Berry. By their Means we found out the Prisoner, and took the Breeches and some of the Goods in his Lodging in Grays-Inn-Lane, one side of the Mattress was taken off his Bed, he made use of it for a Sheet. <rs id="t17380222-2-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17380222-2-punish15" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-2-punish15" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-2-defend41 t17380222-2-punish15"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
