<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-22">
               <interp inst="t17350116-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-22" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-22" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-22-off95-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-22-defend157 t17350116-22-off95 t17350116-22-verdict98"></join>
         
               <p>25. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-22-defend157" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17350116-22-defend157" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-defend157" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-defend157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            ,* was indicted for <rs id="t17350116-22-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               privately stealing a Shew Glass lined with Velvet, value 40 s. A Mother of Pearl Snuff-box with a Silver Rim, value 16 s. two Tortoise-Shell Snuff-boxes with Silver Rims, value 32 s. a Silver Snuff-box value 7 s. 6 d. 16 Pair of Silver Shoe-buckles, value 9 l. 9 s. 13 Pair of Silver Knee-buckles, value 3 l. 7 Silver Girdle-buckles, value 21 s. 13 Silver Stock-buckles, value 1 l. 13 s. 13 Pair of Silver Sleeve-buttons, with Stones, value 3 l. 15 s. 40 Pair of Brass Shoe-buckles gilt, value 5 l. 5 Metal Girdle-buckles gilt, value 12 s. 11 Pair of Metal Knee-buckles gilt, and 8 Brass Cane-heads gilt, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350116-22-victim159" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Bill 
                        <interp inst="t17350116-22-victim159" type="surname" value="Bill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-22-victim159" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-22-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-22-off95 t17350116-22-victim159"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350116-22-cd96" type="crimeDate">January 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-22-off95 t17350116-22-cd96"></join>.</p>
               <p>*Alias <rs id="t17350116-22-alias-1" type="alias">Faulkner</rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-22-person160">
                  Edward 
                  Bill 
               <interp inst="t17350116-22-person160" type="surname" value="Bill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person160" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are my Goods. I make 'em my self, I live in <placeName id="t17350116-22-crimeloc97">St. Martin's Court next to Castle Street against Cranbourn Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-22-crimeloc97" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's Court next to Castle Street against Cranbourn Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-22-crimeloc97" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-22-off95 t17350116-22-crimeloc97"></join>. The Shew-Glass stood in my Shop<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160007"></xptr> Window, half in, and half out. It was taken away on the seventh of January, about seven at Night. I was then at a Neighbour's House, and hearing an Outcry, I ran to see what was the Matter, when my Wife told me we were undone, for the Shew-Glass was lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-22-person161">
                  Ann 
                  Kenring 
               <interp inst="t17350116-22-person161" type="surname" value="Kenring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person161" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing in the Room next the Shop with the Child in my Arms. My Mistress and two more Gentlewomen were sitting in the same Room. I was looking towards the Shop Window where we had a Glass Lamp, and I saw a Man clap his Arm over the Shew Glass and take it away. So, so! says I, You are mighty full of your Play methinks, to steal the Shew Glass: Why that's a fair Robbery. For I thought it had been taken in jest by a Gentleman who was with my Master. But as the Man did not turn back, I begun to fear he was in earnest, and so I followed with the Child in my Arms, and cry'd, Stop Thief. I saw him with the Glass under his Arm; he was then no farther from me than from hence to that Chair, and he was not afterwards out of my sight till he dropt the Glass, and was taken by the Pine Apple Door in Castle-Street. I am sure that the Prisoner is the Man. I was almost close to him when he dropt it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-22-person162">
                  Nicholas 
                  Byrom 
               <interp inst="t17350116-22-person162" type="surname" value="Byrom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person162" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was turning the narrow Passage from Castle-Street into St. Martin's Court, a Man past by me with something very Combustible under his Arm. And presently, the Maid crying Stop Thief! I turned about and saw the same Man drop something that made a great Noise under the Lamp. That Man was the Prisoner, for he was taken before he was out of my sight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-22-person163">
                  Robert 
                  Prat 
               <interp inst="t17350116-22-person163" type="surname" value="Prat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person163" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Coming from Charing-Cross, and turning up Castle-Street I heard a Cry of Stop Thief. It being dark I went into the middle of the Street, and stooping down, I saw the Prisoner run, and the Maid follow him. I stopt him against the Pine-Apple Eating-House, and then he cry'd Stop Thief, and said the Thief was run before, but I told him he was mistaken. The Maid came up to us with a Child in her Arms, and bid me hold him fast for he was the Thief. And so I obliged him to turn back. I saw the Shew Glass upon the Ground, and the People were picking the Toys out of the Kennel. I led the Prisoner to the Prosecutor's Shop, and a Constable being sent for, he came, and carried the Prisoner before Mr. Justice Deveil, who committed him to Newgate that night.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner denied the Fact, but called no Witnesses.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17350116-22-verdict98" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-verdict98" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350116-22-punish99" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-22-punish99" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-22-defend157 t17350116-22-punish99"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
