<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-11">
               <interp inst="t17360908-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-11" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-11" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off55-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend101 t17360908-11-off55 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off55-c73" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend103 t17360908-11-off55 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off57-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend101 t17360908-11-off57 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off57-c73" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend103 t17360908-11-off57 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off59-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend101 t17360908-11-off59 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-11-off59-c73" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend103 t17360908-11-off59 t17360908-11-verdict61"></join>
         
               <p>16, 17. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-defend101" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Dwyer 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend101" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend101" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-defend103" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     O Neal 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend103" type="surname" value="O Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend103" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-defend103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17360908-11-off55" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off55" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off55" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360908-11-victim105" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Maintrew 
                        <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim105" type="surname" value="Maintrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim105" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's High-way, putting him in fear, and taking from him a silver Watch, value 40 s. a Tortoishell Snuff-box, value 20 s. a pair of silver Shoe buckles, value 6 s. a pair of Knee-buckles, value 5 s. a pair of silver Spurs, value 25 s. a silver Stock buckle, value 5 s. a Cambrick Stock, value 1 s. a Holland Shirt, a Hat, a Peruke, a Cloth Coat. Wastcoat, Whip, and other Things, and 2 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-11-cd56" type="crimeDate">July the 31 st</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off55 t17360908-11-cd56"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off57 t17360908-11-cd56"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off59 t17360908-11-cd56"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080006"></xptr>They were a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17360908-11-off57" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off57" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off57" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17360908-11-victim106" type="victimName">
                        Daniel 
                        Hawkins 
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim106" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim106" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-11-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , in an open Place near the King's High-way, putting him in fear, and taking from him 32 silver Buttons, 7 Guineas, 7 Shillings, in Money and other Things
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-11-cd58" type="crimeDate">August the 3 d</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off55 t17360908-11-cd58"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off57 t17360908-11-cd58"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off59 t17360908-11-cd58"></join>.</p>
               <p>They were a third Time indicted for <rs id="t17360908-11-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a black Gelding, value 12 l.
            </rs> the Goods of Daniel Hawkins, August the 3d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-person107">
                  James 
                  Maintrew 
               <interp inst="t17360908-11-person107" type="surname" value="Maintrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person107" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . July the 31st, I was coming from Horton in Buckinghamshire; at <placeName id="t17360908-11-crimeloc60">Beggars-bush, between Acton and Kensington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-11-crimeloc60" type="placeName" value="Beggars-bush, between Acton and Kensington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-11-crimeloc60" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off55 t17360908-11-crimeloc60"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off57 t17360908-11-crimeloc60"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-off59 t17360908-11-crimeloc60"></join>, there is a Bridge, and by that Bridge there is a Dunghill and a Gate. On the middle of the Bridge I met a Man upon a black Horse: I was attack'd by him and another who came up to him; they had each of them a Pistol in their left Hands, and a Truncheon in their right. They made me dismount, and carry'd me over the Gate, into a Field, then put me into a Ditch and searched my Pockets: They took away the Things mention'd in the Indictment, and which I swear to. They gagg'd me and stripp'd me quite naked; my Hands were ty'd behind me, my left Leg fasten'd up to my Hands, and my right Leg lash'd to the other: Then they drew me out of the Ditch into a Furrow, where I lay 'till 12 o'Clock at Night, when a Man coming by released me. I am positive to the 2 Prisoners, for it was light enough to see their Faces; I heard nothing of them, 'till they were taken up for robbing Mr. Hawkins, 3 Days afterwards; then I went to see them, and knew them to be the Men that robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Barns. Dwyer was taken up on suspicion of robbing Mr. Hawkins, and to save himself he desired before Mr. De Viel to be made an Evidence. I was in pursuit of O Neal when my Beadle stopp'd him; and he too desired to be made an Evidence: I have got the Slugs which I drew out of O Neal's Pistols, which we took from him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-person108">
                  Daniel 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17360908-11-person108" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person108" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday the 3d of last Month, I was robb'd by the 2 Men at the Barr, about a quarter of a Mile from Stone-bridge, on the Harrow road, about 9 o'Clock at Night. O Neal catch'd hold of my Horse and led him into Mr. Newman's Ground, and Dwyer lay'd hold of me, and led me about 20 Poles length into the Field. Under a Hedge they laid me down; O Neal took 7 Guineas and some Silver from me, and cut off my Silver Buttons; they cut my Coat and Wastcoat down, and took Cloth and Buttons together, and the Buckles out of my Shoes: When they had robbed me, I was going to get up, but Dwyer struck me with his Stick, and say'd, they had not done with me; then O Neal pulled a Handkerchief out of his Pocket, and ty'd my Hands behind me; but before he had done, Dwyer got upon my Horse and rode away with him. O Neal bid me lye still, for he should bring me more Company presently. Mr. Newman met them both upon my black Horse as they were riding off; they rid as far as they thought proper, then turn'd up my Horse, and I found him again.</p>
               <p>Constable. I took these Buckles upon O Neal.</p>
               <p>Hawkins. These are the Buckles they took from me. I heard nothing of the Men 'till Thursday, when a Man came from Turnham green and told me a Man was taken there, with such Goods as I had lost upon him; I went and saw O Neal there, and had him before a Justice.</p>
               <p>Newman. I came from Paddington with Mr. Hawkins: We drank together at Halsden-green; and he went away about half an Hour before me. As I came home, I met 2 Men upon his Horse, within a quarter of a Mile from the Place where he was robb'd, I knew the Horse very well; and O Neal rid hindmost. The next Morning I heard that Mr. Hawkins had been robb'd in my Field, and there my Maid found his Whip: We printed Bills for the Horse; Dwyer was taken and confess'd in hopes of being made an Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-person109">
                  Joseph 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17360908-11-person109" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person109" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 2 Prisoners lodged in my House in James's street, near Grosvener square. They told me they dealt in Lace and Holland, and carry'd Packs about the Country. They lodged about 9 Days with me, and in that Time they lay out 4 Nights, and the last Time 2 Nights successively: Once when they came home they quarrell'd and fought about sharing some Money, and a loaded Pistol was found in their Bed: My People told me of that, and I went for a Constable to charge them on suspicion; but the Constable would not come without a Warrant; I could not find a Justice at home, so I came back to my House, and found the 2 Men were gone; but Dwyer coming to a Pawnbrokers to redeem a Coat, he was taken up on suspicion of being a Highwayman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-11-person110">
                  John 
                  Stokes 
               <interp inst="t17360908-11-person110" type="surname" value="Stokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry'd Dwyer before Justice De Viel, who examin'd him two several Times; at last he confess'd that O Neal and he had robb'd near Brentford. I went to Brentford and found out Mr. Hawkins: O Neal was now taken, and when Hawkins saw them both, he knew them. Dwyer made him a Bow, and asked him if he had used him ill or hurt him: The silver Buttons were found upon Dwyer, and the Buckles upon O Neal, before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Dwyer. I can't tell what to say to it.</p>
               <p>O Neal. 'Tis a Folly for me to say any Thing; I am in a Fever and cannot dispute. Both <rs id="t17360908-11-verdict61" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-verdict61" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment. <rs id="t17360908-11-punish62" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-11-punish62" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend101 t17360908-11-punish62"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-11-defend103 t17360908-11-punish62"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
