<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-39">
               <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-39-off199-c176" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-defend255 t17370907-39-off199 t17370907-39-verdict203"></join>
         
               <p>42. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-defend255" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Fuller 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-defend255" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-defend255" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-defend255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370907-39-defloc196">St. Margaret's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-defloc196" type="placeName" value="St. Margaret's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-defloc196" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-defend255 t17370907-39-defloc196"></join>, <rs id="t17370907-39-deflabel197" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-defend255 t17370907-39-deflabel197"></join>; was indicted, for that he not having God before his Eyes, but being moved and seduced by the Instigation of the Devil, the <rs id="t17370907-39-cd198" type="crimeDate">15th, of April</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-off199 t17370907-39-cd198"></join>, <rs id="t17370907-39-off199" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-off199" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-off199" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-39-victim257" type="victimName">
                           Adam 
                           Cluff 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-39-victim257" type="surname" value="Cluff"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-39-victim257" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-39-victim257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-off199 t17370907-39-victim257"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Feloniously, Willfully, and of his Malice aforethought, did make an Assault, and with the But-end of a certain Musquet, val. 5s. which he held in both his Hands, in and upon the left Part of the Breast of the said Cluff, near the left Pap, did strike; giving him then and there, with the But-end of the said Musquet, on the left part of the Breast near the left Pap, a mortal Bruise; of which mortal Bruise, he languished, &amp;c. from the said 15th, Day of April, to the 23d, of the same Month, and then Dy'd
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d, Time indicted on the Coroners Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person258">
                  Edward 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person258" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person258" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Morning the 15th of April, I happen'd to be in <placeName id="t17370907-39-crimeloc200">St. James's Park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-off199 t17370907-39-crimeloc200"></join>, and there I saw <rs id="t17370907-39-deflabel201" type="occupation">Colonel</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-defend255 t17370907-39-deflabel201"></join> Fuller Exercising the Serjeants and Corporals. I stood by to see them Exercise 'till they had done. The Colonel sent all the awkward ones, - those that Exercised awkwardly, to the Hole, to the Drill Serjeants. There was the Deceased and one Inon, and 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person259">
                  Elisha 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person259" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person259" type="given" value="Elisha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Corporal Maxfield, and Corporal Turner sent down. The Moment they don't Exercise right, they are sent down to the Drill-Serjeant. After the Exercise was over, and the Men were dismiss'd, the Colonel went down to the Drill-Serjeant's, and struck Cluff under the right and left side of his Jaws, and his Throat, with his Fist.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in an open Place?</p>
               <p>Richards. Yes; a vast open Place, 'tis a plain Place in a Bottom, I could see every Thing that pass'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near enough to hear what was said to the Deceased before he struck him?</p>
               <p>Richards. He found Fault with him for not Exercising Right, and that put the Colonel in a Passion with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Deceased the first Man, that the Colonel spoke to at the Drill-Serjeants.</p>
               <p>Richards. I can't say that for all the World.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see him speak to, or strike any one beside the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Richards. No; but I heard him find Fault with many of them, as he pass'd by them.</p>
               <p>Q. You talk'd of the Hole, - What Place is that?</p>
               <p>Councel. 'Tis a little plain Place in the Park.</p>
               <p>Richards. If they don't Exercise well, they are sent there, to the Drill Serjeant, for farther Exercise, - to learn farther, and the Colonel follow'd them thither to see them Exercise himself.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070020"></xptr> He found Fault with many of them, before he came to Cluff, but when he came to him, he call'd him Chuckle-headed Dog, and struck him with his fist under the right and left side of his Jaws</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had he not a Firelock upon his Shoulder?</p>
               <p>Richards. Yes; he had a Firelock upon his Shoulder at the same time</p>
               <p>Q.  How many blows did he gave him</p>
               <p>Richards. I saw him strike the Deceased three Blows, on the sides of his Neck, and upon his Throat.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the Blows given with Violence?</p>
               <p>Richards. They seem'd to be pretty hard</p>
               <p>Q. After the Deceased had been struck did he say any Thing?</p>
               <p>Richards. I did not hear him say a Word, not one Word; but the Colonel catch'd the Firelock with his Hands, and jobb'd it against his left Breast, because it did not lye right upon his Shoulder. He took it out of his Hands and jobb'd the Guard of the Firelock against his Breast</p>
               <p>Q. How often did he do this?</p>
               <p>Richards. Once I don't say it was the Butend, but the Guard of the Firelock, that is the Part where the Trigger is. He made him rest his Firelock according to this new Method of theirs, - with the left Hand across the Breast. The Colonel did it to make him hold it lower; he did not rest his Piece as he should have done, so the Colonel took it out of his Hands, shewed him how to rest it with a proper Motion, then he went at him, and jobb'd this sharp part against his Breast, and threw the Stock across his Shoulder, telling him, if he did not do better in the Afternoon, than he had done in the Morning, he would send him to the Savoy</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike him any more than one Blow?</p>
               <p>Richards. No, no more; but then he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Deceased the only Man that the Prisoner struck?</p>
               <p>Richards. He struck none of them but him.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Week was this?</p>
               <p>Richards. This was on the Friday; and on the Wednesday Evening following, about 7 o'Clock, I went to Chapel Street, Westminster, and being sadly grip'd, I call'd in at a Shop that had been a Gin shop, for half a Quartern of Cordial Water, and while I was in the Shop, Adam Cluff (the Deceased) came by the Door, stooping, bending, and coughing; so I said, Adam, - I heard you were bad and kept your Bed; I shook Hands with him, and told him, I was heartily glad to see him. Oh! says he, (with his Hand across his Breast ) I am a dead Man; for the Blows that Colonel Fuller gave me, has occasioned my Death. I am a dead Man, and shall not recover it. I bid him not be afraid, but have a good Heart, and go Home and take Care of himself. Oh! says he, I will go home as fast as I can, - m, Officer is not in Town, but he has sent me Word he will see me righted.</p>
               <p>Councel. You say you was at a Distance when you saw all this; how many Yards might you be off?</p>
               <p>Richards To look down Hill, - it was not much farther than the Length of this Court. There was no Body between us, but the Ranks of Corporals and Serjeants - I believe I might be 10 Yards distant. - I believe it might be 20 or better..</p>
               <p>Councel. Have not you declared it was 50 Yard?</p>
               <p>Richards. It could not be 50 Yards. I said it was about 20 or 30 Yards, - I never said it was 50 in my Life.</p>
               <p>The Surgeons were ordered to be called next.</p>
         
               <p>Note, Colonel Fuller's Trial being very long, we are obliged for want of Room to defer the remaining Part of it for a few Days. With which will be publish'd the rest of the Capital Cases, viz. The Trial of 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person260">
                     William 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person260" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person260" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , for stealing a Silver Watch from Mr. 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person261">
                     Eman 
                     Wilque 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person261" type="surname" value="Wilque"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person261" type="given" value="Eman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , in the Street. John Hickman, for forging and publishing a false and counterfeit Note for 56 l. with Intent to defraud 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person262">
                     Edward 
                     Jasper 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person262" type="surname" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person262" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , Esq, of Tower-Hill. 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person263">
                     William 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person263" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , otherwise Snock Jones, for robbing Mr. Willoughby, of his Watch, under Aldgate. Likewise the Trials of 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person264">
                     William 
                     Runnington 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person264" type="surname" value="Runnington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person264" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , the Butcher, for the Murder of 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person265">
                     William 
                     Reynolds 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person265" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                in Honey Lane Market. 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person266">
                     John 
                     Wharton 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person266" type="surname" value="Wharton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , charg'd on the Coroner's Inquest with the Death of 
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person267">
                     James 
                     Strainer 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39-person267" type="surname" value="Strainer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person267" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , by throwing a Piece of Wood at the said Strainer, upon the Gunnel of a Lighter. P - d F - s for robbing Mr. Harris at the Crown-Tavern Thread needle-Street, with a great Number of other remarkable Trials, fully and carefully taken.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17370907-39">
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-39" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS AT THE SESSIONS OF PEACE, Oyer and Terminer, FOR THE CITY of LONDON, AND County of MIDDLESEX, ON</p>
                  <p>WEDNESDAY the 7th, THURSDAY the 8th, and FRIDAY the 9th, of SEPTEMBER,</p>
                  <p>In the 11th Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign.</p>
                  <p>BEING THE</p>
                  <p>Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY</p>
                  <p>OF THE</p>
                  <p>Right Honourable Sir John Thompson, Knight,</p>
                  <p>LORD - MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>For the YEAR 1737.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VII. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. ROBERTS, at the Oxford-Arms in Warwick-Lane M.DCC.XXXVII.</p>
                  <p>(Price Six-Pence.</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS AT THE Sessions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, For the CITY of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>The Remainder of the TRIAL of FRANCIS FULLER, Esq;</p>
               <p>Coroner. I had a great many Surgeons to view the Body of the Deceased, but I don't call them; the Colonel will call them; they were all of an Opinion that it was a natural Death. I was present when the Body was open'd; but it had been buried 12 Days, before it was taken up. The Occasion of which, was my receiving an anonymous Letter, which I have here to produce.</p>
               <p>The Letter was read.</p>
               <p>May 3d, 1737,</p>
               <p>Sir. I am a Friend of your's, and a Lover of Justice, which is the Occasion of this. Adam Cluff, a <rs id="t17370907-39-viclabel202" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-39-victim257 t17370907-39-viclabel202"></join> in Holbert's Company was buried last Night; he was Murder'd by Colonel Fuller, by a Punch in the Side; by which Method several of his Soldiers have Died. He languished 6 Days and then Died; he always declared this was the Occasion of his Death, and the Searchers know it, as well as the whole Regiment; 'tis known in Town and Country, as well as at Court, and if you'll get the Body Examin'd, it will appear to your Reputation.</p>
               <p>Your Friend, Will. Thompson.</p>
               <p>P.S. I would have you acquaint some Justice of the Peace, and Officers of the Army, and then proceed your self.</p>
               <p>Coroner. Mr. Westbrook open'd the Body, and the rest of the Surgeons were by, viz. Mr. Edmunds, Mr. Tagg, Mr. Lewis, Mr. Davis, Mr. Harris, Mr. Young, and Mr. Ormered.</p>
               <p>Mr. Westbrook. I was apply'd to by the Church-Wardens of the Parish, (on Account of this Letter in the Coroner's Hands) to attend the Inquest. I had notice that the Body was prepared, and was ready for us. When I came to the Church-yard, I had some Conference with the rest of my Brethren; most of them were of Opinion, that we ought to let the Body alone; that it was not safe for us to meddle with it, on Account of our Healths. The Body had been Buried so long, that we thought we could make no Discovery, and that we should endanger our selves besides. But however, I ventur'd and open'd the Body with the greatest Circumspection. The out-side was very putrid. By the Hint I had from the Letter, I judged the Damage was agreed to be in the Breast only, so I open'd it; but I found nothing that seemed to be the effect of Violence, which could be the Occasion of his Death. 'Twill not be amiss to acquaint the Court, what we thought would be the appearance, if the Deceased had received a Punch that had occasion'd his Death, viz. Fractur'd Ribs, or extravasated Blood in the inside of the Body; but there was neither. These things would have appeared, if the Man had Died of such a Hurt, and we know of no other Appearance, which we might expect to have seen. This will be an Answer to the Question, - Whether we could be Judges of the Deceased's Case, when he had been Buried 12 Days. After I had taken the Flesh clean off the Ribs, I split them down with my Knife, and made my Man break them off, and every one of them snapp'd loud and strong; which they would not have done; if they had been Fractur'd. The Chest was free from extravasated Blood, but upon farther enquiry, I found an appearance of Matter upon the Membrane of the Breast. This Membrane we call the Mediastinum;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070023"></xptr> it divides the Breast into two Parts; it opens in the Center and receives the Heart in the Middle. On the left side, there was an Appearance of Matter, - perhaps half an Ounce or something more. Some of my Brethren turn'd their Heads away on Account of the Stench, and did not observe this; but I call'd to them, that they might judge of it. They disputed a little while, whether it was Matter or not; they thought it might be some little quantity of Fat, but I shew'd them plainly that 'twas impossible it should be Fat, and that it was Matter. From the Circumstances of the Case it is plain, that this Matter was the Consequence of an Inflamation on the Mediastinum, near the middle of the Cavity of the Breast, but it was on the left Side of the Breast, and I apprehend, by it's being far remov'd from the Ribs and the Breast-Bone, that it was not occasioned by an outward Blow; for it had been occasion'd by the bending-in of the Ribs, it would have been nearer the Place where the Blow was given. For this Reason I imagine it was the Effect of some natural Cause; and that the Matter proceeded from an inward Inflamation, and there suppurated. The outward Parts of the Body were so bad, we could perceive no Appearance of any outward Bruise, the inward Parts we could perceive plainly.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a Blow given on the middle of the Thorax, might not such a Blow occasion the Matter:</p>
               <p>Mr. Westbrook. I think that's not the Case. On the bending-in off the Ribs, by an outward Blow, the Lining of the Breast may be strain'd, and an Inflamation may happen on that Part where the Blow was given. This Membrane divides the Breast a cross, 'tis in the middle of the Hollow of the Breast, and not contiguous to the outward Part. I verily believe that this Matter did not proceed from any outward Blow, it was the Effect of an Inflamation, and not of any Blood spilt. 'Tis possible indeed that Blood in a Fortnight's Time may occasion Matter; but that is not the Case, because the Lining of the Breast kept the Matter in a suspended Way, it did not fall down into the Bottom of the Cavity, and as far as the Matter had fallen upon the Membrane it had corrupted and eaten it, - exactly as far as the Matter had spread. I think the Inflamation proceeded to a Degree of Corruption, and this Conjecture tallies pretty well with the Complaints which I heard the Deceased had made before. Therefore I gave my Opinion on the Coroner's Inquisition that I believed he died a natural Death.</p>
               <p>Counc. Were the Searchers present at the Coroner's Inquisition, - who searched the Body before he was buried?</p>
               <p>Mr. Westbrook. I can't tell, - we pay but little Regard to what they bring in.</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis, Surgeon. I was present when the Body was opened, and my Opinion is, that he died a natural Death. I attended him in his illness; the first Time I was with him, was the 21st of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever attended him before?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before this Accident?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. I can't justly tell; but he was lame when he was last under my Hands; I believe it was about 2 Months before. On Thursday Morning the 21st of April, I attended him first, his Complaint was, that he had taken Cold, had a Cough and stitches in his Side. I advised him to be blooded in the Arm: then I ordered him an oily Medicine for his Cough, and told him, if his Stiches continued, he must be let Blood again. These were the only Complaints he made to me. When I attended him this Time, his Cloaths were open, and I saw his Breast bare, but I perceived no Signs of Violence at all. I was going up Stairs to him, but he met me upon the Stairs, and said he would not trouble me to come up, he would come down to me. I saw nothing upon his Breast, nor did he complain of his having received any Blow.</p>
               <p>Counc. This was the very Day after he met the first Witness at the Brandy Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at his Breast?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. I did not put away his Shirt to look at it; but it being open, I saw his Breast. This was on the Thursday, and on the Saturday he died. On the Friday I saw the Corporal of the Company, and he told me, that the Deceased was then taking the Medicines I had order'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this Corporal tell you of any other Complaints that he made?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. No, he only said - he was taking his Medicines. I have been Surgeon in that Regiment about 7 Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Deceased any more before his Death?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. No. I never had any Patient under Cure that ever complain'd he had received any Hurt from Colonel Fuller. I have 7 Companies under my Care; and I have the Infirmary Regiment likewise, and I never heard any of the Men ever complain of any Violence that the Colonel had been guilty of toward them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070024"></xptr>Q. What are your Sentiments concerning the Death of this Man?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. 'Tis my Opinion he died of a Paralytic Fever: the Symptoms of which I have mention'd before, viz the Cough, and the Stitches in his Side. We could discover no Marks of Violence.</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard Mr. Westbrook's Reasons why the Deceased did not come by his Death by any outward Violence. Are they good Reasons?</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. Yes, I agree with him entirely.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person268">
                  John 
                  Ormerod 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person268" type="surname" value="Ormerod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person268" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was present at the opening the Body of the Deceased, and I believe he dy'd a natural Death. My Reasons are those two which Mr. Westbrook has already given, that either there would have appear'd extravasated Blood, or fractur'd Ribs, and I believe those Signs are inseparable from Accidents of this kind. I have open'd Bodies where there has been no external Wound, and yet I have always found these Signs. I believe he died a natural Death.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person269">
                  Edward 
                  Edmonds 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person269" type="surname" value="Edmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person269" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was at Mr. Westbrook's right Hand when the Body was open'd; I agree with him, and believe he died a natural Death, and for the same Reasons that Mr. Westbrook has given. In making my Observation, I saw a small Inflamation) on the left Lobe of the Lungs, beside one on the Pleura, which I think, (with the other Inflamation) occasion'd his Death. The Collection of Matter, (to be sure) was from an Inflamation; but if that had been caused by any outward Blow, there must have been the Symptoms that have been before mentioned.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person270">
                  Archibald 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person270" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person270" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I likewise was present when the Body was open'd. My Opinion is, that he died a natural Death, and that it did not proceed from any external Violence whatever; no Signs having appear'd to us upon the opening of the Body. Mr. Westbrook's Reasons weigh with me, and I'm of the same Opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any additional Reasons?</p>
               <p>Mr. Harris. I can only say, that he complain'd of a Pain in his Side, for which a Barber let him Blood; I ask'd the Barber what sort of Blood it was, and he (the Barber) told me, 'twas very fizy.</p>
               <p>G. That's not proper Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person271">
                  Richard 
                  Tagg 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person271" type="surname" value="Tagg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person271" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present, and agree on the 'forementioned Symptoms, that there had been no Violence, but that the Man died a natural Death.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person272">
                  William 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person272" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person272" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I have the Misfortune to be deaf, I hope the Court will indulge me - When the Body was inspected I was present: According to the best Observation I could make, there were no Signs of any outward Injury; to all Appearance he died a natural Death, there were no visible Marks of Violence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Shipton was call'd and sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. To Mr. Shipton. You have heard the Reasons given by the Surgeons that induce them to believe the Deceased died a natural Death; do you imagine their Reasons are good?</p>
               <p>Mr. Shipton. Yes; for this Reason. In Fevers, and lingering Illnesses, the Blood will be corrupted  but where Death is occasioned by external Violence, that Violence will be perceptible a Fortnight after. In such a Case as this, there would have appear'd an extravasation of Blood, or a Fracture of the Sternum, or Ribs.</p>
               <p>Q. To the Coroner. Can any other of your Witnesses give any farther Account of the Violence offer'd the Deceased, than what the first Witness has done?</p>
               <p>Coroner. No; none of them can say so much. There are none else, but People who speak to his Complaints, and one Man, who can say some little Matter beside.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire the Drill Serjeant may be called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person273">
                  Joseph 
                  Gage 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person273" type="surname" value="Gage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person273" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Drill-Serjeant. Colonel Fuller came down to see the Serjeants and Corporal's exercise, who were under my Care, and he walked along a single Rank, and found Fault with some People, before he came to the Deceased. When he came to him, he found Fault with him likewise, - that he kept his Elbow too high; and the Deceased not taking it lower, he struck him on the Elbow two or three Times.</p>
               <p>C. But here's a Man saw him strike the Deceased on the Jaws.</p>
               <p>Gage. I saw nothing more than I have related. I attended on the Colonel, and saw no more, and this was at the resting of the Firelock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the Prisoner take the Deceased's Firelock out of his Hand?</p>
               <p>Gage. No; I did not see him take the Firelock out of his Hand at all. I must have seen it, if he had done so, - for I was very near them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you see him give the Deceased a Blow with the But-end, upon his Breast?</p>
               <p>Gage. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How near were you to them?</p>
               <p>Gage. I was attending the Front; within 3 or 4 Yards of them.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Caldecat. On the 18th of April - the 17th I believe it was, - the Deceased went to Epping, and the 18th I saw him in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070025"></xptr> Morning'; he was coming down Stairs. Country-man, says I, how d'you do? Very bad says he, - come in and sit down. I am very ill, says he, for I was base fuddled last Night, and I have a Pain in my Breast and all over my Body. I got so much Liquor last Night, (says he) that I had a great many Falls, and I believe, I have broke something within me. The Deceased had been at the Green Man, summoning Men, against the next Field-Day. He told me he had had so many Falls, that he believed he had bruised or broke something within him, and he was not able to stand to exercise the next Day.</p>

               <p>Q. When did he exercise?</p>
               <p>Gage. He exercised that Day (the 16th of April,) almost an Hour after the Blows. And next Day he Exercised as usual, without any Complaint. On Monday he came about half an Hour too late, and I asked him the Reason of his being too late, and he told me he had hurt his Foot, or his Leg, I can't tell which.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person274">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person274" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person274" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the Deceased was Exercising before the Drill Serjeant, and I observed the Colonel to strike him with his Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the Colonel strike him with the end of the Piece?</p>
               <p>Jones. I can't say I saw any such Thing, and I was nearer than the first Witness.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabout did he strike him?</p>
               <p>Jones. Somewhere about the Head or Face, but I did not see him strike him with the Piece.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him, when he performed that Part of his Exercise, which they call, - resting the Musket?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Colonel take the Musket out of his Hand?</p>
               <p>Jones. To the best of my Remembrance, he took it out of his Hand, and put it upon his (the Deceased's) Shoulder, telling him at the same Time, that he did not do the Motion, that he had shewn him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he then give him a Blow upon the Breast with the But-end of it?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did not see any Thing of it, and I was between Richards (the first Witness) and the Serjeant who was exercising the Men.</p>
               <p>General 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person275">
                  Wills
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person275" type="given" value="Wills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Fuller is my first Major; and ever since I have had the Regiment he always appear'd a good-natur'd Man, and has often beg'd off Men from Punishment. I never knew him guilty of an ill-natur'd Action in my Life; on the contrary, I have pardon'd Men at his Request. I don't remember that I had ever any Man complain'd of him, but once, and that was about five Years ago. A Man complain'd he had struck him with his Cane, and upon my speaking to Mr. Fuller about it, he told me he never more would carry a Cane, or ever strike any of them again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-39-person276">
                  Lord
                   Nassau Paulet
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person276" type="surname" value="Nassau Paulet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person276" type="given" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Colonel Fuller several Years. I never saw an ill-natur'd Action committed by him in my Life. He is a Man that always behaves with Decency, and I take him to be as good-natur'd a Man, as any I. know.</p>
               <p>Major General 
               <persName id="t17370907-39-person277">
                  Barryl
               <interp inst="t17370907-39-person277" type="given" value="Barryl"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-person277" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five and twenty Years. I never saw him ill natur'd or troublesome; and I have been often drinking with him in Company, at Times when Men most expose their Passions. I never knew him guilty of an ill-natur'd Action in my Life.</p>
               <p>The Jury without withdrawing, <rs id="t17370907-39-verdict203" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-39-verdict203" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted the Prisoner, and found that Adam Cluff died a natural Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
