<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370114-42">
               <interp inst="t17370114-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-42" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-42" type="date" value="17370114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-42-off211-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-42-defend328 t17370114-42-off211 t17370114-42-verdict212"></join>
         
               <p>51, 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-42-defend328" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-42-defend328" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-defend328" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-defend328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370114-42-defloc209">Christ-Church. Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-42-defloc209" type="placeName" value="Christ-Church. Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-42-defloc209" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-42-defend328 t17370114-42-defloc209"></join>, was indicted, for that 
               <persName id="t17370114-42-person329">
                  Samuel 
                  Broughton 
               <interp inst="t17370114-42-person329" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person329" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 16 of Sept about the Hour of 12 at Night, having stolen 6 yards of Cloth, val. 21 s. the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-42-victim331" type="victimName">
                     Jacob 
                     Chitty 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-42-victim331" type="surname" value="Chitty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-victim331" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-victim331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-42-off211 t17370114-42-victim331"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , then fix'd on certain Racks and Tenters; he the said Allen afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17370114-42-cd210" type="crimeDate">17 of Sept</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-42-off211 t17370114-42-cd210"></join>. 3 yards, parcel of the said Cloth <rs id="t17370114-42-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               did receive, knowing it to be stole.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Mr. Satchwell In September last I was robb'd of six Yards of Cloth, the Property of Mr. Chitty 
               <persName id="t17370114-42-person332">
                  Samuel 
                  Broughton 
               <interp inst="t17370114-42-person332" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person332" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken up for another robbery, and he informed Mr Davis, that the Prisoner Allen had three Yards of this Cloth I went to him, and he told me he had no such Thing. I told him I must search his House; and when he found I had a search Warrant, he sent his Man to search for it, and he brought us these three Yards of Cloth. Here it is, and this is the other Part from whence it was cut; 'tis rough, and is not yet manufactur'd.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did not Mr. Allen say, he was not at Home when it was pledged at his House?</p>
               <p>Satchwell. He said his Man took it in, and blam'd him for it. I asked him why he did not advertise it; and he made no answer at all.</p>
               <p>C. You say he blam'd his Man for taking it in; on what Account did he blame him?</p>
               <p>Satchwell. He said the Goods were not manufactur'd, and any body might see they had been stole.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was his Man by, at this Time?</p>
               <p>Satchwell. Yes, and he own'd he took it in.</p>
               <p>Councel. I would ask you whether Mr. Allen was not bound over to prosecute the Principal Felon.</p>
               <p>Satchwell. Yes, he was.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Did you prefer this Bill, before, or after his being bound over to prosecute?</p>
               <p>Satchwell. Afterwards I did, and I went with a Warrant to take him up, once or twice myself, and I sent several People to ask for him; but I was told he had secreted himself; he might have taken his Trial last Sessions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-42-person333">
                  George 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17370114-42-person333" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person333" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In October last I went to New-Prison to see Broughton, and I asked him if he knew any Thing of Satchwells Goods, and he told<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140020"></xptr> me, he had stole some from him, and that 3 Yards were pawn'd to a Pawnbroker in Smock-Alley. I told Satchwell of this, and he got a Search Warrant, and Mr. Allen read the Warrant himself. I was there at the same Time, Mr. Allen said he had no such Goods as he knew of, but when Satchwell insisted on searching, then Mr. Allen bid his Man go up and look, the Man went up Stairs, and brought down these very Goods; Satchwell own'd them immediately, and Mr. Allen said, any one might see those Goods were not honestly come by, and he told us he was not at Home when they were brought, but that his Man had taken them in, in his absence. The Man own'd he took the Goods in.</p>
               <p>- Barnes, Constable. I know nothing of these Goods, but I believe Mr Allen to be a very honest Man. There was a Watch lost some Time ago; and 'twas pawn'd with him; I had, (upon Enquiry) such a Character of him, that I only asked him about it, and he immediately deliver'd it to me.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Vane. I was robb'd some Time ago by a Servant; and I went to Mr. Allen's and enquir'd after my Goods, he desir'd me to call again in 2 or 3 Hours; I did, and he deliver'd me all the Things, without any Trouble.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-42-person334">
                  Thomas 
                  Bullmore 
               <interp inst="t17370114-42-person334" type="surname" value="Bullmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person334" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last August I lost a Watch, and was inform'd it was pawn'd at Mr. Allen's: I got Barnes the Constable to go with me with 2 Search Warrant to his House, but the Justice told me he was so worthy an honest Man, that we should have no need of using the Warrant; he has in his Neighbourhood a universal good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-42-person335">
                  Michael 
                  Allcock 
               <interp inst="t17370114-42-person335" type="surname" value="Allcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person335" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd with Mr. Allen at this Time, and I took in these 3 Yards of Cloth, my Master being out. I had liv'd there not half a Year, and was never in the Business before. Broughton brought it, I did not know him, nor did I ever see him before.</p>
               <p>Coun. Did you acquaint your Master with the Receipt of this Cloth.</p>
               <p>Allcock. No, upon my Oath, when Mr. Satchwell and Davis came to enquire after it, that was the first Time he knew any Thing of it. It had not been in the House above a Month. We book the Things that are receiv'd, but my Master seldom looks over the Goods that are pledg'd, 'twould be an endless Trouble to do that. I took Broughton to be a Dyers Servant, and told him, 'twas not well of him to use another's Goods, but he told me the Cloth was his own, and was sent him out of the Country. When Mr. Satchwell came to ask for it, my Master asked me if I knew of any such Thing; I said yes, and by his Order, I went up and fetch'd it.</p>
               <p>Satchwell. When I enquired after the Cloth, the Man said nothing of his remembering it, but went up Stairs and brought it down. ( Here the Record of Broughton's Conv ction was read )</p>
               <p>Counsel. We shall shew this is most inveterate Malice. When the principal Felon was taken up, Mr. Allen was desired to enter into a Recognizance to prosecute; he did so, and by this Indictment the Recognizance is forfeited.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mawson. Headborough. I went with Satchwell to search Mr. Allen's House. When we enquired for the Cloth, he hesitated a little, and asked his Man about it; he bid him go up and see if there was any such Thing, and he brought it down to us; but Mr. Allen reproved him for taking it in. <rs id="t17370114-42-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-42-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
