<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-16">
               <interp inst="t17370706-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-16" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-16" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-16-off84-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-defend147 t17370706-16-off84 t17370706-16-verdict87"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-16-off85-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-defend147 t17370706-16-off85 t17370706-16-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>20. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-defend147" type="defendantName">
                     Hans
                      Mac-Connel, otherwise <rs id="t17370706-16-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-defend147 t17370706-16-alias-5"></join>Connel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-defend147" type="surname" value="Mac-Connel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-defend147" type="given" value="Hans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-defend147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of St<placeName id="t17370706-16-defloc82">. Ann's Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-16-defloc82" type="placeName" value=". Ann's Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-16-defloc82" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-defend147 t17370706-16-defloc82"></join>, was indicted for that he, <rs id="t17370706-16-cd83" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-off84 t17370706-16-cd83"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-off85 t17370706-16-cd83"></join>, <rs id="t17370706-16-off84" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-off84" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-off84" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-16-victim149" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Hooper 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim149" type="surname" value="Hooper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim149" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an Assault, and with a certain Knife, value 6 d. which he held in his Right Hand, in and upon the Throat of the said Robert, did strike and cut, giving him a Mortal Wound of the Breadth of 6 Inches, and the Depth of 3 Inches, of which Wound he instantly died.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>He was again indicted for <rs id="t17370706-16-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17370706-16-victim150" type="victimName">
                        Catherine
                         the 
                        <rs id="t17370706-16-viclabel86" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-victim150 t17370706-16-viclabel86"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-16-person151 t17370706-16-viclabel86"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17370706-16-person151" type="victimName">
                              Robert 
                              Long 
                           <interp inst="t17370706-16-person151" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17370706-16-person151" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17370706-16-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim150" type="surname" value="the"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim150" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-16-victim150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and giving her a Mortal Wound in the Throat, of the Breadth of 6 Inches, and Depth of 3 Inches, of which Wound she instantly died
            </rs>, June 16.</p>
               <p>He was likewise charged by Virtue of the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person152">
                  Robert 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person152" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person152" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday, June 16, about I at Noon, I went out to Bromley, and left my Wife well at Home; when I return'd, I found my Wife murder'd, her Throat was cut, and the Child's Neck bone was disjointed; it's Head was cut almost off, it hung only by a bit of Skin to the Body. I lost 2 Watches out of the House, and my Wife's Wedding-Ring was taken off her Finger. The Motto was, - God alone, - made us two one. I came Home about a quarter after 9, and there was a dismal Sight for me; they both lay on their Backs with their Throats cut. I heard what had happen'd before I came Home, for Mr. Shelley and Scott met me as I was returning from Bromley, and told me my Wife was murder'd. I imagine they were both knock'd down first, for on each of their Heads, there was the Appearance of a Blow, which seem'd to be given by a Hammer. When I got Home the Doors were shut, but there was Dr. Sprag, Dr. Hooker, Dr. Wilkinson, Mr. Hales, and the Father of the murder'd Child in the House. Mr. Jetsome was there likewise; but I was so 'frighted, I don't remember what any of them said to me.</p>
               <p>Councel. Look on that Ring?</p>
               <p>Long. 'Tis very much like my Wife's Ring: the Poesy is the same, and 'tis about the same Size, I believe it to be the same, but I won't swear positively that it is the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person153">
                  Richard 
                  Wentworth 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person153" type="surname" value="Wentworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person153" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I remember the Prisoner; on Thursday was 3 Weeks I met him in Ropemekers Fields by Lime house, about 5 o'Clock, within half a quarter of a Mile from Mr. Long's House. He enquir'd for Mr. Long's House; I told him I did not know any such Person; then he went about 10 Doors further, and stopp'd at Mrs. Chapman's House. When he went from me he leaned upon the Posts before Mrs. Chapman's Door, but I did not hear any Thing he said there.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to swear the Prisoner is the same Person?</p>
               <p>Wentworth. Yes; he is the Man that spoke to me: I was with him before the Justice, and I am sure he's the same Person that I spoke to in Ropemaker's-Fields.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person154">
                  Margaret 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person154" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person154" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner again very well: I am positively sure he's the Person that spoke to me that Day the Murder was committed. 'Twas on a Thursday, but I don't remember the Day of the Month; he stopp'd at my Door a Moment or two before 4 o'Clock. First he survey'd the Gentlewoman's House, then he came up and lean'd upon one of the Posts, and asked which was Mr. Long's, - Mr. Staples's Brewer. Madam, says he, (for he gave me that Title) do you know where Mr. Long lives? I ask'd him, if he was sure he liv'd in that Street? He paus'd a little, and then he said he did not know, - but he was informed that he lived in one of the new Houses against the School. Presently Mr. Hester's School came into my Head, and I said, Sir you are mistaken in the Street; so I bid him go thro' that Arch (to which I pointed) and ask for the School, and 'twas likely he would hear of him there.</p>
               <p>Q. What Cloaths had the Prisoner on?</p>
               <p>Chapman. I can swear that he had the same Coat on then, that he has on now, but he had then under it, a green duffled Waistcoat. I have Reason to remember his Physiognomy, because he told me he hoped to have the Pleasure to see my Ears nail'd to the Pillory, or else he would cut his own Throat: I know him from 5000 Men.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance do you live from Mr Long's?</p>
               <p>Chapman. I live in Ropemakers-Fields, and he lives at the Limekilns, about 3 Stones throw from my House. He stood a moment or two after I directed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060016"></xptr> him: I took him to be a Bailiff, and that he kept prating to me 'till he could seize his Prey.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Before the Justice she swore I had a Cinnamon colour'd Coat.</p>
               <p>Chapman. I have sworn to his Coat, and you'll find some body else will swear to it, by and by.</p>
               <p>- Gray I have look'd at the Prisoner, and have taken a great deal of Observation upon him: (have observed him well.) I saw him that Thursday after 3, 'twas not 4, - I won't say to a Minute or 2. I was above Stairs, putting on my Cap, and I looked out of my middle Window (for there's 3 in the Front) and saw the Prisoner standing cross the Kennel, and looking up to the Window. I thought he stood loitering there to stare at me, because I was without my Cap, so I slipp'd it on and look'd out again; still he look'd stedfastly up at me; then I imagin'd he saw something in the Beaufet that he wanted, for he did not look like another Man. After this I saw him go to Chapman's House, which is exactly over the Way: I expected News (from a Friend,) and at last I thought he might be enquiring for me; so I came down Stairs, but he was gone, - I saw no more of him. I took particular Notice of him at that Time, and I am sure he's the Man that spoke to Mrs. Chapman, but I cannot swear to his Cloaths. The Monday after, when the Prisoner was carry'd to the Justice's House, I saw him pass thro' the Room where I was, and that very Minute I knew him, and said to Mr. Betty, - that's the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person155">
                  Eliz 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person155" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person155" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 5 and 6 o'Clock the Day the Murder was committed, I saw a strange Man in Mr. Long's House. As I passed the Door, I saw him within the Door. I can't Swear positively 'twas the Prisoner, but 'twas such a jolly, full upright Man. 
               <persName id="t17370706-16-person156">
                  Robert 
                  Hooper 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person156" type="surname" value="Hooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person156" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Child, came about half a dozen Minutes after to buy a half-penny-worth of Cherries of me, and I serv'd it, but the Child throwing down a Penny, I said, my dear, you must have more; so I served it another Halfpenny-worth. I saw it come out of Long's House, but I can't say I observ'd it to go in again: I heard of the Murder about 2 Hours after.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person157">
                  Marget 
                  Hope 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person157" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person157" type="given" value="Marget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work at Mr. Birch's, at the Lime-Kilns. The Day Mrs Long was kill'd, about a Quarter before 6, I saw a full-body'd jolly fac'd Man, with a dark Wig full of Powder, come out of Long's House and he came towards me, as far as the second Post from Long's Door, - towards Lime-house Corner. He stopp'd as if he wanted to make Water, or was in a Consternation; then he turn'd round, stopp'd short again, and went away towards Limehouse Marsh Wall. I can't swear the Prisoner is the Man, but 't was one very like him.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from him, when you saw him come out of Mr. Long's?</p>
               <p>Hope. About as far as from the Place where I now stand to the other Corner of this Court. ( Pointing to the Bale-Dock ) The Reason I took Notice of him, was this; the Day before, a Man well dress'd made Water before us all, and I thought this Man was going to do the same, and I resolved if he did, to affront him for his Impudence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person158">
                  Benj 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person158" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person158" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner some Years: I remember, the Day the Murder was committed, I met him about half an Hour after 6, and shook Hands with him, near Mr Hoar's Yard at Limehouse Marsh Wall.</p>
               <p>Q. What Cloaths had the Prisoner on?</p>
               <p>Harper: I won't swear to any Cloaths: - He had a green Jacket on. I asked him to go and drink a Mug of Beer, and he said he could not stay. I then went on to Dick's-Shore, and there I heard of the Murder.</p>
               <p>Q. You met a Man and talk'd with him, can you remember nothing concerning his Cloaths?</p>
               <p>Harper. I will not swear to any Cloaths.</p>
               <p>C. You are sworn already to speak all that you know; recollect yourself: - What colour'd Cloaths had he on? If you remember, you must tell us.</p>
               <p>Harper. If I meet a Man, it does not follow I should take Notice of his Cloaths</p>
               <p>Councel. Don't be angry; - I must ask you, upon your Oath, if he had not a green Waistcoat, or Jacket on, when you met him at the Marsh Wall?</p>
               <p>Harper. I won't swear to Cloaths: -</p>
               <p>Councel. I ask you upon your Oath, if you have not said already, that he had a green Jacket on?</p>
               <p>Harper. Why to the best of my Knowledge he had a green Jacket on, - and much such a Coat as he has on now.</p>
               <p>C. You are not to conceal any Thing, but to speak the Truth to the best of your Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Harper. To the best of my Knowledge he had the same Coat on then, that he has on now, and a green Jacket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long has that Witness known me?</p>
               <p>Harper. Seven or eight Years: At first he used to sell Callicoe; then he used to buy Shells, and sell China Wrappers.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060017"></xptr>The Evans confirmed Harper's Evidence; but he could not swear positively to the Prisoner, because he walked a little before them, while they talked and shook Hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person159">
                  Mary 
                  Streffen 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person159" type="surname" value="Streffen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person159" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 4 and 5 in the Afternoon that the Murder was committed, I was sitting within Door by myself, and was knitting. A Man knocked at the Door, and asked if Mr. Long was at Home; I told him he did not live here, and while I was directing him, I let my Stitches fall, which prevented me from taking Notice of his Face: I look'd after him, and saw him lift up the Latch of Long's Door, but I can't say I saw him go in. He had a caped Coat on, something darkish, dirty Ruffles, and was much such a sized Man as the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person160">
                  Lydia 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person160" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person160" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 3 and 4 - I can't say exactly, - it might be more, I went past Long's House; 'twas the Day she was murder'd. The Casement was open, and I saw a Man in the Room, he laughed, and shut the Casement as I passed by. I take it to be the Prisoner, I verily believe him to be the same Man. When he was before the Justice, he stood among 4 or 5 Men, and when I saw him, I thought I should have dropp'd down, - I was so surprized. I went out into the Yard for a little Air, and I said to Mr. Hone, if you'll go in with me, I'll shew you the Man, that look'd out of Long's Window, or one very like him: And at this Time, no body had told me that he was the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person161">
                  George 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person161" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person161" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday Night after the Murder between 11 and 12 o'Clock, I went to the Prisoner's House in Ratcliff-highway; I saw him, and he every Way answer'd the Description given of the Murderer. This is the Ring that his Wife sold the Day after the Murder, to Mr. Bond. That which was taken from Mrs. Long, being in the Advertisements that were publish'd, Mr. Bond sent to let us know he had bought such a one. The Prisoner said he would carry us to the Pawnbroker he bought it of, and he told us, he gave 19 s. for it. We went there at this Time, only to ask them about the Ring, but the Man answering the Description given of the Person that was seen in Long's House, we went again on Monday to take him up; when the Constable took him, he said he had 2 Witnesses to prove where he was when the Murder was done; and I said, - what need you talk of that, before you are charged with it. Mrs. Long was at my House on the Sunday and Monday before she was murder'd, with the Ring on her Finger, and we talked about the Poesie: I believe the Ring that has been produced is the same, but there are no particular Marks on it</p>
               <p>Counc. When you went to take up the Prisoner's Wife on the Saturday, did not you tell her your Suspicion with Regard to the Murder?</p>
               <p>Rhodes. I charged the Officer with his Wife, on Suspicion of being concerned in the Murder, and (I suppose) I told her the Reason of my Suspicion. The Prisoner carry'd us to a Pawnbrokers, where he said he bought the Ring and a Snuff-box, and the Pawnbroker looked over his Books, but he could find no such Things set down; indeed he did say, he did not always set down what he sold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person162">
                  Giles 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person162" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person162" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received this Ring on Friday the 17th of June, and gave her 15 s. for it: If the Price was not approv'd of, she was to have it again. On Saturday I found such a Ring, two Watches, and 3 Spoons were advertised. The Ring having the Poesie mentioned in the Advertisement, I sent Notice I had bought such a thing; upon this, Mr. Rhodes came to see it: He seem'd positive 'twas Mrs. Long's Ring; therefore I told him what Discourse had pass'd between the Prisoner's Wife and me, when she was at my Shop, and by recollecting that, we found where the Prisoner lived. As to the Motto of the Ring, 'tis a common one, and there may be 500 such Rings about the Town.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person163">
                  Mary 
                  Randal 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person163" type="surname" value="Randal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person163" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Dog-Tavern at Billinsgate: The Prisoner I have known about two Years. He came to our House a little after One o'Clock on this Thursday, and dined with my Spouse upon Mackarel, in a Box at one Corner of the Kitchen. He said he was to attend a Trial at Guildhall, between Mr. Young (who lives at the Queen's-Head in Alhallow's-Lane ) and his Servant. Mr. Randall had some Business at the Crown Coffee-house, so he went out with the Prisoner between 3 and 4 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so Particular as to this Thursday?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Randall. Because the Prisoner and his Wife came the Sunday following to our House, and she said, Lord, Mrs. Randall, I have been taken up on Suspicion of Murder, and told me about her selling the Ring: And he told me some People had said, if he had a green Waistcoat, they would swear it upon him. I remember the Cloaths he wore that Thursday: He had had the same Coat he has on now; and a blue Waistcoat, which my Spouse took Notice was very dirty.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person164">
                  Moses 
                  Jennings 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person164" type="surname" value="Jennings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person164" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , confirmed Mrs Randal's Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr Gill Attorney. I sent the Prisoner this Subpaena on the 15th of June, to attend the next Day at 3 o'Clock at Guild hall, as a Witness in a Cause depending between 
               <persName id="t17370706-16-person165">
                  William 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person165" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Plaintiff, and Mr Young, Defendant, and he came to the Crown Tavern a little before 4 o'Clock, and staid there till 5, then we went into the Hall together, and I saw him there several Times, walking to and fro in the Hall, between 5 and 6; there was not more than a quarter of an Hour's Space between the Times of my seeing him, and a little after 6, we all went entirely to the Tavern again, and staid till 8. I don't know that he left the Room from 6 to 8.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waiteman confirm'd Mr.Gill's Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harrison, gave the same Account, that the Prisoner came to the Crown about 4, that he staid there 'till near 5, then they all went to Guild hall, and from 5 to 6 there was not a quarter of an Hour passed, but he saw him in the Hall. At 6 the Witness was not well, therefore he came away.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sympson, gave exactly the same Account with the former Witnesses, with this Addition, that the Prisoner wore then a caped Coat and a blue Westcoat.</p>
               <p>Mr Young and Mr. Dennevet, gave the same Account with the preceeding Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person166">
                  Honour 
                  Thompkins 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person166" type="surname" value="Thompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person166" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and another Witness gave an Account, that they saw a Ring with the same Motto in the Prisoner's Wife's Possession, the Saturday before the Murder was committed.</p>
               <p>The Prosecutor then call'd 
               <persName id="t17370706-16-person167">
                  Francis 
                  Pearse 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person167" type="surname" value="Pearse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person167" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who deposed, that he had known the Prisoner some Years, that he saw him twice, the Day the Fact was committed; once about 2, and afterwards about 4; that he was then walking towards the Lime-kilns, but he did not speak to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person168">
                  Mary 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person168" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person168" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17370706-16-person169">
                  Sturgeon 
                  Langham 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person169" type="surname" value="Langham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person169" type="given" value="Sturgeon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person169" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , saw a Man at Lime-house that Day, very like the Prisoner, but could not swear he was the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person170">
                  George 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person170" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person170" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that a Coat was brought to him the Day after the Murder, to be scower'd, he believ'd it was the same the Prisoner had upon his Back; but there was no Blood upon it.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370706-16-person171">
                  Betty 
                  High 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person171" type="surname" value="High"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person171" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Constable, search'd the Prisoner's House the Monday following, and found nothing to give any Light into the Affair; he found 2 foul Shirts, and asked if the Prisoner had any more, the Maid told him she had just given the rest of them out to be washed, but could tell nothing of the Washer-woman, not where she liv'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-16-person172">
                  Hannah 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17370706-16-person172" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person172" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for the Prisoner, swore she likewise saw him June 16, about 4 o'Clock at the Crown Tavern, and afterwards at Guild hall. <rs id="t17370706-16-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-16-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
