<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-10">
               <interp inst="t17390607-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-10" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-10" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-10-off47-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-10-defend97 t17390607-10-off47 t17390607-10-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>338. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-10-defend97" type="defendantName">
                     Jarvis 
                     Hare 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-10-defend97" type="surname" value="Hare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-defend97" type="given" value="Jarvis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-defend97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390607-10-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a grey. Gelding, value 20 s.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-10-victim99" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Row 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-10-victim99" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-victim99" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-victim99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-10-off47 t17390607-10-victim99"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17390607-10-cd48" type="crimeDate">May 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-10-off47 t17390607-10-cd48"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Row. On the 12th of May, I ty'd a grey Horse to a Post at the Bottom of <placeName id="t17390607-10-crimeloc49">Pudding-Lane, in Thames-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-10-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="Pudding-Lane, in Thames-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-10-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-10-off47 t17390607-10-crimeloc49"></join>, while I went to Mr. Demiller's, an Oyl-Shop at the Corner of St. Magnus Church, to ease myself. I was gone about eight or ten Minutes: When I came back my Horse was gone, and I was ill, and unable to run about to see for him. I thought the Carmen might have play'd the Rogue with him, but a Woman told me, she saw a Boy get upon him and ride him away; and I never saw the Horse again 'till I saw him in the Green-Yard, which was about six Hours after I lost him. The Green-Yard is a Pound, belonging to the City; I am sure the Horse I found there, was the same I lost: I bought it of Mr. Thompson in White-Chappel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-10-person100">
                  Michael 
                  Kitchen 
               <interp inst="t17390607-10-person100" type="surname" value="Kitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person100" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going along Shoe-Lane with my Fish, and saw a Man lay hold of the Horse, (the Prisoner being upon it) and somebody said, he believed the Horse was stole. I said, I made no Doubt but it was stole; for the Prisoner had been try'd for stealing Horses: So I took the Prisoner and brought him through Newgate, towards the Compter. As I came along, a Man told me he knew who the Horse belonged to. I bid him fetch the Man, and he brought the Prosecutor, who own'd it directly. When I took the Prisoner, he told me a Man gave him the Horse to carry to the Royal Exchange.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I asked the Prosecutor to let me ride, and he gave me Leave, so I rode to TempleBar, an they took me, and put me in the Compter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-10-person101">
                  John 
                  Nettlefold 
               <interp inst="t17390607-10-person101" type="surname" value="Nettlefold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable In Cheapside, at the Top of Wood street Kitchen gave me Charge of the Prisoner, on Suspicion of stealing the Horse: So I put the Prisoner in the Compter, and sent the Horse to the Green-Yard, to be pounded. About an Hour afterwards Mr. Row came and owned it. It was the same Horse that I took with the Boy on his Back.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-10-person102">
                  Ann 
                  Simons 
               <interp inst="t17390607-10-person102" type="surname" value="Simons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person102" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Victualling House in the Minories. The Owner of the Horse (William Row) is an Acquaintance of mine, and I know his Horse. A young Lad, and an old mean-looking Man with him, brought the Horse to my Door, and having fastened him there, they came in, and called for six or eight Penn'orth of Veal. I having heard the Man (Row) say, he would never lend his Horse to the best Friend he had, - not even to his Wife, I asked them if Mr. Row was coming? I told them I was sure it was his Horse, and asked them if the Farmer was dead, because I knew he had been ill of an Asthma. By God, says the Boy, I bought the Horse at a Country Fair. I have a great many People come to my House, and am tender of swearing positively to the Prisoner, but there was an old mean looking Man with him, about fifty Years old, and he said, - damn it, - it was his own, and he bought it at such a Fair, but they both seemed to be surprized, and paid me nine Pence Half-penny, and went away. I knew the Horse, and gave him a Crust of Bread at the Door, as the Farmer used to do. This was (I think ) last Saturday was a Month. And about three Days ago the Farmer told me, he was to go to the Old Baily for Horse-stealing: I was surprized, and said, - What! you to go there for Horse-stealing, if you are, I will bail you, as far as a hundred Pounds; but at last I found he joked, and then I told him, I had seen his Horse with such Persons at the Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was going down the Lane, where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070010"></xptr> This Man says the Horse was ty'd to the Post, - I was going to my Father, who sells Brass Hooks  at Coffee-Houses about the Exchange, and Billingsgate. , and this Man bid me ride his Horse a little Way , - not ride him too far: So I rode him to Temple Bar, and was coming back with him, the People stopped me, and 
               <persName id="t17390607-10-person103">
                  Michael 
                  Kitchen 
               <interp inst="t17390607-10-person103" type="surname" value="Kitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person103" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             charged the Constable with me, and said he knew me very well; so I was carry'd before my Lord-Mayor, and was sent here. I have Witnesses to call, - but they are not hereabout. <rs id="t17390607-10-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390607-10-punish51" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-10-punish51" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-10-defend97 t17390607-10-punish51"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
