<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-27">
               <interp inst="t17390906-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-27" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-27" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-27-off123-c127" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-defend191 t17390906-27-off123 t17390906-27-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>457. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-defend191" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Fowke 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-27-defend191" type="surname" value="Fowke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-defend191" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-defend191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of London, <rs id="t17390906-27-deflabel122" type="occupation">Labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-defend191 t17390906-27-deflabel122"></join>, was indicted, for that he on the 31st of August, in the 11th Year of the Reign of her late Majesty Queen Anne, at the Parish of Alhallows in the Wall, <rs id="t17390906-27-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               married 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-27-victim193" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Parsley 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim193" type="surname" value="Parsley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim193" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and her had to his <rs id="t17390906-27-viclabel124" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-victim193 t17390906-27-viclabel124"></join>: And afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17390906-27-cd125" type="crimeDate">10th of October, in the 9th Year of his Present Majesty</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-off123 t17390906-27-cd125"></join>, at the Parish of <placeName id="t17390906-27-crimeloc126">St. Andrew Wardrobe</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-crimeloc126" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew Wardrobe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-crimeloc126" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-off123 t17390906-27-crimeloc126"></join>, feloniously married 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390906-27-victim195" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Fowke 
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim195" type="surname" value="Fowke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim195" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-27-victim195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Widow; Sarah, his former Wife, being then in full Life
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution having open'd the Charge and the Nature of the Offence, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person196">
                  George 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person196" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person196" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk of Alhallows London Wall, and this is the Register Book of that Parish.</p>
               <p>Counc. See if you find the Entry of Fowke's Marriage in 1712.</p>
               <p>Fisher. Here it is. Clerk reads.</p>
               <p>''Marriages. (The Title at the Top) Thomas</p>
               <p>''Fowke and 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person197">
                  Sarah 
                  Parsley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person197" type="surname" value="Parsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person197" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Aug the 31st, 1712.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long have you been Clerk?</p>
               <p>Fisher. About five Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. Is the Person living, who was Minister in 1712.</p>
               <p>Fisher. No. The Minister, Clerk, and Sexton, are all dead: But this is the Book in which the Entries were then made; 'tis the Register Book of our Parish. I came in, on the Death of my Predecessor: His Name was 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person198">
                  Samuel 
                  Wallington 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person198" type="surname" value="Wallington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person198" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he had been Clerk twenty-seven Years. The Minister keeps it in his Possession, and I fetched it from his House Yesterday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person199">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person199" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person199" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner: He's my Son in-Law, by marrying my Daughter-in-Law; her Name was 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person200">
                  Sarah 
                  Parsley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person200" type="surname" value="Parsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person200" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner, - but twenty-seven Years the 1st Day of last August.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you at the Wedding?</p>
               <p>Wilson. No; I staid at Home to dress the Wedding Dinner: But a Kinswoman of my Husband's, was at the Wedding, and one 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person201">
                  John 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person201" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person201" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave her away. They all went out together, and at Night I bedded them. I remember it all very well. Why they lived together in my House a Fortnight, before they took a House for themselves. The Prisoner had two Children by her: They are both now alive, and the eldest is in her 26th Year; that was a Daughter, and the Son is, - (stay, I would not tell a Lye) the Son is in his 25th Year. They lived together a great while in Bishopsgate Parish.</p>
               <p>Counc. Is 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person202">
                  Sarah 
                  Parsley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person202" type="surname" value="Parsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person202" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             living or dead.</p>
               <p>Wilson. She died three Quarters of a Year after he marry'd this second Wife. The Books are here to shew it.</p>
               <p>Counc. When did she die?</p>
               <p>Wilson. She has been dead about three Years, I believe. I cannot remember the Year, - I would not tell a Lie, if you'd give me all the World.</p>
               <p>Counc. After they had taken a House for themselves, how long did they live together?</p>
               <p>Wilson. About six Years; and he all the time acknowledged her for his Wife.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say you remember their going out to be married on the 31st of August.</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes, very well: It was on a Sunday Morning, twenty-seven Years ago. I might very well remember it, for I was married to her Father five Years before, at the same Church, by Dr. Richardson.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say they lived together five or six Years afterward.</p>
               <p>Wilson. Between six and seven they lived together, and then Tom. Fowke (the Prisoner) left her, and she was forced to go to the Parish where he served his time, for Relief of her and her two Children. When she was sick, I saw her, and she died with Grief.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was the last Time you saw her alive?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I believe it was two Years before she died, less than two Years, but I heard from her within that time. 'Tis now about 5 Years since I saw her, - within five Years, I am sure of it, - but I am old and don't remember particular Days. He cohabited with her sometime after the Marriage at my House, and they lived together six or seven Years I dressed the Wedding Dinner,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060013"></xptr> tho' I did not go to the Wedding. We were not young Folks, nor so flashy as to want to go to Weddings.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say he lived with her six or seven Years?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes: And after that he left her, and liv'd upon the Strole, and lov'd to gad about, as Men do too much that have the Breeches, and she was forced to put herself and Children on the Parish, while he lived where he pleased, as most Men like to do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person203">
                  Robert 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person203" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person203" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner; I knew his Wife, 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person204">
                  Sarah 
                  Parsley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person204" type="surname" value="Parsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person204" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , before she was marry'd to him: And I knew her after she was marry'd, six or seven Years. I saw her alive, the 24th of April, 1736, at the House of one Raddish, at the Sign of Hackney Town, in Bishopsgate-street. She had lived there about fourteen or fifteen Years. I am sure she was alive then, for I drank a Pint of Ale there, and saw her, but when she died I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you at the Wedding?</p>
               <p>Crane. No; but I remember their living together after they were marry'd, and he and I worked together after that. 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person205">
                  John 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person205" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave her away, is my First-Cousen, and I was a Relation of Sarah Parsley's, at a vast Distance. After the Prisoner left her, she made her Application to this Raddish, who was Clerk to a Brewer, and kept an Alehouse, and he took her to be his 24th of April 1736, because I was then at work, at Joiners Hall, and having 15c.wt. and one Quarter of Lead to carry, I went there to hasten the Carman, and this appears by my Books.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person206">
                  James 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person206" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person206" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk of Butalph Bishopsgate, this is the Register-book of that Parish.</p>
               <p>Counc. See for the Burials in September 1736.</p>
               <p>Stanley. Here is the Entry of 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person207">
                  Sarah 
                  Fowke 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person207" type="surname" value="Fowke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person207" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Burial.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads. ''Burials; September 1736, Sarah ''Fowke, the 9th. Aged 47.'</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person208">
                  Ann 
                  Fowke 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person208" type="surname" value="Fowke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person208" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner to my Sorrow. I was married to him the 10th of October 1735. We were married at <placeName id="t17390906-27-crimeloc127">St. Andrews Wardrobe</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-27-crimeloc127" type="placeName" value="St. Andrews Wardrobe"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-27-crimeloc127" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-off123 t17390906-27-crimeloc127"></join>, and Mr. Wright, the Coroner, gave me away. He was the Father, and persuaded me to have him. I knew the Prisoner about three Years before I was married to him, but not for any Harm. I was a Widdow, and of the same Name with the Prisoner, but not related to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you know me longer than three Years? Did not you know me seven or eight Years before Marriage?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fowke. I can't justly say: He lived in the Neighbourhood, but I belive not seven or eight Years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long did you live with me before Marriage?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fowke. Not at all. I did not live with you in any Dishonesty.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She was my Housekeeper, in St. Margaret's, Westminster, three Years.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fowke. He never was able to keep a Table in his Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person209">
                  John 
                  Hinton 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person209" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Register-Clerk of St. Andrew Wardrobe, and this is the Register-Book of Marriages.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads. ''Married in St. Andrew's Ward-robe ''and St. Ann's Black Fryars, Anno Domini ''1735, October 10th, Thomas Fowke, ''Widower, of St. Margaret's Westminster, ''and Ann Fowke, Widow, of the same ''Place: By 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person210">
                  William 
                  Grainger 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person210" type="surname" value="Grainger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person210" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>I was present at this Marriage, but 'tis impossible for me to remember Faces. I have often seen the Woman, because I have been called upon other Trials.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person211">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person211" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person211" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390906-27-person212">
                  Jane 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person212" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person212" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were called out, to give Evidence for the King against Thomas Fowke; but they did not appear.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prisoner, as a Point of Law, took Notice of the long Separation there had been between the Prisoner and his first Wife. That it might be presumed, after so long an Absence, he might not know she was living and that there was a Proviso in the Statute, which restrained it from extending to any Person whose Husband or Wife should continually remain for the Space of Seven Years beyond the Seas; or whose Husband or Wife should absent himself or herself for Seven Years, within any Part of his Majesty's Dominions, the one from the other; and the Party so left, not knowing the other to be alive: And as there had been no Proof given of the Defendant's knowing his first Wife was alive, they hoped he was not within the Statute.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As to her Separation, there's Raddish to call; I don't know his Christian Name: but he's the Person she lived with.</p>
               <p>Raddish appeared; but the Prisoner would not have him sworn for him: Upon which he was called by the Council for the Prosecution, and sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person213">
                  John 
                  Raddish 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person213" type="surname" value="Raddish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person213" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Sarah Parsley: she lived with me sixteen or seventeen Years, or upwards. She died the 6th of September 1736, and was, (I think) buried on the 9th.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173909060014"></xptr>Council. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Raddish. No; but I have seen him at my House several times before the Death of the Woman, and he has seen her often at my House.</p>
               <p>Council. Have you seen him at your House, within nine or 10 Years last past?</p>
               <p>Raddish. I have seen him who they said was her Husband; but I never spake three Words to him in my Life; - I don't know him; I never saw him to take Notice of him; but I have seen him, and when he has been gone, People have told me, That Man was Sarah Parsley's Husband. He has been often at our House.</p>
               <p>The Witness being old, and his Sight weak, he was ordered to go to the Bar, and look at the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Council. Now you have seen him, do you know him? Have you ever seen him before?</p>
               <p>Raddish. Yes: I reckon he is the Man; I have seen him at my House; but I cannot justly tell how long before her Death: I believe it might be a Year. This was the last Time I saw him, and before he went out of the House, I sat down by him, and when he was gone, the People told me he was Sarah Parsley's Husband.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he then see Sarah Parsley?</p>
               <p>Raddish. I don't know whether she was dead or alive then.</p>
               <p>Counc. Just now you said it was before her Death.</p>
               <p>Raddish. I can't well tell when it was.</p>
               <p>Counc. At the time this Man was in your House, did she come into the Room to you?</p>
               <p>Raddish. She did not then; there was only he and I in the Room: I don't know where she was at that time: She commonly went out of the House when he came in, and staid till he was gone.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he ever come but that Time?</p>
               <p>Raddish. As they told me, he had been there a great many times; but I never saw him to know him but that time: and then I sat down with him, and talk'd with him, about its being fine Weather - a fine Season; but I was not with him Half a Quarter of an Hour. When he went out, the Neighbours asked me if I knew who that Man was? I said no; they told me it was Sarah Fowkes's Husband: And I am sure she was then alive.</p>
               <p>Counc. And how long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Raddish. About four or five Years ago. The Prisoner is the Man; I believe he is the Man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Crane. About ten Years ago, the Prisoner and I went into Raddish's House, and had a Pot of Beer; but I did not see his Wife. He reported that she lived with Raddish, and was his Whore; this was about eight or nine Years ago; he often said, she was a Whore and a Bitch, and lived with old Raddish, and tuck'd him up, and lay with him. This he often said, between eight and nine Years ago. I am positive it was within nine Years, and that within that Time I have asked him, When he saw his Wife? And he has said, - D-mn her, I have not seen her, - so long. We often talked about her; I have had some Conversation with him since that Time; but his Wife was not mentioned, except once, and that was about three Months ago; I then saw him in the Tipstaff's House, and ask'd him, how he could be so base, to marry another Woman, when his first Wife was alive? D-mn it, (said he) what's that to you?</p>
               <p>Counc. How long ago is it since you had any Conversation with him about his Wife, in her Life-Time?</p>
               <p>Crane. I can't be positive to half a Year. 'Tis nine Years ago, or thereabout.</p>
               <p>Counc. Are you sure it was within ten Years, or eleven Years?</p>
               <p>Crane. No.</p>
               <p>Council to Raddish. Did not she die at your House?</p>
               <p>Raddish. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-27-person214">
                  William 
                  Merriman 
               <interp inst="t17390906-27-person214" type="surname" value="Merriman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person214" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Sarah Fowke: She lived next Door to me. She died in September, and I buried her the 9th, 1736. I know nothing of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17390906-27-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17390906-27-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-27-punish129" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-27-defend191 t17390906-27-punish129"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
