<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-33">
               <interp inst="t17380628-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-33" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-33" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-33-off164-c209" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-33-defend283 t17380628-33-off164 t17380628-33-verdict167"></join>
         
               <p>38. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-33-defend283" type="defendantName">
                     Alice 
                     Gibson 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-33-defend283" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-defend283" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-defend283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380628-33-defloc163">St. John, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-33-defloc163" type="placeName" value="St. John, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-33-defloc163" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-33-defend283 t17380628-33-defloc163"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380628-33-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Watch and Chain, value 3 l. a Steel Seal set in Brass, value 1 d. and three Guineas, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-33-victim285" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Burwood 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-33-victim285" type="surname" value="Burwood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-33-victim285" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-33-victim285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-33-off164 t17380628-33-victim285"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17380628-33-person286">
                        John 
                        Gibson 
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-person286" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-33-person286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-33-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-33-cd165" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-33-off164 t17380628-33-cd165"></join>.</p>
               <p>Burwood. I had been to see a Consort on Board a Ship, and came back very much in Liquor. So being in Liquor, I met this Woman about Eleven o'Clock (last Friday 'twas a Week ago) and she carry'd me to her House, over against <placeName id="t17380628-33-crimeloc166">Gun-Dock</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-33-crimeloc166" type="placeName" value="Gun-Dock"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-33-crimeloc166" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-33-off164 t17380628-33-crimeloc166"></join>, and the we went to Bed: - Yes, I did lie with her all Night indeed; and we drank 3 Bowls of Bembow before we went to Bed, - that, to be sure, did not make me a bit soberer than I was before. About Five in the Morning I'waked, and miss'd my Bedfellow, that Party, there at the Bar, - and I found another Woman a-bed with me. My Watch and all my Money was gone, and another Party was in Bed. I am pretty sure there was but one Party a-bed with me at a Time. I am sure I had the Money with me when I came into this House; for I call'd at Mrs. Gaskin's as I came along, to change a Guinea, and she had no Change.</p>
               <p>Gaskin. Aye, my Name is Gaskin.</p>
               <p>Burwood. I came from Mrs. Gaskin's between 10 and 11 o'Clock, and Mrs. Gaskin's House is not above half a Mile from the Prisoner's, and I am sure I had my Watch and Money there.</p>
               <p>When I miss'd them in the Morning, I never spoke to the Party that I found in Bed with me; but I got up and went down Stairs, and asked the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280019"></xptr> Prisoner for my Watch, telling her, - I thought the Money was enough, - without taking Watch and Money too. She told me, - truly I pawn'd my Watch over-night for a Guinea. To whom? says I: Why to myself, says she, as for your Money, I have none of it. - As to what we drank before we went to bed, - there was I, and there was she at the Bar, - and the other Party; - we had a Sneaker of Bembow a-piece. The Prisoner told me, I should not have my Watch again, unless I paid her a Guinea; - but I paid her none, - I went to the Justice and took a Warrant to search for my Watch; and had her before the Justice; she told the Justice I had pawn'd the Watch for a Guinea to her, I told her I would give her the Guinea to have my Watch again; and then she said she must go Home and fetch it; but upon searching her in a publick House we found the Watch upon her. She said I deliver'd it to her as a Pledge, but I am sure I never pull'd it out of my Fob, while I was in her House. As to the Reckoning, there was 3 Shillings to pay, and as I had but three Guineas and one Shilling in my Pocket, I paid the Shilling for the first Bowl when it came in, - for 'tis the Custom of those Houses to make People pay as Liquor comes in, but as I had no more Silver, they trusted me 'till Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-33-person287">
                  Sarah 
                  Gaskin 
               <interp inst="t17380628-33-person287" type="surname" value="Gaskin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-person287" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Burwood is a Lodger of mine, and lay out that Night. When he came Home in the Morning, he told my Servants what had happened last Night, but he did not care I should know it. So he went to Mr. Edwards, the Headborough, and made his Complaint; and they got a search Warrant, and a Warrant for the Prisoner. When she was before the Justice, she insisted upon it, that the Watch was pledg'd to her, and refuss'd to deliver it without Burwood paid her a Guinea: He agreed to that, and Justice Cross's Clerk and the Constable went with her to fetch it; but 'twas a rainy Day, and they turn'd into an Alehouse, where the Clerk felt under her Arm, and there was the Watch.</p>
               <p>Headborough. This is the Watch that was taken from her Person. When the Prisoner made his Complaint to me, I went with him to Justice Cross, and he granted us a search Warrant, and a special Warrant, and I went to serve it, at the Prisoner's House. I asked her if she had not got the Man's Watch? She told me yes, and that the Man had pawn'd it to her for a Guinea. He refuss'd to pay the Guinea, so we carry'd her before the Justice, and he committed her. She said she knew nothing of his Money, but she offered me the Watch to keep, 'till he paid the Guinea.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Between 10 and 11 o'Clock that Night, I and another young Woman met the Prosecutor; and he asked if he should go Home with us? When we came Home, I asked him for Money: He said, he had no more than a Shilling and Two: pence Halfpenny; the Shilling he gave to me, and I fetch'd him Liquor for it. I asked him if he had any more Money (when the Liquor was drank.) He said no; but he pull'd out his Watch, and deliver'd it to me on the Bed-side. Next Morning between 4 and 5, he waked, and asked for the Watch. I told him I had it, and would give it him for a Guinea he had pledg'd it for. He made no Answer, but went out; and returned with another Man: I told them again, that there was 20 s. due upon it. Some of the Money was for Liquor, the rest I charge for his Night's Lodging. <rs id="t17380628-33-verdict167" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-33-verdict167" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
