<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360115-46">
               <interp inst="t17360115-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-46" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-46" type="date" value="17360115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360115-46-off261-c251" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-defend358 t17360115-46-off261 t17360115-46-verdict265"></join>
         
               <p>52. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360115-46-defend358" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Skinner 
                  <interp inst="t17360115-46-defend358" type="surname" value="Skinner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-defend358" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-defend358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17360115-46-defloc260">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-46-defloc260" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-46-defloc260" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-defend358 t17360115-46-defloc260"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360115-46-off261" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-off261" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-off261" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing 2 Quart Bottles of Brandy, 1 Quart of Rum, 1 Pint of Red Wine, 1 Pint of White Wine, 4 Bottles of Beer, and 2 Quarts of Cyder
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360115-46-victim360" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Brome 
                  <interp inst="t17360115-46-victim360" type="surname" value="Brome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-victim360" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-victim360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-off261 t17360115-46-victim360"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , the <rs id="t17360115-46-cd262" type="crimeDate">30th of May</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-off261 t17360115-46-cd262"></join> last.</p>
               <p>Councel. This Woman is indicted for stealing the things mentioned in the Indictment; the Prosecutor <rs id="t17360115-46-viclabel263" type="occupation">kept a Publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-victim360 t17360115-46-viclabel263"></join>, and the Prisoner was his <rs id="t17360115-46-deflabel264" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-46-defend358 t17360115-46-deflabel264"></join>. They were conveyed by her to the House of one Blagget, who lived at the next Door. Pray, Mr. Brome, give the Court an Account of this Affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-46-person361">
                  Rd 
                  Brome 
               <interp inst="t17360115-46-person361" type="surname" value="Brome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-person361" type="given" value="Rd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was not my Wife, but my Servant. she lived with me a Year and a Quarter at Mile-end Green. I had a good Trade, yet I run out; I entrusted her with every thing, and she embezzled my Goods: She went from me last June at which time I could prove nothing upon her. When I had had her before the Justice, she confessed taking the Goods mentioned; but there was no Confession taken in Writing, and these things were taken without my Knowledge-that's all.</p>
               <p>Councel. Aye - you are willing to be gone -  Pray, how came you first together? In what Manner did you live with her?</p>
               <p>Brome. She was recommended to me by Mr. Coombes, who had lived with her in a criminal way.</p>
               <p>Councel. And how did you live with her?</p>
               <p>Brome. As a Servant I paid her 6 l. - a Year</p>
               <p>Councel. Was not Part of the Goods in your House marked with her Name and yours?</p>
               <p>Brome. Yes.</p>
               <p>Councel. And how come you to mark your Goods with your Servant's Name?</p>
               <p>Brome. I was afraid of an Execution; so thought to make over some of my Goods to her.</p>
               <p>Councel. And had you no other Reason to mark your Goods so? Pray, how came you to sign this Paper?</p>
               <p>Brome. It was a voluntary Act of my own. The Case was this; - At that Time I was not capable of proving she had taken any thing from me.</p>
               <p>Councel. Why, this is a general Release.</p>
               <p>Brome. The Reason was this: Mr. Coombes, who kept her Company, and does so now, - she was with Child when she came to me, - He gave me Money to take her. - Some time after - about October last, there was some Discourse among them, and he took me into an Arbour, and asked me the Reason we could not agree; if we could not agree he said I must turn her away. Upon this -</p>
               <p>Coun. I fancy you was not so kind to her as you used to be?</p>
               <p>Brome. No, Sir, all Familiarity between us was then broke off, - and says I, What Mr. Coombes, have you been thereabouts since? Do you want me to father another Kid for you? -</p>
               <p>Councel. But why did you give her a general Release?</p>
               <p>Brome. I suspecting the Thing, taxed him with it, - I one Day discovered - don't dash one so! - there's no Occasion for it - she wanted to come to Bed to me; I would not suffer it, but thrust her down Stairs and hurt her shoulder. - I turned her away for this Reason, - I came into the Kitchen one Day, and saw something a Boiling, which I believe was to cause an Abortion. So, says I, - then you shall stay no longer here - No Murder in my House!</p>
               <p>Councel. How came you to know she was with Child?</p>
               <p>Brome, Mr. Coombes partly confessed it. - The Release was my own Act, and I did it because I wanted one from her. And now, Gentlemen, you have the Middle and both Ends on't.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173601150020"></xptr>Prisoner. Pray ask Mr. Brome if he agreed with me to be his Servant?</p>
               <p>Brome. I did agree to take her, and in that Condition: I believe the Bargain was made at Temple-Mills, - I had 23l. 10s. with her.</p>
               <p>Council. What was you to have 23l. 10s. to take her as a Servant? Was not you to father ther the Bastard?</p>
               <p>Brome. Yes.</p>


               <p>Blagget's Maid deposed, she received several Things mentioned in the Indictment over the into Blagget's House, and some the Prisoner brought herself under her Apron.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Some of these Things are set down to Mr. Blagget, as many as amount to 9s. 10d.</p>
               <p>- Earwood. When these two came together, they came on equal Terms; the Major part of the Goods her Friends put into the House, they come into the House together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-46-person362">
                  Thomas 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17360115-46-person362" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-person362" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I thought she had been his Servant, but the Money was advanced to buy Goods.</p>
               <p>Harris. Brome did say that if Mr. Coombes would give him a Bond for 20l. he would not prosecute her. Several others appeared, and swore they lived together as Man and Wife, and that she had the Charge of the Liquors. The Jury <rs id="t17360115-46-verdict265" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-46-verdict265" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
