<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-11">
               <interp inst="t17350116-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-11" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-11" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-11-off44-c64" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-11-defend84 t17350116-11-off44 t17350116-11-verdict48"></join>
         
               <p>11. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-defend84" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Ambrook 
                  <interp inst="t17350116-11-defend84" type="surname" value="Ambrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-defend84" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-defend84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17350116-11-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               Murder of her male Bastard Infant, by throwing it, as soon as born, out of a Window 2 Stories high, in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17350116-11-person85">
                        William 
                        Ambrook 
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person85" type="surname" value="Ambrook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-11-person85" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-11-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , upon the Tiles covering a Shed adjoining to the said House, and thereby giving the said Bastard one Mortal Bruise on the left Side of the Head, of which mortal Bruise he instantly dyed
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350116-11-cd45" type="crimeDate">December 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-11-off44 t17350116-11-cd45"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person86">
                  Samuel 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person86" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person86" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Standing at my Garden-Door in <placeName id="t17350116-11-crimeloc46">Crown-Alley in upper Moorfelds</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-11-crimeloc46" type="placeName" value="Crown-Alley in upper Moorfelds"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-11-crimeloc46" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-11-off44 t17350116-11-crimeloc46"></join>, on Saturday, about four in the Afternoon, I heard the Noise of a Window clapping to; upon which I went into the Garden and saw something lye upon Mr. Clark's Shed which joins to William Ambrook's House. I could not guess what it was, but I poked it down and laid it in the Alley, and then I perceiv'd that it was a New-born Child. I believe there was some Life in it, for I thought I saw the Body move. Several People came round it presently, and I staid four or five Minutes, or perhaps a Quarter of an Hour, and then it was taken away, and as I understood, was carried to the Watch-house. It was a Male Child. There is a Window over the Shed where I found the Child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person87">
                  Ann 
                  Ambrook 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person87" type="surname" value="Ambrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person87" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person87" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my Husband's Sister. She came to our House about Noon, and said she was extreamly ill for want of a Stool. I gave her some Stuff to make her go to stool, and then undrest her, and put her to Bed. I went up two Hours after, and found her standing upright in the Bed with her two Arms thus. She said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160005"></xptr> she was almost distracted for want of a Stool - I went up again at half an Hour past three, and then she said she was better and I saw no more of her till after the Misfortune; for about four I heard that a Child was flung out of the Window, but I did not go to see the Child till Monday, and then I saw it in the Watch-house. Nor did I go up to the Prisoner till the Constable came, and that was about five o'Clock. I found things in a disorderly Condition, with the Signs of a Delivery by the Bed-side. I had no Notion of her being with Child till I heard of a Child being thrown out of the Window, and then I concluded it must be hers, for the Room where she was has a Window that looks out upon the Shed where the Child was found. I asked her how she came to do such a thing, and she said, she did not know she did, for thro' the Extremity of Pain she thought the Room was on Fire when she threw it out - Before she came to our House, she lived a <rs id="t17350116-11-deflabel47" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-11-defend84 t17350116-11-deflabel47"></join> in the next Alley which is White-Cross Alley, with Mr. Pomeroy a Watch Maker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person88">
                  Peter 
                  Debrather 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person88" type="surname" value="Debrather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person88" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I am an English Man born and bred, but I have been a great many Years out of the Land, and dont very well understand English, but I will speak so well as I can. As I was into my Garden, I heard the People in the Alley, and one said, Pray come and see the Cruelness in this Alley; so I went, and looked upon my Watch, and it was half an Hour after four, and the People surrounded me, and pull'd me, and said, Why don't you search for the Mother? Whereup, I fetch my short staff, and charge this Gentlewoman, 
               <persName id="t17350116-11-person89">
                  Sarah 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person89" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person89" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person89" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to aid and assist; and so we went to Ann Ambrook's Door, and she said, You need not go any further, for here it is to my Sorrow. I asked her, where? and she told me above. Whereup, I being quicker than the Women, went up first, but I see such a Sight, that I run down so fast as I came up - and running down four or five Pair of Stairs.</p>
               <p>Court. Four or five Pair of Stairs?</p>
               <p>Debrather. I dont know how to call it, but it was four or five Steps - and then call'd in the two Women, Ann Ambrook and Sarah Newman, and put them forwards, and left them in the Room to take care of the Prisoner, while I went to the Church-Warden, and he brought a Midwife to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person90">
                  Joel 
                  Fremoult 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person90" type="surname" value="Fremoult"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person90" type="given" value="Joel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. The Church-Wardens of Shoreditch Parish sent for me to view the Child on Monday Evening; there was a large Contusion in the left side of the Head; I took off the Scalp, and found a large Quantity of extravastated and congeal'd Blood; there was no Fracture, for the Scull of so tender a Child is not properly Bone, but rather Grisle; but there was a Prohiberance in the Scull it self where the Bruise was: which I believe was the Cause of its death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person91">
                  Susan 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person91" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person91" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person91" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Pomeroy's House last Saturday, and there was the Prisoner's Sister who broke open the Prisoner's Trunk, in which we found this Child-bed Linnen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-11-person92">
                  Margaret 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17350116-11-person92" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person92" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-person92" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there at the same time, and saw this Linnen taken out. The Prisoner's Sister and Pomeroy's Maid produced a Key with which the Trunk was opened, but it was with a great deal to do.</p>
               <p>Susan Anderson, again. There was a Key put into the Lock, but it would not open it, and so it was forced open with a File.</p>
               <p>Then the Statute on which the Prisoner was Indicted, was read by order of Court.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17350116-11-verdict48" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-verdict48" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350116-11-punish49" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-11-punish49" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-11-defend84 t17350116-11-punish49"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
