<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381011-26">
               <interp inst="t17381011-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-26" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381011"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-26" type="date" value="17381011"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381011-26-off116-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-26-defend230 t17381011-26-off116 t17381011-26-verdict119"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381011-26-off116-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-26-defend232 t17381011-26-off116 t17381011-26-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>30, 31. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-defend230" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Reynolds 
                  <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend230" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend230" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-defend232" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Fletcher 
                  <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend232" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-defend232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17381011-26-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381011-26-victim234" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Blackwell 
                        <interp inst="t17381011-26-victim234" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-26-victim234" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-26-victim234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-26-off116 t17381011-26-victim234"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a Guinea
            </rs>, <rs id="t17381011-26-cd117" type="crimeDate">Sept. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-26-off116 t17381011-26-cd117"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person235">
                  Ann 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person235" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person235" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About 6 o'Clock at Night on the 21st of Sept. I went to Market to buy Meat for my Family, I carry'd out 25 s. and bought 16 lb. of Beef for half a Crown, and a Cabbage, but that I did not pay for; then I went to a House and had some strong Beer, for which I paid 3 d. and paying a Shilling I ow'd, I got the Woman of the House to give me a Guinea for 21 Shillings which Guinea I ty'd up in the Corner of the Handkerchief which was about my Neck, and thrust it between my Stays and my Gown, and then I had 6 d. left in Silver. As I was going Home thro' <placeName id="t17381011-26-crimeloc118">Drury Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381011-26-crimeloc118" type="placeName" value="Drury Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381011-26-crimeloc118" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-26-off116 t17381011-26-crimeloc118"></join> about 3 or 4 Doors from Broad St. Giles's, Fletcher knock'd me down with his Hand, &amp; ran away; and Reynolds came up and asked me if I had hurt myself, and whether I had any Money about me, I told her I had but a Guinea, and that was in the Corner of my Handkerchief. I was not 3 Minutes talking to her before Fletcher returned up, and held both my Arms, while Reynolds tore a Hole in the Corner of my Handkerchief, and got out the Guinea Then I cry'd out, - O my Guinea, my Guinea, she has robb'd me! Will no Body help me! Fletcher ran away, and she try'd to run away too, but I caught Hold of her, and cry'd out again, O, my Guinea, my Guinea! Upon this Fletcher return'd and said, D - mn you what do you want? - and knock'd me down again with his Hand. Reynolds then ran away about the length of this Court, but a Man ran after her and took her immediately, and brought her back to me. She was no sooner came up to me, but she fell upon me, and under Pretence of searching me to see if I had not got the Guinea, she tore off my Cloths in such a Manner, that the Women were forc'd to hold my Petticoats up about me, telling me, if I had 20 Guineas about me, she would have them all. At last a Constable was charged with Reynolds, and she said before the Justice, that she had not the Guinea. Fletcher was taken the Sunday following, and carry'd before Justice Margets, where he confessed he had got it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person236">
                  James 
                  Milbourn 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person236" type="surname" value="Milbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person236" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchmaker, and live at Mr. Jackson's a Cheesemonger in Drury-Lane, a little above Long-Acre. Long-Acre is almost half the Length of Drury Lane from Broad St. Giles's. The Thing was done over-against my Lodgings. On the 20th of last Month, between 7 and 8 at Night, I heard some Body cry out, - O my Guinea, - my Guinea! I look'd out of my Window up two Pair of Stairs, and saw a Woman with a Candle and Lanthorn, by the Light of which I could see Reynolds, with her Arms about Blackwell's Bosom, and a Man about Fletcher's Size, had hold of her Arms. As soon as Blackwell cry'd out, - Now she has got my Guinea, Reynolds made off, and the Man came up again and run Blackwell up against a Door, and asked her where she was going. But a Shoemaker happening to come by, took Reynolds and brought her back to Blackwell. Then I ran down Stairs, and found Reynolds very impudent, and a Constable carried her to Mr. Moulsey's in Drury-lane, and there she called Mrs. Blackwell, a dirty Bitch; and said, if I had Twenty Guineas, you should not have one of them. I search'd her, and found nothing upon her, - but we carried her before Justice Margets, and there she was audacious again, and said she knew nothing of it. I saw her do the Thing by the Light of the Candle and Lanthorn, and am positive to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>Milbourn. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you then swear to the Knowledge of her Face, when you say you saw her but by the Light of a Candle (in a Lanthorn) 2 Stories from the Ground?</p>
               <p>Milbourn. I came down Stairs as soon as she was stopp'd.</p>
               <p>Fletcher's Examination and Confession before Mr. Justice Margets, was produced.</p>
               <p>The Justice's Clerk. I saw Fletcher sign this; and Justice Margets signed it likewise. It was read over to him before he signed it, and - I believe - he signed it voluntarily; I won't say he had no Thoughts of being admitted an Evidence. I believe he was encouraged with a Probability of his being made an Evidence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173810110019"></xptr>The Confession was not read.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person237">
                  Alice 
                  Orford 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person237" type="surname" value="Orford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person237" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday, Sept. 20, I went to a Chandler's Shop, facing Parker's Lane, in Drury-Lane, and as I was coming out of the Shop with my Beer, I heard the Prosecutor, (who was then two Doors off) cry out, O my Guinea, - my Guinea! I sat down my Drink, and went to see what the Matter was. I looked at the Prosecutrix, and thought she could not have a Guinea about her by her Appearance, but some Body brought Reynolds back to her, and she said, - that was the Woman who had taken her Guinea Then Reynolds said, - you Bitch, where should you have a Guinea, let me see if I can find this Guinea about you, and she put her Hands down the Prosecutrix's Bosom and unty'd her Petticoats, but could not find the Money.</p>
               <p>After this the Woman Prisoner (Reynolds) went up Meeting-House-Court, facing Parkers-Lane, and came back again directly to the Prosecutrix, - there was no Thorough-fare in that Court, and the Mob was sufficient to prevent her getting away, and so she came back again of her own Accord to the Place where I first saw her. Fletcher stood by the Corner of the Court, but I can't say whether he was concerned or not.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Parkers-Lane from Long-Acre?</p>
               <p>Orford. About the length of this Court, not a great Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person238">
                  William 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person238" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I took Fletcher and carry'd him before Justice Margets, the Woman swore to him, and he said he could make a Confession. I can't say how it was obtained. Parkers-Lane is about 200 Yards from Broad St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person239">
                  Benjamin 
                  Worts 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person239" type="surname" value="Worts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person239" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             shewed the Handkerchief out of which the Guinea was taken.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person240">
                  Mary 
                  Shrub 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person240" type="surname" value="Shrub"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person240" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Pickerings the Brazier in Drury-Lane, on Wednesday was 3 Weeks, the Woman (Blackwell) was at my Landlord's Door, facing Parker's-Lane, and cry'd out, - she was robb'd. I asked her what was the Matter? She told me she was robb'd of a Guinea, and desired me to hold the Candle; I did so, and asked her if she knew the Person that robb'd her? yes, she said, perfectly well, then says I, was it such a one, or such a one? (holding the Candle to several People in the Croud) Among the rest, I asked her if the Prisoner Reynolds was the Person? No, she was not, 'twas a Man she said, that knock'd her down, and took her Money. On the Vertue of my Oath, she said so once or twice, and was so much in Liquor, that she had been dragg'd thro' the Kennel before I came. At last I asked her, - if I was the Person? - I believe she was so much in Liquor, she was not able to say who it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person241">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Waldron 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person241" type="surname" value="Waldron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person241" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Woman (Reynolds) the Character of an honest Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person242">
                  Susan 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person242" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person242" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Mary Shrub's Evidence, and added, that the Prisoner (Reynolds) when Shrub asked her who robb'd her, came up her self and ask'd her, if she had robb'd her? And the Prosecutrix said no; she could not see the Person in the Croud, who had done it. She could not say whether Blackwell was drunk or sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person243">
                  William 
                  Waldron 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person243" type="surname" value="Waldron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave Reynolds a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-26-person244">
                  Christian 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17381011-26-person244" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person244" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prosecutrix that Night in Bloomsbury, all over Dirt, - and as ragged as I am now. 'Twas pretty near the Fox Ale-house; and the Butcher that she bought her Beef of, was going with her, into the Ale-house. He ask'd her if she knew the Woman that had robb'd her. She told him it was a Man, - a little, short, thick Man, in a checquer'd Shirt; and a Woman (she said) was with him, but she shou'd not know her if she saw her.</p>
               <p>Fletcher. I had a checquer'd Shirt on, and so they took me: I have no Witnesses here but my self. Both <rs id="t17381011-26-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-26-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
