<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341016-2">
               <interp inst="t17341016-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-2" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-2" type="date" value="17341016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341016-2-off5-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-defend32 t17341016-2-off5 t17341016-2-verdict10"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-defend32" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Sword 
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-defend32" type="surname" value="Sword"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-defend32" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-defend32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , a <rs id="t17341016-2-deflabel4" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-defend32 t17341016-2-deflabel4"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17341016-2-off5" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-off5" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-off5" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting Christian, the <rs id="t17341016-2-viclabel6" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-victim35 t17341016-2-viclabel6"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17341016-2-person33">
                        William 
                        Clark 
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person33" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-2-person33" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-2-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her 27 Pewter Spoons, value 3 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17341016-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">Sept. 25.</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-off5 t17341016-2-cd7"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-victim35" type="victimName">
                     Christian 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-victim35" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-victim35" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-victim35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-off5 t17341016-2-victim35"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . About 3 in the Afternoon, as I was coming from the Pyed Bull, in <placeName id="t17341016-2-crimeloc8">May-Fair</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-crimeloc8" type="placeName" value="May-Fair"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-crimeloc8" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-off5 t17341016-2-crimeloc8"></join>, I was met in the Fields by the Prisoner and another Man. I had some Pewter Spoons in a Basket, and the Prisoner stopt me, and said, Damn your Blood, what do you sell such Spoons as these for? They are not good Metal, and so he took 2 Dozen and 2 from me, and gave them to his Companion, who went off with them, and I ran away: but the Prisoner follow'd me to <placeName id="t17341016-2-crimeloc9">Carnaby-Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-crimeloc9" type="placeName" value="Carnaby-Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-2-crimeloc9" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-2-off5 t17341016-2-crimeloc9"></join>, and abused me very much, and I cry'd out for my Life, and a Mob got about us; but for all that, he took another Spoon from me there Rolus Bolus, in the Presence of all the People.</p>
               <p>Court. When was this?</p>
               <p>Clark. I have forgotten the Day of the Month effegs; but it was about 3 Weeks ago, and upon my crying out, the Prisoner was taken and carry'd before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person36">
                  John 
                  Wing 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person36" type="surname" value="Wing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person36" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of September, I saw the Prisoner assault the Prosecutor in Carnaby-Street, and she hung by his Arm, and cry'd, and said he had robb'd her in May-Fair, and she wanted a Constable; and I saw him take one Spoon out of her Basket. He pretended her Spoons were bad Metal, and that she has no Power to sell them, because she had not got a Licence to hawk them. I took the Spoon out of his Hand, and advised him to make her Satisfaction for the Spoons he had taken from her in May-Fair, and so to go about his Business, and not oblige her to prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person37">
                  Edward 
                  Greenwell 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person37" type="surname" value="Greenwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person37" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner take the Spoon from her at a Tin sho Door in Carnaby Street; Mr Wing advised him to make her Satisfaction; but he refused, and so he was carry'd before Justice Lambert, where he was required to discover his Companion. He said he knew where he was, but he would not tell us.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I saw this Woman first by the Turn-Stile in Band street she sighed, and said, she had been at the Pyed Bull, an there they had broke her of two Dozen of Spoons. What Spoons? says I. And then she shew'd me one. I ask'd her the Price, and she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160003"></xptr> told me 18 d. a Dozen. I let her know that I belong'd to the Trade, and if the Spoons were good Metal, and she came honestly by them, she could not afford to sell them at that Price. Whereupon she run away, and I afterwards happen'd to call in at a Gin-shop in Carnaby-Market, and while I was there, this Woman came by, and so I goes to her, to know what Authority she had to hawk such Goods. You are one of the Rogues that sells Buttons about the Streets, says she, and then she flew upon me, and struck me in the Face, and then taking up one of her Spoons, she said, See here, you Rogue, here is my Spoon, I neither stole it nor is it bad Metal; and what has such a Rogue as you to do with it? I took the Spoon out of her Hand to look at it, and then John Wing said, Now by God she shall swear a Robbery against you. A great Mob gather'd about us, and they took her part more than mine, and so I was carry'd before Justice Lambert, and committed to the Round-house. As for what she says of the 2 Dozen of Spoons, I never touched 'em, for I meddled with none but that one Spoon as she shewed me in Carnaby-Market.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person38">
                  Elizabeth
                   Mac Claghan
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person38" type="surname" value="Mac Claghan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person38" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person38" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor sold two Spoons to a Woman at my Cellar-door for 6 d. and two old Spoons. I said it was too dear, upon which the Prosecutor swore that I stole some Spoons out of her Basket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person39">
                  Susan 
                  Cullimore 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person39" type="surname" value="Cullimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person39" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person39" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came into the Pyed-Bull at May Fair, and would have sworn that one of the Men there had robb'd her of 3 Dozen of Spoons.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person40">
                  Andrew 
                  Tate 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person40" type="surname" value="Tate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person40" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 18 or 20 Years, I am a Brasier, and I have trusted him in my Shop 8 Years, and always found him very honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person41">
                  William 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person41" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person41" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He work'd for me from Midsummer to Christmas, and then he went to Mr. Gaskin - He behav'd himself very well in my Service.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person42">
                  John 
                  Gaskin 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person42" type="surname" value="Gaskin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He work'd with me 3 Months, he lay in my Shop; and I trusted him with all my Goods, but never mist any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-2-person43">
                  Richard 
                  Hodgins 
               <interp inst="t17341016-2-person43" type="surname" value="Hodgins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person43" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Serjeant. The Prisoner has been 8 Years in Colonel Skelton's Company, in the third Regiment of Foot Guards. He has likewise served Captain Lendsey, Captain Strode, and Captain Godard; who have all trusted him, and have all said they found him very honest.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341016-2-verdict10" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-2-verdict10" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
