<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-47">
               <interp inst="t17350116-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-47" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-47" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-47-off199-c197" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-defend300 t17350116-47-off199 t17350116-47-verdict203"></join>
         
               <p>50. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-47-defend300" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Heybourn , alias <rs id="t17350116-47-alias-9" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-defend300 t17350116-47-alias-9"></join>Habron</rs>, alias <rs id="t17350116-47-alias-10" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-defend300 t17350116-47-alias-10"></join>Williams</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-defend300" type="surname" value="Heybourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-defend300" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-defend300" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350116-47-off199" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-off199" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-off199" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entring the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350116-47-victim302" type="victimName">
                           Michael 
                           Mullington 
                        <interp inst="t17350116-47-victim302" type="surname" value="Mullington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-47-victim302" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-47-victim302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-off199 t17350116-47-victim302"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and stealing a Silver Tankard value 6 l. a Silver Mug value 50 s. and four Silver Spoons value 30 s. <rs id="t17350116-47-cd200" type="crimeDate">December 14</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-off199 t17350116-47-cd200"></join>. in the Night
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-47-person303">
                  Michael 
                  Mullington 
               <interp inst="t17350116-47-person303" type="surname" value="Mullington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person303" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17350116-47-viclabel201" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17350116-47-crimeloc202">three Cups in Bedford Street near Bedford Row in Holbourn</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-crimeloc202" type="placeName" value="three Cups in Bedford Street near Bedford Row in Holbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-crimeloc202" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-off199 t17350116-47-crimeloc202"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-victim302 t17350116-47-viclabel201"></join>. I got up about seven in the Morning, found my Cup-board wrench'd open and mist my Plate. One Mr. Johnson came to my House to enquire for Mrs. Thomas, who lived next Door to me, and told me, that a Woman had offer'd such Plate as he had heard I had lost, to a Pawn-broker, but he had stopt it and she was sent to St. Martin's Round house. I went to her at last and she confest that she hid her self in my Club-Room 'till the Family was all abed, and then wrench'd open my Cup-board, and took the Mug and Spoons from thence, and the Tankard off the Table, and then unbolted the Back-door which she left open, and so went away about four in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-47-person304">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17350116-47-person304" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person304" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Reynold a Pawn broker in Hart-Street, Covent-Garden. An Old Woman who lives at Mr. Johnson's, brought this Tankard and two Spoons to me, to be pledged as from him. I stept over to Mr. Johnson, and he told me that he knew nothing of it, any farther than that it was sent by a Woman who accidentally called at his House. I carried this Account to my Master, and thereupon he refused to meddle with the Plate. Mr. Johnson came over not long after, and said she offer'd to pawn it to him for a Guinea, and would sell it outright next Day. My Master advised him not to be concern'd in it, but to get a Constable, and take her up upon Suspicion. Accordingly we went and stopt her as she was going away with the Plate in her Apron. She said it was given her by her Aunt Hastings who was a Captain's Widow and lived in the Trinity Alms-houses at Mile-End. She was carried to the Round-house, and afterwards before the justice. She confest that the Plate was the Prosecutor's and that she hid her self in his House 'till the Family was abed and then forced open the Cup-board, and took the Plate, and let her self out at the Back-doors.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tickeridge. Between twelve and one at noon, Mr. Johnson sent for me and said there was a Woman in his House that offer'd to pawn a Tankard with him for a Guinea. I told him I suspected the Plate was stolen and advised him to apprehend her. As I was standing in my Shop she came out of his House with the Plate in her Lap. I stopt her, and said Mistress you han't paid your Reckoning. What do ye mean by that? says she, you're an impudent Fellow - She was carried before the Justice, and sent to the Round-house where the Prosecutor found her. Afterwards before Justice Hilder she confest that she conceal'd her self in Mullinton's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160013"></xptr> Club Room, and in the Night took the Tankard off the Table, and wrench'd open the Cupboard-door, and took from thence the rest of the Plate, and then opened the Back-door and got out between four and five in the Morning. She went by two Names, Williams and Hephourn, and she said that her Husband was a Soldier in the Scotch Guards in the Barracks at the Tower, and that he often beat her to make her do such things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-47-person305">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17350116-47-person305" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person305" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A little before six in the Morning the Prisoner came to my House in Hart-Street. I keep a Chandler's Shop. She called for a Quartern of Liquor and paid me three Pence for it, tho' she did not drink a Spoonfull of it, but she had some Coffee. She complain'd of being greatly fatigued with sitting up three Nights with her Aunt at Mile-End, and coming from thence in the Rain, for it was a very wet Morning; but she said her Aunt had done better for her than she expected, and had left her some Plate. She shew'd me a Silver Tankard, a Silver Mug and four Silver Spoons, and said, she wanted a little present Money upon some of them. My Servant carried the Tankard and two Spoons to Mr. Reynold, upon which she was taken up. When she was in the Round-house, I asked her if she had Friends, she said Yes, Mrs. Thomas at a Box-makers, the Corner of Gray's-Inn-Passage. I went thither, but could not find her. But I went into the Three Cups and called for a Pint of Beer, which happened to be the Prosecutor's House. I told 'em a Woman was taken up with a Parcel of Plate which I believed to be stolen. The Landlord went with me to the Round-house. The Prisoner was carried before the Justice, and the Prosecutor swore to the Tankard, the Mug and three Spoons, but was not positive to the fourth, because he had some Plate with his Second Wife, and did not very well know the Marks of it. Upon which, the Prisoner said, They are all your's Mr. Mullington. I hid my self in your Club-room, and when you were abed I took the Tankard off and all the rest out of the Cup-board.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say, but that I have been very silly in what I have done.</p>
               <p>The Jury found her <rs id="t17350116-47-verdict203" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-verdict203" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350116-47-punish204" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-47-punish204" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-47-defend300 t17350116-47-punish204"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
