<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-38">
               <interp inst="t17341204-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-38" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-38" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-38-off194-c192" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-defend273 t17341204-38-off194 t17341204-38-verdict199"></join>
         
               <p>37. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-defend273" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Bell 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-defend273" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-defend273" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-defend273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-38-off194" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-off194" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-off194" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch value 10 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-victim275" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Tireman 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-victim275" type="surname" value="Tireman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-victim275" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-victim275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-off194 t17341204-38-victim275"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17341204-38-cd195" type="crimeDate">October 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-off194 t17341204-38-cd195"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tireman. As I was going with my Nephew Dawson, betwixt the <placeName id="t17341204-38-crimeloc196">Old Change</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-crimeloc196" type="placeName" value="Old Change"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-crimeloc196" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-off194 t17341204-38-crimeloc196"></join> and <placeName id="t17341204-38-crimeloc197">St. Paul's Church-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-crimeloc197" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Church-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-38-crimeloc197" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-off194 t17341204-38-crimeloc197"></join> about 4 o'Clock in the Afternoon of my Lord Mayor's Day; we were hussel'd about by 3 or 4 Fellows till I was almost out of Breath. When I came to the Trunkmakers at the Corner of Cheapside<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040017"></xptr>I miss'd my Watch, and turning back, and speaking of it, I met one 
               <persName id="t17341204-38-person276">
                  William 
                  Beck 
               <interp inst="t17341204-38-person276" type="surname" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person276" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said he had taken particular Notice of a tall Fellow in a Cape-Coat who was gone towards the Old Change; and perceiving a great Crowd about the Swan Tavern Passage, I stept forward in hopes of finding some of the Fellows that hussl'd me; but being a little behind he hipp'd to me and said, pointing to the Prisoner, There goes the Man that has got your Watch; the Prisoner was in a Cape Coat and red Breeches: I suppose he heard what was said, for he presently mended his Pace, we follow'd and seized him by the Nag's-head Tavern-Door. Ye Dog, says I where's my Watch. Presently the Watch was dropp'd and Beck took it up, and said Here is your Watch, I had like to have catch'd it; and so he gave it me all dirty. We carry'd the Prisoner to the Star Alehouse, and afterwards before a Justice, but he would confess nothing.</p>
               <p>W. Beck. As I was standing with my Shop-Mates by the Pastrycook's Shop at the End of Cheapside to see my Lord Mayor's Show, a Crowd of Men came thrusting along. Says my Mate, That tall Fellow there in a Cape-Coat looks like a Pick-Pocket. The Mob turn'd back towards the Old Change, and the Prosecutor turn'd about too and said he had lost his Watch. I went back with him, a great many crouded into the Swan Passage but could not get thro', and so they came out again. The Prisoner was in a Cape Coat. I pointed to him and others and said, There they go by the Joyner's Stand. We follow'd and the Prosecutor took hold of the Prisoner by the Nag's-head Tavern; but the Prisoner was not that Man in the Cape Coat that I saw at first, but there was another Man close by who turn'd about and run, and just as he turn'd I felt something hit against my Foot. I stoop'd down and found it was the Watch.</p>
               <p>Court. Did the Watch fall from the Prisoner, or the other Man?</p>
               <p>Beck. They had both Cape Coats. The Prisoner stood at my Left Hand. I held him by the Right Shoulder, and the Prosecutor held him on the other Side, and the Watch fell at my Right Foot a Yard from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Court. If the other Man had taken the Watch, is it likely that he would follow the Prosecutor with it, stand quietly by him, and then throw it away when he was not in Custody, nor so much as suspected.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-person277">
                  John 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-38-person277" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person277" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner in a Cape Coat and red Breeches and two or three more Men husseled me, and my Uncle Mr. Tireman so that they could not go one Way or other for 2 or 3 Minutes, and then they went back and Mr. Tireman miss'd his Watch. The People said those Fellows had been larking about for 2 or 3 Hours, we follow'd them. Beck told us they were at the Swan Door; my Uncle and I passed the Prisoner without minding him, but Beck hipped and said, There goes the Man up the Old Change. The Prisoner then mended his Pace. We pursued, and Mr. Tireman and I collered him; Beck was then a little behind us, and no body else was near us. When Beck came up, I did not indeed see the Prisoner drop the Watch, but I saw his Hand under his Coat, and presently Beck stoop'd and took the Watch up from between the Prisoner's Legs. and said, Here's your Watch, I had like to have taken it before it fell to the Ground.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There was a hundred Mob about us.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dawson. There was no body, before the Watch was drop'd, but Mr. Tireman and I, and Beck and the Prisoner; but presently afterwards the People gathered about us. We carry'd the Prisoner into the Star Passage, where 2 or 3 Fellows would have rescued him; but a Gentleman drew his Sword and made 'em keep off.</p>
               <p>[Then Beck was called in again, for the Witnesses were examined apart.]</p>
               <p>Court. Where did the other Man in the Cape Coat stand.</p>
               <p>Beck. At my Right Hand, the same Side as the Watch fell.</p>
               <p>Court. Who else did you see there when the Watch was dropt?</p>
               <p>Beck. There was a Mob of 20 People about us, and they were going to seize him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040018"></xptr>Court. For what? Did any body charge him?</p>
               <p>Beck. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Where was Mr. Dawson then?</p>
               <p>Beck. I don't remember that I saw him till we came into the Star Alehouse, nor that I saw him before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dawson. I had hold of the Prisoner. There was no Man in a Cape Coat but the Prisoner, and I was with him before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tireman. Mr. Dawson was with me when I lost my Watch, when we took the Prisoner, when we were at the Ale-house, and before the Justice. There was no Man in a Cape Coat but the Prisoner, nor any body near us when the Watch was dropt.</p>
               <p>Court. Beck! What Business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Beck. I am a Cabinet-maker, I work in Baldwin's Gardens.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have Witnesses to my Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-person278">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-38-person278" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person278" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I keep the White Bear Inn in Gray's-Inn Lane. I have known the Prisoner 9 or 10 Years; he sets his Horse up at my House; he goes in the Country for two or three Months, and buys Woollen Cloth; he is a <rs id="t17341204-38-deflabel198" type="occupation">Cloth-worker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-38-defend273 t17341204-38-deflabel198"></join> by Trade and has a very honest Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-person279">
                  John 
                  Copeland 
               <interp inst="t17341204-38-person279" type="surname" value="Copeland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Taylor, and have work'd for him; he's a very honest Man as can be in the World; I have known him eight or nine Years.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Copeland. And I can say the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-38-person280">
                  Richard 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17341204-38-person280" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person280" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five or six Years; I have dealt with him for Yorkshire Cloth - the last Parcel I bought was at this Lady [Elizabeth Johnson's] House; it came to 14 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baker. I have known him three Years, and never heard a Character of him to his Prejudice. I have dealt with him for Cloth to the value of about 20 l.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-38-verdict199" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-38-verdict199" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
