<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390906-37">
               <interp inst="t17390906-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-37" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390906-37" type="date" value="17390906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390906-37-off170-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-37-defend271 t17390906-37-off170 t17390906-37-verdict173"></join>
         
               <p>469. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390906-37-defend271" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17390906-37-defend271" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-defend271" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-defend271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390906-37-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, val. 50 s. from the Person of 
                     <persName id="t17390906-37-person272">
                        Richard 
                        Summer 
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person272" type="surname" value="Summer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-37-person272" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390906-37-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17390906-37-cd171" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-37-off170 t17390906-37-cd171"></join>.</p>
               <p>Richard Summer. On the 29th of July I met the Prisoner in <placeName id="t17390906-37-crimeloc172">Well Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-37-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="Well Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390906-37-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390906-37-off170 t17390906-37-crimeloc172"></join>, between Charterhouse-Lane and Long-Lane, and she ask'd me to make her drink; so she pick't me up, and carry'd me to a House, and we went up Stairs: I staid an Hour with her, drinking Gin, and when I came down Stairs, I found she had pick'd my Pocket of my Watch. She was a Stranger to me, but yet I would go and drink with her, and I had my Watch when I went into the House with her, for I look'd to see what it was a Clock, when I was about 3 or 400 Yards from the Door. While we were above Stairs together, we only sat talking together, - she on one Chair, and I on another, we and after we had talk'd and drank together, we came down Stairs, and in the Entry she pick'd the Watch out of my Fob; - 'twas not in the Room, - 'twas in the Entry, and I felt her Hand in the Pocket when she took it out: As soon as she had pull'd it away from me, she ran into another House: I did not cry, Stop Thief, but I ran after her, and could not overtake her before she got into the House; and when I enquired for her at that House, the People told me there was no such Woman there. About 10 Days afterward I took her, and she was carry'd before the Lord Mayor, who committed her to Newgate; when she was before him, she deny'd the Fact.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He says he was in a Room with me, up one Pair of Stairs, - 'tis a Ground room of mine, where I have liv'd these two Years: He was above Stairs indeed, in a Room next Door to me, where there is only two Stools, and a Chair. He put another Woman in the Warrant with me, and he keeps her out of the Way, and prosecutes me, because my Name's Allen, and I threw a Pot of Water in his Face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390906-37-person273">
                  Esther 
                  Rawlins 
               <interp inst="t17390906-37-person273" type="surname" value="Rawlins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person273" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day the Prisoner was carried to my Lord Mayor's, they had no hearing, so they went to Guild-hall to have a Hearing there, and they call'd in at an Alehouse by Guildhall: One Moll Gunn was with us, who had (caused) this 
               <persName id="t17390906-37-person274">
                  Bess 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17390906-37-person274" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person274" type="given" value="Bess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (to be) taken up; and Moll Gunn said to the Prosecutor, - if he did not swear directly that this Bess Allen had the Watch, Bess would do her a Mischief; upon which he said he would swear it downright, because she should not hurt her. In the next Place there is Bess Barnes, who says this Gentleman was robb'd in her Entry, by 
               <persName id="t17390906-37-person275">
                  Betty 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17390906-37-person275" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person275" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - by the same Token he said he would swear downright to her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He promised to fetch Moll Gunn's Gown out of Pawn; he treated her with a Dinner every Day at the Cat Alehouse in Charterhouse-Lane, to keep out of the Way.</p>
               <p>Summer. This Woman (Rawlins) was the very Person that impeach'd the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Rawlins. The last Time the Prosecutor gave Gunn a Dinner, she was angry that I came to take a Bit with them, and he would not let me.</p>
               <p>Summer. I did not hinder you.</p>
               <p>Rawlins. She (Moll Gunn) said she could do his Business for him, in swearing against this Woman, and now she's run away.</p>
               <p>Summer. This Woman came after me to the Cat, and said she could swear it upon her; she was the Person who pawn'd the Watch. <rs id="t17390906-37-verdict173" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390906-37-verdict173" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
