<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-14">
               <interp inst="t17380628-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-14" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-14" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-14-off71-c100" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-off71 t17380628-14-verdict73"></join>
         
               <p>16. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-defend129" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret
                      Poland, of <placeName id="t17380628-14-defloc69">St. Mary, Whitechappel</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-defloc69" type="placeName" value="St. Mary, Whitechappel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-defloc69" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-defloc69"></join>, otherwise <rs id="t17380628-14-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-alias-2"></join>
                        Margaret
                         the 
                        <rs id="t17380628-14-deflabel70" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-deflabel70"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17380628-14-person130">
                              James 
                              Mayfield 
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person130" type="surname" value="Mayfield"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person130" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                     </rs>; otherwise <rs id="t17380628-14-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-alias-3"></join>Margaret the Wife of 
                           <persName id="t17380628-14-person131">
                              James
                              <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280009"></xptr> Tweed<interp inst="t17380628-14-person131" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                     </rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17380628-14-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-alias-4"></join>Irish Peg</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17380628-14-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-alias-5"></join>Margaret the Wife of 
                           <persName id="t17380628-14-person132">
                              John 
                              Fosset 
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person132" type="surname" value="Fosset"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                     </rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17380628-14-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-defend129 t17380628-14-alias-6"></join>Margaret the Wife of 
                           <persName id="t17380628-14-person133">
                              Charles 
                              Poland 
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person133" type="surname" value="Poland"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person133" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17380628-14-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-defend129" type="surname" value="Poland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-defend129" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-defend129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, <rs id="t17380628-14-off71" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-off71" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-off71" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               for that 
                     <persName id="t17380628-14-person134">
                        Mary 
                        Haley 
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person134" type="surname" value="Haley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-14-person134" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-14-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , having stolen a flower'd Mantua Silk Gown, value 23 s. May 29, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-14-victim136" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Draper 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-14-victim136" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-14-victim136" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-14-victim136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-off71 t17380628-14-victim136"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Shop, she the said Poland, the same did receive, knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-14-cd72" type="crimeDate">May 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-14-off71 t17380628-14-cd72"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Record of Haley's Conviction was read.</p>
               <p>Thomas Draper deposed as in the foregoing Trial.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person137">
                  Jane 
                  Draper 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person137" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person137" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of May I had six Gowns stole out of my Shop, all at once; upon which I went down Rosemary-Lane, to describe them to the Shop-keepers, and there I saw the Prisoner delivering the Gown out of her Apron to another Person, in a Hugger Mugger Manner. I charg'd the Prisoner with having got my Goods; D - mn your Eyes (said she) did you see any with me? I told her yes, and went for an Officer; when I return'd, she was gone; but I found her in Harris, the Thief-taker's House, who is her Bail. She was eating with Harris's Wife, and as soon as she saw me, she d - mn'd my Eyes, and ask'd me what I could prove against her? I told her, I had seen my Goods upon her. But what (says she) can you prove upon me now? I took hold of her, and tho' she beat me and bit me, I got her into an Alehouse; and there she said, I should not have the Gown, unless I gave her the Money; at last she sent for it, but would not deliver it, till I had paid her for it. Then she went out, and returned with Harris the Constable; now d - mn you (says she) charge him with me, or I will charge him with you. Harris asked me if I had got a Warrant? I told him no; then lay down the Goods, says he. I did so, and he bid the Prisoner take them up, which she did, and fell to tearing it, and wiping the Table with it, telling me it was her own, and d - mn her Eyes, she would do what she pleas'd with it. When she was before the Justice, she cry'd and begg'd for two or three Days Liberty, that she might find out the Thief. I gave a Week, and at the End of that Time she brought the Girl to me. I look'd at the Girl, and said, I was sorry if she was guilty, for I have Children of my own. The Girl is a poor Match-Girl, and 'tis not likely she should have such a Gown to dispose of fairly, for 6 s. 6 d. The Prisoner I have seen standing in the Street with common Thieves; and she liv'd with a noted Thief, one Fosset, and sold the Goods he stole.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You know you have got two Husbands in the Lane; pray do you know that I have as many Husbands as you have laid in the Indictment?</p>
               <p>Draper. Not so many Husbands, - but a hundred Fellows. You had two but the Night before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person138">
                  Phillis 
                  Waldon 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person138" type="surname" value="Waldon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person138" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner have the Gown in her Lap.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own it; I bought it fairly in the open Street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person139">
                  Mary 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person139" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person139" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near the Place which the Creature, and the Thieves she deals with, frequent. There were two Fellows hang'd for her, a little while ago. I saw her have the Gown in her Apron, and 'twas worth 20 s. to have sold it again. I keep a Shop myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person140">
                  William 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person140" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person140" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I took Charge of the Girl, and had her before the Justice, where she own'd she stole the Gown.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Girl came down the Street, with the Gown upon her Arm, and said it was to be sold. I bid her 5 s. 6 d. and 6 s. for it. At last I told her, if she would bring any Body to say it was honestly come by, I would give her 6 s. and 6 d. for it. When I offer'd it to Sale, I ask'd no more than 8 s. and 6 d. for it. The Girl told me she liv'd in East-Smithfield, and that her Mother was just gone down Rag Fair; she went after her, to bring her to me, and I follow'd her, but the People told me, I need not scruple it, for the Girl was very honest. When they claim'd it, I offer'd it them for 6 s. and 6 d. - I was not willing to lose so much Money; but I did lose it, and a Shilling beside, for the Discharge of the Warrant. The Husband of the Woman beat and abused me, and when they were inform'd I was going to Law with them, they arrested me for 4 l. 10 s. I got Bail, and the next Day they took me up upon this Affair.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Sturt. The Prisoner bought this Gown in Rosemary-Lane, and that's a Place to buy such Things in. She agreed to give the Girl 6 s. 6 d. for it, if she could tell her whose it was. The Girl said 'twas her Mother's, and that she liv'd in East Smithfield, and was just gone down Rosemary-Lane. The Prisoner offer'd it me for 8 s. She said it was worth more for the Credit and Service 'twould do. My Husband is an Instrument-maker in Rosemary Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person141">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person141" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person141" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner gave 6 s. 6 d. for it, and went down the Fair to call her Mother; but she returned, and said, her Mother was taken sick, and was gone out of the Fair, so the Prisoner gave her the Money.</p>
               <p>Jere. Listen. I keep an Alehouse in Rosemary-Lane. When the Girl was taken, Mrs. Draper was sent for; so (said she to the Girl) you little B - ch, is it you that have robbed me? and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280010"></xptr> turning to the Prisoner, she said, - Peg, I am not willing to do the Girl any harm, for I don't know what my own Children may come to; and when we come before the Justice, I won't say any Thing, nor don't you, Peg.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person142">
                  Sarah 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person142" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person142" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17380628-14-person143">
                  Ann 
                  Dobson 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person143" type="surname" value="Dobson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person143" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spoke to the same Effect with 
               <persName id="t17380628-14-person144">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person144" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person144" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person145">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Goughton 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person145" type="surname" value="Goughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person145" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Prisoner a good Character, and confirm'd some Part of Lister's Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-14-person146">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17380628-14-person146" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person146" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I had the Prisoner before Mr. Justice Farmer, and she was discharged at the Request of Mrs. Draper. She said then, - We are all Dealers in a publick Way; and they do buy of Children that are sent out with Things I have seen Children of 8 or 9 Years old sell Things of considerable Value. When she was taken up a 2d Time, she said, - we are all subject to buy Things in this misfortunate Way, I have done it myself; and I should not have troubled myself about it, if Mr. Andrews had not sent me a Letter, to inform me he had Orders to sue me for an Assault; but if any one attempts to put out one of my Eyes, I will put out one of theirs.</p>
               <p>John Brown. The Gown to be sure is worth more than she gave for it; and our Dealers won't give above half Value for Things 'Tis worth more Money than I can 'praise it to; in our Business I think 'tis worth about eight Shillings. <rs id="t17380628-14-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-14-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
