<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-29">
               <interp inst="t17360721-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-29" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-29" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-29-off141-c152" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-29-defend227 t17360721-29-off141 t17360721-29-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-29-defend227" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Phillips 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-29-defend227" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-defend227" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-defend227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of Fulham, was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-29-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Mare of an Iron-grey Colour, value 6 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-29-victim229" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Millet 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-29-victim229" type="surname" value="Millet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-victim229" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-victim229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-29-off141 t17360721-29-victim229"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17360721-29-cd142" type="crimeDate">July 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-29-off141 t17360721-29-cd142"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Millet. My Stable was broke open early in the Morning, July 6, and an Iron-grey Mare, Bridle and Saddle were stollen. I cannot say the Prisoner took her; but I found her at the pewter Platter in St. John's Street; but I have got my Mare again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-29-person230">
                  William 
                  Enmery 
               <interp inst="t17360721-29-person230" type="surname" value="Enmery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between one and two o'Clock in the Morning, July 6, the Prisoner came with the Mare to my Master's House: He called me up, and ordered her a Feed of Corn; I live at the Barley Mow, near Kent street Turnpike. I unlocked the Stable Door, and turn'd her in. He told me he had rid 60 Miles since 10 o'Clock last Night: I felt under the Saddle, and the Mare was but just warm; she was not heated at all, so I thought it impossible he should have come so far. He asked me to let him go to bed, and I let him lie in my Bed with my two little Children. In the Morning, when the Children got up, he sent them down Stairs to order another Feed of Corn; and while they were gone, he opened my Box, which was in the Chamber, robbed me of my Money and Watch, and then he went away with the Mare.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. I was Hostler at the pewter Platter: And last Tuesday was Fortnight, the Prisoner came with the Mare, about 8 or 9 o'Clock in the Morning. Hostler, Hostler, says he, take my Mare: I rubbed her down, and he gave me a Pint of Beer. Afterwards Mr. Millet came, and took this very Mare out of the Stable, and said it was his.</p>
               <p>Millet. I swear 'tis my Mare.</p>
               <p>Defence. I made no Operations in taking the Mare: I did not break the Stable, nor take the Mare. It was a young Man who used to go with me to Emmery's House; he told me what he was going about, and I have had no Friends this 17 Years, 'till I kept Company with this young Man. I am but 17 Years old, and never wronged any body in my Life before <rs id="t17360721-29-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17360721-29-punish144" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-29-punish144" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-29-defend227 t17360721-29-punish144"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
