<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-37">
               <interp inst="t17351210-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-37" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-37" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-37-off151-c154" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-37-defend231 t17351210-37-off151 t17351210-37-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>47. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-defend231" type="defendantName">
                     Anna Maria 
                     Thorn 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-37-defend231" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-defend231" type="given" value="Anna Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-defend231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , <rs id="t17351210-37-deflabel150" type="occupation">the Elder</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-37-defend231 t17351210-37-deflabel150"></join>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17351210-37-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351210-37-victim233" type="victimName">
                           Anna Maria 
                           Thorn 
                        <interp inst="t17351210-37-victim233" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-37-victim233" type="given" value="Anna Maria"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-37-victim233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-37-off151 t17351210-37-victim233"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , the Younger, aged fifteen Years, by shutting her up in a cold Room in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17351210-37-person234">
                        John 
                        Falkner 
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person234" type="surname" value="Falkner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-37-person234" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-37-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100010"></xptr> silk Dyer, and there keeping her from March the twenty fifth till November the seventh following, without Fire, sufficient Meat, Drink, and other Things, necessary to nourish and preserve her Life, for want of which Necessaries, she languished from the said twenty fifth of March, to the said seventh of November, and then miserably perished and died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person235">
                  Thomas 
                  Falkner 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person235" type="surname" value="Falkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person235" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Corner of the <placeName id="t17351210-37-crimeloc152">Roll's Buildings in Fetter lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-37-crimeloc152" type="placeName" value="Roll's Buildings in Fetter lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-37-crimeloc152" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-37-off151 t17351210-37-crimeloc152"></join>. A Fortnight after Lady-Day, the Prisoner came to lodge at my House, with her three Daughters, Dorothy the eldest, Charlotte the second, and Anna Maria the Deceased, who was youngest, and about fifteen Year's old. They staid till November following, when 
               <persName id="t17351210-37-person236">
                  Anna 
                  Maria 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person236" type="surname" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person236" type="given" value="Anna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             died. In two or three Days after they came, my Wife, and Maid, told me they miss Victuals out of the Closet, and watching to see how it went, saw the Deceased come out of the Closet. I ordered the Cupboard Door to be locked, and then she came to them, and asked for Victuals, and said she was almost starved. I bid my Wife give her some Bread and Cheese, or Butter - It was five or six Weeks after this, the Deceased complained she had had no Victuals for two Days, but a Bit of Liver. I willing to examine into the Matter, peeped through a Slit in the Partition, and saw the Prisoner and Miss Dony [Dorothy] sitting at Dinner, and Miss Charlotte, and the Deceased standing by them, trembling. The Prisoner gave the Deceased a Bit of Bread, and about half an Ounce of Meat. I looked another time when they had pickled Pork for Dinner, and after the Pork was taken away, the Deceased had a Bit of cold Liver, as big as my two Fingers. When her Mother gave her Victuals, she commonly used to eat it cautiously; but eating this Liver more eagerly, her Mother knocked her on the Shoulder, and said, Hussy! how you cram it in?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever expostulate with the Prisoner for using her Child thus?</p>
               <p>Falkner. I did speak to her about it once; and she told me I was a lying Scoundrel. I did not expect such an Answer, for excepting in this Case, she was as civil a Woman as ever came into a House - The Deceased died on the seventh of November. There was no Apothecary to attend her, nor was any of our Family called to see her, nor do I know that any other Person was - Her Mother had a Fire in the Parlor, but the Deceased was kept in a back Room, where there was no Fire, and where she lay upon a Bed without a Bedstead, and she has been locked in for two or three Days together.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not this in the Summer?</p>
               <p>Falkner It was between April and November.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no Carpet, or Matt under the Bed?</p>
               <p>Falkner I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Charlotte lye in the same Bed?</p>
               <p>Falkner. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And was not she used in the same manner?</p>
               <p>Falkner. She could help her self, because she used to draw the Beer, and lay the Cloth - The Deceased told me she never had any Beer, but only Water - When she first came she looked something better than when she died, though from the first she was vastly thin, and emaciated: but when she was dead she looked like an Anatomy, as if she had nothing but Skin drawn over her Bones - I looked another time when she stood at the Table, and she had only a piece of cold Cabbage given her.</p>
               <p>Q. But might not she have had Meat given her, before or after you looked?</p>
               <p>Falkner. The Mother, and Miss Doney dined first, before I saw them give her any thing - We have a Charcoal dust Tub that stood by her Garret Door, and under this Tub my Maid used to hide Victuals for her - One Day a Roll as hard as Iron was thrown over from the Roll's Buildings into my Yard. I ordered my Maid to butter it, and put it under the Dust Tub; she did. I saw the Girl take it out, and eat it greedily.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Children work?</p>
               <p>Falkner. Doney work'd with her Needle, but Charlotte did most of the House-work.</p>
               <p>Q You say the Deceased was locked up in the back Room? Did not she (the Week before her death) go out with Charlotte to see my Lord Mayor's Shew.</p>
               <p>Falkner Yes; they went out between nine and ten in the Morning, but I don't know what time they came home.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the Deceased walking about the House the Day before her death?</p>
               <p>Falkner. My Journey-man told me she came down Stairs dangling her Arms, as if they were hung on with Wires.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person237">
                  Ann 
                  Falkner 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person237" type="surname" value="Falkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person237" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In two or three Days after the Prisoner came to our House, the Deceased asked my Maid for Victuals - Once I saw the Deceased come from my Closet, I asked her what<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100011"></xptr> she had been there for; she owned she took a piece of Bread - We used to put Victuals for her under the Dust Tub.</p>
               <p>Council. When you gave her any Victuals did she eat it?</p>
               <p>A. Falkner. She used to cram it in her Pocket -</p>
               <p>Q. And would she have done so if she had been ready to starve.</p>
               <p>A. Falkner. I have peeped through the Crevice, and seen the Prisoner give the Deceased Beef - and Pork - and Cabbage. But I think not sufficient.</p>
               <p>Q Do you know any thing of her being locked up?</p>
               <p>A. Falkner. The Mother, and Miss Dony used to go to Market, and when the Basket Woman came with the Meat, Miss Charlotte used to lock the Door while she came down to the Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is at the Expence of this Prosecution?</p>
               <p>A. Falkner. The Parish, I think.</p>
               <p>Q. Who applied to the Parish?</p>
               <p>A. Falkuer. I do not know - I went out on Friday Morning, and when I came home, my Girl, said, she believed Miss Nanny was a dying. Mrs. Funnel who likewise lodges in my House, went and knocked at the Prisoner's Door, and said, Miss, How do you do? Answer, was made, she is dead! Mrs. Funnel, clapt her Hands, and said, O ye wicked Devils! are ye not ashamed to starve the Child to death? The Thing was soon noised about. and I went for the Searchers. When they came the Deceased was in bed, and they gave their Opinion, starved to death - The last Victuals I gave the Deceased, was two Months before she died. It was Bread and Cheese, and she pinned it up in her Petticoat for fear her Sister should take it from her - The Searchers said, the Bed was very clean, but not thick enough.</p>
               <p>Q Did you ever complain to the Prisoner, of her keeping the Child without sufficient Food?</p>
               <p>A. Falkner. Yes; I have said to her, Miss, looks very poorly, is she not well? and she answered, Yes, very well, she eats more than Doe. I said no more, for the Child had begged me not to tell her Mother, because her Mother would beat her, as she did sometimes. When she told me that, I said to her, Miss Nanny, you are a great Girl. and if your Mother beats ye, I wonder I never heard you cry. Madam, says she, my Mamma stuffs her Handkerchief in my Mouth when she eats me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person238">
                  Mary 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person238" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person238" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Servant to Falkner We mist Victuals out of the Cupboard, the Deceased owned she took it. Then the Cupboard was locked and after that she always asked me for Victuals whenever she saw me. I have put Victuals under the Dust Tub, and seen her eat it greedily. I have peeped through the Crack, and seen her standing, when her Mother, and Doee were at dinner with boiled Pork, and Turneps, and saw them give her Turneps, but no Pork - I cannot say, but they might have given her Meat before I looked - I found a hard Roll in our Yard, and laid it under the Dust Tub for her, but did not see her eat it. On a Saturday, when her Mother has been gone out, her Sisters have locked her in, and come down to me to drink Tea.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mary Scot, But the Girl has complained to me, that her Mother starved her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did her Mother keep the Victuals?</p>
               <p>Mary Scott. In the Kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it lock'd up?</p>
               <p>Mary Scot, The Kitchen Door was - sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not the Girl get into the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Mary Scott Yes she used to go in to wash her Hands, and she might have got at the Victuals, but she said, she durst not meddle with it, for fear her Mother should beat her. - When the Prisoner's Son 
               <persName id="t17351210-37-person239">
                  Charles 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person239" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person239" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (between thirteen and fourteen Years old, come home to her, she lock'd him up too, in the Garret, and he complain'd to me that he wanted Victuals, and said he had nothing but Bread and Water.</p>
               <p>Q Why did she lock him up.</p>
               <p>Mary Scott Because he had run away twice from his Master a Jeweller.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person240">
                  Susan 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person240" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person240" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived at Edmonton, I nursed the Deceas'd and the Prisoners other Children. The Deceased was with me from a Month old till she was above thirteen Years Old, and she was very Healthful. When their Father Sir 
               <persName id="t17351210-37-person241">
                  Geo 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person241" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person241" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             dyed, (which was a Year ago last August ) they went home to their Mother who then lived at Tottenham High-Cross - Sir George went by the Name of Thorn, and the Prisoner and he lived together as Man and Wife - I went to see the Deceas'd on Twelfth-Day, and asked her if she was well. Her Mother said, Yes, she Eats and Drinks and Sleeps Well. In March following she ran away from her Mother, and came to my House at Edmonton. she look'd like a Beggar and very thin and Poor, tho' she was a healthy plump Girl before. She complain'd that she had nor her belly full, I gave her some Victuals, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100012"></xptr> she Eat it very well, but as if she had been Starved.</p>
               <p>Q Were not the Prisoners Circumstances reduced, upon the Death of Sir George?</p>
               <p>Sus n Robinson. I can't say as to that: But while I kept the Children, she saw them two or three times a Year, and she then behaved as a Mother should do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr Elleker, who married a Daughter of Sir George's?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person242">
                  Susan 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person242" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person242" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When 
               <persName id="t17351210-37-person243">
                  Charles 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person243" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person243" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             left his Mother he came to me, and has Boarded with me. Mr. Elleker told me he believed I should be paid for maintaining of him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Buxton. I was present when Mr. Holloway and Mr. Freake opened the Body, and Mr. Freake found two or three Ounces of something in the Stomach, which he said look'd like a Cordial Draught.</p>
               <p>Mr. Holloway. deposed that he found the Body much distempered, and by the Symptoms he believed the Death of the Deceas'd might proceed from Natural Causes, and not from want Food.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person244">
                  Dorothy 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person244" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person244" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Mother always shewed the like Favour and Affection to the Deceas'd, as to me and my other Sister. The deceas'd had the same Food as we, and the Victuals was never lock'd up from her. She lay with Charlotte on a good warm Feather-Bed, in the warmest Room in the House. Indeed there was no Bedstead, but a double thick Cloth under it. She always look'd thin, but never complain'd of ill Usage, I never lock'd her in, nor knew that she was lock'd in. I never heard Mr. F. nor his Wife complain that she wanted, but indeed I have heard them say she looked thin. I told them she had a good Stomach, and wanted for nothing. I never heard them complain of her pilfering their Victuals till after she was Dead - Sir 
               <persName id="t17351210-37-person245">
                  George 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person245" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person245" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my Mothers Husband - My two Sisters lived with Nurse Robinson, but I lived at Home - On the Death of Sir George, my Mother's Circumstances were reduced. But we had always Victuals enough. The deceas'd complain'd of a pain in her Legs, on the Wednesday before she dyed, and on Thursday she complained of all her Limbs. My Mamma sent for some Mutton to make her some Broth, which I did, and she eat three parts of a Bason full - in the Afternoon we had Tea. And I advised her to go to Bed, and so she did; and my Sister Charley went to Bed with her. we thought it was only a Cold and so we did not send for an Apothecary, but my Mother gave her some Ale with Brandy and Sugar in it - She was Ill but one Day, and dyed at Ten a Clock on Friday Morning - There is a Law-Suit between Sir George's other Children and us.</p>
               <p>Q Has your Mother any Estate for Life?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person246">
                  Dorothy 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person246" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person246" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We don't know till the Law-Suit is Ended.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person247">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person247" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person247" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person247" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Depos'd to the same Effect and added - I don't believe in my Conscience, that she suffered any thing by Severity. I and my Sister were with her when she dyed. we did not call my Mother to see her dye because my Mother was Subject to Fits, and yet my Mother fell into Fits when she heard it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Freake. The Surgeon depos'd to the same Effect, as Mr. Holloway had done.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person248">
                  Ralph 
                  Harwood 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person248" type="surname" value="Harwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person248" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known the Prisoner ten or twelve Years in Tottenham; she visited my Family in her Husband's time, and always behaved very modestly. The Gentleman went by the Name of Thorn, and lived in a handsome manner, at the Rate of two Hundred Pounds a Year. They were visited by Lord Colrain, and the best of the Parish She was a most indulgent tender Mother that ever I saw; nor did I ever see a more sober and sedate Woman, and was company for the best in the Parish - 'Tis an unaccountable Prosecution. These two Children came home since her Husband died, and her Circumstances being then reduced, she lived more privately - She was as good a Woman as the best in the Parish. Since she was committed to Newgate, she has lain on the Commonside, and been reduced to the utmost Straits rather than make her Case known.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marsh. I have known her twenty Years, she was often at my House in Friday-Street, and I at hers at Tottenham, she was as much of a Gentlewoman, as ever I convers'd with. Her eldest Daughter used to be drest up, and visit with her; but the other two were at nurse, and drest plainer: She was no way cruel, angry, or hasty; but meek and tender; and I can't believe it posible, that she would starve her Child; and I saw no manner of Distinction, that she made of her Children.</p>
               <p>Mr. Husband. In the twenty Years, that I have been Minister of Tottenham, she behaved well, was frequent at Divine Offices, came to Church and received the Sacrament, and was respected by the best part of the Parish; I never heard that she was unkind to her Children, and can't believe she would starve any of them - I am sure I was mightily supriz'd to hear such a Report.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-37-person249">
                  William 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17351210-37-person249" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person249" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Apothecary at Tottenham. All the Children have been under my Care: she was very indulgent to them, and often sollicitous in enquiring after their Health when they had the small Pox. I saw no partiality, nor could discern which of them was most her Favourite.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Dormer. I have known her twenty Years; she lived seventeen Years at my Father's House. I frequently visited her, and she me; she kept one Child at home, but the rest were at nurse till a little before Christmass; she often went to see them, and shewed a Concern when she heard they were ill - One time when the Deceased was not well, the Prisoner came to me, and said, poor Nanny has been very bad all Night with a violent Purging - and she desired me to lend her a Bottle of Red-Wine for her.</p>
               <p>Several others were ready to speak to her Character, but it was thought unnecessary.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351210-37-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-37-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her. And the Court granted her a Copy of her Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
