<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-40">
               <interp inst="t17351210-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-40" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-40" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-40-off163-c179" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-40-defend262 t17351210-40-off163 t17351210-40-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>50, 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-defend262" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Mechlin 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-40-defend262" type="surname" value="Mechlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-defend262" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-defend262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17351210-40-off163" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-off163" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-off163" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351210-40-victim264" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Hallam 
                        <interp inst="t17351210-40-victim264" type="surname" value="Hallam"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-40-victim264" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-40-victim264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-40-off163 t17351210-40-victim264"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by thrusting a Stick into his left Eye, and thereby giving him one Mortal Wound of the Breadth of a quarter of an Inch, and Depth of one Inch and a half, <rs id="t17351210-40-cd164" type="crimeDate">May the 10th</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-40-off163 t17351210-40-cd164"></join>. of which mortal Wound he languished till the next Day and then Died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a Second time Indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person265">
                  Thomas 
                  Arne 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person265" type="surname" value="Arne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person265" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have the Honour to be Numberer of the Boxes of <placeName id="t17351210-40-crimeloc165">Drury-Lane Play-house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-40-crimeloc165" type="placeName" value="Drury-Lane Play-house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-40-crimeloc165" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-40-off163 t17351210-40-crimeloc165"></join> under Mr. Fleetwood - On Saturday Night I deliver'd my Accounts in the Property-Office, and then at eight at Night I came into the Scene-Room where the Players warm themselves, and sat down in a Chair at the end of the Fire - Fronting the Fire there's a long Screen where five or six People may sit. The Play was almost done and they were making Preparation for the Entertainment, when the Prisoner came in and sat down next to me. And high Words rose between him and the Deceas'd about a Stock-Wig for a disguise in the Entertainment, the Prisoner had play'd in this Wigg the Night before, and now the Deceas'd had got it. D - ye for a Rogue, says the Prisoner, What Business have you with my Wig! I am no more a Rogue than your Self, says the Deceas'd. Its a Stock Wig and I have as much right to it as you. Some of the Players coming in, they desired the deceas'd to fetch the Wigg and give it to the Prisoner. The deceas'd having found another Wig, he fetched the Wig in dispute, and gave it to the Prisoner, and said to him, Here is your Wig, I have got one that I like better. The Prisoner sitting by me, took the Wig, and begun to comb it out, and all seemed to be quiet for half a quarter of an Hour. But the Prisoner begun to grumble again, and said to the Deceased, G - D - ye for a black Guard scrub Rascal, How durst you have the Impudence to take this Wig? The Deceased answered, I am no more a Rascal than your self. Upon which the Prisoner started up out of his Chair, and having a Stick in his Hand, he gave a full Longe at the Deceased, and thrust the Stick into his left Eye, and pulling it back again he looked pale, turn'd on his Heel, and in a Passion, threw the Stick in the Fire. G - D - it! says he, and turning about again upon his Heel, he sat down. The Deceased clapt his Hand to his Eye, and said it was gone through his Head: He was going to sink, and they set him in a Chair. The Prisoner came to him, and leaning upon his left Arm, put his Hand to his Eye, Lord! cryed the Deceased, it is cut. No, says the Prisoner I feel the Ball roll under my Hand. Young Mr. Cibber came in, and immediately sent for Mr. Coldham the Surgeon.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I shew any Concern afterwards.</p>
               <p>Arne. I believe he was under the utmost Surprize, by his turning about, and throwing the Stick in the Fire, and he shew'd a further Concern, when he felt of the Eye-Ball.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person266">
                  Thomas 
                  Whitaker 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person266" type="surname" value="Whitaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person266" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Dresser in the House, under a Comedy player. On the Fryday Night the Prisoner asked me to lend him a Comedy-Wig to play Sancho, in the Fop's Fortune. And the next Night, the Deceas'd came and asked me for the same Wig. I told him I had it not, and bid him go to the other Dresser - As I was afterwards waiting in the Hall for my Money, the Prisoner came in, and asked the Deceas'd for the Wig, the Deceas'd answered that he should not have it, and the Prisoner reply'd, you're an Impudent Rascal, and ought to be can'd for your Impudence. Mr. Mills, who was acting Juba, came and said. What's the matter with you? We can't play for the Noise you make, the Prisoner answer'd, This Rascal has got a Wig that belongs to me. Mr. Mills said to the Deceas'd, Hallam, don't be impertinent, but give him the Wig. Hallam still refused, upon which, the Prisoner said, G - D - ye, such little Rascals ought to be made an example of, and so turn'd out of the Room. I being drest in Shape, went up, and undrest. Mr. Woodford bid me bring down a Scimitar, which I did, but, when I came down I could not find him, and so I went into the Scene Room: The Deceased was then standing still between the Door and the Settle. The Prisoner was about three Yards from him, and starting up, he made a sudden Longe (whether stepping or running, I can't say) the Deceas'd clapt his Hand to his Eye, and made a Reel, as if he was throwing himself into the Settle - The Prisoner seem'd to relent.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cole. The Deceased came first into the Scene-Room, and complain'd that the Prisoner had used him ill about a Comedy-Wig. The Prisoner soon followed, and said the Deceased had used him ill and impertinently, and he insisted upon having that Wig - They went out separately. The Deceased came in again. Mr. Fabian, the Author of a Farce to be acted that Night, Mr. Mills, and others, advised<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100015"></xptr> the Deceas'd to see the Prisoner have the Wig, and Mr. Kitchin the Property Man promis'd to help him to a better. The Deceased fetch'd the Wig and gave it to the Prisoner, and then Mr. Kitchen gave another Wigg to the Deceased. The Deceased held out this Wig to shew it, and said he lik'd it better than the other, you saucy impertinent Rascal, says the Prisoner, I wonder how such a litle Scoundrel dared to take a Wig out of my Dressing-Room; the Deceased told him, he had it of the Dresser - D - ye you Dog, says the Prisoner, do ye prate? And rising up from the Settle, he push'd at the Deceased, who then stood stock still, between me and the Settle - I was so near him, that I was afraid my own Eye would have been hurt; he reel'd, and I catched him in my Arms.</p>
               <p>Council. Who does the Dressing Room where the Wig was kept, belong to.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cole. Not to the Deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Has every one a particular Room to dress in?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cole. There were three or four who drest in that Room, but the Deceased did not belong to it. But he said the Dresser gave him the Wig - I believe the Dresser's Name is Greenwood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person267">
                  Francis 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person267" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person267" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased came into the Scene-Room, and said the Prisoner had used him like a Pick-pocket, about a Wig. Mr. Mills. and the Author, and others advised him to go up and fetch him the Wig; he went out, the Prisoner came in, and said the Deceased was a Scoundrel; the Deceased came in, and gave him the Wig: Mr. Kitchen call'd the Deceased to the end of the Room, and lent him another Wig; he shew'd this Wig, and said he would not change with the Prisoner, for he had got a better: The Prisoner answer'd, you are a Scoundrel for taking it at all. The Deceased reply'd, No more a Scoundrel than your self. Some other Words passing, the Prisoner rose up, and I think said, D - ye, you little Dog do ye prate, and then gave him the Blow. He clapt both his Hands to his Eye, and cry'd, O' Lord ! I believe my Eye is put out, and would have fal'n in the Fire, if Mr. Cole had not catch'd him. When he was set down, I asked him how he did; Lord! said he, I believe my Eye-ball is shev'd to the other side of my Head. I believe the Prisoner had him by the Hand, all the while the Surgeon was dressing him - He lived 'till six the next Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person268">
                  Ellis 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person268" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person268" type="given" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came in, when the Deceas'd had receiv'd the other Wig. He said he liked this as well as that the Prisoner had. You are an impudent Scoundrel, says the Prisoner, for taking it out of my Shift (that is, his dressing Place) - No more a Scoundrel than your self, says the Deceas'd, and you are one for calling me Ye impudent Rascal, do you prate? reply'd the Prisoner, and rising up, made a Longe, and push'd at him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person269">
                  Thomas 
                  Salway 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person269" type="surname" value="Salway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person269" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting at the end of the Settle, which will hold five or six People. The Deceased stood by me, and said, If he, (the Prisoner) had had a mind for the Wig, he might have asked me for it in a civil Manner, and not have attack'd me like a Pick pocket. The Prisoner said, you lie; the Deceased return'd I don't lie, or else, you lie; upon which, the Prisoner got up, and I think made one Step, and said, ye little Rascal do ye prate? or some such Words; and then made a push at him with a stick, which enter'd his Eye, and made a Noise like a squashing. He clapt his Hand to his Eye, and the Blood ran down his Face; he totter'd; but I was so shock'd and frighted that I had not power to catch him, but went out of the Room: When the Push was made, he was standing still, about three Yards from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Council. Did he aim at any particular Place?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person270">
                  Thomas 
                  Salway 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person270" type="surname" value="Salway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person270" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He seem'd to be in too great a Passion for that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it not a Stick necessary for my part, as a Spanish Servant?</p>
               <p>Thomas Salway. Yes - The Deceased stood close to my right Shoulder.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Which side of him was towards me when I pushed?</p>
               <p>Thomas Salway. His full Face.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you say, What a passionate Man are you to do this Mischief? and did not I answer, Good God! What will not a Man do in Passion, when he knows not what he does?</p>
               <p>Thomas Salway. There might be such Words.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coldham. Surgeon. On the tenth of May, in the Evening, I was sent for, and drest the Deceased - He died next Day, and I opened the Skull, and found the Stick had passed through the thin Bone that contains the Eye, into the Brain - That Bone is extream thin, and can make but little resistance. Had the Blow been elsewhere, it might have had a less fatal Effect. I was astonished that a Man should die by such an Instrument - when I first attended him, the Prisoner shewed much Concern, and desired me to take all possible care of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100016"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person271">
                  George 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person271" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person271" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Affair, but only was bound over to prosecute, because he had no friends.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I plaid Sancho the Night before, and the Wig I then used was proper for the New Play, and absolutely necessary for my Character; the whole force of the Poet's Wit depending on the lean meagre Looks of one that wanted Food. This Wig therefore being so fit for my purpose, and hearing that the Deceased had got it, I said to him, You have got the Wig I plaid in last Night, and it fits my Part this Night - I have as much right to it as you have, says he. I told him I desired it as a Favour: he said, I should not have it. You are a Scoundrel, says I, to deny me, when I only ask that as a Favour, which is my right. I am no more a Scoundrel than your self, says he, and, and I went to the Prompter's Door to see for Mr. Cibber. Mean while the Deceased went into the Scene Room, and said, that I had used him like a Pick-pocket - The Author persuaded him to let me have the Wig, and the Property-Man brought him another Wig. He threw the first Wig at me. I asked him why he could not as well have done that before. He answered, because you used me like a Pick-pocket. This provoked me, and rising up, I said, D - ye for a Puppy, get out. His Left-side was then towards me, but he turned about unluckily, and the Stick went into his Eye. Good God! says I, What have I done! and threw the Stick in the Chimney. He sat down, and said to Mr. Arne's Son (who was drest in Women's Cloaths) whip up your Coats ye little Bitch and Urine in my Eye; but he could not, and so I did. I begged them to take the Deceased to the Bagnio, but Mrs. Moore said, she had a Room where he should be taken care of. I had then no thought that it would prove his End, but feared that his Eye was in Danger. But next Morning I saw Mr. Turbut, who advised me to keep out of the way, or I should be sent to Jail - I begged him to get the Assistance of a Physician, and gave him a Guinea, which was all the Money I had - From the Beginning of the Quarrel to the end, it was but ten Minutes, and there was no Intermission.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-40-person272">
                  Robert 
                  Turbut 
               <interp inst="t17351210-40-person272" type="surname" value="Turbut"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person272" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had played that Night, and was in the Scene Room when the Deceased came in, and seemed flush'd, and said, Mechlin has used me like a Pick-pocket. I had this Wig of Mrs. Greenwood, the Dresser, and now he wants it; but I think it is as proper for my Character as for his - The Prisoner then came in, and demanded it. Upon which, in a merry way, it was put to the Question, which of them should have it, and it was agreed that the Prisoner should. Mr. Kitchen came in, and said, Here is another Wig. The Deceased then tost the former Wig to the Prisoner, who said to him, why could not you have done this before. He answered, because you used me like a Pick-pocket - You lye, says the Prisoner; and you lye, says the Deceased - You are a Scoundrel, says one, and You are a Scouudrel, says another. At last the Prisoner rising up, said, Ye Puppy, get out, and pushed at him, but I believe not with any particular Aim.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rich, Mr. Fleetwood, Mr. Quin, Mr. Ryan, Mr. Thompson, Mr. Mills, Mr. Lessley, Mr. Black, Mr. Fern, appeared to the Prisoner's Character, and deposed that he was a Man of a quiet and peaceable Disposition.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17351210-40-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-verdict166" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17351210-40-punish167" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-punish167" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-40-punish167" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-40-defend262 t17351210-40-punish167"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
