<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-24">
               <interp inst="t17380222-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-24" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-24" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-24-off106-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-defend184 t17380222-24-off106 t17380222-24-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>27. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-24-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-24-defend184" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-defend184" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-defend184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-24-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing 5 Silver Seals, value 7 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-24-victim186" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Holland 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-24-victim186" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-24-victim186" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-24-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-off106 t17380222-24-victim186"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-24-cd107" type="crimeDate">Feb. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-off106 t17380222-24-cd107"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Holland. I <rs id="t17380222-24-viclabel108" type="occupation">keep a Goldsmith's Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-victim186 t17380222-24-viclabel108"></join> at <placeName id="t17380222-24-crimeloc109">Bishop-Gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-24-crimeloc109" type="placeName" value="Bishop-Gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-24-crimeloc109" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-off106 t17380222-24-crimeloc109"></join>. On Monday Afternoon last, the Prisoner came into my Shop, and asked to see some Seals. I took out a Drawer, and shew'd him. 5 or 6 Doxen. He look'd over them, and asked the Price of one, and another. At last he bid Money<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220011"></xptr> for one, and pull'd out 2 s. with his left Hand. I thought I heard a jingling of something more than Money, and watching his Hand, I perceived one of my Seals with his 2 s. I observed him carefully, and saw him take up another. What will you have for this, says he? I told him he had got one in his Hand already. No, he had not he said, and open'd his Hand, and there was nothing but the 2 s. I told him I was sure he had it, and desired to look into his Hat. He pulled off his Hat and Wig, and open'd his Breast, telling me I might search him. I came round the Counter to search him, and in his Pocket I found these 5 Seals; I had no sooner taken them from him, but he ran out of Doors; I got hold of him again at the Kennel, and in struggling with him I tore his Coat up to his Back. My Man and I with much ado, got him back to the Shop, and sent for a Constable to take Charge of him. These are the Seals, they are mine, and some of them I have had these 3 or 4 Years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was vastly in Liquor; I never knew I had any of them, - I was vastly much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-24-person187">
                  Matthew 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17380222-24-person187" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person187" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave exactly the same Account and deposed farther, that he was not in Liquor, of which he was convinced by the Resistance he made when he was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord I know nothing at all of it, - I was vastly in Liquor; I have People to prove that Liquor disorders me vastly, and I live in the Neighbourhood with a Gentleman that entrusts me with a vast Number of Things. The People of the Goal know I was vastly drunk when I was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-24-person188">
                  George 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17380222-24-person188" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person188" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about a Twelve month; he marry'd an honest Woman in my Neighbourhood, I never heard any bad Character of him; when he's in Liquor he's like a Madman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-24-person189">
                  George 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17380222-24-person189" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person189" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Man deals in Fruit, - his Wife does, and I suppose he does. I never know him to sell Fruit himself, - I don't know any Business he follows - in particular.</p>
               <p>John. I am his Brother in Law; I have known him about 4 Years, and have seen him - not much in Liquor, but when he is - I am always glad to get out of his Company. As to his Character, - I nothing of that.</p>
               <p>Jones. I am a Porter in Borough Market work for his Wife; I have known him 12 or 13 Months. I have heard that he deals in Callamancoes, Muslins, and Handkerchief - not old Handkerchief, - but new ones.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-24-person190">
                  Richard 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17380222-24-person190" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person190" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Porter in the Borough. I know nothing of him, - nothing of any harm. I work for his Wife; if he's in Liquor he'll rattle the Candlesticks and Pewter about like a Madman.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dodson. I live in the Borrough As to the Prisoner I know no Good of him; his general Character is but very indifferent, and I desire to be excused from entering into Particulars.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is because they call me a Molly, and say I am more like a Woman than a Man, and how can I help my Face? <rs id="t17380222-24-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-verdict110" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17380222-24-punish111" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-24-punish111" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-24-defend184 t17380222-24-punish111"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
