<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390718-18">
               <interp inst="t17390718-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-18" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-18" type="date" value="17390718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-18-off88-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-18-defend184 t17390718-18-off88 t17390718-18-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>405. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390718-18-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Kingman 
                  <interp inst="t17390718-18-defend184" type="surname" value="Kingman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-defend184" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-defend184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390718-18-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing three Shillings from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390718-18-victim186" type="victimName">
                           Moses 
                           Wheeler 
                        <interp inst="t17390718-18-victim186" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-18-victim186" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-18-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-18-off88 t17390718-18-victim186"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17390718-18-cd89" type="crimeDate">June 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-18-off88 t17390718-18-cd89"></join>.</p>
               <p>Moses Wheeler. She picked my Pocket of three Shillings, and took it out by Violence. 'Twas on the 17th of June, at the <placeName id="t17390718-18-crimeloc90">George Ale-house, in Queen Street, next Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-18-crimeloc90" type="placeName" value="George Ale-house, in Queen Street, next Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-18-crimeloc90" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-18-off88 t17390718-18-crimeloc90"></join>. I called there between Three and Four in the Morning, for a Pint of Beer, and the Prisoner being standing at the Bar, with the Landlord of the House, I ask'd her to drink. She said, she did not care if she did; so she drank Part of that Pint, and then I called for another, and she drank Part of that too. When the second Pint was out, I gave the Drawer a Shilling, and he gave me Nine-pence out of it. In the mean time a Man came in and sat down in the Box with her, - I suppose he was one of her Gang, - and he told me he would spend a Penny with me, for a Pint of Twopenny. The Prisoner was then in the Inside of the Box, with the Fellow, and I was on the outside. He threw down his Penny on the Table, and I pulled out my Money, to take a Penny to put to it. Upon which she flung her Hands about my Neck, and said, - my Dear, you shall feel me; and at the same time she switched three Shillings out of my Pocket, and flung herself that Minute from me. I told her she wanted to pick my Pocket, and I looked to see what Money was there, and missed three Shillings. I charged her with taking my Money, and put my Hand down her Bosom to see if it was there but it was not. Then I turned her round in the Box, and said, - before you go, I will have my Money, or Satisfaction. She immediately sat herself down, and pulled out a Box, like a Tobacco-box, and opened it; there was about fifteen or sixteen Shillings in it; and she asked me if that was my Money? After this she stooped, and shifted some down by her Side, and then she cry'd, - now<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180019"></xptr> damn you, - you Son of a Bitch, - I will go with you to the Compter, and away she went to the Poultry Compter (a little before 5 o'Clock) and rapped at the Wicket; the Door was presently opened, and she was let in, but they shut me out. There happened to be a Man at this Time sitting at the Compter Gate, and I desired him to go for my Brother: He came to me, and then we knocked at the Gate, and asked for the Woman; they deny'd her, but in the Morning we got her out, and took her to Wood street Compter; and as we were going along, she took out her Box, with the Money, and said, - here you Son of a Bitch, here's your three Shillings again, - I believe you want a Shilling more than I do, and I'll give you another Shilling to take it, and she up with her Fist and gave me such a Stroke on the Face, that she swelled up my Eyes.</p>
               <p>Jury. We would desire to know if the Prosecutor had been out all Night?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. I had been out with Work that Night, and had come from Dick's Shore, at Lime-House: I parted with my Master there, about Twelve o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Jury. Upon your Oath did not you know that this George Ale-house was a disorderly house?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. No: I never was in the House but once before in my Life. The Doors were open, and I was dry with walking so far; so I went in for a Pint of Beer. I found the Prisoner used to keep Company with one 
               <persName id="t17390718-18-person187">
                  Frank 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17390718-18-person187" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person187" type="given" value="Frank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person187" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Smuggler, in the Compter, and that the People at the Compter let her out and in. When she had done Mischief, she used to whip down thither to be screened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-18-person188">
                  Richard 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17390718-18-person188" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person188" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor sent a Watchman for me, about Five o'Clock in the Morning, and I went directly to the Poultry Compter, where I found him keeping Guard, lest the Woman should be let out. He told me she had picked his Pocket of three Shillings and some Half-Pence. I asked the Turnkey what Time they let People in, to visit the Prisoners. He told me at Six o'Clock. Why, says I, this Woman came in without a Constable, and 'tis not half an Hour past Five now: You let People out to go a robbing; the Woman is in the Gaol, and and I must look for her. He said he would not look for her, and bid me get in, and look for her myself; and be damned; I searched, and could not find her; then I said I would complain to the Sheriff. D - mn it, he did not care if I did, and one Fellow was going to strike me. After this, we search'd for her again, and at last we found her in the Prison, a-bed with a Man. When we had got her out, she said, - now, damn you, what do you want with me, you foolish Dog, - you can only return me to the Place where you found me, - you can only send me home again, no, my dear, said I, you sha'n't go home again, we'll move you to Woodstreet Compter. As we were carrying her thither, she would go cross Honey Lane Market; O, said I, I find you know the nearest Way thither too; and when we were got into the Market, she pull'd out her Box, - Here, - you poor Dog, said she, I know you want Money, - here's your three Shillings again, and a Shilling more for you to take them, and I will go about my Business. No, my Dear, said I, you shall not go. Why, said she, you don't know, you foolish Dog, what you're about, I let my - out to be bowl'd at, and you are to be one of the Bowlers: And when we got her near Sir William Biller's Office, she struck Wheeler in the Face, and gave him a black Eye. At the Compter she was well known; the People there cry'd, - how do you do, Moll? but her right Name is Sarah Kingman. When we carry'd her before Alderman Parsons, she beg'd hard to be sent again to the Compter, but he sent her to Newgate, and when we came under Newgate, she watch'd her Opportunity, and gave the Prosecutor another Blow in the Face, and bid him kiss her - , now he had done his worst, and she would be revenged on him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ravis, the Constable, depos'd, that the Prisoner was a notorious Offender; that she had been once transported by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17390718-18-person189">
                  Sarah 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17390718-18-person189" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person189" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-person189" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He confirm'd the Account given of her impudent Behaviour, and of her beating Wheeler, as they were carrying her to Woodstreet Compter, and to Newgate. He said, the Prosecutor was as sober as any Man could be. <rs id="t17390718-18-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-18-verdict91" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, <rs id="t17390718-18-punish92" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17390718-18-punish92" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-18-defend184 t17390718-18-punish92"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>. The Jury recommended her for Mercy
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
