<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-25">
               <interp inst="t17361208-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-25" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-25" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-25-off144-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-25-defend244 t17361208-25-off144 t17361208-25-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080019"></xptr>37. 
               <persName id="t17361208-25-defend244" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17361208-25-defend244" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-defend244" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-defend244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17361208-25-person245">
                  John 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17361208-25-person245" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-person245" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken) for <rs id="t17361208-25-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-25-victim247" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Lyon 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-25-victim247" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-25-victim247" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-25-victim247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-25-off144 t17361208-25-victim247"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's High way, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Knife, value 2 d. and 3 s. 1 d. and a Farthing in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17361208-25-cd145" type="crimeDate">Nov. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-25-off144 t17361208-25-cd145"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-25-person248">
                  James 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17361208-25-person248" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-person248" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About Eight o'Clock at Night, Nov. 29, I had just got through the Bars at <placeName id="t17361208-25-crimeloc146">Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-25-crimeloc146" type="placeName" value="Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-25-crimeloc146" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-25-off144 t17361208-25-crimeloc146"></join>, when I was seized on one Side by the Prisoner, and a Man took hold of me on the other Side, and they said they must have my Money. I was going to lift up my Voice, and to call out aloud, but the Man seized me by the Throat and prevented me. He held me thus, while the Woman opened this Pocket and took a Knife and 3 s. and 1 d. and a Farthing from me. The Man ask'd her, if she had got it, and held me a little while that she might get off; but I followed her to a House in Charterhouse Lane, - I know her to be the Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know the Prisoner to be the Woman?</p>
               <p>Lyon. The Lamps gave a good Light, and I followed the Man and she too into the House.</p>
               <p>Q. And did these two People who had robb'd you, suffer you to follow them into a House?</p>
               <p>Lyon. The Man struggled very hard against my coming into the House; but the Landlord said - let the Gentleman come in: So I went in, and he asked me if I would please to go up Stairs and drink a Bottle of China Ale, and have a pretty Girl. The House is not above 20 or 30 Rods from the Place where I was robb'd, and the Landlord is a Rabbit Man.</p>
               <p>Q. So the Man that robb'd you, let you follow him into the House; is this the Case?</p>
               <p>Lyon. That is the Case; and that is the Woman that took my Money.</p>
               <p>Q. So the Man and the Woman that robb'd you, went into the Rabbit-House, and you followed them into the Rabbit-House.</p>
               <p>Lyon. Yes; and I saw four Men and four Women there, so I was glad to get out again; but I went and got a Constable and took them</p>
               <p>The Constable. He came to me and said he was robb'd between Smithfield Bars and Charter-house-Lane, and gave the same Account of the Fact, and of what he lost. He desired me to go to this Rabbit House, but I told him there was a Constable and a Headborough lived on each side of the House, and it would be better for him to get either of them to go with him: He desired I would go, and at last I went with him; but going down the Lane, he catch'd hold of the Prisoner and charged me with her. Upon this, Pendall the Rabbit-Man came up, and bid him let the Woman go Did not you come into my House, says he, and drink a Bottle of China Ale? And did not I give you 3 d. out of your Shilling? But at last Pendall said he would give the Prosecutor what he had lost, if I would discharge the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. If he was so positive to the Man and the Woman, why did not he take you to the House, and charge you with the Man?</p>
               <p>Constable. The Man was gone, he said.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray Mr. Lyon who are you? Have you any Persons here to give an Account of you when you come to take a Life away, and entitle your self to 14 l. I expect something more than this Story.</p>
               <p>Defence. This Lyon turn'd upon me in the Street, and pull'd me by the Sleeve, so we came down together to the Rabbit-House, and went up Stairs together; we had a Bottle of China Ale, and I had no more from him than a Groat all but a Farthing. He swears this against me because I would not oblige him, - no says I, if you give me 3 d. three Farthings to make a Whore of, I will keep it to make my self honest</p>
               <p>Q. Here, Lyon, was not you in Drink at this Time?</p>
               <p>Lyon. No; tis well known I was not I had been at Supper at Mr. Gardner's, at the White-Horse in Castle Alley: I was not up Stairs with her at all. <rs id="t17361208-25-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-25-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
