<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-38">
               <interp inst="t17351210-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-38" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-38" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-38-off154-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-38-defend251 t17351210-38-off154 t17351210-38-verdict157"></join>
         
               <p>48. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-38-defend251" type="defendantName">
                     Ralph 
                     Refue 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-38-defend251" type="surname" value="Refue"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-defend251" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-defend251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17351210-38-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing one Guinea
            </rs>, from the Person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-38-victim253" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Lerougetell 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-38-victim253" type="surname" value="Lerougetell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-victim253" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-victim253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-38-off154 t17351210-38-victim253"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17351210-38-cd155" type="crimeDate">December 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-38-off154 t17351210-38-cd155"></join>.</p>
               <p>Edward Lerougetell. Between four and five in the Afternoon, as I was coming down the Minories, the Prisoner stooped before me, and took up a Shilling, and asked me if it was not good. I told him I could not tell. He washed it, and said, he believed it was, and invited me to go and drink with him, but I refused, and told him I had Business to do. I went to the White Hart, and paid for a Gun, and Gun Barrel. And when I came out with my Goods, the Prisoner again invited me to drink. I still refused, but he still kept me company, and asked me what Countryman I was, and where I lodged. I said I came from Jersey, and lodged at 
               <persName id="t17351210-38-person254">
                  John 
                  Simmons 
               <interp inst="t17351210-38-person254" type="surname" value="Simmons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's at Green Bank. He said, he was going that way I had got a Bible, &amp;c under my Arm; it was going to slip down, and I went to save it, upon which, he took it from me, and would needs carry it for me. When he had got it, he went into an <placeName id="t17351210-38-crimeloc156">Ale-house the Half-moon and Star in East Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-38-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="Ale-house the Half-moon and Star in East Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-38-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-38-off154 t17351210-38-crimeloc156"></join>. I was obliged to follow him for my Bible. As soon as I went in I found another Man who was his Acquaintance, and they two went to Cards. The Prisoner sat close by me, and asked me to Cut. I told them I did not understand Cards, and had no mind to meddle with them. But however, they persuaded me to lay a Shilling upon the Game. I lost that and another, and then I won three Shillings, and at last I ventured fourteen Shillings out of a Guinea that I had in my Pocket. I grew very uneasy, and wanted to be going. I put my Hand in my Pocket to pay, and had got the Guinea between my Fingers, when the Prisoner husseld my my Hand, and said sit down, but presently I mist my Guinea The Prisoner, and his Companion jumpt up. The Landlady shut the Fore-door, and opened the Back Door to let them out. I went to follow them, but she stopt me, and said, I should pay the Reckoning before I went, or else I should leave my Goods. I accordingly left Goods to the value of thirty Shillings, and then pursued the Prisoner, and seized him in Nightingale Lane, and brought him back to the House, where when I came, they put out the Candles, and I fearing some mischief, shriek'd out. At last I got a Constable, who carried the Prisoner before the Justice. The Prisoner told him that I laid the Guinea in the other Man's Hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And so you did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-38-person255">
                  Edward 
                  Lerougetell 
               <interp inst="t17351210-38-person255" type="surname" value="Lerougetell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person255" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No. I did not. The Justice sent for the Landlady, and she said she saw no such thing. Then I must go back to the House to secure my Goods. So we all went back, and the Prisoner gave the Woman a Guinea, and said, Change that, and let's drink to my Reformation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-38-person256">
                  Benjamin 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17351210-38-person256" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person256" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Prisoner was first at the House he had no Money, that I saw, but when he returned, he gave the Landlady a Guinea, and bid her change it, and drink to his Reformation.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17351210-38-verdict157" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-verdict157" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17351210-38-punish158" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-38-punish158" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-38-defend251 t17351210-38-punish158"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
