<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-22">
               <interp inst="t17370420-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-22" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-22" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-22-off110-c120" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-defend168 t17370420-22-off110 t17370420-22-verdict114"></join>
         
               <p>24. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-22-defend168" type="defendantName">
                     Susanna 
                     Moore , otherwise <rs id="t17370420-22-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-defend168 t17370420-22-alias-1"></join>Page</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-defend168" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-defend168" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-defend168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370420-22-defloc109">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-22-defloc109" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-22-defloc109" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-defend168 t17370420-22-defloc109"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-22-off110" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-off110" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-off110" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 4 l the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-22-victim170" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Webb 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim170" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim170" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-22-victim172" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Thompson 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim172" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim172" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-22-victim172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17370420-22-cd111" type="crimeDate">March 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-off110 t17370420-22-cd111"></join>
               </p>
               <p>Robert Thompson. I was coming thro' <placeName id="t17370420-22-crimeloc112">St. James's Park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-22-crimeloc112" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-22-crimeloc112" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-off110 t17370420-22-crimeloc112"></join> the 18th of March, about 9 o'Clock at Night, and the Prisoner met me. We were acquainted before; Robin, says she, what makes you out so late to Night, are you come away from your Master? No, says I, I am just come from Kensington with my Master's Watch, and I am going Home with it as fast as I can. I went away from her a little Way, and she call'd me back again, Robin, Robin, says she, give me one Kiss; I did so, and went from her again; but I had not gone far, before I miss'd the Watch. Upon this I ran back and catch'd her; I challeng'd her with it, and another Woman that was with her, but she ran away. I held the Prisoner, and while I was charging her with the Watch, a Man came up and ask'd me what Business I had with his Wife? but one of the King's Footmen coming up with a Flambeau, he ran away, and I brought her down to Spring-Gardens, and asked her to give me the Watch again: She made no Answer at all, so I carry'd her to a House, and gave her a Pint of Beer, yet she would not give it me, and somebody at this House knowing my Master, sent for him, and he brought this Gentleman with him; they likewise asked her for it, but she would say nothing about it, she would not say whether she had it, or had it not, only she own'd she saw it in my Hand. My Master sent for the Marshal's Man, and she was search'd, but we could not find it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your Master live?</p>
               <p>Thompson. At the George in King-street, Westminster.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was talking with two other Women when I came up to him; so I pass'd him, and 'twas he that call'd after me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-22-person173">
                  William 
                  Blackman 
               <interp inst="t17370420-22-person173" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person173" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th Day of March, - as I verily believe it was, - in the Evening, there came a Man, - they call'd him an Hero-man, and inform'd Mr. Webb (as how) his <rs id="t17370420-22-viclabel113" type="occupation">Boy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-22-victim172 t17370420-22-viclabel113"></join> had lost his Watch; I went with him to the House where the Boy and the Woman were detained. I requested and desired, and said to her, I understand by the Story, you have got the Watch, for God's sake make Restitution: For all I requested and desired her so much, she only laugh'd at me, and bid me kiss her A - se, and I know not what besides, and somewhat else, not fit to repeat to the Honourable Court. So next Morning we went before the Justice, - and a very worthy honourable Gentleman he is, and he examin'd her in a very handsome Manner indeed; he examin'd that Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17370420-22-person174">
                  Susannah 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17370420-22-person174" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person174" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person174" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Page, concerning the Premisses, but she would say nothing at all about it; so the Justice was so good, my Lord, as to commit her to Newgate: And-when we were all coming out at the Door, she told the Lad, if she had a Knife about her, she would stab him in the Jaws. Where's Mr. Webb? He's somewhere in Court, - I'm sure I have been here these 3 Hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-22-person175">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17370420-22-person175" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person175" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sent Thompson to fetch my Watch, and he told me this Woman pick'd his Pocket of it in the Park, that's all I know, only the Woman has a very bad Character.</p>
               <p>Blackman. So far I can say, that the Lad is a sober just young Man, and would not do wrong to any one.</p>
               <p>Q. Yes, he is sober and silly too. What Pocket did you put the Watch into?</p>
               <p>Thompson. My left Coat Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As I came cross the Park, he pick'd me up, and after we had shook Hands, I parted with him; afterwards he came back, and said, I had robb'd him. I told him I knew nothing of it, and they searched me, and found nothing upon me. <rs id="t17370420-22-verdict114" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-22-verdict114" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
