<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-2">
               <interp inst="t17361208-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-2" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-2" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-2-off7-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-defend48 t17361208-2-off7 t17361208-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-2-defend48" type="defendantName">
                     Phillis 
                     Pratter , otherwise <rs id="t17361208-2-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-defend48 t17361208-2-alias-1"></join>Fratter</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-defend48" type="surname" value="Pratter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-defend48" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-defend48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361208-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               privately stealing 12 Yards of Cloth Calimancoe, 21 Yards of Persian, one Yard of green Ducape, four Yards of white Sattin, a Quarter of a Yard of green half-ell damask, half a yard of yellow worsted Damask, a Quarter of a Yard of Holland, three Holland Shirts, three Pair of Scissars, a Pair of Bathmetal Buckles, one Yard of scarlet Tabby, two Yards of blue Velvet, three Yards of Cloth-colour'd Shagreen, one Yard and half of blue Mantua Silk, two Yards of Cloth-colour'd Silk Damask, one Yard of Brocade Silk, and other Mercery Goods
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-2-victim50" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Ryder 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-2-victim50" type="surname" value="Ryder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-victim50" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-victim50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-off7 t17361208-2-victim50"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , in the Parish of <placeName id="t17361208-2-crimeloc8">St. Sepulchre's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-2-crimeloc8" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-2-crimeloc8" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-off7 t17361208-2-crimeloc8"></join> 
                  <rs id="t17361208-2-cd9" type="crimeDate">October 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-off7 t17361208-2-cd9"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Ryder. The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17361208-2-deflabel10" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-defend48 t17361208-2-deflabel10"></join> a Year and three Quarters, and as some of my Servants lay in the Shop, she used to make their Beds. I suspected her to be dishonest, for we frequently miss'd Half-pence out of a Box behind the Counter. Once we told 4 or 5 s. worth, and miss'd 15 d. Another time we miss'd 2 s. 4 d. I taxed her with robbing me, and searched her Trunk; this was Nov. 30 I took out 12 Yards 3 quar. of Cloth-colour'd Calimanco; 21 Yards of yellow Persian, in two Quantities; one Yard of white half-ell Sattin; a Remnant of green half-ell Damask; a Remnant of half-yard yellow Ditto; a Remnant of yellow worsted Damask; two Remnants of Holland and Scotch Cloth; three Holland Shirts mark'd with my Name, some Scissars of my Servants and mine; a Pair of Bathmetal Buckles, these Things I can swear to. We found several other Things at one Mr Jordan's Lodging in Swallow-Street, who was an Acquaintance of hers, and had been at my House several times: Here we found one Yard of scarlet Tabby, some broad black Velvet, three Yards of Cloth-colour'd Shagreen, two Yards and half of yellow, ditto; half a yard of Damask, one Yard 1-8th of blue Mantua; these and several other Things, were taken out of her Box at Jordan's. At one Mr. Markham's, a Baker, we found out two Yards and a Quarter of Cloth colour'd Damask; one Yard of half ell brocade Silk; half a Yard of blue Silk Damask, half a Yard of scarlet Velvet; half a Yard of figur'd Stuff, and two Remnants of figur'd Silk; all these were ty'd up in a Handkerchief of my Journeyman's; and we found likewise 3 s. which was Money we marked, but 'tis not in the Indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-2-person51">
                  Charles 
                  Trap 
               <interp inst="t17361208-2-person51" type="surname" value="Trap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person51" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was my Master's Servant near two Years; but missing some Halfpence out of the Drawer, we suspected her to be dishonest: I put 6 s. in Half-pence into the Drawer my self, and lock'd up the Shop; she went in to make the Bed, and left the Door open: I was then at home, and am certain none went through the Shop. I told the Money over after she was gone out of the Shop, and miss'd 2 s. 4 d. I acquainted my Master next Morning, and she was charged with it; she deny'd it; but my Master insisting on her Boxes being open'd, we found these Goods which have been mention'd, and which I can swear to: I was present when they were found in her Room up two Pair of Stairs. She said nothing at all about the Goods; and as to the Money, she said it was a Picque of the Journeymen to put her out of her Place. I was likewise present at the taking the Goods from the other Places: These were taken at Jordan's in Swallow-Street; I swear they are my Master's. When the Prisoner was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17361208-2-person52">
                  Richard 
                  Brocas 
               <interp inst="t17361208-2-person52" type="surname" value="Brocas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person52" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they were produced, and she confessed she took them. These Goods were taken at 
               <persName id="t17361208-2-person53">
                  Charles 
                  Markham 
               <interp inst="t17361208-2-person53" type="surname" value="Markham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person53" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, a Baker in Westminster, ty'd up in my Handkerchief. Markham had served a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080004"></xptr> Family with Bread where she had liv'd; so he gave her Leave to put the Goods in a Trunk which she had had there a considerable Time. He told us the Trunk was her's, and that she had left it there. She was committed to Newgate before we received Information of these Goods.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jordan. These Goods were left at my House, but I can't say who left them; they were under Lock and Key, and the Box was brought by a Porter for the Prisoner; I cannot say, that the Prisoner put the Goods into the Box, it was at my House before she went to live at Mr. Ryder's, nor did I ever see the Inside of it till Mr. Ryder's Man open'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see it open'd while it was at your House?</p>
               <p>Jordan. She has opened it, but I never look'd into it.</p>
               <p>Q. When she has open'd it, have you never observ'd her to put any Thing in it?</p>
               <p>Jordan. Not to my Knowledge; she never open'd it but once, and that was while she liv'd with Mr. Ryder; it was one Sunday Evening, and then I don't remember I saw her put any Thing in, or take any Thing out.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ryder. I believe both these People to be honest; when she went to their Houses, she might take no more Goods than she could conceal under her Apron, and she might convey them into her Boxes without their seeing her.</p>
               <p>Defence. I am not guilty; I never took any Half-pence.</p>

               <p>Q. Can you give any Account, how Mr. Ryder's Goods came to be in your Boxes?</p>
               <p>Jordan. I have known her three or four Years, she was a Fellow Servant with my Wife, and never heard but that she was honest till now. <rs id="t17361208-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17361208-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-2-defend48 t17361208-2-punish12"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
