<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-5">
               <interp inst="t17390502-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-5" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-5" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-5-off20-c51" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-defend61 t17390502-5-off20 t17390502-5-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>239. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-defend61" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Nash 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-5-defend61" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-defend61" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-defend61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-5-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-5-victim63" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           King 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-5-victim63" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-5-victim63" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-5-victim63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-off20 t17390502-5-victim63"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Pair of Leather Shoes, value 2 s. and 4 s. 5 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-5-cd21" type="crimeDate">April 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-off20 t17390502-5-cd21"></join>.</p>
               <p>Daniel King. On the 12th of April, between Ten and Eleven o'Clock, I was going from the Talbot Inn in the Strand, with a Basket in my Hand, towards <placeName id="t17390502-5-crimeloc22">Kensington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-5-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Kensington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-5-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-off20 t17390502-5-crimeloc22"></join>; and between Knights-Bridge and The Half-way House, I saw two Men about a hundred Yards from me. The Moon shone bright, and they both passed by me about a Foot. Then the Prisoner turned about and came on my Left Hand; the other on my Right. The Prisoner struck me with the But End of this Pistol on the Stomach; the other laid his Pistol on the Ground, about two Feet from me, and then he kneelled down, and pulled off my Shoes; the Buckles he gave me again, and said, damn you, take them again, - they are good for nothing. Then he pulled off my Breeches, and turned them inside out. The Prisoner demanded my Watch; I told him I had none. Then they damned me, and asked me the Reason why my Breeches Pockets were sewed up? I told them there was some Money in one of the Pockets,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020005"></xptr> and they searched it, and took from thence three Shillings, two Six-pences, and about Five-pence Half-penny, or Six-pence, in Copper. Then they searched my Basket, and turned the Straw out of it, but hearing some People coming up, they both ran away. My Face was then towards Kensington, so I turned about to follow them, but my Breeches being about my Heels I could not run; but as the Moon shone very bright, I could see them run, 'till they were fifty Yards from me. I saw the Prisoner's Face, and am positive to him; he had a Handkerchief about his Neck, and the same blue and white Striped-Waistcoat that he has on now: His Hat was cocked, and his Cap was pulled a little over his Eyes, but he was so near me, that I could see his Face very plain. As I followed them, crying, Stop Thief! - I am robbed! Mr. Evans met me, and asked me what was the Matter! I told him I had been robbed of my Shoes, and the little Money I had about me, by two Men. A Woman coming by told me, one of them had run down a narrow Passage, not far off; but I said, as I had saved my Life, I would make the best of my Way Home, and would borrow a Pair of Shoes at the Half Way House. When I had got within a hundred Yards of that House, I met with Mr. Gilpin, who asked me what made me go so uneasy? I told him I had been robbed, I described the Men to him, and went directly Homewards; so I can't tell how the Prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-person64">
                  Thomas 
                  Colcot 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person64" type="surname" value="Colcot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person64" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Brother, my Apprentice, and I were coming from Kensington, on Thursday, April 12, between ten and eleven o'Clock at Night, and between the Half-Way House and Kensington, we met the Prosecutor, and two Men with him. I said, - King! What the Devil do you do without your Shoes! Why, I have been robbed of my Shoes and all my Money, and one of them, says he, had a Striped-Waistcoat on. I was in a Fright for Fear we should be robbed, so we pushed on as hard as we could, and just as we came to Knights-Bridge, in a Bottom, there stood the Prisoner, and two Men on each Side of him. I thought we were beset, and made a little Stand, but one of the Men called me by my Name, and asked me if I had heard of this Robbery? I told them, I knew the Person very well; and I asked them if they knew that young Fellow in the Striped-Waistcoat? No, they said; nobody knew him. I asked him who he belonged to, and where he lived? He told me he lived in Cloth-fair, and was going to Kensington-Gore, to see his Sweetheart, one Mrs. Green's Daughter: I told him it was improper to go a courting without a Coat; he reply'd, he was a Lamp-lighter, and seldom wore a Coat. I said I am afraid you are the Man that committed this Robbery, for you answer King's Description, and somebody holding up a Candle and Lanthorn to his Face, he coloured prodigiously. God forbid, says I, that I should accuse an innocent Man, but you are like the Person that King described. O Lord! (says he) I will go along with you, I won't offer to go away. I thought proper he should be taken into Custody, and he was delivered to the Constable and Beadle.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it a very light Night?</p>
               <p>Colcot. It was Moonlight, but not very bright: Not light enough to distinguish a Man's Face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-person65">
                  Edward 
                  Underwood 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person65" type="surname" value="Underwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person65" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Beadle. On the 12th of last Month I was going my Rounds, three Quarters after Ten o'Clock, and at the Corner of Nag's-Head Court, I saw the Prisoner, and heard him ask a Man if he had seen any Body run that Way, for a Person (says he) has been robbed a little higher? I told him no one had run the Way I came, and I enquired which Way the Man was gone who had been robbed? The Prisoner said he was gone towards Kensington, and he very readily went with us a pretty Wav after the Prosecutor, on the Causeway, by Hyde-Park Wall; then we returned, and the Prisoner with us, searched several Courts. As we were searching, I asked the Prisoner his Name; he told me twas 
               <persName id="t17390502-5-person66">
                  Abraham 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person66" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person66" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; that he was a <rs id="t17390502-5-deflabel23" type="occupation">Lamp-lighter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-defend61 t17390502-5-deflabel23"></join>; that he lived in Cloth Fair; that he courted a Girl at Kensington-Gore, and was then going thither. He told us he was about an hundred Yards from King when he was robbed, and that upon his [King's] crying out, he turned back and pursued the Thieves, with King and two other Men, as far as Bear Court, and then King not caring to go any farther, he gave over the Pursuit likewise. Presently after, I was saying - it was a surprizing Thing the Thieves should get off, and we all so near, and upon that the Prisoner began to move away, and was got about 10 Yards from us, when Mr. Colcot came and asked us, if any of us knew the Prisoner? Telling us at the same Time, that he answered the Description that King had given of one of the Men, therefore he spoke to the Prisoner, and after he had asked him several Questions, I took him into Custody, and we went with him to King, at Kensington, and he said directly, - this is one of the Men that robbed me, - this was the Man that held his Pistol to my Breast, and desired me to take Charge of him. These Shoes we found next Morning.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020006"></xptr> King. They are the same I was robbed of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-person67">
                  George 
                  Whiting 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person67" type="surname" value="Whiting"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person67" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going my Rounds about Two o'Clock, and found a Coat upon the Threshold of a Door, near the Queen's Head, at Knights-Bridge, and this Pistol under the Coat. It has a Crack on each Side the Trigger, and was loaded very high. Mr. Deveil drew the Charge this Morning, and this is the Ball that was in it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. The Pistol has been in my Custody ever since the Prisoner was brought before me. I drew it this Morning, for it was loaded so high, that I was afraid some Accident might happen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-person68">
                  Samuel 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person68" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person68" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Three Weeks ago, (on a Thursday) the Prisoner and I made an Agreement to go out a robbing. Accordingly we set out from Crown Court, in Chick Lane, to the Wall between, Knights-Bridge and Kensington. We stood Two Hours (I am certain) by the Half-Way House, and let several People pass, who we thought were not worth our Trouble to rob; and then I asked him if we should go Home? No, he said; he wanted Money for the Holidays, and would have it from somebody; so we resolved to attack the first Man we met, which happened to be this Mr. King. I was a little way a-head of [before] the Prisoner, when he demanded his Money and clapped his Pistol to his Breast, but upon his stopping the Man, I turned back, and while he stood with his Pistol in that Posture, I kneeled down and took off the Prosecutor's Shoes, because the Prisoner said he wanted a Pair, so I took them off, - as he bid me. The Prisoner asked me if the Buckles were Silver? The Prosecutor said, - no, they cost him but a Groat, so I gave him them again. When we had got every thing, we went off, and met two Men, and when we had passed them we ran faster. I bid the Prisoner keep along with me; he would not; but ran away from the Causeway down the Middle of the Road, and fell all along. But I observing a Woman to look out of the Window, kept strait along, 'till I came to a little Turning by the White-Bear, and I ran down that Turning, and got over a Wall into Hyde-Park, and so into Grosvenor Square. Then I went Home, and saw no more of the Prisoner 'till I was taken. The Prisoner had two Striped-Waistcoats on, a white Apron, a Cotton-Cap, a white pair of Breeches, and an old Coat, with a plush Cape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-5-person69">
                  Thomas 
                  Cutter 
               <interp inst="t17390502-5-person69" type="surname" value="Cutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person69" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Coat which the Watchman found, the Prisoner owned to be his, and desired to have it because he had nothing on but a Waistcoat. Mr. Deveil let him have it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. The Prisoner deny'd the Coat to be his when the Watchman brought it; but finding the Evidence strong, he owned it; And said he lent it the Evidence that Night to rob in. The Evidence and the Prisoner were both before me at that Time.</p>
               <p>Defence. Catherine Sommerly. Once or twice I have seen the Evidence in a ragged Coat, with a Sort of a Plush-Cape to it. Once he came to our House in it, and said he was going to a Master, to treat with him about lighting his Lamps. Another Time he came in it, and staid half a Day. I live in Short's-Gardens, Drury-Lane.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. When the Prisoner was brought before me, he was desirous of being made an Evidence, and if the Prosecutor had not sworn positively to him, I should have consented. He confessed this Robbery, and eleven or twelve more, and accus'd the Evidence of being an Accomplice; upon which I granted a Warrant to take him, [the Evidence] but the Prosecutor could swear only to the Prisoner. I took his Confession in Writing, and only told him that Confession should not be produced against him. I said nothing to him about his Confession, till after King had sworn to him. <rs id="t17390502-5-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-5-punish25" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-5-punish25" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-5-defend61 t17390502-5-punish25"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
