<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-3">
               <interp inst="t17361013-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-3" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-3" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-3-off11-c46" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-3-defend52 t17361013-3-off11 t17361013-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>3. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-defend52" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ingle 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-3-defend52" type="surname" value="Ingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-defend52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-defend52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 3 Crimson Mohair Bed Curtain lined with Thread Sattin value 30 s. and 3 yellow Camblet Bed Curtains head with Sattin value 20 s. and one Callico Quilt value 10 s.
            </rs> the Goods of the most<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130005"></xptr> noble 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-victim54" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     <rs id="t17361013-3-viclabel12" type="occupation">Duke</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-3-victim54 t17361013-3-viclabel12"></join> of Chandos<interp inst="t17361013-3-victim54" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-victim54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-3-off11 t17361013-3-victim54"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17361013-3-cd13" type="crimeDate">September 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-3-off11 t17361013-3-cd13"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-person55">
                  Richard 
                  Lund 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person55" type="surname" value="Lund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person55" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These Goods were in my Custody (I being Groom of the Chambers) at my Lord Duke's House at Cannons; they were part of General Pepper's Furniture, and my Lord bought them about seven Years ago, but fearing there might be Vermin in them, they were laid in a Room over the Stables, and I believe none of the Servants in the House ever saw them but my self.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long have you lost these Things?</p>
               <p>Lund. I did not miss them 'till my Lord ordered me into Berkshire; and I think that was the 27th of September.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have had them 3 Years since May last.</p>
               <p>Lund. The Goods were taken away in Curtains, but I took them in the Prisoner's Lodging made up into Cloaths. After I had missed them, I was walking down the Town, and I saw this Gown through the Window: I suspected it was part of the Lining of the Camblet Curtains. This Mohair Gown I found in his Wife's Drawers, and this Skirt of a Child's Coat is the same yellow Sattin that lined the Curtains. I found some Pieces not made up; here is a Piece of a Curtain, four Breadths of Camblet a little faded; and I shall now produce a Curtain to answer it. Here is a Breadth and a half of the same Camblet, this is a Head Curtain, and here is the other: Now here is a single Breadth of the same found at his Lodging. This is a Wastcoat made of the Crimson Mohair. Here, Gentlemen, is a yellow Curtain lined with yellow Sattin; this piece of the same I found at 
               <persName id="t17361013-3-person56">
                  Thomas 
                  Loyd 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person56" type="surname" value="Loyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person56" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's where he lodged, and this yellow Gown, which has been worn. I found a piece of the Crimson Mohair in his Sister's House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-person57">
                  Robert 
                  Bunn 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person57" type="surname" value="Bunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person57" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We took these Things out of the Prisoner's Lodging, and went before Colonel Dobbins; when we came back we searched his Sister's House, and found these two quilted Coats; one is all Crimson Mohair, and the other is Crimson Mohair paned with white Sattin, and here is a Camblet yellow Gown faced and robed with Crimson Mohair; she told us her Brother gave them to her, he was present and owned he did so. All these Things which we found on them we compared before Colonel Dobbins, with the Remainder, which Mr. Lund had in his Custody, and we took them to be the same Goods. The Prisoner told us he bought them of a Servant of the Duke's who is now dead.</p>
               <p>Lund. These Breadths of crimson Mohair I took with the Petticoats, and if you compare them with the Curtains I have brought, you will find them to be the very same. We found these five Breadths of Sattin hid in a Hedge in that Gentleman's Field. 'Tis my Opinion he took them, though he said he bought them of a Maid Servant for a Guinea; that Maid had a very honest Character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Wife wore this Gown publickly when she went to the Duke's House.</p>
               <p>Lund. I know nothing of that. The rest of the Servants was unacquainted with this Furniture.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Lund has entrusted me all over the Duke's House: I used to look after the Waters, and there never was laid any Thing to my Charge before.</p>
               <p>Lund. He did look after the Waters, and has been all over the House, even in the Water Closets; but I have missed these two Years a silver Tea Canister that weighs 7 oz. and the Reason he was turned out of my Lord's Service, was for a suspicion we had of his hiding himself by my Lord's Library Door, where the Maids put their Mops and Brooms, and cutting out a Pannel of the Wainscot. I had a good Opinion of him 'till then, but he was then turned off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-person58">
                  Herbert 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person58" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person58" type="given" value="Herbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with Mr. Lund, and saw these Goods taken at the Prisoner's, and his Sister's Lodging. He told us he had given his Sister what we found upon her, and that he bought them for a Guinea. We found 5 Breadths of white Sattin in a Hedge in one of my Fields; the Woman (his Sister) directed me to it. I never knew any thing of him 'till this Affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-person59">
                  John 
                  Chertsy 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person59" type="surname" value="Chertsy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I thought (as how) he bought them: I asked no Questions on neither side.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. Those Things I bought, and if you please I will tell you how. I used to go up and down the House to fetch the Ashes away, and clean the Grate Hole in the Kitchen. A young Woman that lived there, asked me three or four times whether I was almost married, because if I was (she said) she had some things that would be of service to me, and she would sell them to me. I said no - sometimes I said I was, sometimes I was not; but however, one Day I was sitting by the Fire-side in the Garden Lodge, and this Creature brought the things to me. John, says she, I have brought the Things I was telling you about. I hope, said I, I shall not come into trouble about them. No, said she, I care not who sees them, or who hears of them, but I would not have them come to my Father's Ear. I bought them, and kept them in my Cupboard a Fortnight, and when I was turned away,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130006"></xptr> they gave no Account of the Occasion why I must go; so I took these Things with me, and had this Wastcoat made, and wore them publickly, which I should not have done, if I had had any suspicion of their being stolen. My Sister asked me for a Bit to make her a Petticoat, I bid her take some, but not too much.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say you saw some of the Things openly in the House? (To Lund)</p>
               <p>Lund. Yes, I saw a Piece hang down towards the Window as I was passing along, and it being the House of Loyd that was convicted for stealing his Grace's Lead, I got leave to search. I asked him in the Presence of Mr. Russel, and the Constable if he had no more of the white Sattin than what we found there, and he declared to us that he bought no more than lined him a Wastcoat; but afterwards in searching we found these five Breadths, which he owned he gave his Sister.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I sent a Piece by a Baker to a Woman at Totteridge, who was going to britch a a Boy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-3-person60">
                  Robert 
                  Marshal 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person60" type="surname" value="Marshal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person60" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-3-person61">
                  Samuel 
                  Tayler 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person61" type="surname" value="Tayler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person61" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-3-person62">
                  Silas 
                  Axtell 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person62" type="surname" value="Axtell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person62" type="given" value="Silas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-3-person63">
                  John 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person63" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person63" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17361013-3-person64">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Chasely 
               <interp inst="t17361013-3-person64" type="surname" value="Chasely"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person64" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-person64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spoke to the Prisoner's Character; some of these had known him from a Child, and all declared they took him to be a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There is my Master Snow can speak to my Behaviour in his Service.</p>
               <p>Mr. Snow. The Prisoner came recommended to my chief Gardener from the Duke of Chandos: Mr. Hear likewise gave him a good Character. He has work'd in my Gardens three Years, has always behaved very modestly, and appears to be a laborious, honest, useful, diligent Fellow; he has had great Opportunities of being dishonest; I have Ponds of Fish, a great deal of Fruit, and he has had frequent Access to the House; when I have been in Town, he has lain in the Laundry, full of Cloaths, for the security of the House, yet I never lost any thing. I cannot think he stole these Things, because he has worn them publickly in my service; if he had stole them, surely he would have sold them or dy'd them. I think him a very honest Fellow, and useful to the Publick. If your Lordship, and the Jury shall think otherwise, I hope he may be recommended to her Majesty's Favour.</p>
               <p>Marshal. I have seen him wear the Wastcoat publickly to and from the Duke's House.</p>
               <p>Russell. I have seen him wear a handsome red Wastcoat, which I thought he might have bought in Monmouth Street; I believe it is the same that is here I cannot say I ever heard of his dishonesty before this Affair.</p>
               <p>Lund. He might have worn all these Things, and none but my self, and one Footman more could know them. <rs id="t17361013-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
