<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-59">
               <interp inst="t17360908-59" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-59" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-59" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-59" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-59-off234-c223" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-defend356 t17360908-59-off234 t17360908-59-verdict238"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-59-off235-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-defend358 t17360908-59-off235 t17360908-59-verdict239"></join>
         
               <p>69, 70. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-defend356" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Burroughs 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend356" type="surname" value="Burroughs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend356" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-defend358" type="defendantName">
                     Bryan 
                     Carney 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend358" type="surname" value="Carney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend358" type="given" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-defend358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, Burroughs for <rs id="t17360908-59-off234" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-off234" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-off234" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver Watch and a silver Chain, value 4 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-victim360" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Orr 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-59-victim360" type="surname" value="Orr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-victim360" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-victim360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            ; and Carney for <rs id="t17360908-59-off235" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-off235" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-off235" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same knowing it to be stole
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-59-cd236" type="crimeDate">August the 4th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-off234 t17360908-59-cd236"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-off235 t17360908-59-cd236"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Orr. My Lord, and you Gentlemen<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080015"></xptr> of the Jury (Reading) I committed the Thing to writing, that I might not forget any Thing material, nor trouble the Court with any Thing that was trifling. This I did when the Thing happen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. 'Tis not usual Sir to read a Testimony; you may use your Papers to refresh your Memory, but it has always been the Custom for Witnesses to give their Evidence, Viva Voce.</p>
               <p>Orr. My Lord, I will endeavour to do it. August the 4th at Night, I came to the <placeName id="t17360908-59-crimeloc237">Hamburgh Coffee House in Drury Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-59-crimeloc237" type="placeName" value="Hamburgh Coffee House in Drury Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-59-crimeloc237" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-off234 t17360908-59-crimeloc237"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-off235 t17360908-59-crimeloc237"></join>. I lost a silver Watch value 4l. After a pretty long Walk, coming to my Lodgings in Clare Court, near Covent Garden, at this Coffee House I call'd, not knowing the Character of the House. I stay'd there to refresh my self, and had a little Punch. I paid my Reckoning, was coming away, but being a little grip'd. I call'd for a small Dram. (Reading.) I committed my Thoughts to writing, having time to do it, and am better able to express them in that Light; and I humbly conceive (my Lord) it will set the matter clearer. I put my Hat and Watch upon a Chair, in the Room where I was sitting.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a publick Room?</p>
               <p>Orr. It was a publick Room: The following Part of my Declaration, will shew both where it was, and how. Being a little grip'd, I call'd for a small Dram, and then a Girl came up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say you was in the Publick Room?</p>
               <p>Orr. It was a publick Coffee House, I made no scruple of going up Stairs, because I've known such Houses to have Rooms above, for reading News, and private Letters. I was in a private Room; tho' I don't know but all the Rooms are publick in some sort. On calling for a Dram, the Prisoner came up Stairs, I bid her make haste, and fetch it to me. My Watch and Hat were lying by me then upon the Chair between me and the Door. The Girl took up my Watch, and run down Stairs; immediately I follow'd her, and took hold of her at the Foot of the Stairs, and demanded my Watch. She desired Money before she'd give it me; first half a Guinea, then a Crown, then Charity because she was poor. I judg'd a Prison or a Workhouse fitter for her than that. There was no Bed in the Room, and I can assure you, on all the Principles of Honour, I called there thro' Innocence and Ignorance. Ignorance with Regard to the House, and Innocence with Regard to myself: I called for my Watch, none answer'd; I contested with the Girl, in Order to have my Watch again. Carney was near her; whether she deliver'd it to him when I came down, or how it was convey'd from her, I know not. That Night I thought it expedient for me to go away, but I came again next Morning. I desired the Mistress of the House to get my Watch again, or I would have a Warrant, and take them all up. She said she knew nothing of the Watch, or who the Person was; but afterwards she own'd the Man, her Servant; the Girl an Attendant on some Occasions. I had a Warrant on Suspicion for the Woman of the House, but when the Constable came, not a Woman in the House was there. I came several Days after to find my Watch; Carney, the now Prisoner at the Barr, said he would see, and help me to it, in a little Time. A Day or 2 after this, I came again, to see if he had any Notice of it. He said 'twas pawn'd for a Guinea and a half, and that with 18 d. would soon redeem it. I desired him to carry me to the Pawnbrokers, that I might be sure it was my own, then I'd redeem it. He said then I might swear Felony against the Pawnbroker, and would not do it: saying, he would fetch it in 3 Minutes Time. This made me suspect he had a hand in detaining the Watch. He said he had seen the Girl, and she had put her self in better Order, and had bought Cloaths with the Money, commending her for her Industry. On this, my Lord, I brought the Constable to take the Mistress of the House, and Girl if found. I charg'd the Constable with the Prisoners at the Barr, and carry'd them to Justice Midford, and he on the Evidence given, thought proper to commit them. A few Days afterwards, the Watch was found at a Pawnbroker's, pawn'd in Carney's Name for 6 s. I gave the Constable the Marks, by which with Certainty he might know, if it was mine: we found it so; I went to see it, at 
               <persName id="t17360908-59-person361">
                  Mary 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person361" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person361" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person361" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. Upon the Back was stuck a Paper, Carney 6 s. This appears both by the Paper and their Books. The Girl, my Lord, was found and taken up by Warrant, and she own'd, taking the Watch, in the manner now related. Captain 
               <persName id="t17360908-59-person362">
                  Midford
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person362" type="given" value="Midford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person362" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Constable, and others, knows she own'd it. She fell upon her Knees and begg'd she might not be sent to the same Prison with him, for fear he should knock her on the Head, for being an Evidence against him.</p>
               <p>Carney. Ask him upon his Oath if he did not leave the Watch with the Woman for 6 s.</p>
               <p>Orr. Upon my Oath I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person363">
                  Mary 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person363" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person363" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Carney brought the Watch to me for 6 s. and he desired me to take care of it, for that it had been left for that Sum, with the Person who sent him.</p>
               <p>Burroughs. He pick'd me up in the Street, at the End of Princes Street in Drury Lane.</p>
               <p>Carney. Ask Mrs. Barret if she did not tell me, I might have a Guinea upon it, and whether I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080016"></xptr> did not say, no, 'tis left but for 6 s. and I must have no more upon it.</p>
               <p>Barret. Yes, 'tis very true.</p>
               <p>Orr. Did not you (to the Pawnbroker) own, that he pawn'd it at twice for 3 s. and 3 s.</p>
               <p>Barret. Yes.</p>
               <p>Orr. When did he pawn it?</p>
               <p>Barret. I cannot tell the Time.</p>
               <p>Orr. Was it Night or Day?</p>
               <p>Barret. It was one Morning in August.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person364">
                  Arnwood 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person364" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person364" type="given" value="Arnwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to serve the Warrant upon Burroughs, at the Coffee House, but when we came there the Girl was gone. I bid Mr. Orr charge me with the Fellow; he did, and I carry'd him before Justice Midford, and there he say'd he knew nothing at all of it. I enquired of the Pawnbrokers in th' Neighbourhood, and found it at Barret's. The Woman of the House directed me to find Burroughs in Lincoln's Inn Fields; I took her and carry'd her before the Justice; there she own'd that Carney took the Watch from her, and when she desired him to let the Gentleman have it again, he d - d her for a Bitch, and said he should not have it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Business, Sir?</p>
               <p>Orr. I am a private Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Carney. Ask the Gentleman if he is not a Parson?</p>

               <p>Orr. I don't see that will affect the Cause at all; I am a private Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Carney. A Clergyman may be a private Gentleman: I desire he may Answer?</p>
               <p>Orr. I don't conceive he has a Right to that: I have the same Right of Prosecution if I am, or am not.</p>
               <p>Q. He has a Right to enquire, and if he insists upon it, you must answer his Question, you hear Sir, what it is.</p>
               <p>Orr. I am not a Clergyman. I live in America: I have been here 3 Months, and this Fall I return to America again.</p>
               <p>Burroughs's Defence. I was coming up Drury Lane about 9 o'Clock at Night, and at the Corner of Princes Street, that Man stopp'd me, and ask'd me, if I would drink a Glass of Wine: Thank ye, Sir, says I, so he carried me to the Hamburgh Coffee House in Drury Lane; we went up Stairs; and he called for a quartern of Brandy; we staid there some Time, and then we called for a Bottle of Cyder: Then he told me if I would have some Concerns with him, he would make me a Present: After this he pull'd out his Watch, and having no Money to pay the Reckoning, he gave me the Watch to pawn for 6 s. there being no Body else in the House, I gave Carney the Watch to pawn for him; he went and brought 3 s. what do you bring this for? says I, you should have brought 6 s. I thought, says he, you said 3 s. so I sent him back for 3 s. more; he had 1 s. for Porterage, the rest of the Money was paid into the Gentleman's Hand. And the very next Morning he came and demanded his Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person365">
                  Anne 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person365" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person365" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing at the Hamburgh Coffee House Door. and I saw the Prisoner ( Burroughs ) and the Prosecutor go into the House; she call'd for a Candle, and they both went up Stairs together. They call'd for a Quartern of Brandy; 
               <persName id="t17360908-59-person366">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person366" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person366" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             carry'd it up; then I went away: In about an Hour's Time, I came again, and saw the Prosecutor talking to Mrs. Hill at the Barr, and they were both drinking Punch. Next Day he came for his Watch, and says he to Carney, Young Man do you know where the Girl lives, that I was in Company with last Night? Carney said he did not know justly, but would endeavour to find her out; I shall not mind (says the Prosecutor) giving her the Trifle of Money, but the Watch I value, and would not part with it for 20 l. Carney said he was sure the Girl would give him the Watch again, when she saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are you? (To this Witness.)</p>
               <p>Cooley. I keep the Bar at Hill's Coffee House in Drury-Lane. Mrs. Hill is out of Business now, when she settles, I shall keep her Barr again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person367">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person367" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person367" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mrs. Lee at the Hamburgh Coffee House; the Prosecutor and the Prisoner came in about 9 o'Clock: the Girl came in first, and the Prosecutor follow'd her. He called for a Room: I took a Candle off the Barr, and li't them both up Stairs; he call'd for Wine, then a Gill of Brandy, I carry'd it up my self, 'twas Cherry Brandy: I came down, and in some little time the Bell was rung again; I went up, and he spake for 18 d of Punch: I left them an Hour or better; then he called for Cyder, and then a Gill of Brandy, then call'd to pay, and the Reckoning was 3 s. and 6 d which he gave me. Then they both came down Stairs; and my Mistress being gone to a Neighbour's Mrs. Hill took care of the Barr, and the Prosecutor went up to the Barr, and spoke to her: they had a Tiff of Punch, and drank it at the Barr, Hill, Burroughs and the Prosecutor. Then Burroughs and he went up Stairs again, and they had 18 d of Punch again; I carry'd it up, and heard him ask Burroughs if she call'd to stay with him all Night? Yes, says she, if you'll make me a Present, but not else. He said he would not desire any Woman's Company for nothing: what he had was little, but he would make her amends some other Time: he pull'd out 3 s. and 6 d. and some Half-pence, but the Girl did not care to oblige him for that: he had a silver Watch, (he said) which he would leave at the Barr, for half a Guinea; the Prisoner told<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080017"></xptr> him the People there did not take Pawns, but said he might leave it with her for half a Guinea; well (says he) I have a Friend hard by, will redeem it for me next Morning; so I came down, and heard no more. In a little Time they both came down Stairs again: I went out, and saw no more of them that Night.</p>
               <p>Carney. Ask her whether she did not see the Prosecutor put the Watch into the Woman's Hand to pawn that?</p>
               <p>Clark. I was in the Room, when the Watch was in her Hand, but I can't swear he gave it her. She hold it publickly in her Hand, and after that, I saw it lie on the Table.</p>
               <p>Orr. Ask her (lest she should play the Jesuit) whether she saw the Watch in the Girl's Hand, up Stairs or below.</p>
               <p>Clark. Up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Orr. Ask her whether I did not hold the Girl by the Coat, and demand my Watch?</p>
               <p>Clark. I did not hear him demand it at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person368">
                  Sarah 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person368" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person368" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On a Thursday Night, in the latter End of August, the Woman Prisoner, and the Prosecutor came into this Coffee House: the Woman first, and he follow'd her immediately; they both desired to be li't up Stairs; Mary Clark li't them up, and they call'd for Liquor, but I did not mind what: They staid an Hour, or an Hour and half: Then they call'd for the Reckoning and paid it. The Woman of the House being sent for out, I look'd after her Barr, and in a little Time, the Woman and he came down Stairs: He stopp'd at the Barr, to speak with me: He asked me to drink a Glass, of Punch with him; I said I would if he pleased, so he desired me to make it. He told me he was a  Foreigner, a Crelian and asked me to drink a Dram, after the Punch; we drank a Glass of Rack, and for Punch and Rack, he paid half a Guinea. He told me he had now but little Money left, but says he, I don't live far off. I told him the Servant should call him a Coach. and told him London was a sad Place - if he had no Money: Madam says he, I will not have a Coach, nor will I go home: Tho' I have not Money, I have Money's worth, and if you'll give me your Company to Night, I'll leave my Watch with you, 'till next Day. I said, I never went with any Gentlemen farther than the Coffee Room, and never took Pawns on such Accounts; he importuned me: Said he liked me better than the Girl, and if I would consent, he would give me Satisfaction: He begg'd of me not to be so unkind; but I refusing, he said, well, I must return to my former Girl: I left that to his Discretion, and up Stairs he carry'd her again, and staid half  Hour: Then the Prisoner came down a Step or two before him, and in the Coffee Room, he took hold of her and said he would have his Watch again: She said with all her Heart, if he would give her the half Guinea he had promis'd her. He call'd her Hussy and Slut, and said he would not stay with her all Night; No matter that for says she; you have had my Company, and shall be as good as your Word. He took fast hold of her Coats, and said she should not go. Well says she, if you won't stay with me all Night, give me a Crown. He would give her nothing, and would have his Watch too. I thought he would have torn the Cloaths off her Back. I asked him how he could use the poor Creature so unkindly, To have her Company and give her Nothing: Says I, if I had given you mine, I suppose you'd have serv'd me so. I threatned to call the Watch, so they both went out of the House together; but, it seems, he let her go, and came back to the Woman of the House and insisted on her making good his Watch. After many Words he went away, and came again the next Day, or the Day following, and enquired after the Girl: I told him he look'd like one that would take more care of his Conscience, than to charge her with Felony, when he had had her Company, and when he knew he had offer'd it me upon the same Terms. He said he had been put in a right way, and if he had not his Watch again, he would swear a Robbery against us all.</p>
               <p>Orr. My Lord, I humbly conceive, as she can swear so well, that she will answer some Questions as well.</p>
               <p>Burroughs. Pray, Sir, did not you lye with me? - Upon your Oath.</p>
               <p>Orr. Upon my Honour and my Oath, my Lord, I did not.</p>
               <p>Burroughs. My Lord he did, against a Chair.</p>
               <p>Orr. I touch'd her no way on the Face of the Earth, except when I laid hold of her Petticoats; and upon my Honour and Oath, I made no offers to Hill, nor did I drink any Punch at the Barr. (To Hill ) was I drunk or sober, Madam?</p>
               <p>Hill. I took you to be sober; you talk'd in the same serious manner, that you do now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-59-person369">
                  Thomas 
                  Archer 
               <interp inst="t17360908-59-person369" type="surname" value="Archer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person369" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Hamburgh Coffee House one Sunday Night, and this Gentleman came in and said he had left a Watch with a Girl for a Trifle; what it was, or who she was, I could not tell; but he said nothing of its being stolen: He desired Carney the Waiter to get it again, or find the Girl out, and he would make him any reasonable Satisfaction.</p>
               <p>Orr. My Lord, I have a Person to prove that upon the Difficulty of this Prosecution, they said the would produce People who should Rapp fast enough</p>
               <p>A Witness. I was talking to Barret about the Watch she had taken, and she said, I wish as well off on Account of that Watch. a with this (Mr. Orr's) for I have heard some say, they could find People enough to R</p>
               <p>Barret. I said, I wish'd I was as this 6 s. Watch. Burroughs <rs id="t17360908-59-verdict238" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-verdict238" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-verdict238" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty, Felony only
            </rs> Carney <rs id="t17360908-59-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17360908-59-punish240" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-punish240" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-59-punish240" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-59-defend356 t17360908-59-punish240"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
