<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-56">
               <interp inst="t17370216-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-56" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-56" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-56-off246-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-56-defend342 t17370216-56-off246 t17370216-56-verdict250"></join>
         
               <p>63. 
               <persName id="t17370216-56-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-defend342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17370216-56-off246" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-off246" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-off246" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch and a Shagreen Case, value 14 l and a Gold Seal set with five Diamonds, value 3 l.
            </rs> from the Person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-victim344" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Rogers 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-56-victim344" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-victim344" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-56-off246 t17370216-56-victim344"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370216-56-cd247" type="crimeDate">Feb. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-56-off246 t17370216-56-cd247"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person345">
                  Edward 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person345" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person345" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday Night, this Gentleman and I was coming past the <placeName id="t17370216-56-crimeloc248">Two Blue-Posts at Temple-Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-56-crimeloc248" type="placeName" value="Two Blue-Posts at Temple-Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-56-crimeloc248" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-56-off246 t17370216-56-crimeloc248"></join>, and the Prisoner ask'd us to give her a Pint of Wine. We went into the House with her, and when we had finish'd the Wine, she and I went into another Room; when we had done our Business, we return'd to the Room where we had left the Gentleman. She was no sooner enter'd, but she said she wanted to speak with the Drawer, and away she ran smartly thro' the House, and the Door was shut upon her. I had my Watch when I went in, and when I came out I miss'd it. The Case was found afterwards under the Table. I lodge in Bell-yard, and went to my Lodging about a quarter of an Hour after she ran out of the Tavern, and then it was I miss'd it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person346">
                  Dillon 
                  Wye 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person346" type="surname" value="Wye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person346" type="given" value="Dillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Confirm'd the above Evidence; adding, that he saw the Prosecutor playing with the String of his Watch before he retired with the Prisoner, and that he thought a Lady in her Garb would not have done such a Thing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rogers. I went back to the Tavern to enquire for the Woman the same Night, and I told them I had lost my Watch, but the Doors were shut, and they would not let me come in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person347">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Manning 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person347" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person347" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Gentleman came on Monday to enquire for his Watch; and after he was gone, I found the Case in the Feathers, that was the Room they went first into. I shew'd him where the Prisoner liv'd in Chancery-Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person348">
                  Philip 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person348" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person348" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drew the Wine, and carry'd it into two separate Rooms. They both came in together with the Lady, and they stay'd about a Quarter of an Hour; she came out, and went thro' the House very briskly, about six Minutes after they came out of the private Room, and our Cook shut the Door after her. When they paid the Reckoning they said nothing about what they had lost; but one of them return'd in about half an Hour, and knock'd at the Door, my Master was ill, and he order'd the Door not to be open'd any more that Night. Next Morning my Fellow Servant shew'd him the Lady's Lodgings in Chancery-Lane, and gave him the Case that was found under the Table.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. At Temple-Bar I met these Gentlemen, and went into the Tavern with them; we drank a Glass a-piece, and then I went with the Prosecutor into another Room, and we had a Pint of Wine there. While we were in this Room together, he call'd the Drawer, and bid him go into the other Room, and ask the Gentleman if he had got his Snuff-box; the Gentleman sent Word he had it not; well then, says he, I have left it at the Fountain, where I supp'd to Night. They kept me 'till between 11 and 12, and he drew his Sword, and said, if I offer'd to go out of the Room he would run me thro', and getting up to take hold of me, he fell down, for he was pretty much fuddled, and so I got out of the House, and I heard no more 'till next Night the Prosecutor came with two or three Men and took me out of my Bed.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rogers. I was there twice on Monday, and she denied her self.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person349">
                  Betty 
                  Pyke 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person349" type="surname" value="Pyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person349" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person349" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17370216-56-person350">
                  William 
                  Vizard 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person350" type="surname" value="Vizard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person350" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , never heard of her being a Thief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-56-person351">
                  Nanny 
                  Millan 
               <interp inst="t17370216-56-person351" type="surname" value="Millan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person351" type="given" value="Nanny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her three Years, she is a <rs id="t17370216-56-deflabel249" type="occupation">Mantua-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-56-defend342 t17370216-56-deflabel249"></join>, I work'd for her, and never heard any Thing dishonest of her.</p>
               <p>Councel. Have not you heard of her being more Trades than one? Don't you know of her being a lewd Woman? <rs id="t17370216-56-verdict250" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-56-verdict250" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
