<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-64">
               <interp inst="t17370420-64" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-64" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-64" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-64" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-64-off332-c351" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-64-defend504 t17370420-64-off332 t17370420-64-verdict334"></join>
         
               <p>78. 
               <persName id="t17370420-64-defend504" type="defendantName">
                  Constant 
                  Seers 
               <interp inst="t17370420-64-defend504" type="surname" value="Seers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-defend504" type="given" value="Constant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-defend504" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-64-off332" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-off332" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-off332" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Cloth Serge Coat, value 20 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-64-victim506" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hookham 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-64-victim506" type="surname" value="Hookham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-victim506" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-victim506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-64-off332 t17370420-64-victim506"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370420-64-cd333" type="crimeDate">April 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-64-off332 t17370420-64-cd333"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. Last Wednesday se'en-night, I order'd my Man to clean my Cloaths, and he hung this Coat on the Rails of the Stairs. I sent him out of an Errand, and went backward my self to a Stable I have in the Yard, after I had lock'd the Hatch at the Door. In a little Time my Brother came to see me, and he stopp'd the Prisoner in the Entry with the Coat upon her. I made her come back, into the Yard, and there she fell upon her Knees, and begg'd I would forgive her. She had one Pair of Pattens on her Feet, and another Pair in her Apron.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-64-person507">
                  John 
                  Hookham 
               <interp inst="t17370420-64-person507" type="surname" value="Hookham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person507" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had bought a Pair of Shoes about a Month ago of a Woman in that House, and she order'd me to call for something else, so I did, and the Coat happening to fall down, I only went to take it up.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. My Lord, I have not had a Woman Servant in my House these five Years. My Sister comes to make my Bed, when she's at Leisure; when she is not, my Man-servant does it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-64-person508">
                  Edmund 
                  Manning 
               <interp inst="t17370420-64-person508" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person508" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 9 or 10 Years; she goes about with China and old Cloaths. I have entrusted her to collect Rent for me to the Value of 100 l. and she never wronged me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. Ask him if he has known, or entrusted her within these three Years?</p>
               <p>Manning No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. I would ask him, whether she has not had the Character of a drunken, disorderly Woman for these three Years?</p>
               <p>Manning. I never heard any thing but that she was honest.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. This very Person apply'd to me to make up the Matter, and to know the Circumstances of the Fact; I told him, he should hear them in this Place; and the Mother of the Prisoner was with him, and declared in his Presence, that she was a drunken, idle, disorderly Person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear this?</p>
               <p>Manning. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how could you give her this good Character?</p>
               <p>Manning. Drunkenness is not Dishonesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-64-person509">
                  Michael 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17370420-64-person509" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person509" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew her dishonest; she will drink Gin indeed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-64-person510">
                  Ann 
                  Manson 
               <interp inst="t17370420-64-person510" type="surname" value="Manson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person510" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-person510" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her many Years, I never heard of her wronging any Body.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you keep Company with the Prisoner much?</p>
               <p>Manson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she not had the Character of a drunken Woman these 3 Years?</p>
               <p>Manson. I never saw her drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you whether she has not that Character?</p>
               <p>Manson. Why - as to Drunkenness - I never heard any thing of Theft.</p>
               <p>Q. Why don't you answer the Question?</p>
               <p>Manson. Why, yes I have heard something of that; but a Person is not to be hang'd or transported for Drinking.</p>
               <p>Jury. I desire to know how the Gentleman can live in a House, without a Woman?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hookham. Sir, If you desire to know the Oeconomy of my Family, I'll give it you in a few Words. My Sister, when she has Leisure, comes to make my Bed; when she has not, my Man does it.</p>
               <p>C. The People that have appear'd to the Prisoner's Character, have behav'd in so odd a Manner, that they need call some Persons to their own. <rs id="t17370420-64-verdict334" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-verdict334" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-verdict334" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17370420-64-punish335" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-64-punish335" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-64-defend504 t17370420-64-punish335"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
