<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381011-15">
               <interp inst="t17381011-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-15" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381011"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-15" type="date" value="17381011"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381011-15-off72-c118" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-15-defend152 t17381011-15-off72 t17381011-15-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>17. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-defend152" type="defendantName">
                     Margery 
                     Stanton 
                  <interp inst="t17381011-15-defend152" type="surname" value="Stanton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-defend152" type="given" value="Margery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-defend152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17381011-15-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 5 s a Guinea and a Shilling, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381011-15-victim154" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Pierce 
                        <interp inst="t17381011-15-victim154" type="surname" value="Pierce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-15-victim154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-15-victim154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-15-off72 t17381011-15-victim154"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17381011-15-cd73" type="crimeDate">June 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-15-off72 t17381011-15-cd73"></join>.</p>
               <p>Pierce. About 12 o'Clock at Night, on the 12th of June, I was going Home to my own House in Bond-street, in the Parish of St. George Hannover-Square, and the Prisoner pick'd me up; she came a-cross the Way to me, and took me to a Door, where she and I stood talking together about the Space of Time that I have been speaking here; then she went into the House, and carry'd away my Watch and Money with her. I had not got 5 Doors from the Place before I missed it. - But with Respect to the Thing, - here's a Woman can give a much better Account of it than I can.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was the Door open where you talk'd with the Prisoner?</p>

               <p>Peirce. Yes, but I did not go in, I don't suppose that both my Feet were over the Threshold; and I am sure I was not with her above 3 Minutes, but while I stood there, she went in and fetch'd me a Glass of Liquor, I refused to drink it, and she vow'd, if I would not drink it she would pour it into my Bosom; then she went in, and shut the Door. When I missed my Watch and Money, I went back and knock'd at the Door, no Body would open it, but they told me, if I would come in the Morning I should have my Things again.</p>
               <p>Jury. Could she take your Watch and Money in 3 Minutes, and you not miss it?</p>
               <p>Peirce. I had both Watch and Money in my Hand but 2 Minutes before she pick'd me up; and as soon as she went in I missed a Guinea, a Shilling, and my Watch too.</p>
               <p>Jury. Are you a marryed Man or a Batchelor Friend?</p>
               <p>Peirce. A married Man.</p>
               <p>Juryman. Then you had no need to go abroad.</p>
               <p>Peirce. I went the next Day to the House, to enquire after my Watch and my Money, and the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173810110014"></xptr> Minute the Prisoner saw me, she ran into another House, and so I lost her. 'Twas a dark Night, but when she came out with the Glass of Liquor, she brought a Candle with her, so I saw her Face. She mov'd her Lodging upon this very Account, else I should have taken her up before. About 3 Months afterward, I happen'd to see her, so I took her up, and carry'd her before a Magistrate; and she told him she did not know me - she had never seen my Face before in her Life. 'Tis true, I had been drinking, - but I was - sensible.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you take up another Woman for this Fact?</p>
               <p>Peirce. After I took this Gentlewoman up, she got a Man to appear for her before the Justice, who told me I had taken up one or two Women before, tho' I never charg'd any other Woman with this Robbery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He swore before the Justice that he lost his Watch in the House, and the Woman that he had taken up before came and made an Affidavit, that she who robb'd him made her Escape.</p>
               <p>Peirce. There was another Woman before the Justice, but I charged only the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person155">
                  Martha 
                  Cassedy 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person155" type="surname" value="Cassedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person155" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the Prisoner in my Life, - I hope you'll excuse me, - I never was here before, - I mean, I never saw her 'till I saw her here; but I have seen the Prosecutor, and the Prisoner is not the Woman he brought into my House in Wardour street; she was a lusty clever Woman, and brought the Prosecutor in, about 10 or 11 at Night, and call'd for a Pint of Two-penny, - about 6 Months ago.</p>
               <p>Peirce. I am sure I never carry'd but one Woman to her House.</p>
               <p>Cassedy. And that Woman was not the Prisoner. He drank Part of a Pint of Two-penny in the Tap-Room with the Woman he brought in, and then they both went out together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person156">
                  Mary 
                  Driskell 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person156" type="surname" value="Driskell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person156" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Peirce met with me, about 2 or 3 Months ago, between 9 and 10 at Night, in Coventry-Court, in the Hay-market; and he laid hold of me, and swore I was the Woman that had robb'd him of his Watch. Another Man that was with him acted the Constable, and they dragg'd me to Bond-street, and us'd me very ill for 3 Hours; but when I threaten'd to send for my Husband, and People that knew me, they let me go.</p>
               <p>Peirce. I never saw this Creature in my Life, 'till I saw her before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Driskell. Yes; I went before the Justice, and there he knew me perfectly well, and said, - why you are the Woman I took up before, - I have nothing to say to you. He had taken me up for stealing his Watch, and us'd me ill, telling me for 3 Hours together, I was the Woman; so when the Prisoner was carry'd before the Justice, I went with her.</p>
               <p>Peirce. I beg she may be ask'd what House I carry'd her to in Bond street?</p>
               <p>Driskell. I don't know; - but I believe I could find my Way to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person157">
                  Hannah 
                  Dwyer 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person157" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person157" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I live in Belton street, St. Giles's. The Prisoner came to live with me in the Beginning of June, and staid with me 'till Peirce came and took her out of my House. She never lay a Night all that Time, out of my House, but kept close, and work'd very endeavouring, for her Bread, at Plain-work and Washing. As for her Character, I never heard nothing of her, but what was very extraordinary. She never went out at all, - never but about Business.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person158">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person158" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person158" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She liv'd with me about 2 Years, in Ale's-Yard, and left me last April. I never saw any thing but what was just and honest in her, so I preferr'd her to Mrs. Smith, and she preferr'd her to Mrs. Dwyer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person159">
                  Dorothy 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person159" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person159" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She liv'd between four and five Months with me, and went from me last April to Mrs. Dwyer; I never hear'd but she behav'd her self well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-15-person160">
                  Eliz 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person160" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person160" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her from a Baby; she clears Headcloths, and uses her Needle. She made some Shirts for my Husband, and was going with me to buy Trimmings for them, when the Prosecutor came with a Butcher and a Constable, and said, I believe this was the Woman that took my Watch, for I remember she had the Sign of the Small Pox in her Face, so he carry'd her before a Justice, and she was committed to Jail. Upon this I got a Lawyer to appear for her, (an Acquaintance of mine) and Peirce went to the Lawyer's House in Compton-street, and told him he was a Party concern'd, and so the Lawyer has got him to be try'd for Scandal in the King's-Bench, The Lawyer's Name is Luttwiche, - he practises the Law, - but whether he is a Lawyer or not, I cannot tell. I have ask'd the Prosecutor how he could charge a Woman who had liv'd so well? Why (says he) if you're her Friend, give me a Silver Watch, or disburse 5 l. and I'll acquit her, else I will swear down-right that she had it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor to Cassedy. Have not you often told me in your own House, that the Prisoner's Name was 
               <persName id="t17381011-15-person161">
                  Margery 
                  Madge 
               <interp inst="t17381011-15-person161" type="surname" value="Madge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person161" type="given" value="Margery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and could tell me where she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173810110015"></xptr> might be found; and that you and she had had many Quarrels about my Watch</p>
               <p>Cassedy. No, never in my Life.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. God forgive them all! they'd swear a Man's Head off for a Farthing. <rs id="t17381011-15-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-15-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
