<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-50">
               <interp inst="t17350116-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-50" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-50" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-50-off215-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-defend321 t17350116-50-off215 t17350116-50-verdict219"></join>
         
               <p>53. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-defend321" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17350116-50-defend321" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-defend321" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-defend321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17350116-50-defloc214">St. Dunstan in the West, in the County of Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-50-defloc214" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan in the West, in the County of Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-50-defloc214" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-defend321 t17350116-50-defloc214"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17350116-50-off215" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-off215" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-off215" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Linnen Bag, seven Portugal Pieces of the value of thirty six Shillings each, a Moidore, and sixteen Guineas, the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350116-50-victim323" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Pollamounter 
                        <interp inst="t17350116-50-victim323" type="surname" value="Pollamounter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-50-victim323" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-50-victim323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-off215 t17350116-50-victim323"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17350116-50-person324">
                        Mary 
                        Glascock 
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person324" type="surname" value="Glascock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-50-person324" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-50-person324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17350116-50-cd216" type="crimeDate">December 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-off215 t17350116-50-cd216"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Nicholas Pollamounter. On the twenty sixth of December, I took Coach in Westminister with Mr. Cornish. We were going to his House in Sheer-Lane to drink a Bowl of Punch. And just as we came out of the Coach, two Girls asked me to drink a Glass of Wine; and I being in a good Humour, we went with them into the <placeName id="t17350116-50-crimeloc217">Angel and Crown Tavern, at the Corner of Sheer-Lane, by Temple-Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-50-crimeloc217" type="placeName" value="Angel and Crown Tavern, at the Corner of Sheer-Lane, by Temple-Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-50-crimeloc217" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-off215 t17350116-50-crimeloc217"></join>. 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person325">
                  Mary 
                  Glascock 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person325" type="surname" value="Glascock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person325" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keeps the House, and the Prisoner lives with her. We had two Bottles of Wine, and some Cakes. Mr. Cornish was with me. The Prisoner came up into our Company and drank with us. I had got eleven Portugal Six and Thirty Shilling Pieces, a Moidore and sixteen Guineas in a Bag. I pull'd out this Bag to pay the Reckoning which was 6 s. 3 d. The two Girls were dismist. The Prisoner rung the Bell, the Door was open, and another Girl whose Name was 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person326">
                  Margaret 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person326" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person326" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in. She and I went into another Room. When we had been some time together, she went away, and presently after she was gone, I mist my Bag and all my Money. I went directly to the Room where I had left the Prisoner and Cornish, and complained of my Loss. Well, says the Prisoner. Don't make a Disturbance here, for this is a very honest House. I know the Girl, and if you'll give me some Reward for my Trouble I'll see if I can't find her, and help you to your Money again. So he and Cornish went out to look for her. The Prisoner and she returned, and Cornish follow'd them. The Prisoner insisted upon a Discharge, and Cornish writ one. The Girl returned the Money. Cornish and the Prisoner counted it. The Prisoner received four Six and Thirty Shilling Pieces for returning it, and then I put the rest up in my Right-hand Breeches-Pocket, where I thought it would be safe. The Prisoner, besides having the four Portugal Pieces, insisted that I should call for a Bowl of Arrack Punch, which I did, and after that we had another. We were not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160015"></xptr> now in the Room above where I first went with the two Girls, but in a Room below Stairs. At drinking the second Bowl, the Landlady, Mary Glascock, called Cornish out of the Room, and then there was only the Prisoner and I and Peg Bouther together. Peg went away in six or eight Minutes. And in four or five Minutes after she was gone, I mist my Money again, and begun to make a Noise about it. The Prisoner then pretended that he did not know the Girl - I had no mistrust that they would have served me so a second time - I was not very sober - nor quite drunk, because I knew Peg full well when I met with her the next Morning. But Cornish was quite sober, for he drank nothing but Water with a Toast in it, all the while he was in our Company</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I in the House when the Girl returned the Money?</p>
               <p>Pollamounter. Yes, you and she were both together?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am cautious of asking Questions, because I know you will swear any thing - But were not you robb'd three times - were you not robb'd of a Crown by one of those two Girls that came in with you?</p>
               <p>Pollamounter. No; I gave her a Crown freely.</p>
               <p>P. Council. What Employment are you of?</p>
               <p>Pollamounter. None - I had an Estate in Cornwall - and this Money that I lost, I had upon a Mortgage.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person327">
                  Hugh 
                  Cornish 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person327" type="surname" value="Cornish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person327" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Pollamounter and I coming out of a Coach at Temple-Bar, he met with two little Girls who asked him to drink. We went with them to the Angel and Crown, where he treated them with Wine and Cakes. The Prisoner came up into our Company, and said, he never saw so much Impudence as in them Girls - One of the Girls went away. Pollomounter pulled out his Bag to pay the Reckoning, which was 6 s. 3 d. The Bell was rung, and presently in came 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person328">
                  Peg 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person328" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person328" type="given" value="Peg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and sat by Pollamounter. In a little time he and she went out together. But he soon returned alone, and told us he had lost his Money. The Prisoner said, Be easy - I know the Girl, and I will go see for her. He went; returned, and said he could not find her. Then he desired me to go with him, which I did. We went to a Brandy Shop in Sheer-Lane, where he drank a Dram, and then went back, and I followed. I went into a Room below Stairs, opposite to the Bar, and there was he and Peg and Pollamounter. They talk'd of returning the Money, and a Discharge was insisted on. Peg took the Bag out of her Pocket and delivered it. The Prisoner told sixteen Guineas, a Moidore, and Six Six and Thirty Shilling Pieces at first, but afterwards there was one more of these Portugal Pieces produced, and then he cast up the whole to be 30 l. 15 s. I counted it after him, and then gave it to Pollamounter, who put it in his Pocket. This being done, we had a Bowl of Arrack Punch, but I drank nothing but Water with a Toast. In a little time I was called into the Kitchen to Mrs. Glascock, who said, she wanted to speak with me. I did not find that she had any great Business to talk about, but only to tell me how good natur'd it was in Pollamounter to take his Money again, and be easy without prosecuting the Girl - I returned to the Room I came from, and found only Pollamounter, and the Prisoner there, for Peg was gone Pollamounter felt in his Pocket and mist his Money again, upon which, he grew very uneasy. The Prisoner endeavour'd to set me and him at odds, by insinuating that I had got the Money. I insisted upon calling in the Watch, but the Prisoner said the Watch would not come into that House: And at the same time declared that he did not know the Girl. But she was taken next Day at his Door, and carried to the Cock Ale-house. She at first denied that she had ever seen Pollamounter, but afterwards confest that she had taken his Money, and said, she would help him to it again in a little time, for she had not got it all in her own keeping.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Who was with you when I first came into your Room, after you had sent for Mrs. Glascock?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160016"></xptr>Cornish. I know nothing of her being sent for. But when you came up first there was Pollamounter and I and the two little Girls - You came up upon a Squabble that he had with one of them, because he had given her a Crown and he wanted it again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not he say she had robb'd him?</p>
               <p>Cornish. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mrs. Glascock was sent for upon this Quarrel, and I went up in her stead. Did not Pollamounter pull Peg Boucher into the Room?</p>
               <p>Cornish. No - She came in of her self.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not Pollamounter Charge you with having his Money?</p>
               <p>Cornish No, but you did your endeavour to insinuate that I had it, and then as if he and I had been going to quarrel, you push'd me on the Breast, and said, You shan't sight.</p>
               <p>Pris. Were not you and he going to fight?</p>
               <p>Cornish. No - I was going to call the Watch, but you said it was a City Watch and should not come in there.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Do ye know of any Reward the Prisoner had?</p>
               <p>Cornish. Pollamounter complain'd that there were four Six and Thirty Shilling Pieces wanting, but said he was willing to take what there was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person329">
                  Margaret 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person329" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person329" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person329" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , alias Smith. I was at a Brandy-Shop in Sheer Lane when Will. Jones (who is Mary Glascock's Porter ) came and said his Mistress wanted me. So I went to her House which is the Angel and Crown, and there I found her, and Ann, the Daughter, and 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person330">
                  Jack 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person330" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person330" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner. And this Jack Smith called to me, and said Peggy'l There's two Gentlemen above, Pollamounter and Cornish, and Pollamounter has got a great deal of Money. Now if you can get it you shall have 6 s. out of every Guinea; and I, and Mary Glascock and Ann the Daughter, will have a Crown a-piece. I'll ring the Bell for a signal, and then you shall come up and introduce your self and take him into a private Room; and when you have got the Money you shall go into this Room below - The Prisoner lives with Mary Glascock - but she is not his Wife - but - something else - So the Prisoner went up and rung the Bell, and I went in. The Prisoner pointed to Pollamounter's right Pocket where his Money was. I asked Pollamounter to go into another Room with me, which he readily agreed to, and so we went together and there I pick'd his Pocket, and making an Excuse to go out, I went down and into the Room the Prisoner and I had agreed upon. Mary Glascock, and Ann the Daughter presently came to me Ann the Daughter took the Bag and was going to tell the Money, but Mary Glascock. said that no body should tell it till the Prisoner came down. The Prisoner coming he told nine Six and Thirty Shilling. Pieces, Sixteen Guineas, and one Moidore. But when Mary Glascock, and Ann the Daughter told it they could make but seven Six and Thirty Shilling Pieces. Then the Prisoner and Glascock went out, and Ann the Daughter staid in the Room with me. The Drawer brought us a Gimblet with which Ann the Daughter fastned the Door within side, and blew the Candle out that Pollamounter might not find us. But in a little while the Prisoner came to the Door, and we let him in, and he told us that Pollamounter had mist his Money and made a great Noise, and threatned to suppress the House if the Money was not return'd, and therefore, says he, you must give it him again, but you may get something of him for returning, and we will share that among us in the same manner as we agreed to share the whole. But be sure you get a Discharge, or else you may hang'd for it, upon 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person331">
                  Jonathan 
                  Wild 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person331" type="surname" value="Wild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person331" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Act. So they all went out and left me in the Room, and by and by the Prisoner brought Pollamounter to me, and said, Here's the Girl! She only took it in Jest. Cornish came in presently after them, and then a Discharge was writ, and I return'd the Money, but I got nothing for returning it. Then they all sat down and a Bowl of Punch was brought in - The Prisoner called me out into the Kitchen, and said, Stay, Peggy and drink<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160017"></xptr> him down dead drunk, and then you may get the Money again, and he wont know how he has lost it; and we will divide it in the same proportion as we first agreed upon - Pollamounter order'd a Chicken for Supper, and then there was another Bowl of Arrack Punch made stronger than ordinary, And this made Pollamounter quite drunk. Then Mary Glascock called Cornish out of our Company, and no body was in the Room but the Prisoner and I, and Pollamounter. Now, says the Prisoner, I believe it will do. And upon that I took the Bag of Money a second time out of Pollamounter's Pocket, and gave it to the Prisoner who was present. He carried it to the Bar, and I followed him. He took out four Guineas; but Cornish coming out of the Kitchen sooner than was expected, the Prisoner gave me the Bag, and what was left in it, and said, We have not time to divide it now: carry it home and burn the Bag, and we will make the Division to-morrow. So I went away, and next Day, just as I was going in at the Angel and Crown Door to make the Dividend, Pollamounter and Cornish met me, and carried me to the Cock Ale-house in Fleet-Street - While I was there, one 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person332">
                  John
                   Drink-water
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person332" type="surname" value="Drink-water"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me in the Prisoner's Name, and said, if I did not send him the Money, it would be found upon me, and I should be hang'd: But if I gave it to him, and then charged it upon Cornish, the whole House would swear it - While we had this Discourse, Pollamounter and Cornish were gone out of the Room, and there was no Constable, nor any body but one Man that stood at the Door - So I gave the Money to Drinkwater, to carry to Smith - From the Cock, I was carried in a Coach to the Constable's House at the Swan, hard by Sir Richard's - The Prisoner came thither. I went into the Kitchen and spoke to him, and he said, If you will say that Cornish had the money, my Drawer, and all the House shall swear it, and so we shall all get clear.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She has not said one thing that's true - How should I tell her the Prosecutor's Name was Pollamounter, when he was a Stranger to me?</p>
               <p>Boucher. Well enough, for you were a great while drinking in his Company, and might hear Cornish call him by his Name -</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person333">
                  Edward 
                  Redman 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person333" type="surname" value="Redman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person333" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Drawer. Pollamounter and Cornish, and two little Girls came in and asked for a Room. I shewed them up Stairs, and carried them a Bottle of Wine. In five Minutes the Bell rung, I ran up again. Pollamounter bid me take a Candle and shew him another Room, which I did, and he went into this Room with one of the Girls. They had a Pint of Wine there, and staid a Quarter of an Hour, and then he call'd again, and bid me fetch a Constable, for the Girl had got a Crown of his Money. But the Girl said, he gave it her, and nothing was sreer than Gift, and so I left 'em. He rung again, and bid me send my Mistress. When I went down, the Prisoner was just come in a Doors, and my Mistress desired him to step up; which he did and sat down to drink with them in the Room that they first went into, and they seemed to make a Joke of the Crown - One of the little Girls went away, and then Peg Boucher came in. The Door of Pollamounter's Room stood open, and as I was going by there with Peg to shew her into another Room, Pollamounter pulled her in, and set her upon his Knee.</p>
               <p>K. Council. What did that Girl Boucher come in by her self and call for a Room?</p>
               <p>Redman. No, there was another Gentleman with her, and I was going to shew them both into a Room, when Pollamounter pulled her in.</p>
               <p>K. Council. What, in the presence of the Gentleman?</p>
               <p>Redman. Yes.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Sure the Gentleman was very angry?</p>
               <p>Redman. No, not at all.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Did he so easily quit he: then? - It looks a little strange, but what became of him?</p>
               <p>Redman. He said no more but went away very quietly - The Bell rung again, I went up and Peg was still upon Pollamounter's Knee. He called for a Candle and another Room, I shewed Peg and him into the same Room<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160018"></xptr> he was in before with the other Girl. They had a Bottle of Wine together. She staid a Quarter of an Hour with him, and then came down and went out - He followed in five Minutes, and asked me if I knew the Girl or where she was. I told him, no. He said she had pick'd his Pocket of forty Pounds. Then the Prisoner and Cornish, and the other little Girl came down, and the Prisoner said, I am sorry for your Loss, I have some knowledge of her and will try to find her out. So Pollamounter came into the Kitchen. The little Girl went away, and the Prisoner and Cornish went out together to see for Peg, but while they were gone, Peg came in again by her self and asked Mrs. Provost, the Bar-keeper; where Pollamounter was; he was then gone out of the Kitchen into another Room below Stairs. The Bar-keeper called me, and I shewed Peg in, and she said to him, Sir, I have taken your Money in a Joke, and I'll willingly return it if you'l forgive me. But before she delivered it, Cornish came in, and she gave the Money to Cornish in Pollamounter's Presence. They counted it, and said, there was thirty Pound fifteen Shillings, but they said some Jacobus's were missing; Peg cry'd, and declar'd that she did not take a Farthing more - When Peg first came into the House the Prisoner did not speak a Word to her, for he was then above Stairs - Nor was he in Company with Pollamounter and Cornish when the Money was returned, and counted, for he went into the Kitchen and staid drinking with three or four Friends and did not go any more into the other Company. Pollamounter having got his Money again, called for a broild Fowl and Mushroom Sauce, and a Bowl of Arnack Punch. When the Supper was ready Cornish came into the Kitchen and invited the Prisoner and Mrs. Glascock to eat with them, but they both refused. Cornish went back, and when they had all supt, Pollamounter and Peg beginning to talk about going to bed, Cornish left them, and came into the Kitchen and call'd for a Bottle of Wine by himself. Pollamounter had another Bowl of Punch. The Prisoner desired Cornish to go in and see that his Friend Pollamounter, did not lose his Money again; but he would not go. I went my self soon after, to snuff the Candles, and Peg was then gone. Pollamounter asked me where she was, but made no complaint then; tho' it was not long before he came into the Kitchen with a Stick in his Hand, and after a time he said to Cornish, You Rogue you have got my Money! and with that he shivered his Stick to pieces by striking it upon the Table, and then said, If I have not my Money again, I'll swear against all the House.</p>
               <p>K. Council. What Room did Pollamounter and the two Girls go into at first?</p>
               <p>Redman. The Nine at the Stair's Head and in a Quarter of an Hour Peg and the Gentleman came in, and I was going to shew them into the Eight on the Left-hand at the Stair's Head. And the Door of the Nine being open, Pollamounter pulled her in as she was going by, and in five or six Minutes he left Cornish, and the Prisoner, and the two little Girls, and went with Peg into another Room?</p>
               <p>K. Council Do you make a Practice of carrying Gentlemen and such Ladies into private Rooms?</p>
               <p>Redman. I am a Servant, and is my Business to oblige my Mistresses Customers. I would wait upon you, or any other Gentleman if need required.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person334">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person334" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person334" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Pollamounter and Cornish coming out of a Coach, they forced me, and this other little Girl into the Tavern.</p>
               <p>K. Council. How old are you?</p>
               <p>E. Smith Sixteen - We sat drinking together a little while, and then I went with Pollamounter into another Room, where he gave me a Crown and was very impudent; and then he wanted his Money again, but I would not give it him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not he say that you robb'd him?</p>
               <p>E. Smith. No, he own'd he gave me a Crown - I was with him three Quarters of an Hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person335">
                  Mary 
                  Reeves 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person335" type="surname" value="Reeves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person335" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two Gentlemen took us both in by force.</p>
               <p>K. Council. How old are you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160019"></xptr>M. Reeves. Sixteen.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Sixteen? She don't look to be above twelve.</p>
               <p>M. Reeves. He took the other young Woman into a private Room, and gave her a Crown, and wanted to be rude with her, but I suppose she would not let him, and so he wanted his Money again, but she went away with it.</p>
               <p>K. Council. How came you to stay after she was gone?</p>
               <p>M. Reeves. I did not know she was gone, but thought she was coming in again, so I staid a Quarter of an Hour, and then Peg Boucher came and opened the Door.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Was not the Door open when she came?</p>
               <p>M. Reeves. I cannot say but it might be a jar. She opened it and said, I thought it had been other Company. And with that Pollamounter pull'd her in and sat her upon his Knee and kist her - The Prisoner was then in our Company, and did not stir out of the Room till she was gone.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Was any body with her?</p>
               <p>M. Reeves. No, there was no Soul with her.</p>
               <p>K. Council. The Drawer swore that himself and a Gentleman were with her.</p>
               <p>M. Reeves. But I am sure there was no such thing - Pollamounter went with her into another Room where they staid a quarter of an Hour, and then he came back and said she had robbed him, and then I went away.</p>
               <p>Mother Provost, the Bar-keeper. Pollamounter and Cornish came in with the two little Girls: They went up, called for a Bottle of Wine, and in near half an Hour I heard a Noise above. The Prisoner coming in at the same time, and Mrs. Glascock not being well, she desired him to go up; which he did, and staid with them. By-and by Pollamounter came down and said he had lost his Money. The Prisoner and Cornish came down after him, and the Prisoner offer'd to do him what Service he could, and so went out with Cornish to see for Boucher. While they were gone, she came in and asked me where Pollamounter was. The Drawer shewed her in, and she returned the Money. Pollamounter then ordered a Fowl and Mushroom Sauce for Supper, and two Bowls of Punch. And after the Money was restored, the Prisoner never went into Pollamounter's Company, but staid drinking in the Kitchen with Mr. Longbotham, and five or six more, and was not out of the Kitchen in all the time - Pollamounter was in a little Room joining to the Kitchen. Cornish after he had supped with Pollamounter, came into the Kitchen, and Mrs. Glascock said to him, Take care of your Friend's Money, for he has lost it once and may lose it again. Cornish, answered, Damn him he has got more Money than Brains !</p>
               <p>K. Council. Was Peg gone before this Advice was given?</p>
               <p>Provost. No, she was there then - But soon after, Pollamounter came into the Kitchen, and cry'd he had lost his Money - He charged his Friend with having it, but however they both went away very lovingly together.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Did any Man come in with Peg at first?</p>
               <p>Provost. I do not know - but there might.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Was it not the Porter?</p>
               <p>Provost. I am not sure that any body came in with her.</p>
               <p>K. Council. Did the Porter or the Drawer go up with her?</p>
               <p>Provost. No, upon my Oath - no indeed. neither of them - no body went up with her,</p>
               <p>K. Council. This again directly contradicts the Drawer's Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person336">
                  Thomas 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person336" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person336" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between eight and nine at Night, I and four more went to the Angel and Crown Tavern, and sat down in the Kitchen to drink: the Prisoner soon after came into the Kitchen, and we asked him to take a Grab, but he refused, and said, he was going with Cornish to look for a Girl that had pick'd a Gentleman's Pocket of Thirty Pounds. Thereupon he and Cornish went out, and while they were gone, the Drawer came in and said the Girl was come<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160020"></xptr> back of her self; and soon afterwards the Prisoner and Cornish returned, and presently Pollamounter came out of a Room and said, Now I have got all my Money, lets have a Fowl and a Bowl of Punch. Then he and Cornish went into the Room again where they staid about an Hour, and then Cornish came into the Kitchen and called for a Bottle. In a Quarter of an Hour Pollamounter followed him, and asked where the Woman was, and turning to Cornish, asked him, if he had got his Money? Cornish answered no. Pollamounter struck his Stick upon the Table, and said he had lost his Money in that House, and he would prosecute the Girl and all in the House but he would have it again - And from the time that the Prisoner came in from looking for the Girl, to the time that Pollamounter came and said he had lost his Money, the Prisoner was not once out of the Kitchen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person337">
                  Henry 
                  Moythen 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person337" type="surname" value="Moythen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person337" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . of Drury-Lane, 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person338">
                  Robert 
                  Longbotham 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person338" type="surname" value="Longbotham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person338" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Marshals-Court Officer in Belton-street, 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person339">
                  Giles 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person339" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person339" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Cutler, and 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person340">
                  Gilbert 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person340" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person340" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed much to the same effect. Moythen indeed said that the Prisoner and Cornish returned in five Minutes; and Longbotham said it was half an Hour; And Jackson, was more particular than the rest as to the Words that past between Pollamounter and Cornish in the Kitchen: For according to him the Dialogue ran thus. Pollamounter said to Cornish, You have got my Money. No, I have not, says Cornish. D - it, says Pollamounter, you never gave it me again. By G - but I did; says Cornish. D - ye, but you did not; says Pollamounter. And, D - you, but I did. Says Cornish. Why then by G - , says Pollamounter, this Bitch has got it again; and as she is gone, I'll charge the House with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person341">
                  Ann 
                  Steer 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person341" type="surname" value="Steer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person341" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick-House, the Queen's-head in Ship-yard by Temple-bar. I have known Pollamounter two or three Months. H. came to my house the Day after he lost his Money, and said, he had taken 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person342">
                  Peg 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person342" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person342" type="given" value="Peg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she was committed to the Counter, and that she had likewise taken up the Prisoner, upon account of his being in the House at the same time, but did not know who had got the Money. He told me next Day that he had been to the Compter, and the Girl complaining that no body sent her any thing to support her, he gave her something: And that she said she was sorry the Prisoner was in Custody because he was innocent. But Pollamounter told me, that all he wanted was to get her to be an Evidence. And Mrs. Pollamounter told me, that all the Money her Husband could get, was to carry to his Whore in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you never hear him say that he offer'd her Money to swear against me?</p>
               <p>Court. Call in Pollamounter - He ought to hear what is sworn against him - now proceed.</p>
               <p>Ann Steer, to Pollamounter. You said, the Girl told you she was sorry the Prisoner was to suffer, because he was innocent: And that you gave her Money, and would give any Money to have her made an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Pollamounter. I never said any such thing, nor over gave her a Penny; this Woman Steer, offer'd to compound the Matter with me, but I refused - there was O Brian, Macdonald and Marclough -</p>
               <p>Ann Steer. I offer? - It was you that offer'd it, and said you could make a Hundred Guineas of it. For my Part, I never saw the Prisoner in my life before, But I have heard you and Cornish quarrel and threaten to blow one another up - You and he together owe me above 10 l.</p>
               <p>Esau Steer. Three Days ago, when Pollamounter had been a Raking all Night, and breaking Lamps and Windows, he came to me and said he had been advised to take the whole House up, and then he should get a Hundred Guineas more than he had lost - some Soldiers came after him one Day, and said, he belonged to Col. Churchill's Regiment, and was a Deserter.</p>
               <p>Pollamounter. You shew'd me forty Guineas, and brought People to compound this Villany.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160021"></xptr>Prisoner. I have some Witnesses to my Character - Mr. Jones will you be so good as to speak?</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. I came hither only out of Curiosity - But as the Prisoner has called upon me, I can say that I have known him five Years - He's an <rs id="t17350116-50-deflabel218" type="occupation">Officer to the Sheriff of Middlesex</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-50-defend321 t17350116-50-deflabel218"></join>, and I never heard before, that he was - a Thief.</p>
               <p>P Council. Do you think he would combine with Whores to pick Pockets?</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. I think he had no occasion to do so, for he could get Money without taking such Methods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person343">
                  Robert 
                  Crown 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person343" type="surname" value="Crown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person343" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of his Security, I have known him Fourteen or fifteen Years, a very honest Man, and I don't believe he'd be guilty of what he is charg'd with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person344">
                  Henry 
                  Daintry 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person344" type="surname" value="Daintry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person344" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And I gave Security for him to the Sheriff - he has a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person345">
                  James 
                  Myat 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person345" type="surname" value="Myat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person345" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew him Twenty Years ago. I have drank with him within these two Years - He had a fair Character as to that part of the Story about Thieving.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-50-person346">
                  Edward 
                  Tresham 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person346" type="surname" value="Tresham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person346" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17350116-50-person347">
                  William 
                  Kirk 
               <interp inst="t17350116-50-person347" type="surname" value="Kirk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person347" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed that he had a very good Character.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17350116-50-verdict219" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-50-verdict219" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
