<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390117-45">
               <interp inst="t17390117-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-45" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-45" type="date" value="17390117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-45-off204-c209" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-defend317 t17390117-45-off204 t17390117-45-verdict206"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-45-off207-c209" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-defend317 t17390117-45-off207 t17390117-45-verdict206"></join>
         
               <p>124. 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-defend317" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-defend317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of <placeName id="t17390117-45-defloc200">London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-45-defloc200" type="placeName" value="London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-45-defloc200" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-defend317 t17390117-45-defloc200"></join>, <rs id="t17390117-45-deflabel201" type="occupation">Gent</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-defend317 t17390117-45-deflabel201"></join>. was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17390117-45-cd202" type="crimeDate">28th of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-off204 t17390117-45-cd202"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-off207 t17390117-45-cd202"></join>, &amp;c. with Force and Arms, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17390117-45-crimeloc203">St. Dunstan in the West</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-45-crimeloc203" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan in the West"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-45-crimeloc203" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-off204 t17390117-45-crimeloc203"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-off207 t17390117-45-crimeloc203"></join>, <rs id="t17390117-45-off204" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-off204" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-off204" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               did feloniously steal, &amp;c. a certain Parchment Writing, purporting to be a Commission, bearing Date at Westminster, Aug. 21. in the tenth Year of the Reign of her late Majesty Queen Anne, directed to 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person318">
                        Isaac 
                        Hawkins 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person318" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person318" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esq; 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person319">
                        Charles 
                        Brome 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person319" type="surname" value="Brome"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person319" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person320">
                        Henry 
                        Tate 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person320" type="surname" value="Tate"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person320" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person321">
                        Robert 
                        Abney 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person321" type="surname" value="Abney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person321" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , empowering them, [according to the Direction of a certain Order, made by her Majesty, in the Court of Chancery, the 9th of July, before the Date of the said Writing, between 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person322">
                        Philip
                         Earl of Chesterfield
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person322" type="surname" value="Earl of Chesterfield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person322" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and others, Tenants of the Manors of Bradby and Hartshorn, Complainants, and 
                     <persName id="t17390117-45-person323">
                        John 
                        Cantrel 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person323" type="surname" value="Cantrel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person323" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-45-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and others, Defendants] to enter, walk through, and set out the Bounds of the same, and to cause Marks and Posts to be set up at the equal Expence of both Parties; and to certify how high the Defendants ought to keep the Water of the Furnace Pond, and to distinguish the same, by erecting Marks and Posts; and in the said Parchment Writing it was directed, that when they had so done, &amp;c. they should acquaint her Majesty in Chancery with their Proceedings, under the Hands and Seals of two or more of the said Commissioners. And also,
One other Parchment Writing, purporting to be a Return made by the Commissioners, named in the above-said Commission, in which Parchment Writing it is set forth, that the said Commissioners had set out the Boundaries of the said Manors of Bradby and Hartshorn, and that the Waters of the Furnace Pond, should not exceed the Rails and Stoops, formerly set up, to divide the Waters from the Earl's Grounds, &amp;c. And that this Parchment Writing, purporting to be a Commission, was, at the Time of stealing the same, of the Value of 2 s. And which other Parchment Writing, purporting to be a Return to the said Commission, was at the Time of stealing the same, of the Value of 2 s. And were the Goods of our Sovereign Lord the King, against the Peace
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Council for the King took Notice, That the Prisoner had been a <rs id="t17390117-45-deflabel205" type="occupation">Hackney Writer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-45-defend317 t17390117-45-deflabel205"></join>, employ'd by some of the Sixty Clerks in the Six Clerks Office; and the late Master of the Rolls having a Design that some of the Records for their better Preservation should be sent to the Tower, gave Orders to the several six Clerks to get them sorted, that such as were old, and proper, might be sent to the Tower: That this was done about June or July last, and required the Assistance of others beside the Clerks of the Office: That the Records of the Court of Chancery are kept in six Divisions, each belonging to one of the six Clerks, and that Mr. Collins in sorting those which were in his Division, had employ'd one Hewit, who was acquainted with the Prisoner; and that during the Time he was sorting the Records, the Prisoner often came into that Office, and into the Record-Room, and frequently made use of those Opportunities to take away a great Number of Records, Bills in Chancery, Answers, and Commissions issued out of Chancery to assign the Bounds of Manors, &amp;c. That it might be wonder'd, what Use the Prisoner could make of these Records, but the Wonder would cease, when it should appear, that he had two Uses for them.</p>
               <p>First, As all those Records made since the Commencement of the Stamp Act, have Stamps affix'd to them, the Prisoner had Skill in taking them off, and putting them upon new Parchments, and then selling them as original Stamps, to the Detriment of the Crown, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>That the next Use was, to dispose of the Parchments themselves, which he did to various Persons in various Employments: That in particular the Prisoner had sold a Quantity, after he had cut off the Stamps, to one Axtell, for a Shilling, among which the Commission and Return were found, for which he was indicted: That when the Officers of that Court, upon a Review of the Records, found many wanting, one Lulham, a Confederate with the Prisoner, made a Discovery before the Lord Chief Justice of the King's Bench, of his having at various Times received many of these Records, sold the Stamps, and dispos'd of the Parchment, to make Glew, Drum-Heads, and Taylors Measures, &amp;c. &amp;c. That Lulham, the Confederate, being dead, his Information before the Lord Chief Justice would be produced, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Mrs. - Sterling. 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person324">
                  Curtis 
                  Lulham 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person324" type="surname" value="Lulham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person324" type="given" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my Son; he died the 13th of last November. This (the Name at the Bottom of the Information) is his Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Uriah Shewdall. This is an Information sworn before the Lord Chief Justice Lee, by Curtis Lulham, in my Presence; I believe I saw him write his Name to it. It was return'd hither but Yesterday.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Defendant, objected to the reading of Lulham's Information, and after the Point had been learnedly argu'd on both Sides, Mr. Shewdall went on in his Evidence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170019"></xptr>Mr. Shewdall. When the Prisoner was brought before his Lordship, by my Lord's Directions, I read over. I believe all the Parts of it in which he was charg'd. I believe, in the Course of his Examination, the whole was read, first one Part, then another; at one Time the whole was not read through, but during the Course of his Examination I believe the whole was read. Lulham was present when the Prisoner was examin'd, and it was read to the Prisoner, that he might know what he was charg'd with, and that he might give Answers in the Presence of Lulham, that my Lord might be the better able to judge of the Fact. The first Information of Lulham was on Oath; then there was a Warrant against the Prisoner, and he was brought before my Lord, and I believe the whole Information was read over to him in Parts.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bennet. I was present all the Time the Prisoner was under Examination, and 'till he was committed. Mr. Shewdall, in the Presence of Lulham, read those Parts relating to the Prisoner; and at another Examination, the whole of it seemed to me to be read in one continued Course, without any Interruption at all. In so much, that Mr. Cruwys thought it was not proper the whole should be discovered, because other Persons were concerned.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cruwys. I was present when the Prisoner was brought before the Lord Chief Justice; at first some Parts were read, but afterwards it was read again, and I believe nothing was omitted; The information was read, which set forth, That Curtis Lulham had been acquainted with the Prisoner about three Months, and that he had frequently seen in his Lodgings a great Number of engrossed Parchments, which the Prisoner confessed, and he believed, were Records of Chancery, and were taken out of the Six Clerks Office. That the Examinant had seen the Prisoner take off the Stamps, and the Cypher and the Lead, and fix the Stamps on other Parchments, with Gum; and that once he saw a great Number of them, which he believed might amount to 150, as near as he could guess, &amp;c. And that one Lister acquainted this Informant, that in offering one Stamp to Sale, the Person detected the Fraud; and that he had heard 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person325">
                  Matthew 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person325" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person325" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late a Writer in the Office, say, he had sold a Stamp, and had paid the Prisoner 18 d. for the same; six Pence whereof was afterwards spent, and that he was present at the Time of its being spent. And that the Informant had seen the Prisoner cut the Parchments long-ways, through the Middle, telling him he sold them to Taylors for Measures, and that he had sold 5 or 6 lb. to one that makes Cloaths to the Charter-house, for 8 d. That he had often seen the Prisoner pull out of his Waistcoat, several Parcels of these Parchments, which he had brought from the Six Clerks Office, and had often seen great Parcels of engrossed Parchment, hid under his Bed. that one time the Informant saw the Prisoner pack up a great Parcel, in a little Hand-basket, and deliver it to one Curwen to sell; and Curwen told the Informant, he sold it. And this Informant asking Curwen, if it would not prejudice any one? Curwen told him, - No; for they were going to the Tower, and would not be wanted. That on the 9th of October, the Informant went to the Prisoner's Lodging, and from thence they both went to the Record-Room where Hewit and Cave were sorting Records; from thence they returned to the Prisoner's Lodging and the Informant saw the Prisoner pull out several Parchments, (which he believed to be Records) and put them under his Bed. And at another time he went with the Prisoner to the Six Clerks Office, about the Close of the Evening, and saw him go to a Seat near the Window, (a Seat under the Window) and heard him ratling the Parchments. And that afterwards, when they came home, he said he saw several small Parchments, out of which the Prisoner told him he could scratch the Names, and then use them for Common Law Writs.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cart. I am an Agent in the Six Clerks Office; I have known the Prisoner about two or three Years. Mr. Collins, one of the Six Clerks, employ'd me to sort the Records, in the long Vacation; He has a particular Part of them under his Care, and I was employ'd to sort those which were in his Office. I began in August, and left off in September. I have observed the Prisoner to come several times, into the Office, to speak to Hewit, who was a Person employ'd with me in sorting the Records. Sometimes he staid a longer, and sometimes a shorter Time; he might sometimes stay half an Hour. I never observed him to meddle with any Thing, but I did not keep my Eye on him, because I did not suspect him. I believe he might be there about seven or eight times while we were thus employed. Sometimes he came alone; sometimes Lulham came with him, and sometimes his (the Prisoner's) Brother; and sometimes one Conrade. He might very easily steal some of the Records, for there, was another Room, where Duplications, &amp;c. lay,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170020"></xptr> and through which he must pass to come to the inner Room.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bennet. Upon Lulham's Information I took up the Prisoner; I found him in his Lodging in Charterhouse-lane, and found several Parchments, cut and mangled, in a Drawer, upon which I set the initial Letters of my Name.</p>
               <p>- Axtel, a Dealer in Books in Moorfields, gave an Account, that about the latter End of August, or Beginning of September, the Prisoner came to his Stall, and asked him, if he would buy any Parchment? That he went with him to his Lodgings in Charterhouse-lane, where the Prisoner shewed him four Bundles, (without any Stamps) which weighed 12 lb. and for which he paid him a Shilling, and the Beer they drank made the Price come to 17 d. That besides this, there were some Pieces in the Bottom of a Basket, which the Prisoner gave the Witness into the Bargain, and which were delivered afterwards to Lulham and one of Mr. Cruwys's Clerks, at the Castle near Moorgate, but the large Pieces the Witness's Wife sold at a Turner's Shop, to make Drum-heads. The smaller Pieces, he intended to have sold to make Glew, had they not been called for. That these small Pieces he deliver'd, were sealed up at the Castle, before they were carry'd to Mr. Cruwys. And the Witness verily believed they were the same Pieces, which he had from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person326">
                  Henry 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person326" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person326" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he was with Lulham when he went to enquire of Axtel for the Parchments. That Axtel informed them, his Wife had sold them, but that he had some little Bits at his Lodging, unsold, which he fetched; and told them, he believed they were the same he bought of the Prisoner. That they were sealed up, with a Seal of the Man of the House, and that Axtel took the Impression of the same in his Pocket. And, that in his Opinion it was impossible for Lulham to slip any Parchments in among these Pieces unobserved. That these Pieces, so sealed up, were carry'd to Mr. Cruwys's, and after the Seals had been compared with the Impression, the Bundle was opened.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cruwys deposed, That after Axtel had satisfied himself that the Seals were right, he lock'd up the Parcel, and it was never out of his Custody, till it was opened at the Six Clerks Office, where, the Pieces were put together, and Axtel signed them, the first time (he thought) they were open'd.</p>
               <p>The Pieces were put together, and read; they all appeared to be mark'd by Axtel, except one Piece, and the Endorsement on the Back was, Dom. Chesterfield contra Cantrell, it was proved to be the Return to the Commission, and was signed by Hawkins and Brome, two of the Commissioners; Mr. Baily swore he believed the Names to have been of their own Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baily, Mr. Bateman, and Mr. Cheek, prov'd that such Proceedings had been in the Court of Chancery.</p>
               <p>A Person employ'd in the Office by Mr. Collins, deposed, That he had search'd among the Records for the Commission in the Case of the Earl of Chesterfield and Defendants, and it could not be found, nor the Return thereto; that he found it mentioned in the List of those under Mr. Collins Custody, and, tho' he had search'd all the Rooms, he could not find it.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-45-person327">
                  John 
                  Conrade 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person327" type="surname" value="Conrade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person327" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Curtis Lulham about five Months; he told me he was an Attorney; but I found out that he was a Packer, or Cloth-Drawer. I was with him at the Six Clerks Office about the Beginning of last September; he wanted to speak with Mr. Hewit, and went into the Record-Room, and took up a Bundle of Parchment; then he cut the String they were ty'd with, and was going to put them into his Pocket, but Hewit coming in, he threw them down again. He lodged with the Prisoner in the same Room, and I once saw him bring in a Bundle of Parchment in a Hand-basket, and he d-mn'd my Eyes out, and bid me feel the Weight of them. I took them in my Hands, and judged there might be about 10 or 11 lb. of them. Then he open'd them, and cut off some Slips; some he threw into the Grate, and some he laid aside; the rest he put into the Basket again, and that was put under the Bed. I did not observe whether there was any thing on the Slips he put by.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you never receive any Stamps from the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Conrade. What I received from him, Lulham gave him to give me: He ow'd me Money, and gave me three Stamps to sell. I was taken up on this Account, and was confined a Fortnight.</p>
               <p>Mary Crosby. Lulham lodged with the Prisoner in the same House. I never saw any Parchments there, but once, and that was a great while ago, and no body was then in the Room but he and my Daughter. The Night the Prisoner was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170021"></xptr> sent to Newgate, he came up Stairs with a Candel in his Hand, and said he was sorry for what he had done, - he had wrong'd the Prisoner, and was so vex'd, he knew not what to do: I believe, (says he) it will break my Heart, and fell a-crying.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know of the selling any Parchment for the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Crosby. I never saw any but once.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you never receive any from 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person328">
                  Sarah 
                  Dickenson 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person328" type="surname" value="Dickenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person328" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Crosby, Yes; my little Grand-daughter brought them to me, and desired me to carry them to Mr. Midgley, a Taylor; he gave me 7 d. or 8 d. and I gave the Money to the Girl.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-45-person329">
                  Lambert 
                  Greenaway 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person329" type="surname" value="Greenaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person329" type="given" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person330">
                  John 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person330" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person330" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person331">
                  John 
                  Hartshorn 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person331" type="surname" value="Hartshorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person331" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person332">
                  Christopher 
                  Coats 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person332" type="surname" value="Coats"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person332" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person333">
                  Edward 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person333" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person333" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390117-45-person334">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person334" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person334" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spoke to the Prisoner's Character, and said they never heard any Harm of him before. Some of them gave an Account of the Prisoner's having been put to some Inconveniencies by disobliging his Father, who, notwithstanding that, allowed him something Weekly or Monthly, for his Support.</p>
               <p>- Sterling, (Lulham's Mother) gave an Account of her having lost several Things out of her Room, and that she had seen her Knives, Forks, a Fishing-Rod, and several things she had lost, in the Prisoner's Room. That about a Fort-night or three Weeks after Michelmas last, she went to his Room, to get her Son to write her three Bills, to stick upon three empty Houses, and saw the Prisoner taking off the Stamps from some Parchments; that he (the Prisoner) asked her to dispose of some Parchments for him, telling her he had 30 or 40 lb. wt. to dispose of, at 2 d. or 3 d. a Pound. That, her Son being ill, she waited till the Prisoner had taken off a Stamp, and then he wrote the Bills; and she seeing a great many Stamps upon Slips of Parchment in a Drawer, the Prisoner told her, he had a great many more. The Witness added, That as to his general Character, she had heard People say he was a great Rogue, and they wondered she would let her Son keep him Company.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her, if she did not come to me for Relief, when the Execution was in her House?</p>
               <p>Sterling. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-45-person335">
                  Matthew 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17390117-45-person335" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person335" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was concerned with Mr. Cave in sorting the Records. The Prisoner has come to me, to the Office, to ask me a Question, perhaps, upon my own Affairs; Lulham sent me a Letter the Day the Execution was in her House, to let me know it; and as the Prisoner was out of the Way, he desired me to come. And when we came home together, the Prisoner said that Sterling had given him the Fishing-Rod for his Trouble. I have known him from a Child, and never knew him Guilty of any such Thing. But Lulham I have met in the Street with Parchments in his Handkerchief; tho' I think it impossible for a Man to take 10 or 12 lb of Parchment out of the Office, without being seen.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Prisoner never desire you to sell any Stamps for him?</p>
               <p>Hewit. He has. He brought me a Replication three or four Months ago, I can't tell exactly the Time, and I went about the Office, to see if any Body wanted one: But that which I endeavour'd to sell for him was a true Stamp, and the Impression was through the Parchment. I could have sold it for him if it had not been very dirty.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17390117-45-verdict206" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-verdict206" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-verdict206" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty of taking a Parchment Writing, val. 1 d. from the Records in the Court of Chancery, purporting to be a Commission under the Broad Seal, and another parchment Writing annex'd thereto, val. 1 d. purporting to be the Return to the said Commission
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted for <rs id="t17390117-45-off207" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-off207" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-off207" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two other Parchment Writings from the Records of Chancery, val. 2 s.
            </rs> and was found <rs id="t17390117-45-verdict208" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-verdict208" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-45-verdict208" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty as above, val. 1 d. each
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
