<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370526-11">
               <interp inst="t17370526-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-11" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-11" type="date" value="17370526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370526-11-off57-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-11-defend104 t17370526-11-off57 t17370526-11-verdict60"></join>
         
               <p>12. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370526-11-defend104" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17370526-11-defend104" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-defend104" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-defend104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370526-11-defloc56">St. Paul's Shadwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-11-defloc56" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Shadwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-11-defloc56" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-11-defend104 t17370526-11-defloc56"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370526-11-off57" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-off57" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-off57" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370526-11-victim106" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Lambert 
                        <interp inst="t17370526-11-victim106" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-11-victim106" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-11-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-11-off57 t17370526-11-victim106"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of 12 in the Night, and stealing 6 Pair of Kid Gloves, value 12 s. 6 Pair of Stockings, value 12 s. a Tea-spoon, value 2 s a Silk handkerchief, value 3 s. and 12 s. 6 d in Money
            </rs>, the Property of William Lambert, <rs id="t17370526-11-cd58" type="crimeDate">August 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-11-off57 t17370526-11-cd58"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-11-person107">
                  William 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17370526-11-person107" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-person107" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I hir'd the Prisoner as a <rs id="t17370526-11-deflabel59" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-11-defend104 t17370526-11-deflabel59"></join> in June, and she liv'd with me 2 Months, she behav'd ill, and would get fuddl'd. On the 27th of August I lost 6 Pair of Kid Gloves, 6 Pair of Worsted Stockings, and a new Silk-Handkerchief No one could take them but her self, for there was no Body in the House but her self and me.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not prosecute her sooner?</p>
               <p>Lambert Because she kept out of the Way. She came in that Night fuddl'd; I told her she should stay no longer than Morning, and I thought she went to Bed, but she took the Things and went away between 12 and 1, and took the Key of the Street Door away with her: the Till was broke open, and 12 s. and 6 d. was taken out; there was no Body in the House but she and I</p>
               <p>Q. Did you owe her any Wages?</p>
               <p>Lambert. She had her Wages before Hand: She had a Guinea of me, which was more than her Wages came to.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Recommendation of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Only from a Nurse that look'd after a Child of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you enquire for her, after this 27th of August?</p>
               <p>Lambert. After she was gone, I spent much Time in enquiring after her.</p>
               <p>C. Why, you have indicted her for breaking open your House.</p>
               <p>Lambert. She took away the Key of the Door, she lock'd me in, and her self out. - I was forc'd to have the Lock broke in the Morning.</p>
               <p>C. Was there not a Suit commenced against you for her Wages, after she went away?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Yes; I was serv'd with a Copy of a Writ from the Court of Common-Pleas She dropp'd it one Term, and next Term they brought another. I employ'd a Man to defend me, and he took my Money, but did not defend me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not after you had been serv'd with this Action that you indict'd her?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I told her, before the Action was brought, that if she did not make Satisfaction for the Things taken away from me, I would have her before a Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Soon after she went away from me.</p>
               <p>Q. I thought you said you could not find her.</p>
               <p>Lambert. I never saw her but once, and then I had no Warrant; so I thought I had no Power to apprehend her.</p>
               <p>Q. Why, here was an Attorney prosecuting a Suit for her, how came it that you did not apply to him, to know where his Client was?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I did enquire of the Attorney, and he said, 'twas no Matter where she was, and they hid her from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not this Woman give Evidence on your Behalf in a Cause which was depending in the Court of Exchequer.</p>
               <p>Lambert No; not in the Court of Exchequer. I never had any Prosecution with Regard to my Business, in the Court of Exchequer. I had an I format on against me 4 Years ago at the Excise-Office, and none since. She gave no Evidence for me.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, whether you have not apply'd a second Time to her to give Evidence?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Not on any such Account. She was with me at the other End of the Town - not at the Exchequer. It was on Account of a Dozen of Candles which a Man had of me, and 'twas a Twelvemonth before he offer'd to pay me.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, if you have not apply'd to her as an Evidence?</p>
               <p>Lambert. No other - than in speaking the Truth. She carry'd the Candles.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Lambert I am not sure whether 'twas in June or July. I am sure it was not since she went away. When I desired her to give Evidence I did not threaten her, I only desired her to speak the Truth.</p>
               <p>A Woman. I know nothing of her robbing him; only one Morning he asked me if I had seen<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173705260011"></xptr> his Servant? and he asked me if she had brought any Thing to me? I told him, she never brought any Thing to me in her Life.</p>
               <p>Another. I know nothing of the Robbery; - she has been a little given to Drinking, and has us'd him ill; they used to quarrel.</p>
               <p>Defence. He had been up the Night before making Candles, and I thought he would not rise the next Day till late, so I having a little Business to do abroad, of my own, I opened the Shop about 7 o'Clock in the Morning, and clean'd it out; then I lock'd the Street Door, and took the Key with me. I spoke to a Neighbour, and desired her to give an Eye to the House, telling her I expected no body but the Exciseman. I staid longer than I expected, before I could speak with the Person I wanted, and was afraid he would abuse me, as he often has done, when I went home. However, in the Evening I went home, and begged ten thousand Pardons for staying and carrying the Key with me, tho' twas a Door that opens in Half, and I knew he could open it. He call'd me drunken Bitch, and said I should come in no more.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I took the Prisoner Apprentice in 1704 She liv'd with me ten Years as a covenant Servant, and since that she marry'd our Gardiner, and has buried our Family; latterly she has been a little given to Drinking. She is as honest a Woman, and as clean a clever Creature as lives.</p>
               <p>Another. Since the 27th of August I know she has been at Capt Wills's at Ratcliff Cross</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wills. I know the Prisoner to be an honest Woman; I have known her 12 Years When she came from Lambert's she went to a Lodging in Brick-street; since that, she liv'd with me, and was taken out of my House in January last. She had been then with me a Fortnight, and was every Day up and down: I trusted her with every Thing in the House.</p>
               <p>A Woman. I have known her a Twelvemonth. She nursed me in my Lying in, and I trusted her with all the Keys of my Shop, and found her very honest. When she came from Lambert's she came to me, and was with me five Weeks, and I sent her out on Errands every Day. She was openly every Day in my Shop. From my House she went to Madam Wills -</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wills. And she was with me till January last.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. The Prisoner is a very just honest Woman, and never was hid from him, but was up and down in the Streets to get her Bread. Lambert came once or twice to my House in Brick-street to ask for her, and she was never hid from him; tho' when he came to my House, she was out at Work; yet she went by his Door every Day; and as for this Felony, I never heard a Word of latterly.</p>


               <p>Lambert. I did seek after her, and spent Time and Money, but I could not find her. I have the Warrant in my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it dated?</p>
               <p>Lambert. It was last Sessions.</p>
               <p>A Witness. She was with me some Time, and Lambert has gone by divers Times when she was sitting at my Door with her Knitting. He has gone by divers Times on the other Side of the Way.</p>
               <p>A Man. Mr. Lambert was serv'd with a Copy of a Writ, at 
               <persName id="t17370526-11-person108">
                  Jane 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17370526-11-person108" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-person108" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Suit; the particular Time I cannot recollect, but 'twas about 8 or 9 Months ago, and he employ'd one king to defend him. This was about her Wages, and he told me he would give her a Guinea to make up the Matter. I went to her and offer'd her that, but she refused to make it up.</p>
               <p>Q. At that Time when he offer'd the Guinea, did he charge her with Felony?</p>
               <p>The Witness. He said she had wronged him of many Things, but he did not say she had broke his House: He only said he had lost several Things, and he believ'd she had taken them. He told me where she liv'd (in Brick street) and I went to her Lodging; I did not see her then, but she came a Day or two afterwards.</p>
               <p>C The Prosecutor is falsify'd in many Instances by every one of these People. In order to convict this Woman of Burglary, and to take away her Life, he has forsworn himself. The Reason why he did not prosecute her before, he says, was because she absconded.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17370526-11-verdict60" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-11-verdict60" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner, and the Court order'd her a Copy of her Indictment. And,</p>
               <p>The Prosecutor was taken into Custody.</p>
            </div1>
