<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340911-60">
               <interp inst="t17340911-60" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-60" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-60" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-60" type="date" value="17340911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340911-60-off266-c262" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-60-defend399 t17340911-60-off266 t17340911-60-verdict269"></join>
         
               <p>71. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340911-60-defend399" type="defendantName">
                     Mark 
                     Halpen 
                  <interp inst="t17340911-60-defend399" type="surname" value="Halpen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-defend399" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-defend399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17340911-60-off266" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-off266" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-off266" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assault"></interp>
               assaulting and wounding 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340911-60-victim401" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Hawkins 
                        <interp inst="t17340911-60-victim401" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-60-victim401" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-60-victim401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-60-off266 t17340911-60-victim401"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , one of the <rs id="t17340911-60-viclabel267" type="occupation">Clerks of the Exchequer</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-60-victim401 t17340911-60-viclabel267"></join>, in the Execution of his Office
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hawkins. On the <rs id="t17340911-60-cd268" type="crimeDate">30th of June</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-60-off266 t17340911-60-cd268"></join> was Twelvemonth, about seven in the Evening, I was going to my Seat in the Exchequer-Office, to enter some Writs. My Seat is within two of the upper End. Mr. Halpen was then sitting in Mr. Umfreville's Seat, which is the fourth below mine. As I pass'd by him, he said, You have serv'd me with a Summons from the Baron, but I am not oblig'd to take notice of it - I went to my Seat, and coming down to go to the filing Chest, near the Office Door; He said, I am going to Tunbridge, and must have some Money. I answer'd, I believe you'll be mistaken - You have impos'd upon the Court, and the Baron has been inform'd of it. God damn you, says he, You lie! What do you mean by that? says I. I tell you, says he again, God damn you, you lie! I told him it was like his Irish Manners. If I was to be born again, says he, I would chuse to be born in Ireland, for I never was asham'd of my Country, and damn you you dare not go out of the Office. I reply'd that I did not fear him or any Gentleman. He struck me on the Breast, and afterwards taking hold of the small End of his Whip, he struck me a violent Blow over the Eye, with the Butt End. I was confin'd under the Surgeon's Hands for near two Months, and it appearing that my Life was not out of Danger, the Baron committed him to Newgate - My Eye is still painful to me at times, and I find a decay in my Sight when I apply closely to reading or writing - Mr. Halpen indicted me before my 
               <persName id="t17340911-60-person402">
                  Lord 
                  Hardwicke 
               <interp inst="t17340911-60-person402" type="surname" value="Hardwicke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person402" type="given" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for an Assault.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. Did not you strike Mr. Halpen?</p>

               <p>Mr. Hawkins. Yes, I did after he struck me on the Breast, and then another Person interposing, Mr. Halpen reached over him, and struck me with his Whip.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-60-person403">
                  Barton 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17340911-60-person403" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person403" type="given" value="Barton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Halpen was sitting in Mr. Umfreville's Seat when Mr. Hawkins came in about 6 a Clock, and as he was going up to his Seat, Mr. Halpen forc'd his Discourse to him, about a Summons taken out before the Baron, and said he had no Copy, and should not mind any thing of it - Some other Words pass'd, and Mr. Halpen gave the Lie - And again, as Mr. Hawkins was coming down towards the Filing-Chest, Mr. Halpen said, You lie. Mr. Hawkins said, It's not Gentleman like; but it's like your Irish Manners. Mr. Halpen dared him to go out of the Office, to which he answer'd, that he was willing to meet any one. Then there was a Scuffle between them, but I can't tell who begun first, for I heard Blows before I saw any. I think the first Blow that I saw, was receiv'd by Mr. Hawkins on the Breast, and Blows were repeated - The first Blow that was offered was given by Mr. Halpen; but there was a little Scuffle before that - By a Scuffle I mean a rushing in upon one another - I cannot justly charge my Memory whether the Scuffle was before that Blow or not - I am sure there was no Scuffle before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-60-person404">
                  Mr. 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17340911-60-person404" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person404" type="given" value="Mr."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On the 30th of June I was sent for to the Mitre Tavern, to dress a Wound on Mr. Hawkins's Right-eye - The Wound was made with a bruising Instrument. It divided the small Vessel of the temporal Artery. Mr. Halpen said, that he had given Mr. Hawkins that Wound, and lash'd him, and would lash him again.</p>
               <p>Defendant's Council. Was not Mr. Hawkins abroad next Day?</p>
               <p>Mr. Holloway. No; but he went to Bloomsbury on Monday, for which I reprimanded him - I should not have given him leave to have gone abroad in less than a Week or ten Days - I believe that he's perfectly recover'd, I don't apprehend that his Eye is weaker than before.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110022"></xptr>For the Defendant.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rawlins. On Saturday about 6 in the Afternoon, Mr. Halpen came into the Office. I was then sitting at Mr. Oliphant's Seat, which is three Seats from Mr. Hawkins's - Mr. Hawkins came in, and to the best of my Remembrance, he gave the first Blow - I was near them and in a convenient Place for seeing what was done - They were both in an upright Position, walking down the Office. Mr. Hawkins went foremost, and turning short, near the Door, he took Mr. Halpen by the Arm to shove him out. This was the first that I saw, and there could not be a Blow with out my seeing; for my Eye was stedfastly upon them all the time. Mr. Halpen was talking first with me, and Mr. Hawkins came in and interrupted him - I saw Mr. Halpen give Mr. Hawkins several Blows, but none on the Breast. Mr. Hawkins struck Mr. Halpen in the Face with his Fist, and then they closed. I saw all the Blows that were given - The Blow on the Eye was after some struggle.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-60-person405">
                  John 
                  Case 
               <interp inst="t17340911-60-person405" type="surname" value="Case"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person405" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I was passing by and saw them both in Contempt with one another. They were engaged before I came, but heard Mr. Hawkins say, that he did strike Mr. Halpen for giving him the Lie; and charged me with him at the same time; and Mr. Halpen reply'd, I struck him second with the Whip - I examin'd them a-part, and carry'd them to the Mitre Tavern, and there Mr. Hawkins said, he would fight him for ten Guineas, and a Sword was sent for.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hawkins. I had three Witnesses, but they are out of Town There have been 8 several Trials about this Affair - It has cost me 170 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Halpen. By the Virtue of your Oath did not you strike me on the 9th of June?</p>
               <p>Court. That's out of the present Question.</p>
               <p>Mr. Halpen For his part, he's a Lawyer, and can have Law for nothing; but it has cost me near 200 l. The Jury found the him <rs id="t17340911-60-verdict269" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-60-verdict269" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
