<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-31">
               <interp inst="t17370216-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-31" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-31" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-31-off156-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-31-defend204 t17370216-31-off156 t17370216-31-verdict158"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-31-off156-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-31-defend206 t17370216-31-off156 t17370216-31-verdict158"></join>
         
               <p>35, 36. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-defend204" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Dwyer 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend204" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend204" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-defend206" type="defendantName">
                     Bryan 
                     Macgrass 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend206" type="surname" value="Macgrass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend206" type="given" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-defend206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17370216-31-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seducingAllegiance"></interp>
               feloniously procuring 
                     <persName id="t17370216-31-person207">
                        Richard 
                        Murphey 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person207" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-31-person207" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-31-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , a Subject of our Lord the King, to enlist and enter himself into the Service of the French King, being a Foreign Prince, without the leave of our present Lord the King under his Sign Manual first had and obtained
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370216-31-cd157" type="crimeDate">Feb. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-31-off156 t17370216-31-cd157"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the King having opened the Indictment and the Evidence, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-person208">
                  Richard 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person208" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person208" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was born in Ireland, and have been about 3 Years in England. In January last, I came in Company with the Prisoner Dwyer, being introduced to him by some of his Partners.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Who brought you acquainted with them?</p>
               <p>Murphey. One 
               <persName id="t17370216-31-person209">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person209" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person209" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met them first at the Rising Sun in Duke Street, by Lincoln's-Inn-Fields. I went there to enquire for one Serjeant Archdeacon, by William Clark's Direction, but he was gone the Night before, with fifteen Recruits for France. Clark met me there, and he told me that I should have come the Night before, and that I had lost my Passage this Time: But if I design'd to go, I must come by and by; for there would be a Gentlemen there again, who would tell me what I must do.</p>
               <p>Councel. What pass'd when you came in Company with Dwyer first?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Clark's Brother said, there was a Man would direct me what to do; so I ask'd Dwyer where Archdeacon was, he told me, he went away last Night, and that I should have come then. I told him my Cloaths were in Pawn; that I was in Debt, and could not come without my Things I told him I had an Uncle in France, who was a Priest, and if I went over, he would redeem me, says he, there is no Occasion of Redemption, for if you have a Friend there, you may have your Liberty. As for your Cloaths, says he, there's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160012"></xptr> no such Thing as having them redeem'd by me, for I was once very ill us'd about some Cloaths that I got out of Pawn for a Man, and was forced to make my Escape thro' a Coffee-House Then we talked of the Pay, and I was to have (he said) Seven Pence Half-penny a Day.</p>
               <p>Councel. Whose Service was you to go into, - the King of France's?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I was to go to Dunkirk, and was to have Seven Pence Half penny a Day. After this Mr. Macmillan came in, and he sat himself down to hear what pass'd. Dwyer told me, I was too low for the Service, and that when there was no War, they took no Men under his (Dwyer's) Size; but Macmillan said, I wore a low Shoe, when he wears other Shoes he'll do very well.</p>
               <p>Councel. So if you wore high heel'd Shoes, they were to make a Man of you. Did you see the Prisoner Macgrass at that Time?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Not at that Time; but afterward I did. They agreed to send my Cloaths after me, and Mr Brettle said, I should get a Note from them to that Purpose. They were pawned in my Name, but before I went abroad, they were to be left in Clark's Name; he was labouring to delude more People into the Service of France.</p>
               <p>Councel Was any Thing sign'd between you?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Not at that Time. We had several Meetings together after this; and to one of them the Prisoner Dwyer brought his Captain; they call'd him Captain Linderkin, this was at the Crown in Short's Gardens, and Will. Clark and the Prisoner Macgrass were present.</p>
               <p>Councel. I ask you if there was any Agreement drawn in Writing at that Time?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Yes; there was a Note wrote by Dwyer, and Clark, and Macgrass sign'd it. This is the Note sure enough, and Bryan, Macgrass, and William Clark signed it, at the present (same) Time. I saw Dwyer write it, and I desired Macgrass to sign it; he said he suppos'd 'twas no Harm, and so he did sign it. - I am sorry he was concern'd in it, because I believe he was innocent, - only he knew on what Account my Cloaths were to be redeem'd, the Day before the Note was made.</p>
               <p>Councel. Then how can you say you believe him innocent?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Because he never propos'd any Thing at all to me about the Affair.</p>
               <p>Coun. Pris. This Note is said to be a Promissory Note, and 'tis in the Singular Number, - my Objection is, that two Men have sign'd it.</p>
               <p>The Note was read,</p>
               <p>A Suit of Cloaths, a pair of Silver Buckles, the Goods of Richard Murphey, now at the Pawnbrokers, and alter'd into William Clark's Name, to be deliver'd free of all Charges, on the Agreement between him and 
               <persName id="t17370216-31-person210">
                  Philip 
                  Dwyer 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person210" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person210" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Councel. So they would not venture to mention what that Agreement was. Did you go to the Pawnbrokers to alter the Name, in which the Cloaths were pawn'd?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Yes, Dwyer and Macgrass, and Will. Clark went with me, and the Name was changed: Clark wrote his Name upon a bit of Card, and the Pawnbroker put it upon my Cloaths.</p>
               <p>Councel. What was the Agreement mention'd in that Paper?</p>
               <p>Murphey. To procure a Man or two for him.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was Macgrass present at any Time when Dwyer and you talk'd about your being enlisted?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Yes, the Day before he was taken, and then Dwyer told Macgrass, that this young Man (meaning me) had a Design to go abroad; but, said he, Times are hard upon him, - his Cloaths are in Pawn, and he will have Security they shall be sent him; and he desired me to pronounce the Agreement, made between him and me. Macgrass was his Friend (at present) and he bid me tell him the Agreement we were upon; so I told Macgrass what I had propos'd about my Cloaths.</p>
               <p>Councel. What was you to do in France?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I was to procure a Man or two, or to pay for my Cloaths, when they came to me.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was there any mention made of what you were to do?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I was to pass Muster for a Friend, in Buckley's Regiment.</p>
               <p>Councel. You talk'd of Seven-pence Half-penny a Day; what was you to have that Pay for?</p>
               <p>Murphey. To serve like another Man.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you to serve as a Soldier, or was you not?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I did not go so tight upon them, - they told me I was to have Seven-pence Half-penny a Day.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was not you to do a private Soldier's Duty?</p>
               <p>Murphey. They told me I might pay for a Soldier when I came there, and might work at my Trade every Day.</p>
               <p>Councel. So he told you, if you could get any Body to muster for you, you might follow your own Business?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Yes, Sir, when he wrote the Note about the Cloaths, he told every Thing I was to do; and I told him, - I don't expect to be serv'd but like a common Soldier: Friends we met (says I) and Friends we'll part. He told me he had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160013"></xptr> good Friends abroad, and when I was got to France, he would give me two Holland Shirts.</p>
               <p>Councel I would ask you this Question, - Was you to go there to be hired as a Soldier, with encouragement, that when you came there, you might get some body to appear for you in the Regiment as a Soldier, or was you to go over and appear for some body else?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I was to appear for my self; but they said I might follow my Business</p>
               <p>Councel. Pray mind the Question. Was you to go over and appear for any body else, or was you to go as a Soldier your self? and if you had any Occasion to be absent, you might have some body to Muster for you.</p>
               <p>Murphey. I might have any body to appear in a Muster for me. Dwyer said, he would not enlist me; but I said, I desir'd to be serv'd as other Men, or else I would part with him: So he told me, I might pass Muster, and follow my Trade too.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did Macgrass hear all this?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I believe not. Macgrass desired me to propose what I was upon; so I told him all.</p>
               <p>Councel. What did you tell him?</p>
               <p>Murphey. I told him I would procure a Man or two, and so get my Cloaths clear; and I shew'd them one Man, and I told them, I would get another when I got to France: For it I could not get one or two Men to enlist in the Regiment, I was to pay for my Cloaths and my Passage when I got to France.</p>
               <p>Councel. And was it not mention'd to you, that if you could not get a Man or two, you was to stay there yourself?</p>
               <p>Murphey. That was not mention'd.</p>
               <p>Councel. Why what was you to have 7 Pence Half-penny a Day for?</p>
               <p>Murphey. They told me I might follow my Trade, and get a Man to pass Muster for me in Case of Necessity. Macgrass was not present when Dwyer and I had all this Discourse. All the Concern he had in this Affair, was in Short's Gardens, when the Agreement was reduced to Writing, and he signed it.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-person211">
                  Andrew 
                  Macmillon 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person211" type="surname" value="Macmillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person211" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the Rising-Sun by the Romish Chapel in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields, when Dwyer and Murphey were there. I was not one of their Company, they were at a Table, and I was by the Fire Side. I heard what they were upon, so I told one Mr. Brettle. -</p>
               <p>Councel. What did Dwyer say to Murphey?</p>
               <p>Macmillon. I got Brettle to go with me to the Rising-Sun, so we sat down, and I took up a News-Paper (the Penny-Post) and that they might not think I minded them, I seemed Intent upon the Paper. I heard Dwyer say, Why did not you come Yesterday at Five o'Clock? Murphey said, How could I come without Cloaths? Dwyer said, They would have been sent after him. Murphey told him, He would have Security that he should have them before he went; and they talked a good deal in Irish, that I could not understand. At last I said, If the Man is going out of the Kingdom, it is not proper he should leave his Cloaths behind him, if he could take them with him. Aye! but, said Dwyer, he'll have Seven-Pence Half-penny a Day when he comes there. I heard them talk about his Landing somewhere about Calais, and about his Pay, but I heard nothing of what he was to do for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-person212">
                  Thomas 
                  Bonniface 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person212" type="surname" value="Bonniface"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person212" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. When I went to take the Prisoner Dwyer, I attempted to search him, and he pulled out a Paper from his Pocket and put it into the Fire; I endeavoured to take it out of the Fire, and as my Hand was upon the Paper, he set his Foot upon it and burnt my Hand, but with much Difficulty we saved it. Macgrass was taken at the same Time, but we found nothing upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-31-person213">
                  James 
                  Brettle 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person213" type="surname" value="Brettle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person213" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the Prisoners were taken. Murphey told me that Dwyer had the French King's Authority about him for enlisting Men, and he said, if we searched him, we should find it. We had Mr. Ibbot the Messenger with us when they were taken. We carried them to Mr. Hodges's, the Corner of Short's-Gardens. Ibbot searched Macgrass, and the Constable searched Dwyer. While he was searching Dwyer, he (Dwyer) pulled a Paper out of his Pocket and put it into the Fire, the Constable went to take it out, and he set his Foot upon the Constable's Hand and held it down in the Fire, but I drew my Hanger and made the Constable take it out. That's the Paper, it is burnt a little, and it was preserved with Difficulty.</p>
               <p>The Paper was wrote in French, but in English it runs as follows.</p>
               <p>'' The Irish Regiment of Buckley. Soldiers '' Furloe. We who have undersigned, to all, '' unto whom it may appertain, we have given '' Leave to 
               <persName id="t17370216-31-person214">
                  Philip 
                  Dwyer 
               <interp inst="t17370216-31-person214" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person214" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Voluntier in the Colonel's '' Company in Buckley's Regiment, to go '' to England for 6 Months, to recruit for the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160014"></xptr> '' said Colonel's Company. The said Dwyer '' was born in Tipperary, aged 43 Years, five '' Feet five Inches high, Chesnut colour'd Hair, '' Blue Eyes, short Nose, and good Legs.</p>
               <p>Signed. Macgray, Capt. Lieut. Dated at Avence, Counter-sign'd. Macheire, Major. Oct. 12, 1736. Approv'd and sign'd. Henezie, Lieut. Col. Enter'd. Dettez, Commissary of War.</p>
               <p>Dwyer. I never agreed with him about any Money: I told him there was but little for his Pay, and he said he had some skill in the Irish Character, and would improve himself in France. I was sick when this Furloe was given, 'tis a Soldier's Ease; and when I was seized, I happen'd to burn the Paper in a surprize, thinking it would do me harm.</p>
               <p>A Juryman. We would know whether the giving and receiving of Money, is absolutely necessary to the enlisting of Men?</p>
               <p>Mr. De Veil. No; Voluntiers are enlisted every Day, without a Farthing of Money; and when they have had the Act read to them, and the Articles of War, and they assent to them before a Magistrate, they are to all Intents and Purposes, as much Soldiers, as if they had received a Thousand Pounds. Reading the Act, and assenting to the Articles before a Magistrate, cannot be done in such Cases as these, where Persons enlist for Foreign Service. Both <rs id="t17370216-31-verdict158" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-31-verdict158" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
