<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-57">
               <interp inst="t17351210-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-57" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-57" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-57-off241-c317" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-57-defend443 t17351210-57-off241 t17351210-57-verdict244"></join>
         

               <p>74. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-57-defend443" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Gardner 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-57-defend443" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-defend443" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-defend443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17351210-57-off241" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-off241" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-off241" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17351210-57-victim444" type="victimName">
                        Edward 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-victim444" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-57-victim444" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-57-victim444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-57-off241 t17351210-57-victim444"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , by striking, beating, and throwing him against a wooden Form, in a Drinking Room, and thereby giving him one mortal Bruise on the back Part of his Head, <rs id="t17351210-57-cd242" type="crimeDate">November 27</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-57-off241 t17351210-57-cd242"></join>/, of which mortal Bruise he languished till the next Day, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroners Inquisition for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-57-person445">
                  Henry 
                  Passer 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person445" type="surname" value="Passer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person445" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the <placeName id="t17351210-57-crimeloc243">White Horse Ale house in Castle-Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-57-crimeloc243" type="placeName" value="White Horse Ale house in Castle-Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-57-crimeloc243" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-57-off241 t17351210-57-crimeloc243"></join>, on the twenty seventh of November, between five and six in the Afternoon. 
               <persName id="t17351210-57-person446">
                  Philip 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person446" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person446" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Porter, was in Liquor, and the Prisoner was playing the Rogue with him. The Deceased came in, and sat down in a Box. He was in Liquor too, and very much, but not so drunk as a beast, for he did not reel about the House. Harris had lent his Coat to the Prisoner, who went out and whited it, and coming in again he tost the Coat about till it fell upon the Deceased, and whited him He got up in a Passion, and went to the Prisoner's Brother and Sister (who kept the House, and were then at Dinner) and complained that he had been abused by their Black-guard Brother. Mrs. Gardner desired him to be easy; but he kicked the Grid-iron about, and threw the Candle and Candle-stick against the Grates. Upon this, the Prisoner struck him first, and gave him three Blows on the Face; I think it was with his open Hand. At the first Blow, the Deceased stood about half a Minute, and then fell back with the Nape of his Neck against the Bench. I took him up, his Eyes were fixt. An Apothecary's Apprentice being in the Room, let him blood, and then he spoke, and was something better, and I went away. He lived about twenty two Hours. He and the Prisoner were intimate Acquaintance, and had been at Breakfast together but two Mornings before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was the Fall occasioned by the Blow, by his being in drink?</p>
               <p>H. Passer. I cannot say, which. He said himself when he came in, that he had been drinking Punch, and was full of Liquor,</p>
               <p>Prisoner Did he offer to sit down when he fell?</p>
               <p>H. Passer. I do not know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-57-person447">
                  Thomas 
                  Critchet 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person447" type="surname" value="Critchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person447" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr. Gardner, the Prisoner's Brother. 
               <persName id="t17351210-57-person448">
                  Phillip 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person448" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person448" type="given" value="Phillip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Watchman had been fuddled all Day. The Deceased came in much in Liquor. Harris's Coat was whited, and thrown upon him, and he flirted it off upon the Deceased, who I believe was a sleep. He got up, and thinking the Deceased had done it, he went to my Master and Mistress in the Bar-room, and said, D - me, must I be abused by your Blackguard brother? Then returning to his Seat, he took a Candle-wick, threw it violently against the Grates, and said, D - your Black guard House; and brustling up to the Prisoner, called him Names and abused him, and I think held up his Fist at him. The Prisoner struck him three times on the side of his Face pretty quick; but whether with his Hand open, or not, I cannot say. The Deceased spoke not a Word more, but stood half a Minute, and whether he was going to sit down, and thought the Bench just behind him, or was stunned with the Blow, or the Liquor was the Cause of it, I do not know; but he fell down backwards. The Prisoner is as good natured a Man as lives, and I believe there was no Enmity between them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-57-person449">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Manton 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person449" type="surname" value="Manton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person449" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While the Coat was gone out to be whited, to make Sport with Harris, the Deceased came in, I asked him to spend a Penny in Brown Two-penny. No Boy, says he, I have been drinking Punch all Day; he leaned his Head upon the Bench, and seemed to be sick with drinking, when the Prisoner came in with Harris's whited Coat on, and frisked about, and then pulled it off, and shook it upon Harris, and Harris put it on the Deceased, and whited him with it. The Deceased got up in a Passion, and curst, and swore, and called him Names, and kicked the Gridiron about, and threw the Candle-stick against the Grates. I do not know whether he threw it at the Prisoner, or not. The Prisoner said, who do you abuse, and struck him three Blows. He stept back, and fell with the side of his Head on the Bench. I blooded him, and then he was a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100034"></xptr> little better. He died about six in the Evening. I believe the Fall was the Cause of his Death, and not the Blows the Prisoner gave him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he fall by the Blows, or the Liquor?</p>
               <p>N. Manton. If he had fallen by the Blows, he would have fallen immediately, but he stept back, and made a little pause.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Did not Harrison tell him that it was he and not me that threw the Coat upon him?</p>
               <p>N. Manton. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-57-person450">
                  Daniel 
                  Woodham 
               <interp inst="t17351210-57-person450" type="surname" value="Woodham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person450" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On Denuding the Skull, on the back part of the Head, I found much extravasated Blood between the Skull and the Skin. I took off the Top of the Skull, and found the Brain tumified. I found no Bruise on his Temples, and I believe the Blow he received by the Fall was the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>Capt. Picksat and Mr. Lawrence, deposed that the Prisoner was a peaceable quiet Man.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17351210-57-verdict244" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-verdict244" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-verdict244" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17351210-57-punish245" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-punish245" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-57-punish245" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-57-defend443 t17351210-57-punish245"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
