<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360505-33">
               <interp inst="t17360505-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-33" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360505"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360505-33" type="date" value="17360505"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360505-33-off184-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-33-defend246 t17360505-33-off184 t17360505-33-verdict186"></join>
         
               <p>40. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-defend246" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Stephens 
                  <interp inst="t17360505-33-defend246" type="surname" value="Stephens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-defend246" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-defend246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he <rs id="t17360505-33-cd183" type="crimeDate">March 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-33-off184 t17360505-33-cd183"></join> on 
               
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-victim248" type="victimName">
                     Catherine 
                     Skelton 
                  <interp inst="t17360505-33-victim248" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-victim248" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-victim248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-33-off184 t17360505-33-victim248"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17360505-33-off184" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-off184" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-off184" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilfully, maliciously, and feloniously, did make an Assault, and with both his Hands and Feet, in and on the Ground, the said Skelton did cast and throw; and the said Skelton so lying, he the said Stevens did divers Times strike and kick, giving her then and there, on the Head, Face, Stomach. Belly and Sides, several Mortal Wounds and Bruises, of which Wounds and Bruises from the 15th to the 20th of the same Month she languished and languishingly liv'd and then and there died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was indicted a second time on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person249">
                  Hannah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person249" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person249" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased died last Saturday was Six Weeks: On Monday before the Prisoner beat her and stamped on her in a violent Manner, and drag'd her out by the Hair of her Head. I saw no Provocation given, for she was darning a Stocking, and he struck her in the Face with his Hands and Feet, and stamped upon her right Side, so violently, that there was a great deal of Blood came out of her Nose. On the Tuesday he beat her again, and stamped upon her in the Entry, drag'd her out of the Brandy-shop, stamp'd upon her again, and she cried out, Dear, God, save my Life, he has killed me!</p>


               <p>Q. What Relation was the Prisoner to Skelton?</p>
               <p>Smith. They were Bedfellows I believe. This was in <placeName id="t17360505-33-crimeloc185">Bridges-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360505-33-crimeloc185" type="placeName" value="Bridges-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360505-33-crimeloc185" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360505-33-off184 t17360505-33-crimeloc185"></join>, where he had co-habited with her three Years, I sell Oranges just by them at the Door of the Play-house. I have seen him pull her in, and lock the Door upon her, and have heard her cry out, Murder.</p>
               <p>On Wednesday I saw the Deceased, and said Katey, how came you to be so used? and she told me, that he came up again at two a-Clock and whipt her so violently, that the Scourges were on her Face when the Coroner sat on her Body. I saw her when she was dying on Saturday Night a Quarter before 9, and she died a quarter of an Hour before 10. She sent 
               <persName id="t17360505-33-person250">
                  Jenny 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person250" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person250" type="given" value="Jenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for me. I went and found her sitting upright in her Bed; she said she was dying, and wished I would send f r a Minister: I am starv'd says she, pray let me have a Gill of Wine. I sent Jenny Hall for it to the Genoa Arms. Then she desired me to go to her Father, and tell him that 
               <persName id="t17360505-33-person251">
                  William 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person251" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person251" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had killed and murdered her; but my Father, says she, won't do me Justice, I hope the World will. There was not, my Lord, a free Place, from Head to Foot, but all black as the Gentlemens Gowns.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Physician or Surgeon?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, Mr. Coldham was sent for, after she was dead: He would not let any one come near her while she was alive. I went to Stevens, to tell him the Deceased desired to have a Minister sent for: G - d D - n 
               <persName id="t17360505-33-person252">
                  Kate 
                  Skelton 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person252" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person252" type="given" value="Kate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , say he, the Minister, and you too; if she dies, she must be buried. This was at the Castle the Corner of Vinegar-Yard. I do believe she might be a little out of her Senses between whiles, because she told me, my Husband lay across the Feet of the Bed, and he was not there. and talk'd of a Child burning in the Fire.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I ask what time you saw me beat her, and whereabouts it was?</p>
               <p>Smith. From two a-Clock to 8 a-Clock on Monday, I saw him beat her several Times in the Brandy-shop; then she went in, there he locked her in and beat her, and she cried out, Help! Murder!</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173605050010"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person253">
                  Sarah 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person253" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person253" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by on Monday, and I went in for a Farthing's worth of small Beer; and while I was there, the Prisoner came in and tapp'd her in the Face; she said Will, don't beat me, and then he gave her a Punch in the Eye: I believe the Blow might do her a Prejudice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the tap in the Face given with Violence?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. I can't say that; but a Man's Hand is heavy, I can tell that my self. Then he said, Kate come go to bed; says I, do Kate, go up with him, and the Woman in the Shop, said fye upon you, to stand by and see a Woman beat; why says I; if we say any Thing he'll beat us. She went up with him, and the next Morning she told me she was kill'd Will. Stevens had kill'd her; he had laid her down and trampled upon her. On Saturday I heard she was dead, and was so surpriz'd that I have never been myself since. I saw her after she had been dead about an Hour; when she was laid out, and after Mr. Coldham had opened her; her Side very black and bruised, but I cannot tell which Side, and there was a Plaister on it, other Parts of her Body was much bruised, and her poor Eye sunk in her head.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I ask if you never heard of her falling down Stairs drunk?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. No never, I know once the Prisoner threw her down Stairs, and put-her Finger and Thumb out of joint.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person254">
                  Ann 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person254" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person254" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up Stairs on Friday to see the poor Creature, and ask'd her if I should do any Thing for her; she desired me to get her half a Pint of Beer. I did, and made it hot, with Sugar and Nutmeg: I am afraid said I, that the Fellow has murdered you Mrs. Thomas. Says she. I am not long for this World, then the World will see this, when I am dead; and on Saturday she died. I was there when she was dead, and pull'd the Plaister off her Side, and there was not a free Place from the Crown of her Head to the Sole of her Feet, all black as a Shoe, and the Stripes in her Fore-head were as big as my little Finger; both Sides were black, but the right side was blackest. About a Month before, I saw her Arms whaled as thick as a Cane; I have seen him beat her so, that I thought no Christian Creature could have lived. About half an Hour before she died, I says to her, Katey, do you want any Thing? Will Stevens was hanging over her, and he said you want something under your Head; and he put her Petticoat behind her Head; there is no Occasion for it now, says she. I saw her after she was dead, and never saw the Fellow of her in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person255">
                  Susan 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person255" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person255" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming through the Play-house Passage on Saturday Night, and the Prisoner was standing there. I asked him how she did; he said very bad, and told me I might go up to see her. Jenny Hill was with her; her hands were very cold and she in a clammy Sweat. She told me she was very bad, and that she had desired Stevens to get her some Small-beer; but he not coming, I made her half a Pint of Sage Tea. The Woman in the Room help'd me to get her up, and we made her Bed, and aired her Sheets, and got her to Bed again, for she told us she was very faint. When she was got to bed, she put her Hands round my Wast, gritted her Teeth, and with a very low Voice, said he had killed her. After she was dead, I saw a Plaister on her Right-side, and her Body was all over Bruises. I believe she was now and then not in her Senses, for she told me, that Jenny Hall had bepissed her self, and talked of a Child burning. She died with her Head in my Bosom.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person256">
                  Margaret 
                  Rialton 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person256" type="surname" value="Rialton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person256" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Night she came to my Room, and begged I would let her sit up there that Night, for Stevens had threatned to murder her; this about a Month before. I said, Kitty, be persuaded and go home: if I go home, says she, he will murder me. On Tuesday she came again, and said, Will. had beat her with a Broom stick, which he made her fetch out of the Closet, and broke her Arm, and put out her Finger. I said you are a Fool to live with him, you are not married to him; Aye, says she, it is fine talking, if I should go home to my Fathers, he will get me away again; he has threatned to murder me, but he need not do any thing more, he has done enough already. When she was dead, one came and told me that 
               <persName id="t17360505-33-person257">
                  Kate 
                  Plump 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person257" type="surname" value="Plump"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person257" type="given" value="Kate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was gone; with that I ran and met the Prisoner with a full Pot of Beer upon the Stairs. I viewed her Body; her Right-side and Shoulder were very black, and her left Eye, and her right Finger and Arm.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person258">
                  Mary 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person258" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person258" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday Morning she was waiting in my Shop for Stevens; when he came in, she desired him to go to bed, for he had been up all Night: He bid her get up Stairs, and gave her some Blows, not very unmercifull, about the Head, but she got a black Eye: I told him, if he must abuse the Woman, he must take her up Stairs. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173605050011"></xptr> saw no more Blows, nor did I hear her cry out; they went up Stairs together. On Tuesday Morning, she had two Strokes on the Forehead, and a black Eye. I had been ill, and the Deceased looked after me. (Dr. Coldham was my Surgeon,) and I was afraid he had beat her for being with me; but she told me no, Griffiths, I wont belie him, he is not against my doing good to any one. The next Day she fell before the Fire, and told me her Pains were too great to bear. I asked her what occasioned her Pains; and she told me, they who laid her out would see how she had been used by him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coldham. About the latter end of March, the Church Wardens of Covent Garden Parish sent to me, to desire me to open the Deceased. I viewed the Body, and saw several Bruises on her Arms and Sides; I cut into them, and found they went no farther than the Fat, so they could not be mortal. On opening the Body, I found both the Lobes of the Lungs adhered to the Breast, and in the right Lobe was formed a large Ulcer, with a Collection of Matter; the Liver was of a parboil'd Complection, and larger than ordinary, the Stomach much diminished, and the Tone entirely lost. I believe the Occasion of her Death was from a Complication of Disorders occasioned by irregular living.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hicks. I assisted Mr. Coldham, and am of the same Opinion.</p>
               <p>Jane Hill. I was with her two Days before she died, and never heard her complain; she was never easy when he was away from her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360505-33-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cooling 
               <interp inst="t17360505-33-person259" type="surname" value="Cooling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with her the Night she died, and did not hear any thing of her being murdered.</p>
               <p>Several Persons giving the Prisoner the Character of an honest, quiet Man, and others deposing that the Deceased was excessively addicted to drinking, the Jury <rs id="t17360505-33-verdict186" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360505-33-verdict186" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted the Prisoner, and found on the Coroner's Inquest, that Catherine Skelton died a natural Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
