<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381011-6">
               <interp inst="t17381011-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-6" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381011"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381011-6" type="date" value="17381011"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381011-6-off30-c79" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-defend96 t17381011-6-off30 t17381011-6-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas
                      Jones, alias <rs id="t17381011-6-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-defend96 t17381011-6-alias-3"></join>Brown</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-defend96" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-defend96" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-defend96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was <rs id="t17381011-6-off30" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-off30" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-off30" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               indicted for privately stealing a Gold Watch, val. 23 l. a Cornelian Seal, set in Gold, value 20 s and a Steel Chain, val. 6 d. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381011-6-victim98" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Jackson 
                        <interp inst="t17381011-6-victim98" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-6-victim98" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381011-6-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-off30 t17381011-6-victim98"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17381011-6-cd31" type="crimeDate">Sept. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-off30 t17381011-6-cd31"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jackson. On the 9th of Sept. about 7 at Night, or about 7 or 8 Minutes after, I was coming over the Bridge: The first House upon the Bridge from Southwark, on the Right Hand, is a Paper-Shop, kept by the Widow Stone, - (a very honest good Woman) and the next is an empty House, here there was a little Stop, and the Prisoner gave 3 great, hearty Jumps at me, and jump'd upon me: I could not tell what he jump'd at, - but he jump'd my Watch out of my right Fob, with his left Hand. I miss'd it that Minute; he sprang on the other Side of the Way, and I cry'd out stop Thief. I felt it go out of my Pocket, and saw him run away to a Lamp on the other Side of the Way, 3 or 4 Doors from 'Squire Brooks's. Two other Men were with him, but who they were I can't tell. I am sure the Prisoner is the Man: it was not then dark; so I had the Benefit of the Day-light and the Moon too, and I saw his Face, as much as I desire to see the Face of any Man in my Life. He was exactly in the same Cloaths (upon my Oath) that he is in now. The Watch he robb'd me of, was worth 23 l. the Seal a Guinea, and the steel Chain, (Diamond-cut) was worth a Shilling, - but it cost more. When I saw him run away, I cry'd heartily out after him, but he got through the Gate, into the Burrough, and I heard nothing of him 'till he was taken as a Gambler, (or Money Dropper) the Tuesday following. For being in Trouble and Distress for my Watch, and for my being so unjustly serv'd, I went to Mr. Bird, and told him my Trouble. Says Bird, as you're an old Friend, we'll leave Notes of Description at Bridewell, New-Prison, the Marshalsea &amp;c. of this good Man; and he being taken on Tuesday for Gambling, he sent Mr. Bushel, an Apothecary in St. Paul's Church-yard, to the Compter with me, and I told the Man that tends the Prison, I did not want to hurt any body, but the Man that I meant, was a little taller than I, about 26 Years old, in a light brown Coat, with a slit Sleeve, and a chitterling Shirt. When I saw him, I knew him to be the Man, and here are 2 Witnesses, that I then declared him upon my Sacred Oath to be the Person that robb'd me. On Tuesday, I waited upon my Lord-Mayor, and he was so worthy and so good, as to give me a Warrant of Detainer against him. After that, I brought 3 or 4 Gentlemen of Credit to see him, and then I said again he was the Man; and now I will swear the same to the Day of my Death.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173810110010"></xptr>Prisoner. What Stockings had I on? - if you saw me, and took such Notice of me, why did not you stop me?</p>
               <p>Jackson. When you say this you say but little; because I did cry stop Thief, and you sprang away before I could lay hold of you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You say you knew all my Cloaths, - what Stockings had I on?</p>
               <p>Jackson. I am sure you had a good - Stock of Impudence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-person99">
                  John 
                  Hudson 
               <interp inst="t17381011-6-person99" type="surname" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 9th of last Month, between 7 and 8 at Night, I was going over the Bridge, and at the farther End I saw 3 or 4 People bustling together, and wondered what they were doing. But presently out ran a middle sized Man, and Mr. Jackson cry'd out stop Thief, that Fellow has got my Watch. The Man ran off, and Mr. Jackson took me into Mrs. Stone's Shop, and I told him where I liv'd. He carry'd me afterwards to the Compter to see the Prisoner, but as I did not see his Face when the Thing was done, I could not swear to him. I can only say 'twas such a Siz'd Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-person100">
                  John 
                  Nicholson 
               <interp inst="t17381011-6-person100" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Mr. Jackson came to the Compter, he described the Prisoner before he had seen him, and when he (the Prisoner) was brought to him, he down'd on his Knees, and said, - by the living God that is the Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he knows that I have been in any Compter before?</p>
               <p>Nicholson I have seen him before, I have known him 2 or 3 Years by Sight. - If I must speak, - I know he has a very bad Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-person101">
                  William 
                  Whitaker 
               <interp inst="t17381011-6-person101" type="surname" value="Whitaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person101" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with Dr. Jackson to the Compter, where he described the Man, and when he saw him, he said - as God should save him, that was the Man. I asked the Prisoner what Business he followed? He told me he was a <rs id="t17381011-6-deflabel32" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-defend96 t17381011-6-deflabel32"></join> to Mr. Leeson at the George in Belton-Street, Long-Acre.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at Home all that Evening from 6 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I was at Mr. Leeson's House on Saturday the 9th of Sept. (I believe) and saw the Prisoner come in between 6 and 7 in the Evening; he sat till between 8 or 9 o'Clock, then he took a Candle off the Bar, and went up to Bed. I have known him 5 or 6 Years, and as to his Character -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There is no need of his speaking about that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-person102">
                  Hannah 
                  Tooley 
               <interp inst="t17381011-6-person102" type="surname" value="Tooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person102" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Servant of Leeson's; on Saturday the 9th of Sept. he came Home to our House, between 6 and 7 at Night, and sat down till between 8 and 9, then he took a Candle off the Kitchen Dresser, and went up Stairs to Bed. We keep a Publick House, and tho' we have a good many People coming in and out, yet I remember the Prisoner's coming in that Night, because he was taken up on the Tuesday following. I never observed any Thing but Civility by him since I have been in the House, and I have lived with Leeson about 10 Weeks in all, - and about 3 or 4 Weeks, before this Fact was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381011-6-person103">
                  John 
                  Leeson 
               <interp inst="t17381011-6-person103" type="surname" value="Leeson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Mr. Whitaker. On the Prisoner's telling me in the Compter that he was a Servant to this Leeson, I went and enquired at the House concerning him. This Tooley told me she knew nothing at all of him; and I said 'twas a little odd, the Fellow should send me to People that did not know him; he is in the Compter (says I) for Gambling, and on Suspicion of stealing a Watch; they then asked me what Time the Robbery was committed? I told them I could not tell exactly the Time; but then this Tooley recollected him, and said she would make Oath he came in about half an Hour after 8 o'Clock, and seeming to be uneasy, he took a Candle and went up to Bed.</p>
               <p>Leeson was asked what Name the Prisoner went by? He answered, sometimes by the Name of Tho. Brown, and sometimes Tho. Jones. <rs id="t17381011-6-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17381011-6-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381011-6-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381011-6-defend96 t17381011-6-punish34"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
