<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-81">
               <interp inst="t17361208-81" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-81" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-81" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-81" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-81-off402-c394" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-defend592 t17361208-81-off402 t17361208-81-verdict407"></join>
         
               <p>105. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-defend592" type="defendantName">
                     Isaac 
                     Burges 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-81-defend592" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-defend592" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-defend592" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-victim594" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Howson 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-81-victim594" type="surname" value="Howson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-victim594" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-victim594" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-off402 t17361208-81-victim594"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17361208-81-off402" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-off402" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-off402" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               feloniously did make an Assault, and with his Right Hand, on the Left Side of the Head, the said Howson did beat and strike, by Means of which Beating, &amp;c. the said Howson received a mortal Wound on the Right Side of his Head, of which he instantly died
            </rs>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17361208-81-crimeloc403">St. Vedast alias Foster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-81-crimeloc403" type="placeName" value="St. Vedast alias Foster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-81-crimeloc403" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-off402 t17361208-81-crimeloc403"></join>, <rs id="t17361208-81-cd404" type="crimeDate">Nov. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-off402 t17361208-81-cd404"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-person595">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17361208-81-person595" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person595" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person595" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can't say any Thing about the Murder, I did not see it done: The Deceased was my <rs id="t17361208-81-viclabel405" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-victim594 t17361208-81-viclabel405"></join>, and the Prisoner my <rs id="t17361208-81-deflabel406" type="occupation">Journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-defend592 t17361208-81-deflabel406"></join>; November 20 we had been setting a Batch of Bread in the Cellar, and the Deceased was eating his Breakfast there; I called him to carry out his Bread, he came up, and took a Basket, and set it down by the Side of the Counter; I saw the Water in his Eyes, and asked him what was the Matter; he said, Isaac had struck him; then he went behind the Door and set down upon a Sack of Bran; I called him two or three Times, he made no Answer; but the Prisoner coming up, I ask'd him what was the Matter; he said the Boy had struck him, and he would not be struck by an Apprentice; then he went down again. My Wife and I fancy'd the Boy was in a Fit, we got Water and put into his Mouth; as he was a sulky Boy, we still imagin'd he sham'd it. I bid Isaac carry out the Bread, and then we threw Water in the Boy's Face; he seem'd to blow a little, so my Wife sent for some Hartshorn, and clapp'd it to his Nose, but it had no Effect. Then I sent for a Surgeon, and he open'd a Vein, but he did not bleed at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-person596">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17361208-81-person596" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person596" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person596" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave much the same Account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-person597">
                  Sarah 
                  Sands 
               <interp inst="t17361208-81-person597" type="surname" value="Sands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person597" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person597" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account of the good Agreement there had been between the Prisoner and the Deceas'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-person598">
                  Richard 
                  Kemm 
               <interp inst="t17361208-81-person598" type="surname" value="Kemm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person598" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person598" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (Apothecary) About Twelve or One o'Clock, my Master was sent for to Mr. Smith's: He not being at home, I went, and found the Body dead, and without Pulse. The Surgeon came and open'd a Vein, but he did not bleed. We search'd him, and upon his Body, we found only a small Wound just above his Ear, about the Bigness of an Orifice made when a Person is blooded. Mr. Barugh enquired of the Prisoner what he had struck the Deceas'd with; he said he could not tell how it was, - it was some how with his Fist.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-81-person599">
                  Thomas 
                  Barugh 
               <interp inst="t17361208-81-person599" type="surname" value="Barugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person599" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-person599" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Nov. 20. About Noon I was sent for to bleed Mr. Smith's Apprentice; I found him dead, and that he could not bleed; I open'd a Vein, but 'twas to no Purpose. After he was carry'd up Stairs, and the Body was stripp'd, we found a small Wound a little above the Ear: I put my Probe into it, but it would pass no farther than thro' the Skin. While he was laid upon the Bed, there was a great Quantity of Blood came out of his Nose. The Prisoner told me, he only struck him with his Fist. On the Monday following my Master open'd the Head, and we found a Perforation thro' the Skull, triangular, and about the Bigness of the End of this Probe, and a great Quantity of coagulated Blood between the two Membranes of the Brain. The Perforation thro' the Skull, answered directly to the Wound in the Flesh, above the Ear. I take the Perforation to have been made by a Nail, for it answered exactly to the exterior Wound in the Flesh, only it was ragged about the Edges.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frewen. The Monday after this Accident happen'd, I open'd the Head of the Deceas'd. I saw a small Wound, about the Size of an Orifice made by a Lancet, in bleeding: It was transverse, and rather cross the Temple, than from the upper Part of the Head to the lower.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080038"></xptr> It appear'd to me (at first) only a slight Scratch in the Skin. I laid the Scalp bare, with intent to take off the Cranium as low as I could; and I was obliged (from the bearing of the Cranium, to raise the temporal Muscles on each Side, to make way for my Saw. Then I rais'd the Cranium  and found between the Dura Mater and the Pia Mater, a considerable Quantity of congeal'd Blood. Then I examin'd the Perforation thro' the Cranium: It appear'd on the temporal Bone, just above the Ear, and it exactly answer'd the Wound in the Skin, but I could not, with any Instrument I had, find any Passage thro' the Temporal Muscle, for this Muscle lay immediately under the Skin, between the Wound and the Perforation in the Cranium: But I believe the Situation of this Muscle was somewhat alter'd upon the Death of the Person: The flabby Parts may close up, or contract, so as to conceal and cover the Perforation in the Skull. I apprehend, that from the Blow given on the opposite Side of the Head, he might fall upon something Sharp, which gave him that Wound; and there was a Blackness on the opposite side of the Head.</p>
               <p>Defence. The Deceas'd was a strong young Fellow, about 17 or 18; he struck me, and I gave him a Blow, but not with an Intent to kill or murder him. <rs id="t17361208-81-verdict407" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-verdict407" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-verdict407" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361208-81-punish408" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-punish408" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-81-punish408" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-81-defend592 t17361208-81-punish408"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
