<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350226-17">
               <interp inst="t17350226-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350226-17" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350226-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350226-17" type="date" value="17350226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350226-17-off83-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350226-17-defend132 t17350226-17-off83 t17350226-17-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>17. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350226-17-defend132" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17350226-17-defend132" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-defend132" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-defend132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350226-17-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Tea Pot, a Silver Watch, a Silver Snuff Box, a Silk Waistcoat trim'd with Gold Lace, a Silk Waistcoat trim'd with Silver Frogs, two Coats, two Pair of Breeches, seven Shirts, seven Silver Tea Spoons, and other Goods, 280 Guineas, and 10 l. in Silver, the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350226-17-victim134" type="victimName">
                           Isaac 
                           Hawkins 
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim134" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim134" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350226-17-victim136" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Lewis 
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim136" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350226-17-victim136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in their House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350226-17-cd84" type="crimeDate">January 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350226-17-off83 t17350226-17-cd84"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173502260006"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17350226-17-person137">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17350226-17-person137" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and my Partner 
               <persName id="t17350226-17-person138">
                  Isaac 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17350226-17-person138" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person138" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             live in <placeName id="t17350226-17-crimeloc85">Petty France</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350226-17-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="Petty France"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350226-17-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350226-17-off83 t17350226-17-crimeloc85"></join>. The Prisoner was our <rs id="t17350226-17-deflabel86" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350226-17-defend132 t17350226-17-deflabel86"></join>. The Night before the Robbery I came home between twelve and one, and found her in her Scarlet Cloak and Black Hood. I asked her if she had been out, she at last owned that she had, but said she had been at home above an Hour, but happened to fall asleep. Mr. Hawkins came home after me and was in a great Passion with her, for he said he had been at the Door before and knock'd several times but could not get in; and therefore he told her she should stay in the House no longer. She desired me to pacify him, and let her stay two or three Days, because she was not provided with a Lodging. We at last agreed to this, and the next Night he and I went to sup at Mrs. Pattisons, a Snuff-Shop in Great Queen Street. Mr. Hawkins took the Key of the Street Door with him that the Prisoner might not go out again and leave the House. About eleven o'Clock she came to us, and said, the Silver Tea Pot was lost. God send that nothing else may be lost, says I, and so we went home and found the Street Door lock'd- The Lock goes with a Spring, so that she could make it fast without the Key, by pulling it after her when she came out. We found our Box and Drawers broke open, and mist the Goods and Money. We searched all the House, and look'd up the Chimnies in every Room but could see no body. We went up to the Garret where she lay. Her Door was lock'd and the Key without side. We went in and found her Box shut, and so were the Windows, and nothing out of order. We examin'd her, and told her that she must have a hand in this. She said she knew nothing of it, but that she had been out to drink Tea with Mrs. Needham, a Mantua Maker in the Neighbourhood, and had left the Door upon the Latch. She went down into the Kitchen, and as she was coming up again, she call'd out, Mr. Lewis, for God's sake come here! They have begun to fire the House, and it's God's Mercy we were not all burnt. I went down, and she shewed me a place on the Kitchen Stairs where the Board was burnt. I felt it was hot, upon which I told her it must be her doing since we came home, for if it had been done before, it would have been cold. But all that she said to this was, Do you think I would be such a Beast? Then we locked her up in her own Garret, and in a little time she cryed out For God's sake come up. I went to see what was the matter; she said that she had been robbed too. Her Box was then open and so was the Garret Window. She looked out of the Window with the Candle, and said, the Thieves must be gone that way. She told us she had lost two Gowns and a Holland Shirt. But we afterwards found that she had sent those Gowns to pawn.</p>
               <p>Pawnbroker. A Man pledg'd these Gowns with me in the name of 
               <persName id="t17350226-17-person139">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17350226-17-person139" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person139" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the twenty first of January, and he said they were his Wife's.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Needham. An Hour after the Robbery, the Prisoner brought these Gowns to Mrs. Burt's, at whose House I then was, and said, the House was robb'd, and she had brought the Gowns for fear they should be lost too.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Burt. The Prisoner had been drinking Tea with us three Quarters of an Hour, and then she went home, and in an Hour's time she came again with her Gown, and said, the House had been robb'd - I went to see her when she was in the Gate house, and she bid me pawn the Gowns in the name of John Taylor, and so I sent my Husband with them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lewis. Hearing the Gowns were at Burt's House, I asked her about them, and she said they were pawn'd in the Prisoner's Name.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Burt. So they were at first. But when her Name was advertised I was afraid they might be stopt, and so I fetch'd them out, and sent them again in the Name of John Taylor.</p>
               <p>Needham. The Prisoner told me she had a Sweet-heart whose Name was Wilson; that he was a Widower, and a Surgeon, and had 100 l. a Year at Windsor, but at present was a Prisoner in the Fleet, That he had a great many fine Cloths that had been his Wife's, in pawn. That his Cause was to be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173502260007"></xptr> try'd at the opening of the Parliament, and he wanted two or three Hundred Pounds to get himself clear, and then he would marry her. And she desired me about two Months before the Robbery to write a Love Letter to him, which I did. When I went to see her in the Gate-house, a vile Fellow said to me, Ye Bitch if you offer to be an Evidence against her I'll get somebody to swear your Life away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mrs. Needham came and asked me to drink Tea with her; I told her I could not leave the House, because my Master had got the Key, but I put the Lock back and left the Door upon the Latch, and went with her. She having no Fire, we both went to Mrs. Burts in the Broad Way. I staid three Quarters of an Hour, and then returning, I found the Door ajar. The first thing I mist was the Tea Pot which I had left on the Table, upon which I run up in a fright, and fetch'd my Gowns and Cloak and carried them to Mrs. Burt's, Lord, says I, If Mr. Lewis has not been at home and bid the Tea Kettle to frighten me, the House has been robb'd and I am ruin'd. Then I went to Queen-Street, where my Masters were, and acquainted 'em with it. They went home and I followed them directly, and going down Stairs, I found some Tinder that seemed to be on fire on the Stairs, upon which I called and shewed it them. Then going up to Bed I mist my Cloaths, and being in a great fright, I forgot I had carried them out, and thought I had been robb'd. The Night before there being no Coals to make a Fire, I asked them to send for some, but they said there was no occasion, for they were going out and should not be back till twelve o'Clock. When they were gone there being nothing in the House but a bit of Cheese, I went out to get something for Supper.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lewis. There was three Ribs of a Neck of Mutton, and half a Cheese, besides Bread.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It being cold when I came home I sat up in my Cloak and Hood. Mr. Lewis came in at twelve, and Mr. Hawkins at two, and he was in a great Passion, and said he had been twice at the Door and could not get in.</p>
               <p>Several in whose Families the Prisoner had been a Servant gave her a very good Character, and the Jury <rs id="t17350226-17-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350226-17-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
