<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-6">
               <interp inst="t17370420-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-6" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-6" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-6-off29-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-defend76 t17370420-6-off29 t17370420-6-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-6-defend76" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Mudd 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-6-defend76" type="surname" value="Mudd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-defend76" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-defend76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370420-6-defloc28">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-6-defloc28" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-6-defloc28" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-defend76 t17370420-6-defloc28"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17370420-6-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyTreason"></interp>
               that she not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-6-victim78" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Mudd 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-6-victim78" type="surname" value="Mudd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-6-victim78" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-6-victim78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-off29 t17370420-6-victim78"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   her Husband, feloniously, treasonably, and willfully, did make an Assault, and with a certain Knife, value 1 d. which she held in her Right Hand, him the said Thomas, in and upon the right Part of the Back, near the Back Bone, did strike and stab, giving him one mortal Wound, of the Breadth of one Inch, and the Depth of 3 Inches, of which mortal Wound he instantly dy'd
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370420-6-cd30" type="crimeDate">Feb. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-off29 t17370420-6-cd30"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time indicted on the Coroners Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>She was a third Time indicted, for that she not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. in the Fury of her Mind, on Thomas Mudd her Husband, did make an Assault, and with a certain Knife, value 1 d. held in her Right Hand, the said Thomas, in and upon the Right Part of the Back, near the Back Bone, (he not having any Weapon drawn, nor having first stricken) did strike and stab, giving him with the said Knife, one mortal Wound of the Breadth of one Inch, and of the Depth of 3 Inches, of which he instantly died. Feb. 23.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-6-person79">
                  John 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17370420-6-person79" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person79" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17370420-6-person80">
                  Mary 
                  Standridge 
               <interp inst="t17370420-6-person80" type="surname" value="Standridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person80" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner's Mother, lives in a Cellar in <placeName id="t17370420-6-crimeloc31">Carnaby Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="Carnaby Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-off29 t17370420-6-crimeloc31"></join>. The 23d of Feb. I was in the Cellar with 
               <persName id="t17370420-6-person81">
                  Ann 
                  Mudd 
               <interp inst="t17370420-6-person81" type="surname" value="Mudd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and her Mother; the Deceased was going by the Cellar Door, and Mary Standridge call'd him down, when he came to the 3d Step from the Bottom, Ann Mudd struck him a slap in the Face, and he bid her be quiet: She had a Knife by her Side, which she pull'd out and clapp'd it down on a Cupboard which was in the Cellar: then, as he stood upon the 3d Step, she struck him again in the Face, and he bid her be quiet. Then she went and sat down in a Chair by the Fire Side, and the Deceased came down and sat in her Lap, and wanted to buss her, she would not let him, so they both tumbled together out of the Chair upon the Ground; I thought they had been playing together.</p>
               <p>Q. What happen'd next?</p>
               <p>Owen. The Deceased got up first, and the Prisoner when she was up went to the Cupboard where she had laid the Knife, and hurl'd something at him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what it was?</p>
               <p>Owen. I can't be positive what it was; I thought it look'd like a Saucer: After this, she stood some Time at the Cupboard, and then she went to him as he stood in the middle of the Cellar, and he immediately cry'd out, O Lord! I am stabb'd! I am stabb'd! Mother! Mother! She has done for me. I ran immediately to call Standrige's Husband, but when I came back, the Deceased lay on the Ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Instrument in her Hand after he complain'd of being stabb'd?</p>
               <p>Owen. I saw nothing in her Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What Distance of Time might there be, between your going to call Standridge's Husband, and your Return back?</p>
               <p>Owen. I was not gone above 2 or 3 Minutes, and when I came back, the Deceased lay on the Ground in his Blood.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any Surgeon call'd to his Assistance?</p>
               <p>Owen. I went about to see for a Surgeon, but I could not get one.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live?</p>
               <p>Owen. About 4 or 5 Minutes, he did not speak one Word after he cry'd out, he was stabb'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-6-person82">
                  Eliz 
                  Aggleton 
               <interp inst="t17370420-6-person82" type="surname" value="Aggleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person82" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting on the 3d Step from the Bottom, when the Deceased came down and stood by me; the Prisoner came to him, and hit him a slap in the Face, and gave him another Blow or two, as he stood on the Step: She had a Knife by her Side, which she laid down on the Cupboard, and then she said she would fight him; he would not fight with her, so she sat her self down in a Chair, and he went to her, and wanted to kiss her, but she would not let him; he sat down in her Lap, and she push'd him away; then they both fell from the Chair upon the Ground, and she got up, and took some Thing off the Cupboard, and jobb'd it at him as he stood in the middle of the Cellar, he immediately cry'd out, Mother! Mother! I am stabb'd, I am stabb'd, she has done for me! The very Minute that she jobb'd, he cry'd out, and dropp'd down upon his Backside, and I ran up Stairs to call Standridge's Husband.</p>
               <p>Q. After he made this Complaint, how did he fall?</p>
               <p>Aggleton. He fell upon his Back-side, and I saw the Blood trickle down the Floor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live afterwards?</p>
               <p>Aggleton. I was gone about 3 or 4 Minutes, and when I came back he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he well when he came down Stairs?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200007"></xptr>Aggleton. Yes, very well; so I suppose he dy'd of the Wound.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Lambert. The Prisoner was brought before me, and I ask'd her how she could be so Cruel as to Kill her Husband? Why, say'd she, I stabb'd him in the Back with a Knife, for Funn</p>
               <p>The Constable. I was sent for and found the Man Dead; I carried her before Mr. Justice Lambert, and she told him she did it for Funn. I search'd for the Knife, at that Time, and could not find it; but the next Morning her Father brought it to me, and here it is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-6-person83">
                  Peter 
                  Maccullough 
               <interp inst="t17370420-6-person83" type="surname" value="Maccullough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person83" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon I was sent for by the Coroner to view the Body of the Deceased: I found a large Wound between the 9th and 10th Ribs, on the right Side of the Back-bone; the Knife had penetrated into the Cavity of the Breast; the right Lobe of the Lungs was pierced quite through, and a large Blood-vessel, a large Branch quite cut off, which was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner had nothing to say in her Defence, nor any Witnesses to call. <rs id="t17370420-6-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17370420-6-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-6-punish33" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="burning"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-6-defend76 t17370420-6-punish33"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
