<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341016-16">
               <interp inst="t17341016-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-16" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-16" type="date" value="17341016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341016-16-off83-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-defend144 t17341016-16-off83 t17341016-16-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>16. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-defend144" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Pew 
                  <interp inst="t17341016-16-defend144" type="surname" value="Pew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-defend144" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-defend144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17341016-16-defloc82">St. Martin Orgars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-16-defloc82" type="placeName" value="St. Martin Orgars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-16-defloc82" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-defend144 t17341016-16-defloc82"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17341016-16-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341016-16-victim146" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Ward 
                        <interp inst="t17341016-16-victim146" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-16-victim146" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-16-victim146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-off83 t17341016-16-victim146"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by throwing a Knife at him, and thereby giving him one mortal Wound in the left Side of the Belly, near the Navel, the Length of one Inch, and Depth of three Inches, on the <rs id="t17341016-16-cd84" type="crimeDate">22d of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-off83 t17341016-16-cd84"></join>, about one in the Morning; of which mortal Wound, he languish'd till the Hour of 5 in the Afternoon of the same Day, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person147">
                  Ann 
                  Loft 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person147" type="surname" value="Loft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person147" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday Night was three Weeks, I went to visit the Prisoner, at Mr. Pellit's House in Martin's-Lane, where she lived, and I was to stay with her all Night. I happen'd to hurt my Ancle, and she desir'd the Deceas'd, who was her fellow Servant, to fetch up a little Vinegar, to bathe it with, and to bring the Bread and Butter with him. He refus'd at first, but after a little while he went and did as she desir'd. Then she bid him go out of the Room, because I was going to rub my Leg. No, he said, he would not go till he had some Bread and Butter. She told him he had supt already, and should have no more. Upon which, he fell a damning her, and calling her a great many ill Names, and told her, she was a Bitch and a Whore, like her Sister. She said, Don't provoke me so, for fear I throw something at you. She had a Case-knife in her Hand, and she threw it at him, and it struck in his Side. He went out, into the Entry, and coming in again, holding his Hand to his Side, he said, Betty, you have cut me. She said, Where? He shew'd her, and I said, Lord! you have cut him indeed! and she said, Christ! I have kill'd the Man! - His Caul hung out of the Wound - He went to Bed, and she went down, and bid a Watchman call a Surgeon. The Surgeon came and dress'd the Wound; he said it was very bad, and that he must advise with another Surgeon in the Morning, and so he went away. And the Prisoner made some Sage-Tea for the Deceas'd, and sat up with him all Night - He died about 5 a Clock on Sunday in the Afternoon.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marriot, the Surgeon. Between 1 and 2 on Sunday Morning, I was called to assist the Deceas'd. The Prisoner said he had fell upon a Knife, and he did not contradict it. He had a dangerous Wound in the Abdomen, about 5 Inches from the Navel, and rather below it. The Orifice was so large, that a Portion of the Caul hung out, and the Wound was very Deep. Some of the Intestines and large blood Vessels were cut, and he had lost a vast Quantity of Blood. Between 7 and 8 the same Morning I was call'd again by the Prisoner, I desir'd the Assistance of another Surgeon, who came and approv'd of what I did. I visited the Deceas'd again at 11, at 2 and 4 in the Afternoon, and he died about 5. Here is the Case-knife - 'Tis round at the End, but something sharp tho' not pointed; and the Wound exactly answers it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not tell the Surgeon that the Deceas'd fell on the Knife.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marriot. I asked how the Wound came, and was answer'd that he fell upon the Knife. I will not be positive that you made the answer, but there was nobody present but you and 
               <persName id="t17341016-16-person148">
                  Ann 
                  Loft 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person148" type="surname" value="Loft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person148" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , besides my self and the Prisoner, and it was either you or she that said so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person149">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person149" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person149" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same House, I am Mr. Pellit's Book-keeper; I was a Bed when the accident happen'd, and heard nothing of it till 8 o'Clock on Sunday Morning, and then I heard her say her self that she did it, and that she flung the Knife at him. I ask'd her for what reason? And she answer'd, because he call'd me Whore, and I would do it again if he was to call me so again;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160010"></xptr> and if I had not done it, I should have done it another time. Mr. Kindleside the Apothecary was then present, and ask'd her if the Deceas'd had offered any rudeness to her, and she said, No - They were often quarrelling, and she was commonly the aggressor, for she was very Insolent. About 3 Weeks before this happen'd, he was in the Yard, and did something that displeased her, upon which she went out to him: He gave way; she follow'd him: He ran up Stairs, and she after him; but he shutting his Door upon her, she stood Scolding and calling him names for a quarter of an Hour, and then she came down and said, she would be reveng'd on him, and do him a Mischief one time or another.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I never tell you that he was rude?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person150">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person150" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person150" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No - Indeed I have heard you say that he took you by the Hand and offer'd to kiss you, but nothing farther - Another time she threw an Oystershel at him, which cut him in the Head behind the Ear, and it bled pretty much.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kindleside. Between 8 and 9 on Sunday Morning one came and told me that he was afraid the <rs id="t17341016-16-deflabel85" type="occupation">Maid</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-defend144 t17341016-16-deflabel85"></join> had kill'd the <rs id="t17341016-16-viclabel86" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-victim146 t17341016-16-viclabel86"></join> - I went up stairs with Mr. Williams, and found the Deceas'd in Convulsions. I said to the Prisoner, You have kill'd the Man, and how will you like to be hang'd for it? O says she, I don't fear that, for I did it in a Passion. I desired Mr. Williams to take care that she did not escape while I went for a Constable, and indeed she attempted to get away twice; but he forced her into a Chair - I ask'd the Deceas'd how it happen'd. He own'd he call'd her Whore, but said he offer'd no rudeness, and that she was a violent passionate Creature, and had often threatned to do his business; and he believ'd she had done it now. I ask'd the Prisoner the same question, and she answer'd, he aggravated me and call'd me Whore, and if he was to do so again, I would do the same. I found the Knife (that I suppose it was done with) among the foul Knives. It was bloody like rust, up to the Shoulder - that is, to this rising part of the blade - I could not conceive how such a Case Knife that was not pointed, but round at the End, could be thrown so, as to pierce through a strong Coat and Waistcoat, and a Dowlas Shirt, and so far into the Body: Which made me ask the Deceas'd about that particular. He said it was done so quick, that he knew not whether she threw it or struck him with it in her Hand - The Girl 
               <persName id="t17341016-16-person151">
                  Ann 
                  Loft 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person151" type="surname" value="Loft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person151" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             appear'd to be in a fright, and very much concern'd that she had come thither without the leave of her Friends; and that she was the only Witness present when the Mischief was done. Lord! says she, what shall I say? - Say? Replied the Prisoner, What would you say, but that I was in a Passion, and threw the Knife as him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did Mr. Williams here me say so?</p>
               <p>Mr. Williams. I don't remember it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What did I say?</p>
               <p>Mr. Williams. I heard her say she did it because he call'd her Whore. But I was so confused that I could not take notice of every word that past.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own that I threw the Knife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person152">
                  John 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person152" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Marriot and Mr. Kindleside came to my House between 9 and 10 in the Morning, and desired me to go into St. Martin's-lane to take up a Woman that had stabb'd a Man. When I came there, I ask'd the Deceas'd how it happen'd. He said there were very provoking words on both sides. I ask'd him if she threw the Knife or stabb'd him with it. He said he could not tell which. I enquired if he thought there was any premeditated Malice. He answer'd that they had Quarrell'd; and she had threaten'd to do his Business - We found the Knife, and it was 5 Inches from the point Red, and as it were rusty with the Blood.</p>
               <p>Court. Did it look as if it had gone so deep, or that the Blood had only run down so far towards the Handle</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person153">
                  John 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person153" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were streaks of Blood upon it, as if it had so far been cover'd with Blood; and afterwards drawn through a Woollen Cloth, which might be done by pulling it back through his Waistcoat and Coat.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160011"></xptr>Court. Was any part of the Blade cover'd with Blood, or was it all streak'd in that manner?</p>
               <p>Guy. There was no one part intirely Bloody, but it was all streaky except within, about an Inch of the Handle, and there it was not Bloody at all. I took a wet Cloth and rubb'd off some of the Red streaks next to the pin, and then that part appear'd bright, by which I found that though the Red look'd like rust, yet it was not rust but Blood - When the Prisoner heard that the Deceas'd was Dead, she fell into violent Fits, which held her off and on for 5 or 6 Hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person154">
                  Mary 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person154" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person154" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to my House between 7 and 8 on Sunday Morning, I was then coming downStairs; she ask'd where she should find a Surgeon; my Husband ask'd her what was the matter and why she did not call her Master's Surgeon; she said their Man had cut himself, and would bleed to Death. I directed her to Mr. Lewis in Abchurch-lane; she went away, and I soon after follow'd her to her Master's House, and finding her very much confused, I said, I hope you did not do this, she answer'd; I did it sure enough, but he says he won't tell: And I shall have the Surgeon to pay. I went up Stairs and found the Deceas'd half in Bed. I ask'd him how he did, he said, never worse. Somebody knock'd at the Door. A Gentleman (I suppose it was the Surgeon) came up in his Cap, and ask'd the Deceas'd why he did not keep in Bed: By which I guest that the Gentleman had been there before. Then she went for her Master's Surgeon, and I call'd up Mr. Williams. I ask'd the Deceas'd my self how the Misfortune came, but he did not tell me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person155">
                  Samuel 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person155" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person155" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceas'd was my Relation. About 11 in the Morning, as I was going with my Master to Church, a Messenger came and told me that my Kins-man was dying. I was surpriz'd at it, because I had seen him the day before, and he was then very well. As soon as my Master was gone into Church, I went to see my Kinsman, and found the Surgeons in the Room. How in the name of God, says I, did you come by this Misfortune? Don't ask me questions, says he; some words happen'd between us. But tell me, says I, was you doing any thing to her? Did you offer to catch her by the Belly. No, says he. Why then how was it done? says I. Uncle, says he again, I can't speak.</p>
               <p>Court, to Ann Loft. How far was the Prisoner from the Deceas'd when he threw the Knife?</p>
               <p>Ann Loft. About 3 Yards - The Prisoner was sitting on one side of the Table, and I on the other, and the Deceas'd was behind me.</p>
               <p>Court. Did she rise from the Table with the Knife in her Hand?</p>
               <p>Ann Lost. No. She did not rise up at all, for she was cutting Bread and Butter, and so was I too.</p>
               <p>Court. Did not she strike him with the Knife in her Hand?</p>
               <p>Ann Lost. No - She threw it at him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I threw it out of my Hand, but did not know which way it went. I had no design to do the Deceas'd a Mischief, for I ow'd him no ill-will.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person156">
                  John 
                  Braham 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person156" type="surname" value="Braham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She was often a Quarrelling - One time as I came into the Kitchen with some Meat from my Master's Table, she pitch'd a Knife after me.</p>
               <p>Then the Prisoner call'd Witnesses to her Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person157">
                  Margaret 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person157" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person157" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her from a Child, and never knew her in a Passion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person158">
                  Thomas 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person158" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person158" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She was my Servant a Year, and a good Servant she was, and I never did see her in a Passion, and my Wife will say the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person159">
                  Deborah 
                  Lockley 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person159" type="surname" value="Lockley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person159" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her several Years, she was always a very sober Person; and I never heard any thing of her, tending to Passion. She lived with a Relation of mine, who has often told me, that she (the Prisoner) exprest a great deal of Tenderness and good Nature.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person160">
                  Mary 
                  Bray 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person160" type="surname" value="Bray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person160" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 23 Years, and never heard that she was inclin'd to Passion, but was a sober quiet young Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person161">
                  Mary 
                  Kingston 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person161" type="surname" value="Kingston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person161" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A Virtuous modest Girl,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160012"></xptr> and not given to drinking or ill Language.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person162">
                  Thomas 
                  Durant 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person162" type="surname" value="Durant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person162" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Of a very orderly Behaviour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person163">
                  Hester 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person163" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person163" type="given" value="Hester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Just, honest, and dutiful to her Parents.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person164">
                  Deborah 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person164" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person164" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She kept her Mother and 2 Sisters from starving.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-16-person165">
                  Sarah 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17341016-16-person165" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person165" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And impoverish'd herself by her kindness to her Friends - I have known her 12 Years, she behav'd well; and was of so good a Temper, that I never saw her in a Passion.</p>
               <p>Ann Loft, again. I have been acquainted with her 2 Years. She liv'd in the House where I liv'd; and she was very quiet and good Natur'd, and not given to Passion.</p>
               <p>Court. If one Person kills another without a just provocation, it is Murder: And words alone are not a just provocation.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17341016-16-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment. <rs id="t17341016-16-punish88" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-16-punish88" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-16-defend144 t17341016-16-punish88"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
