<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390718-5">
               <interp inst="t17390718-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-5" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-5" type="date" value="17390718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-5-off21-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-defend43 t17390718-5-off21 t17390718-5-verdict23"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-5-off21-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-person44 t17390718-5-off21 t17390718-5-verdict23"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-5-off21-c38" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-defend45 t17390718-5-off21 t17390718-5-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>390, 391. 
               <persName id="t17390718-5-defend43" type="defendantName">
                  
                     <persName id="t17390718-5-person44" type="defendantName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17390718-5-defend45" type="defendantName">
                              Thomas 
                              Eastmead 
                           <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend45" type="surname" value="Eastmead"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend45" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17390718-5-person44" type="surname" value="Eastmead"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-5-person44" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-5-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and Margaret
                   his 
                  <rs id="t17390718-5-deflabel19" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-defend43 t17390718-5-deflabel19"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend43" type="surname" value="Eastmead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend43" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-defend43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17390718-5-defloc20">St. Ann's, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-5-defloc20" type="placeName" value="St. Ann's, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-5-defloc20" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-defend43 t17390718-5-defloc20"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-person44 t17390718-5-defloc20"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-defend45 t17390718-5-defloc20"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17390718-5-off21" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-off21" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-off21" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Pair of Stays, value 5 s. a Green Silk Quilted Petticoat, value 5 s. and a Hoop-Petticoat, value 2 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-victim47" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Connor 
                  <interp inst="t17390718-5-victim47" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-victim47" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-victim47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-off21 t17390718-5-victim47"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , Spinster, <rs id="t17390718-5-cd22" type="crimeDate">July 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-5-off21 t17390718-5-cd22"></join>.</p>
               <p>Connor. I came to Eastmead's House the 1st or 2d of July, about Eleven at Night, with a Gentleman, (one Mr. Fisher) and we staid there all Night, and breakfasted and dined there, the next Day. After Dinner we had a Coach, and Mr. Fisher and Mrs. Eastmead and I, went to my Mother's at Hyde Park, and from thence went round to Brumpton, and Jenny's Whim. I was then dressed in White; and when we came into Piccadilly, I said I would go home, and change my Gown, to keep it clean. So I got out of the Coach, and Mr. Fisher called after me, and bid me come to Eastmond's Bagnio again; he lives in Leicester-Fields. I promised him I would, and when I had changed my Cloaths at my Washerwoman's, I went again to the Bagnio, and asked for Mr. Fisher. Mr. Eastmead told me, he was not there<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180003"></xptr> - and if he was, I should not see him: I said, I was sure he was there, and called out, - Mr. Fisher ! Upon this Mr. Eastmead knocked me down in the Entry, and both he, and his Wife, dragged me into their Back-Parlour, or Bed-chamber, and they beat me in a miserable Manner: When I cry'd out, Mrs Eastmead stopped my Mouth with her Hand, and then they stripp'd my Cloaths off, and would have taken off my Shift, if People had not come into the House, - I had much ado to keep it on. They swore at me, and told me 'twas no Sin to kill me, if they had a Knife. They took from me a Pair of Stays, a Green Silk Quilted Coat, and a Hoop-Petticoat, and I have never heard of my Cloaths since. After he had used me ill, I cry'd out, Murder! Upon which he took me up in his Arms, and flung me out of the House, in such a Manner, that my Face fell upon the Flag-Stones, and I bled a great deal. When I got out of the Coach in Piccadilly, in order to change my Gown, I left Mr. Fisher and Mrs. Eastmead in the Coach, and he (Fisher) bid me come to him again, and not stay long. - 'Tis not the first unhappy Girl they have used so. Mrs. Eastmead owned before Mr. Deveil, That she had my Cloaths; and People came to me to offer me Money not to appear against them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you say you would go up Stairs and see for Mr. Fisher?</p>
               <p>Connor. On my Oath I did not: I only called - Mr. Fisher! - at the Bottom of the Stairs, because if he had been in the Parlour, I wanted to have spoken with him: He had told me he wanted to speak with me. I have known Eastmead a great while, but I have not frequented the House much.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Whose Stays were they?</p>
               <p>Connor. I bought them of Mrs. Eastmead, and paid her for them. I paid her a Guinea and four Shillings for them: One Mrs. Richards saw me pay her for them, about eight Months ago. I paid her a Guinea all at once, and the four Shillings afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person48">
                  Mary 
                  Hopson 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person48" type="surname" value="Hopson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person48" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw her come home that Evening, in a White Gown; she called for her Brown Gown, and put it on. 'Twas about a Fortnight ago Yesterday. She came Home again in about half an Hour, very bloody; her Gown was torn down; her Stays, and her Hoop and Quilted Coat were gone. Her Apron, Handkerchief, and Cap, were very bloody; and she told me, Mr. Eastmead and his Wife had almost murdered her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person49">
                  Margaret 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person49" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person49" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person49" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came home in the Condition Mrs. Hopson has mentioned, and told me she had been almost murdered by Eastmead; That she asked for Mr. Fisher, and Mr. Eastmead told her, he was not there, and he was glad he had got her alone. She returned ( in half an Hour after she had changed her Gown without her Stays; her Gown was rent or cut down with a Knife, her Quilted Coat, and her Hoop was gone; her Dressed-Cap was all over Gore-blood, and her Apron, - you might have rung the Blood out of it. She told us Mrs Eastmead got her into the Parlour, and stopped her Mouth with her Hand, while her Husband robbed her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Eastmead. I desire she may be asked, in what Manner she was robbed.</p>
               <p>Connor. I have told you already, - and have not told one Word of a Lie. They beat me in a violent Manner: I bled at the Nose and Mouth; my Face and Hands were as if they had been dipped in Blood.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eastmead. She came to my House with Mr. Fisher the 2d of July; they lay there all Night, and next Day, they breakfasted and dined together: They had a Leg of Lamb and Green Peas for Dinner, and drank plentifully of Wine and Shrub. In the Afternoon my Wife and they went out in a Coach to Brumpton. He returned to my House, without the Girl, and told me, if Moll Connor should come to enquire for him, I must not own he was there, for she had done him a great Injury. In a little Time she came, and called - 
               <persName id="t17390718-5-person50">
                  Jack 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person50" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person50" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - you Scrub! and she pulled off her Cloaths herself, and would go up Stairs, whether we wou'd or no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person51">
                  Frances 
                  Prince 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person51" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person51" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember Mary Connor's coming to Eastmead's about a Week, - about three Weeks ago. She went out with Mr. Fisher, about a Five o'Clock in the Afternoon. Fisher came back about Eleven o'Clock, and ordered that the Gentlewoman that had been with him the Night before, should not be admitted to him, In a Quarter of an Hour after this, Connor came in, and insisted on seeing the Gentleman, whereof, she was deny'd; upon which she went into the Parlour and pulled off her Cloaths, - her Stays, her Quilted Coat, and her Hoop, and said she would go up Stairs to him. I was at this Time in the Entry, and stood at the Parlour Door and saw her undress herself. Fisher lay up one Pair of Stairs, and she was going up to him, but my Mistress, (Eastmead) pulled her down again, and she struck my Mistress in the Face, and made a great Disturbance at the Door, and said she would be revenged of them, and would send them to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180004"></xptr> Newgate. I saw her pull off her Cloaths in the Parlour, to go to Bed to the Gentleman up Stairs: My Master and Mistress were in the Room at the same Time. I stood at the Parlour Door. There was another young Woman ( 
               <persName id="t17390718-5-person52">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person52" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person52" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) who waited upon Mr. Fisher; she was above Stairs with him, and gave Orders that Connor should not be admitted to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Was there any Blows given to Connor?</p>
               <p>Prince. I saw none, nor any Blood, nor any thing of her Gown being torn, but I saw her strike my Mistress in the Face.</p>
               <p>Jury. Is there a Bed in this Parlour?</p>
               <p>Prince. Yes; a standing Bed: A high Bed, with a Tester.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person53">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person53" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person53" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mary Connor, and remember her coming to Eastmead's: She lay one Night there with Mr. Fisher, and went out with him next Morning in a Coach; as near as I can remember they went out about Seven o'Clock in the Morning. I put them into the Coach together at Seven o'Clock in the Morning. +</p>
               <p>+ At the Desire of the Jury the Witnesses for the Prisoners were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else go with them in the Coach?</p>
               <p>Davis. I can't remember whether any Body went with them, or not. Mr. Fisher returned by himself in a Chair, about Eleven at Night; I saw no more of them, from Seven in the Morning, 'till Eleven at Night. They neither break-fasted, nor dined at our House, - neither Mr. Fisher nor Connor. When he came in at Eleven, he ordered that she (Connor) should not go up Stairs to him, but when she returned, she said, she would go up; so I informed her, the Gentleman desired not to see her, and called my Mistress (Eastmead) to her, who told her she must not go up to Mr. Fisher. She went into the Back-Parlour, and undressed herself; my Master was at the same time below in the Kitchen; my Mistress was in the Parlour with Connor, and I was above Stairs - but I saw her fling her Cloaths off, - for I was coming down Stairs, and telling her, she must not go up. - There was no one but my Mistress in the Room, for my Master was below Stairs, and 
               <persName id="t17390718-5-person54">
                  Frances 
                  Prince 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person54" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person54" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person54" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was gone to Bed when this happened. My Mistress desired her to take her Cloaths, but she said she would not, - for she would send her and my Master to Newgate, and would swear a * Robbery against them; so she went away and left her Cloaths in the Parlour.</p>
               <p>* Though her Evidence amounted to a Robbery, the Indictment was laid only for Stealing, which being a single Felony, a Married Woman could not be found Guilty of such a Fact committed in Company of her Husband; the Law of England presuming she is so much in his Power as to act by his Compulsion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person55">
                  Humphry 
                  Ingram 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person55" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person55" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know Connor, but I had some Acquaintance with one of Eastmead's Maids, and was below in the Kitchen, on the 2d of July, when this Disturbance happened above Stairs, and went half Way up, and heard Mrs. Eastmead say to Connor, you need not undress your self, for here you shall not lie To night. Connor said, she would go up Stairs, and Words arose, and some Blows passed. After this, Connor said, if you won't let me lie here, turn me out. Aye, says Eastmead, go out, - but take your Cloaths with you; No, says Connor, I will not, for I will send you both to Newgate. This was between Eleven and Twelve at Night.</p>
               <p>Jury. How came you to be there that Night?</p>
               <p>Ingram. I went to see their Maid Fanny, She and I were below in the Kitchen, and we were coming up Stairs; for I was going away, if this Disturbance had not happen'd. As the Dispute rose higher, I proceeded higher, and stood at the Top of the Stairs, but went no farther. Frances (Prince) went into the Parlour; I saw her go in at the Door: There are two Parlours, - I can't tell which of them she went into, I think it was into the back Parlour, to assist her Mistress; both the Doors were open, but I could not see far enough to have a View of the Place where the Squabble was. I saw no Blood, - not a Drop; nor did I see Mr. Eastmead all that Night: I heard a Man's Tongue, but I can't take upon me to say it was his.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person56">
                  Robert 
                  Hinder 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person56" type="surname" value="Hinder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person56" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Eastmeads five or six Years, and know nothing but that they are honest People: They keep a handsome House - a Bagnio; I served them with Goods, and they paid me. I don't know that they keep a Bawdy-house.</p>
               <p>Jury. What Goods did you serve them with?</p>
               <p>Hinder. Upholsterers Goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person57">
                  John 
                  Debell 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person57" type="surname" value="Debell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Bricklayer, and have trusted them Scores of Pounds; my Wife keeps a Cheesemonger's Shop: I have dealt with them in both Branches, and they have paid me honestly.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180005"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person58">
                  John 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person58" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners are very honest People, for ought I know. On Monday the 2d of July, I was making some Alterations in their Parlour, and I saw the Prosecutrix there in a Plaid Night-gown, a single Petticoat, and her Smock on; she was shelling Peas with a Gentleman in the Kitchen: I believe she is a common Woman, for I heard her once tell Eastmead, that she was just come out of the Marshalsea, but she need not be afraid, for she would pay her very handsomely. They keep Fanny to sweat and bathe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person59">
                  Antonio 
                  Lucera 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person59" type="surname" value="Lucera"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person59" type="given" value="Antonio"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoners; her I have known 10 Years; she lived with the French and Spanish Ambassadors, and had a good Character: I deal with them in Wine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person60">
                  Isaac 
                  Itorno 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person60" type="surname" value="Itorno"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person60" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her seven Years, him five Years; but I come to speak about Connor. She is a Woman of the Town: She came to me, and told me, - by G-d, she would be revenged on the Prisoners, for not letting her go up to the Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Jury. Pray what Business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Itorno. I am a Marshal's Court Officer; and if a Prisoner in my Custody calls for a Pot of Beer, I let him have it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person61">
                  Richard 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person61" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person61" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Connor hath the Character of a vile notorious Woman; she makes a Property of all the People she gets. The Day after the Quarrel, she call'd on me, and told me she was going to Mr. Deveil for a Warrant for the Prisoners, on Account of a Robbery. A Robbery! says I, Lord, Molly! how can you be so vile, to swear a Robbery against the People that find you Victuals and Drink! I will do it, says she, if I send my Soul to the Devil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person62">
                  Ann 
                  Pollard 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person62" type="surname" value="Pollard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person62" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Connor is a Woman of the Town: I have known her six Years. On the Day this thing was done I was at Eastmead's, and saw Connor come into the House, about Twelve at Noon, in Mens Cloaths, and at Four in the Afternoon she went out again in the same Dress. I remember it, it was the 2d of July.</p>
               <p>Jury. This contradicts all the other Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person63">
                  Mary 
                  Peacock 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person63" type="surname" value="Peacock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person63" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person63" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Connor; but I never knew her to be perjur'd. All that I know of her it, that about a Twelvemonth ago, she came to my House, and lay all Night there with a Man who is my Lodger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person64">
                  Henry 
                  Gotobed 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person64" type="surname" value="Gotobed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person64" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Connor, but I have never seen her since the Fact, nor do I know any thing of the Matter.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you come here for?</p>
               <p>Gotobed. I don't know. I know they keep a Bagnio.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person65">
                  Richard 
                  Temple 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person65" type="surname" value="Temple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person65" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the arresting of Connor, and heard her say she would be reveng'd of the Eastmeads. I know nothing of her Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-5-person66">
                  Frances 
                  Prince 
               <interp inst="t17390718-5-person66" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person66" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are the Things which the Lady (Connor) pull'd off in our House; there are no Cuts in them, nor any Blood upon them.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17390718-5-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-5-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoners; but desired the Court would be pleased to take into their Consideration the Necessity there was of suppressing this House.</p>
            </div1>
