<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17371012-3">
               <interp inst="t17371012-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-3" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17371012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-3" type="date" value="17371012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371012-3-off15-c42" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend46 t17371012-3-off15 t17371012-3-verdict19"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371012-3-off15-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend48 t17371012-3-off15 t17371012-3-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>4, 5 
               
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-defend46" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Car 
                  <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend46" type="surname" value="Car"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend46" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of London, <rs id="t17371012-3-deflabel14" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend46 t17371012-3-deflabel14"></join> and 
               
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-defend48" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Adams 
                  <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend48" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend48" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-defend48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of London, Spinster, were indicted for <rs id="t17371012-3-off15" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-off15" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-off15" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17371012-3-victim50" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Quarrington 
                        <interp inst="t17371012-3-victim50" type="surname" value="Quarrington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-3-victim50" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-3-victim50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-off15 t17371012-3-victim50"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17371012-3-person51">
                        Mary 
                        Prevost 
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person51" type="surname" value="Prevost"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-3-person51" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-3-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Widow, in the Parish of St. Dunstan's in the West, putting him in corporal Fear and Danger of his Life, and taking from him a gold Ring, set with five Diamonds, val. 6 l. 93 Guineas, and 8 s. in Silver
            </rs>, <rs id="t17371012-3-cd16" type="crimeDate">Sept. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-off15 t17371012-3-cd16"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person52">
                  William 
                  Quarrington 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person52" type="surname" value="Quarrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             On the 9th of September, I went to the Bank, and received 100 l. and after calling at several Places, I went to Mr. Daxon, who lives in Forestreet, by Cripplegate; with him I went to the Three Mariners, in the same Street, and staid there 'till about 5 or 6 in the Evening. Then I went into Southwark, to speak to a Friend; he was not at Home, so I waited 'till about 9 for his coming in. Then I came over the Bridge, in Order to go Home, and as I pass'd up Fleet Street, by Temple bar, I met a common Woman in the Street (not the Woman at the Bar) and she asked me to give her a Glass of Wine. I consented, and we went to the <placeName id="t17371012-3-crimeloc17">Angel and Crown, at the Corner of Sheer-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-3-crimeloc17" type="placeName" value="Angel and Crown, at the Corner of Sheer-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-3-crimeloc17" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-off15 t17371012-3-crimeloc17"></join>, close by Temple-bar. The Drawer shew'd us into a Room, up one Pair of Stairs, and a Bottle of Red Port being brought us he departed. We sat together about half an Hour, and then the Drawer came into the Room, and told me, he had peeped thro' the Key-hole, and that the Woman was picking my Pocket. I found there had been a Pique, or a Quarrel between the Woman and him; but upon his telling me, he knew her to be a Pick-pocket, I was a little uneasy. He insisted upon it, that he had seen her pick my Pocket, tho' I was very sure she had not. Then he desired to know, if I had any Money about me, and wish'd I would tell it over, to see if I had lost any. At his Request, I was so foolish and ignorant, as to tell 93 Guineas, and about 20 Shillings over, before the Drawer and the Woman; and I told them, I had lost nothing. Notwithstanding this, Words arose between the Drawer and the Woman, and he turn'd her down Stairs. She was no sooner gone, but the Drawer return'd into the Room, with Mrs. Prevost, and the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person53">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person53" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person53" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and Mrs. Adams desired me to stay in the House, 'till the Woman was quite gone; and told me, it was a happy Thing, that I had lost none of my Money; for the Woman that came in with me, was a common Street-walker, and a Strumpet of the Town. Three or four Minutes after this, I went down Stairs, intending to go Home; but as I was going away, the Prisoner Car, stood at the Kitchen-door, and beckon'd to me. I went to him, and he told me - Sir, you was with a common Strumpet and Pick-pocket; and he desired to know, if I had lost any Money; telling me, if I had - the Gentlewoman of the House would come into Scandal, and would be blam'd. He appearing like a Gentleman, with a silver-lac'd Waistcoat, I thought he would use me like a Gentleman; so at his Request I went into the Kitchen. There were He (Mr. Car) the Prisoner Adams, Mrs. Prevost, the two Drawers, and another Man and a Woman, all in the Kitchen - three Women and four Men in all, besides myself. They desired me to do it - and I did tell out the Money which I had told over before, and inform'd them, I had lost nothing. Mr. Car said, he was very glad I had not, and call'd for a Bottle of Wine to treat me -</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No: I never saw him before, in my Life - but it was at his Request, that I told over my Money in the Kitchen, and he insisted upon treating me, telling me, it should not be at my Expence. I (thinking myself very safe) sat down, and drank Part of his Bottle of Wine, and when that Bottle was out, I called for another, in Answer to Mr. Car's Bottle. When this Bottle was drank out, we had another, and he and I were to club our Shillings a-piece for it 'Twas at Mr. Car's Request, I staid all this while: For he told me, it would be dangerous for me to go out, before the Woman was quite gone - she might (he said) set some-body upon me, to rob me, or knock me down, or carry me away to another House; therefore he desired me to stay: Tho' the Woman was out of the House, yet (he said) she might stand about the Door, to watch for my coming out. It was between one and two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120005"></xptr> o'Clock, when the third Bottle was out: Then he told me, he thought it too late for me to go Home, and that I might stay there all Night, assuring me, I should be very safe. On his persuading me, and telling me, how dangerous it would be for me, with a Charge of Money about me, to go out at that Time o'Night, I agreed to stay, and Mr. Car told me, he would himself see me up Stairs, and safe in Bed; the rest of the Company said, they would all see me safe in Bed; so all those who were in the Kitchen, went up Stairs with me. There were the two Drawers, Mr. Car, Mrs. Prevost, Mrs. Adams the Prisoner, another Man and Woman - they all went up with me. I paid my Reckoning before I went up, and had the rest of the Money in my Pocket. But I had not been two Minutes in the Room, before Mr. Car seiz'd me by the Throat, with his Left-hand, and having a Case-knife in his Right-hand, he swore he would cut my Throat if I made a Noise. Seven People were then present, and they threw me down on the Floor; some of them held my Legs, and some my Arms. Mr. Car, with the Assistance of the two Drawers, threw me down, and when I lay on the Floor, he swore several Oaths, that if I made the least Resistance or Noise, he would cut my Throat from Ear to Ear. Then he took my Money out of my Pocket, and my Ring off my Finger; the Money he put into my Hat, which lay on the Floor; he took from me, 93 Guineas, and about 8 or 10 Shillings in Silver. Then they gave me Liberty to sit down in a Chair, and I saw Car distribute my Money to the People in the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mrs. Prevost, and Mrs. Adams (the Prisoner) present?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes: I was resolved to cry out, when they threw me down, but Mrs. Adams (the Prisoner) stopped my Mouth with an Handkerchief. Mrs. Prevost held one of my Legs, while Car took the Money out of my Pocket. After this, they said, I seem'd to be very much surpriz'd; so Mr. Car order'd the Drawer to go down for a Couple of Bottles of Wine. When the Wine came up, they fill'd a Glass, which I believe was a full Pint-glass, and with bitter Oaths and Imprecations, they forced me to drink it off. Then they fill'd another, and made me drink that. And a third was fill'd, which I drank half off, and then could not get down any more. Two Glasses and a half they forced me to drink - (the two first of which were filled up to the Brim) then I told them, if they kill'd me, I could not drink any more, upon which they undress'd me, and forced me into Bed, and left me, swearing, that if I made the least Noise, they would come and cut my Throat, to prevent my telling Tales. These (as near as I can remember) are the very Words they made use of.</p>
               <p>I lay very uneasy 'till about 9 or 10 the next Morning, fearing, if I stirr'd, my Life would be taken away; and then hearing People go backward and forward in the Streets, I ventur'd to dress myself; then I crept down Stairs, and stole out of the House unobserv'd. I immediately went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person54">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person54" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person54" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for a Warrant for these People, but he not being in Town, I return'd as fast as I could, to the Constable of the Parish, and thought to have taken them up without a Warrant; but he did not Care to do that. Then remembering I had heard Car's Name mention'd in the Company, I enquired for one Car an <rs id="t17371012-3-deflabel18" type="occupation">Attorney</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend46 t17371012-3-deflabel18"></join>, and a Porter at the Middle-temple, told me, there was one Car liv'd in Elm court: I found out his Chambers, and asked the young Fellow, that goes for his Clerk, if Mr. Car was within? He said, No. I asked him when he would be at Home? He could not inform me. I enquir'd if he was out of Town? He could not tell whether he was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see the Prisoner Car before?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; nor Mrs. Adams neither; but I am sure they are the very Persons that did what I have related.</p>
               <p>One Thing (my Lord) I have forgot - Mr. Bird, Sir William's Clerk, advised me to go to Mr. Jones, thinking he might assist me in getting my Money again; and I went to his House, but he was not at Home. I have no more to say, but that I have sworn the Truth, and nothing but the Truth.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the Prisoners apprehended?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Mr. Car was apprehended first, at his Chambers, and he gave Directions where we might find Adams and Prevost, but Prevost was fled.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the Directions right, which he gave you?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I did not go with the Constable to find them. He and Mr. Jones's Man, upon Car's Information, found out, and took Adams.</p>
               <p>Councel. How long was you in Company with the Woman you first brought into the House?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. About half an Hour.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go immediately to this House, after you pick'd her up?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120006"></xptr>Quarrington Some Words were spoken, to before, and then I went with her to this Tavern, and was there with her only, about half an Hour.</p>
               <p>Councel You had been at the Alehouse before, and I suppose, had drank a good many Pots of Beer; how much might you have drank before you came to the Angel?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. About three Pints of Beer, to my own Share, I believe.</p>
               <p>Counc. But then you say, you had a Bottle of Wine with the first Woman?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes; but I did not drink one Glass of it. In such Houses, 'tis usual to call for something. I drank none of the Wine; and as for the Woman, I know nothing of her, any farther than by Conversation.</p>
               <p>Counc. But you drank liberally below Stairs?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; I did not - Car treated me with a Bottle -</p>
               <p>Councel. And you genteely call'd for another, and then there was a third, and a fourth?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No, Sir: There was no more than the third, and that we join'd for.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I can't say I was sober, nor was I so far in Liquor, but I knew every Thing that pass'd</p>
               <p>Counc. Then you was half Seas over?</p>
               <p>Quarrington Yes: as you call it.</p>
               <p>Counc. So after you had drank this Wine, they all of them waited upon you to Bed?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. They did so, Sir: And when they had got me up Stairs, they robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Counc. And will you stand to that, Sir?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes. As I am on my Oath before the Great GOD, I say nothing that is untrue. I have no Interest in prosecuting the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Counc. I think you say, you crept unobserv'd out of the House, the next Morning?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes; I saw Prevost and Adams in the Kitchen, but I ran out of Doors.</p>
               <p>Counc. And did you alarm the Neighbours when you got out?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I went to Sir William Billers as fast as I could, but I did not speak to the Neighbours. I did not well know which Way to proceed.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not Mrs. Prevost and Mrs. Adams offer to stop you, when you ran out?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No, I crept down Stairs, and ran out directly to Sir William Billers: When I return'd, they were gone, and the Doors were shut up. The House was shut up about half an Hour after I got out.</p>
               <p>Counc. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I will not swear exactly to the Time; but 'twas shut up in the Time of my going to, and returning from Sir William's, and Mr. Jones's.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Account did you give to Mrs. Jones?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I was not very Particular in my Account to her, nor did I mention Mr. Car's Name to her. What signified my mentioning the Particulars to a Woman?</p>
               <p>Jury. We desire his Lordship would please to ask the Questions that are proper, and that the Man may not be interrupted.</p>
               <p>Car. When the Woman you picked-up was turned down Stairs, and you follow'd, you say I beckon'd to you. Pray, in what Position was I when you saw me?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. He was standing at the Kitchen-door, and he beckoned me in.</p>
               <p>Car. Who did you see at my Chambers beside my Clerk?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I saw a Woman washing a Room, but I don't know who she was.</p>
               <p>Car. What Name did you go by, that Night?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I never mention'd what my Name was.</p>
               <p>Car. What did you declare to my Clerk, and to the Woman you saw in my Chambers?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I said I had been robb'd, and then I went down Stairs, and said nothing farther. I did not mention who had robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Car. What Declaration did you make to the Constable that you went to first?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I told him what Money I had been robb'd of; I mention'd my Ring, and I desired him to go to the House and take up the People. I told him likewise, that I had found out an Attorney of the Temple, who was concern'd.</p>
               <p>Car. What Time did you go to that Constable?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. The next Day, about 12 at Noon! and I told him I had found where you might be taken; but as the Constable did not approve of taking you without a Warrant, I did not then tell him the whole of the Story.</p>
               <p>Car. What did my Man say when you came to take me?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I asked him if you was within, he did not speak in a Minute or two, seeing the Constable; but you happened to open a Door in another Room, I perceived you, and said, there's the Man that robb'd me; you was frighted, as your Conscience pleaded guilty, - you knew it to be too true.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120007"></xptr>Car. Did not you go into the Kitchen when you came down in the Morning?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; I saw Prevost and Adams in the Kitchen, but I did not speak to them.</p>
               <p>Car. And did you see nobody but Prevost and Adams in the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes; another Woman that was there the Night before, and she was crying out, - or was very sorrowful about something.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Adams. Did not you come into the Kitchen for your Hat and Cane?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; nor did I speak to you or any one else.</p>
               <p>Car. Why did not you call out of the Windows?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I was frighted with your Threats and the Drawer's, and I thought if I stirr'd, I should have my Throat cut. - I durst not stir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sleep any Part of the Night?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I believe I slept about Half an Hour.</p>
               <p>Car. Did you eat nothing in the Kitchen that Night?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes, some cold Lamb, and I cut my Finger I remember; and I remember that you call'd Mrs. Adams your Dear Betsy, and she call'd you her Dear Tommy.</p>
               <p>Adams. Did not the Woman you brought in, rob you of 15 Guineas and a Half?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; she robbed me of nothing.</p>
               <p>Adams. Did not you offer to spend a Guinea in the House, and to give the Drawers Money for taking care of you?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. I did give the Drawer a Shilling that was so officious as to tell me the Woman was picking my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Adams. Was not you so drunk that the Drawer carried you up Stairs upon his Back?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. No; I walked up myself; nobody assisted me.</p>
               <p>Adams. It signifies nothing to ask him any more Questions, - he denies them all.</p>
               <p>Car. Why did not you indict Mrs. Prevost and the Drawers?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Because I was told it signified nothing to indict them, unless they had been in Custody.</p>
               <p>Car. Did you give the same Account in your Information, that you have done now?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. The Truth will never err: I think I gave the same Account in that, as I have done now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person55">
                  William 
                  Stamper 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person55" type="surname" value="Stamper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person55" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I settled an Affair with the Prosecutor a Night, or a Night or two, before he was robb'd, and he invited me to come and dine with him the next Sunday; I went, and he told me he had met with a great Misfortune, and confess'd he had pick'd up a Woman, and had carried her to the Angel. He told me that she was soon turned out of the House, but that he had been robb'd by several People, mentioning no Names. I told That Angel was the worst Angel within the Walls of the City, except the Angel in Bishopsgate street, - they're both Angels. He informed me that he had lost 93 Guineas and a Diamond Ring worth 8 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was robb'd by the first Woman?</p>
               <p>Stamper. No; he said she was turned out of the House, because she was not one of Mother Prevost's Does. He gave me no Account then of the Robbery, but afterwards he digested every Thing into an Affidavit before Sir William Billers. On the Monday after the Robbery, he came and told me that one Car, of the Temple, was one of the Persons that had robbed him. I said, I remembered a Person of that Name, whom I knew some Years ago; and when Car was brought to Alderman Billers's Office, my Curiosity led me to go to see him. I found him telling the Story to Mr. Bird, and that it was the same Person I had formerly known in Bridges street. The Prisoner Car knew me, and told me, that the Prosecutor, disguis'd in Liquor, brought a Woman into the Angel, whom he knew to be a common Pick-pocket; that she was turned out of the House, and that he, Car himself, bid him examine his Pockets; upon which the Prosecutor (he said) pulled out 93 Guineas. Car told me he saw the 93 Guineas, and that the Prosecutor returned him many Thanks for his Care, and desired him to accept of a Bottle of Wine, which he did; and then (he said) they had another, which made the Prosecutor so drunk, that he was carried upon a young Fellow's Shoulders to Bed. This was the Story that Car told me at Sir William Biller's Office.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Stamper. I have known him a Year, during which Time I never heard any Harm of him. He lives upon his Means, having married a Woman of some Fortune.</p>
               <p>Francis Lane, Constable. He gave exactly the same Account with Mr. Stamper; that Mr. Car own'd he called the Prosecutor into the Kitchen, that he advised him to tell his Money over, and that he saw him pull out 80 Guineas which were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120008"></xptr> laid on the Table, and 13 Guineas he kept in his Hand.</p>
               <p>Car. Did not I order my Laundress to go with you to the Place where Mrs. Adams might be found?</p>
               <p>Quarrington. Yes; and she went with us, and enquired for her. When she appeared we took her, and she immediately cry'd out, Oh! you are a base Jade for detecting me - no one knew where to find me but you.</p>
               <p>Adams. To the Constable. Did not you leave me in the Street while you went into a Cook's-Shop for a Dram of Gin?</p>
               <p>Constable. No; my Lord, she was never out of my Sight, - nor did I go any where for a Dram of Gin.</p>
               <p>Car. Might not I have escaped?</p>
               <p>Constable. No, I believe not; I took care that you should not.</p>
               <p>Adams. My Lord, I don't see that 'tis to any Purpose to ask them any more Questions, when they deny all.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. Some few Days ago, - I can't exactly recollect the Time, - Mr. Quarrington apply'd to me for a Warrant to take up the Persons that are untaken; and he told me this Story exactly agreeable to the Evidence he has now given. I have known him and his Parents a great while; I never heard any Harm of him in my Life; I believe him to be an honest Man, and have heard he has married a Woman of a good Fortune, but his Life and Conversation since his Marriage, I know very little of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Car. Mrs. Prevost is the Widow of one Prevost, who was Master of the King's Seal Office in the King's-Bench and Common Pleas, and I thought my Acquaintance with her not degrading. I did Business for her as an Attorney, and was spoke to by Mr. Stevens, an Officer, to attend her this Night; Mr. Salt can inform the Court what my Business was, and he likewise knows the Reason of my being in the Kitchen that very Night. I shall prove that I was at Home, and in Bed in my Chambers in the Temple, by One o'Clock, before the Temple Watchmen went One o'Clock. I will prove, that next Morning Mrs. Prevost sent for me, and that I met Mr. Salt afterwards at Hick's Hall; that the Prosecutor told my Clerk how he was robb'd, and promis'd to reward him if he would help him to find out the People of the House. I was angry when I heard the Prosecutor had been to enquire for me, that they did not ask him where he liv'd. On the 12th of September one 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person56" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Joiner or a Carpenter, - a Man of an evil Fame, - the Man that made Rudkins's Will, he came to me and told me, that a School-fellow of his had been robb'd of 93 Guineas at the Angel, and if I did not find out the Persons before the Money was all spent, the Man would swear the Robbery against me; he said I must come down the Whole, - or the best Part of the Money. I told him I would endeavour to find out Mrs. Prevost and the Drawers, but the People had carried off all their Goods, and were gone off. The Man told me if I had no Money, I had good Books, and must make Money of them. I never kept out of the Way upon this Account; I was sent for to Hampstead upon Business, but I refused to go, because it should not be suspected that I kept out of the Way.</p>
               <p>The Monday after the Robbery, two Gentlemen came from Greenwich, where I live in as much Reputation as any Man that practiseth the Law - in the whole Place, and when I told them I was to be sworn into a Robbery, they laughed at me.</p>
               <p>The Wednesday following this Andrews came again, and I asked him to let me see the Gentleman; he said no, I should not. I told him I would advertise the People, and endeavour to take them up; but he told me that would signify nothing, and immediately he took a Sheet of Paper, and fell to writing, - This Deponent maketh Oath, - without setting down any Name; and what he then wrote was very different from what the Prosecutor has said now. It is very unlikely I should be concerned with Mrs. Prevost and Mrs. Adams, and 2 Irish Drawers, in executing a Robbery. I was so far from calling the Prosecutor into the Kitchen, that I sat with my Leg up in a Chair when he came in, and told us that he did not know how to make us all amends for coming into so honest a House.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person57">
                  Thomas 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person57" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person57" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he informed Mr. Car that Mrs. Prevost desired him to call upon her for Instructions, in Order to his being employ'd in defending her at Hick's-Hall; an Information being there lodg'd against her, for keeping a disorderly House.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salt deposed, That he was concerned in the Prosecution of Mrs. Prevost, for keeping a disorderly House, and that Mr. Car appear'd in her Defence, and he seem'd not to be under any Concern.</p>
               <p>C. Mr. Car is not to be tried by his Looks, but by his Actions.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120009"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person58">
                  John 
                  Craster 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person58" type="surname" value="Craster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Salt serv'd me with a Subpaena on Friday Night, for me to appear at Hicks's-Hall against Mrs. Prevost. She sent for me to her House that Night; and there I found Mr. Car and Mrs. Prevost, with some other Neighhours who were subpaena'd with me on the same Account. Mr. Car told us, that we need not obey the Sulpaana's, for they were not 1 gal ones. We left the House about 12 o'Clock that Night, and left Car behind us. There were Mr. Car, Mrs. Adams, and Mrs. Prevost, and one Mr. Spidel. I did not see Quarrington there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person59">
                  Robert 
                  Thomlinson 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person59" type="surname" value="Thomlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person59" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave an Account that he was sent by a Woman from the Angel to fetch Mr. Car, from his Chambers No. 4. in Elm-Court in the Temple. That when he returned to the Angel, he saw the Woman crying; that she bid him come again in 2 Hours for his Money, which he did, according to his Orders, but found the Doors all shut up, and that he never had any Thing for his Job.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person60">
                  Charus 
                  Phillipson 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person60" type="surname" value="Phillipson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person60" type="given" value="Charus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person60" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to Mr. Car. On Saturday the 10th of September, while my Master was at Hicks's-Hall attending Mrs. Prevost's Affair, the Prosecutor came to the Chambers to enquire for Mr. Car. I told him he was not at Home, he said he came about a Thing which would be of great Advantage; but he would not leave his Name, nor his Business: at last, he said he had been robb'd at the Angel, by the People of the House. Upon this, I called the Laundress, and he told her the same. He did not charge Mr. Car, nor mention his Name; he only in general, charged the People of the House, and desired to know if my Master could give any Intelligence of them. He told us likewise, that when he came down in the Morning, he acquainted them that he had been robb'd, and that he went out in Order to ask Advice of a Friend, but when he return'd, the House was shut up, and the People were fled.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time did your Master come Home that Night?</p>
               <p>Phillipson. To the best of my Knowledge, it was before the Watchman went One. At that Time he had a Leg in so much Hazard, that no Body could think him capable of taking a Man by the Collar and robbing him. He had 9 Holes in his Leg, and he could not walk up Stairs without resting himself. On Monday the 12th of Sept. one Andrews came to the Chambers to enquire for my Master, and he told me he came about one Wilson, and said, 'twas a sad Affair, and he was sorry for Mr. Car, but this Wilson was a School-fellow of his - a particular Friend, and had been robb'd, and if my Master did not compound and settle the Affair, it would be sworn upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this Andrews meant the Prosecutor, when he talked of Wilson?</p>
               <p>Phillipson Because he mentioned the Angel, and I suppose there had not been 2 Robberies committed there.</p>
               <p>Quarrington. My Lord, if I may speak, - this Andrews I know nothing of; I never saw him in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Andrews acquainted with your Master?</p>
               <p>Phillipson. He was concerned with him sometime ago, in a Distress that was made at Wapping.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person61">
                  Martha 
                  Grainger 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person61" type="surname" value="Grainger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person61" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person61" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Laundress. I have forgot the Day of the Month; but I remember 'twas on a Saturday about half an Hour after One, that the Prosecutor came to enquire for my Master; he happen'd not to be at Home. The Clerk ask'd him his Business, and he inform'd us, that he had been in my Master's Company at the Angel the Night before, and after Mr. Car was gone, he was robb'd of 93 Guineas and 11 s. in Silver, and of a Ring, which he valu'd at 8 Guineas; he did not say who robb'd him, but he told us that he lay there all Night, and got up in the Morning; that he came down Stairs and complain'd to the Woman of the House that he was robb'd, and then he said he went out to advise with a Friend; but when he return'd the House was shut up, and the People were all gone. He told us, he should be glad if Mr. Car could give him any Information of them, and where they were gone. He did not then pretend that my Master was concerned. I asked him if he suspected any Person in particular? And he told us no, he did not. I have look'd after Mr. Car's Chambers 8 Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you marry'd?</p>
               <p>Grainger. No, I was hir'd to do his Business.</p>
               <p>Car. What Time was I a-bed that Night?</p>
               <p>Grainger. Before the Watchman came One o'Clock. I was not a-bed when he came Home, he ordered me to get him a clean Shirt against Morning. At this Time he was lame, and had 9 Holes in his Leg.</p>
               <p>C. But he could walk about.</p>
               <p>Grainger. Yes, with his Garters unty'd, and he could not get up 2 pair of Stairs without resting. My Master was very angry because we did not ask the Prosecutor where he liv'd, and he told us, if he came again, he must see him. Accordingly when he came again, my Master was coming out of his Study, upon which the Prosecutor turn'd round, and brought in the Constable, and said, - there's your Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120010"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person62">
                  Jane 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person62" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person62" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Servant in the House when the Robbery was committed, I went to Bed that Night about 12, and I left in the Kitchen only my Mistress, the two Prisoners, and the two Drawers, - no Soul else was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Why, was not the Prosecutor there?</p>
               <p>Lucas. O! yes, the Man that lost his Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not the Drawers in the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Lucas. No, Edwards and Travers, that we call'd Nat, were about the House, but not in the Kitchen. I heard no Noise all Night; but next Morning when I got up, I found the Street Door o'jar, I imagin'd the Drawers had forgot to shut it over Night, I rang the Bell to call them up, and my Mistress was in Bed, but she call'd to me to know the Reason why Nat was not come down, I went up to see what was become of them, and I found their Bed made, and that they had not been in Bed all Night. I came down and told Mrs Prevost of this, and she was 'frighted, - Lord, (says she) they have certainly kill'd the Man, run and call Adams, and see if the Man is safe. I went up, and found the Prosecutor snoaring in Bed, then I ran immediately to Mrs. Prevost, and told her the Man - snoar'd. Lord, (says she directly) we are all ruin'd - ruin'd, let me go and see what I am about. The Prosecutor presently came into the Kitchen, and he cried, - I am robb'd - I am robb'd - I am robb'd! - 3 Times in the Kitchen, - but he did not charge any Body, and away he went. Mrs. Prevost being very timerous and fearful, she went away too, - because she did not know where to go, nor what to do. Call 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person63">
                  Betty 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person63" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person63" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person63" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - says she, - and let her be gone too, till we see whether we are safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any one in the Kitchen beside your self when the Man said he was robb'd three Times?</p>
               <p>Lucas. No, there was none but himself; for my Mistress was doing her Things up in the Bar, - she was so 'frighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you say your Mistress was in Bed?</p>
               <p>Lucas. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Why, when did the Man come down and say he was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Lucas. While we two were talking of it, - she in Bed; - but she got up. She laid in a little Room behind the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. But when the Man came into the Kitchen and said he was robb'd, - she was in some Confusion, and was for packing up her Things to be gone?</p>
               <p>Lucas. Yes, Sir. And indeed I tell the Truth of the Thing, - was it for K - G - I would not tell a Lye to d - n my Soul.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the Words she made use of when she heard the Man say he was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I can't tell whether she heard the Man say he was robb'd, or no</p>
               <p>Q. Why, you say, she cry'd out she was ruin'd, - and undone?</p>
               <p>Lucas. Yes, Sir, - but that was before the Man came down, and she bid me lock up the Doors, till - Things were put in Order.</p>
               <p>Adams Prisoner. Why did not the Man come into the Kitchen for his Hat and his Cane? - And did he not speak to me at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I can't swear whether Mrs. Adams was there or not.</p>
               <p>C. You said there was none but you in the Kitchen when the Man came down Stairs?</p>
               <p>Lucas. Sir, I was busy a dressing my Mistress, - I was busy with her in her Room, and she sent me to call Mrs. Adams.</p>
               <p>C. To give her Notice to go off, - was it not?</p>
               <p>Lucas. Yes, - Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person64">
                  Joseph 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person64" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person64" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All I know of the Matter is this. This Creature (Lucas) liv'd with me about 6 Months, and I believe her to be an honest, harmless Creature. I sent a Porter to Mr. Car in Newgate, to let him know she had liv'd with me. I know Mr. Car, and have employ'd him and paid him, - I know no Harm of him - not I.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person65">
                  Eliz 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person65" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person65" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live over the Way and sell Greens: on that Saturday Morning, - I think 'twas last Saturday was three Weeks, I heard a great Mourning, between 8 and 9 in the Morning, - and I heard a Man say, - Oh! - Oh! - Oh! - I am undone! - What shall I do! Give me my Money and my Ring! And another Voice said, - what would you have me do, I can do nothing 'till they come; then I lost the Voice, and presently the House was shut up.</p>
               <p>Dr. Lilly. I have known the Prisoner Car some Years, he was well born and educated, but I have had no great Acquaintance with him. I thought him too well educated to have been guilty of such a Fact, I always thought him an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. The Gentleman that lost his Money, came to enquire for Mr. Jones, by Mr. Bird's Direction. He said he had been at the Angel, the last Night, and had been robb'd of 70 Guineas, some Silver, and his Watch and Ring. The Woman of the House he said took his Money; - he nam'd none else.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120011"></xptr>Car. I desire 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person66">
                  John 
                  Bundey 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person66" type="surname" value="Bundey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person66" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             may be called; he heard Quarrington's first Complaint.</p>
               <p>Bundey. I know nothing of the Matter, only I heard Quarrington tell Mr. Gold ( a Constable ) that he had been at the Angel, - all Night, - I think, and Mr. Car (he said) was up Stairs with him. He came to Mr. Gold to take Charge of him, for he said that Car had robbed him of 93 Guineas, eight or ten Shillings in Silver, and a Diamond Ring.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Poulson, 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person67">
                  William 
                  Trigg 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person67" type="surname" value="Trigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person67" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person68">
                  Joseph 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person68" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person68" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person69">
                  Thomas 
                  Hitchings 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person69" type="surname" value="Hitchings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person69" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person70">
                  James 
                  Alder 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person70" type="surname" value="Alder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person70" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person71">
                  Andrew 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person71" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person71" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , William and 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person72">
                  Peter 
                  Hack 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person72" type="surname" value="Hack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person72" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person73">
                  Charles 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person73" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person73" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17371012-3-person74">
                  Edward 
                  Mabert 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person74" type="surname" value="Mabert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person74" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and - Pardoe, always took the Prisoner Car to be an honest Man, and never heard any Thing like this of him before.</p>
               <p>Adams. I have no Witnesses, for Mr. Mabson told me the Matter was made up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-3-person75">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17371012-3-person75" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person75" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mabson, I believe, had told Mrs. Adams that the Affair would be made up, for I went to her in Newgate last Tuesday, and she told me she should have no Occasion to trouble her Friends, for Mabson had been with her. Mr. Quarrington was at the Coffee-House with Mabson, and Mabson asked him what he intended to do? He reply'd, he would do nothing without his Attorney.</p>
               <p>The Jury found both the Prisoners <rs id="t17371012-3-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17371012-3-punish20" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-3-punish20" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend46 t17371012-3-punish20"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-3-defend48 t17371012-3-punish20"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
