<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-8">
               <interp inst="t17341204-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-8" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-8" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-8-off46-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-defend80 t17341204-8-off46 t17341204-8-verdict52"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-8-off48-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-defend80 t17341204-8-off48 t17341204-8-verdict52"></join>
         

               <p>8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-8-defend80" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Luelling 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-8-defend80" type="surname" value="Luelling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-defend80" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-defend80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17341204-8-defloc45">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-8-defloc45" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-8-defloc45" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-defend80 t17341204-8-defloc45"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-8-off46" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-off46" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-off46" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch value 5 l. and a Seal value 1 l. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-8-victim82" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Salisbury 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim82" type="surname" value="Salisbury"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim82" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17341204-8-cd47" type="crimeDate">Nov. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off46 t17341204-8-cd47"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off48 t17341204-8-cd47"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17341204-8-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a Hankerchief value 1 s. from 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-8-victim84" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Gain 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim84" type="surname" value="Gain"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim84" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-8-victim84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17341204-8-cd49" type="crimeDate">November 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off46 t17341204-8-cd49"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off48 t17341204-8-cd49"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salisbury. On the 4th of November, coming from the Bedford Arms Tavern in <placeName id="t17341204-8-crimeloc50">Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-8-crimeloc50" type="placeName" value="Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-8-crimeloc50" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off46 t17341204-8-crimeloc50"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-off48 t17341204-8-crimeloc50"></join>, there was a Mob gathered about 2 Men who were fighting. I stood still a little to look at 'em. when presently I felt my Watch drawn cut of my Fob. The Prisoner standing next me on my right Side, I collar'd him before he had got his Hand quite from under my Coat, and said, Sirrah, you have got my Watch, but in struggling he twisted himself about, and as I suppose, conveyed my Watch away to some of his Companions. However, some others assisting me we at last got him into a Tavern, where he was searched. My Watch indeed was not found upon him, but the Constable took from him a Handkerchief which was own'd by Mr. Gain.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How came you to expect me?</p>
               <p>Mr. Salisbury. Expect ye? I suspected ye, because I found your Hand under my Coat at the same time that I felt my Watch drawn out of my Fob.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I was at the Tavern the Gentleman said, they did not expect me to be such a Man; and the Prosecutor himself said, If I would send for any Body to my Character, he would not only discharge me, but down on his Knees and beg my pardon.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salisbury. I said no such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-8-person85">
                  Hannah 
                  Bowen 
               <interp inst="t17341204-8-person85" type="surname" value="Bowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-person85" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-person85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17341204-8-deflabel51" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-defend80 t17341204-8-deflabel51"></join> 7 Years and a half I kept a Sutling. and Lodging-house at White-hall 3 Years ago, and I trusted him to take all my Money when I lay in - He has brought me 14 l. on a Night, and I never knew that he wrong'd me of a Farthing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-8-person86">
                  John 
                  Greencase 
               <interp inst="t17341204-8-person86" type="surname" value="Greencase"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-person86" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 2 Years, he lodg'd in the Room where my Work lay, in St. Martin's le Grand, and I never mist any thing.</p>
               <p>Ann Dean. He lodged in my House 3 or 4 Months. My Husband is a Watchmaker, and he has trusted him several Hours together in our Garret where our Work both Gold and Silver is, and is never lock'd up.</p>
               <p>Court. What Business does he follow?</p>
               <p>Dean. I have heard that he sometimes works upon the Keys as a spare Man.</p>
               <p> Second Indictment.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gain. I was going by when Mr. Salisbury feiz'd the Prisoner, who made a violent Resistance, and cry'd out Murder. I assisted to thrust him into a Coach, and at last we got him into a Tavern, where the Constable searched him for Mr. Salisbury's Watch, but could not find it. At the same time I happened to have Occasion for my Handkerchief, but feeling for it, I 'mist it. The Constable found a Handkerchief upon him. I said, before I saw it, if it is mine it is stained and snuffy; upon which it was produced, and I knew it to be my own - Here it is.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salisbury. I saw the Constable take this Handkerchief out of the Prisoner's Pocket, and Mr. Gain sent to his Mother for two or three more of the same sort, and they matcht exactly.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They were not the same Size by above an Inch.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gain. Here is one of the same sort.</p>
               <p>Then the two Handkerchiefs were compared, and agreed in every particular.</p>
               <p>Mr.Hickman, Constable. Just as I had searched the Prisoner for the Watch, Mr. Gain said, he had lost his Handkerchief, which was stain'd with Snuff. Upon which, I searched the Prisoner again, and found it. Mr. Gain sent for three more which were of the same Size and Colour.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gain. The Prisoner at first said, he had had the Handkerchief a Week, and then he said he found it that Night under the Piazza's - I had used it but two Minutes<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040008"></xptr> before he was taken - When I went to him in the Gate-house, he said, I hope you'll bring in a Bill of Ignoramus, and if you do, I'll give you half a Guinea.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17341204-8-verdict52" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-verdict52" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of both Indictments. <rs id="t17341204-8-punish53" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-8-punish53" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-8-defend80 t17341204-8-punish53"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
