<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340630-11">
               <interp inst="t17340630-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340630-11" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340630-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340630"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340630-11" type="date" value="17340630"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340630-11-off52-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-defend112 t17340630-11-off52 t17340630-11-verdict56"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340630-11-off54-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-defend112 t17340630-11-off54 t17340630-11-verdict56"></join>
         
               <p>16. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-defend112" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Waker 
                  <interp inst="t17340630-11-defend112" type="surname" value="Waker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-defend112" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-defend112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17340630-11-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 50 Guineas, 4 Moidores, 4 other Portugal Pieces, val. 3 l. 12 s. each, the Money of Jo. Hague; a Wig, and two Shirts, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340630-11-victim114" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Touchet 
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim114" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim114" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; and a Hat, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340630-11-victim116" type="victimName">
                           Holden 
                           Bouker 
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim116" type="surname" value="Bouker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim116" type="given" value="Holden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340630-11-victim118" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Hague 
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim118" type="surname" value="Hague"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim118" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-victim118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17340630-11-cd53" type="crimeDate">March 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-off52 t17340630-11-cd53"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-off54 t17340630-11-cd53"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17340630-11-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing several promissory Notes, one for 24 l. 12 s. one for 60 l. one for 10 l. one for 10 l. 10 s. one for 25 l. one for 24 l. 10 s. one for 30 l. one for 19 l. and one 9 l. 15 s. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17340630-11-person119">
                        Joseph 
                        Hague 
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person119" type="surname" value="Hague"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-person119" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340630-11-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in his House
            </rs>, March 3.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17340630-11-deflabel55" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-defend112 t17340630-11-deflabel55"></join>, in January and February last. I went into Lancashire, and as soon as I return'd, I heard he had robb'd me of a thousand Pounds in Cash and Notes,* and that the next Day one Cox, a Portugueze Priest, had brought back some Money and Notes, to the value of above 800 l. I got Advertisements printed, and sent them to the Post-Office - A Gentleman at Bath, wrote me word that he had accidentally met with the Prisoner there, and apprehended him, but advis'd me to send down some Body to swear to him, for he had made so many Friends, by his gay Appearance and extravagant Expences, that otherwise it would be difficult to hold him.</p>
               <p>*Then the whole of the sum is not charged in the Indictment</p>
               <p>Council. Were not all your Notes brought back?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. I had them all again, except one for 60 l. which was an old and, and not much worth, but besides that, I am 67 l. 6 s. out of Pocket.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you never apply to the Prisoner's Mother to make you Satisfaction?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. She offer'd to make the Matter easy; but I told her, she had deceived the Gentleman who recommended her son to me, for he had robb'd his former Master, and had been 4 Years in Town, tho' he pretended he had been come but a few weeks from Portugal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-person120">
                  Samuel 
                  Touchet 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person120" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person120" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday, March 3, I left the Prisoner a Bed, and went out. I return'd before Sermon time, designing to dress myself, and go to Church; but I missing two Shirts, and my Hat, and Wig, and looking about, I found two of the Cash-drawers under the Sink: Upon which I called the Maid, and then went and fetch'd home our Man, who unlock'd the Desk, and found that all the Drawers had been taken <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173406300008"></xptr> out and plunder'd. 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person121">
                  Richard 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person121" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person121" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who took the Prisoner at Bath, brought me my Wig, and one of my Shirts.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-person122">
                  Holden 
                  Bouker 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person122" type="surname" value="Bouker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person122" type="given" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Morning I went out to dine, but was called home by 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person123">
                  Sam 
                  Touchet 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person123" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person123" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said, that he had found two of the Cash-drawers under the Shew-board. The Desk is double and there are three Drawers on each side. I found the Flaps lock'd fast, but upon opening them, there was neither Bill nor Money. I ask'd the Maid where the Prisoner was. She said he went out about 9 a Clock in a hurry, and said, he must be at 9 a Clock Prayers, and would come home at half an Hour past 12. I thought to go and see for him, at the Portugueze Chappel, but considering it was almost his time to return, I waited 'till 1 a Clock, and hearing nothing of him then, I sent Touchet to enquire of the Gentleman who recommended the Prisoner, and went myself to the Water-side, where I heard that some such Person was gone off in the Gravesend-Boat. I immediately got a Post-horse, and arriv'd at Gravesend before the Boat; but when it came in, he was not among the Passengers. So I left a Description of him, and return'd, concluding he was still in Town. I desir'd one to lie at the Water-side, and I myself lay at the Post-house; but the Prisoner came to neither Place. Next Morning, being Monday, I went to all the Persons who were concern'd in the Notes, to let them know the Notes were stoln I return'd at Noon, and found our People at home look'd much pleasanter. They told me, the Portugueze Ambassador's Priest had brought cash and Notes, to the value of 854 l. 14 s. They said, they did not think it safe to stop him - He was one who had recommended the Prisoner. On Thursday, I heard that the Prisoner had been at Brentford, and hir'd a Horse for Windsor. I went to Brentford, and found the Man who left him the Horse; he was under no concern about losing his Horse, for he said, the Prisoner had left 7 l. for Security, and was gone to Windsor, to meet the Prince of Orange. I return'd home, and got 500 Advertisements printed, and left them at the Post-Office, to be spread in England and Ireland. Next Wednesday a Letter came from Mr. Ford, at Bath, advising, that on seeing the Advertisement he had stopt the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. The Prisoner likewise sent me a Letter from Bath, and another from Ilchester - I have them both here - This is that from Bath - I know it to be the Prisoner's Writing.</p>
               <p>Then the Letter was read. It was directed, To 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person124">
                  Joseph 
                  Hague 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person124" type="surname" value="Hague"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person124" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Star, in Castle-Court, near Lawrence-Lane, and dated March 23, 1733.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner therein declares, that his Remorse pursues him so, that he cannot enjoy any part of Pleasure, he had promised himself - Confesses the Robbery - Begs Forgiveness, and says, that in great Confusion he left the Bills, and some Money, with 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person125">
                  Anthony 
                  Campion 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person125" type="surname" value="Campion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person125" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , desiring him to return them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. My People told me, that the Priest, who brought the Money and Notes, said, that he had them from Campion.</p>
               <p>H. Boucker. On the Receit of these Letters, I went to Bath, where I found the Prisoner. He said, he had premeditated the Robbery for several Weeks; that he open'd the Desk, and took out the Notes, and about 80 l. in Cash, and then went to the Portugueze Chappel, where he met Campion, went with him into the Park, and told him what he had done; they walk'd thro' Kensington towards Chiswick. He gave Campion the Notes, and 25 l. in Cash, and Campion advis'd him to go to Brentford, and write to him by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person126">
                  William 
                  Falkner 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person126" type="surname" value="Falkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person126" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then they parted. He went to Brentford, where he hir'd a Horse, and rode thro' Windsor to Reading, where he bought a Whip, silk Stockings, and a Lace for his Hat. Thence he went to Oxford, and so to Bath, where he was taken. Here is his Confession, before the Mayor and Justices at Bath.</p>
               <p>[The Confession being prov'd was read in Court.]</p>
               <p>He herein confesses, that he took the Money and Notes out of the Desk, that he gave the Notes, and 25 l. to Campion, desiring him to return them to Mr. Hague. <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173406300009"></xptr> that he took Horse at Brentford, and rode to Oxford, and from tence to Bath, where he was taken with 21 l. upon him, which was all he had left of his Master's Money, having bought new Clothes, a Wig, Boots, and some other Things, besides having his Pocket pick'd by a Whore at Oxford.</p>
               <p>Boker. After this Confession, he was committed to Ilchester Goal.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know of no Reward, that your Master has receiv'd from the Prisoner's Mother, for making this Matter up?</p>
               <p>Bouker. No; they offer'd me a Bond, but I would have nothing to do with it.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know of any Money, Note or Bond given to 
               <persName id="t17340630-11-person127">
                  William 
                  Havers 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person127" type="surname" value="Havers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person127" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Bouker. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Was Havers never employ'd by your Master?</p>
               <p>Bouker. Not that I know of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. I found the Prisoner at a Coffee-house, in Bath, in Company with a Person. I got a Constable, and charged the Prisoner with the Fact. He at first deny'd it stiffly; but when I shew'd him the Advertisement, he said, sighing, It signifies nothing to equivocate; I am the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-person128">
                  Anthony 
                  Campion 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person128" type="surname" value="Campion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person128" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Morning, between 9 and 10, the Prisoner came to the Portugueze Chappel, and beckon'd me out. We went to Hyde-Park Corner, where he told me, he had robb'd his Master of Money and Notes, and bid me take the Notes, and scatter them at t'other End of the Town, and then he said, some Body that found 'em might be taken up, and so he should escape the better - We walked towards Chiswick, and then he gave me 25 l. and so we parted, and I deliver'd the Notes and Money, to Mr. Cox, to return to Mr. Hague.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker, the Prisoner's Mother. Mr. Ross, who is Mr. Hague's Friend, came to me, and said, if I'd give 30 l. the Affair should be accommodated. My Husband went to give Security for the Money; but Mr. Hague told me, if I placed 20 l. in a Friend's Hands, something might be done - I lodg'd the Money in Mr. Havers's Hands, and afterwards put 5 l. more to it by Mr. Ross's Orders, and Mr. Hague told me he'd stand by what Mr. Ross did.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. I never told her so.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. You did; and you said if I did not comply, you should have a Benefit Ticket.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. I said no such thing.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. My Son is about 19 Years old. He told me that Campion was the first that drew him aside, for Campion kept a School, and having marry'd against his Friends Consent, he was in great Distress - Campion and Cox, the Priest, were examin'd before Justice Lambert, who committed Campion to the Gatehouse, for this very Fact, and Mr. Hague was present then; and bound over to prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. I know nothing of his Commitment.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. No? - Here's the Copy of his Commitment!</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. Then that must have been at his second Appearance, for I am sure there was no Commitment at the first.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. Campion confess'd the Fact before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Court. Did you hear that?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. No; for when the Justice took his Confession, they turn'd me out.</p>
               <p>Court. And will you swear to what was done in your Absence?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. Campion lay in the Gatehouse 'till last Sessions, and then he was discharged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-person129">
                  Louisa 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person129" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person129" type="given" value="Louisa"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Wednesday after the Prisoner was taken, I went, with Mrs. Barker, to Mr. Ross's, and Mr. Hague was there. Mr. Barker, the Prisoner's Father-in-Law, was to give a Bond of 30 l. and Mr. Hague agreed to it; for Mr. Ross, said, Must I make it for thirty Pound? And Mr. Hague said, Yes. And he bid me agree with Mr. Ross, for, says he, If you make it easy with him, I shall be easy.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barker. And Ross said, Down with your ready Rhino.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hague. I know Ross was very eager to make it up, but I gave him no Instructions, for I always said, I would have nothing to do with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340630-11-person130">
                  Judith 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17340630-11-person130" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person130" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Mr. Hague's, and he said, Don't talk to me, but go to <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173406300010"></xptr> Mr. Ross, and what he does, I will stand to. And Ross came to Mrs. Barker's, and said, If you'll place 30 l. there shall be no more of this Affair.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17340630-11-verdict56" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-verdict56" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17340630-11-punish57" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340630-11-punish57" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340630-11-defend112 t17340630-11-punish57"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
