<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-4">
               <interp inst="t17380222-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-4" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-4" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-4-off23-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-defend55 t17380222-4-off23 t17380222-4-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Nathaniel 
                     Hilliard 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-defend55" type="surname" value="Hilliard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-defend55" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380222-4-defloc22">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-defloc22" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-defloc22" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-defend55 t17380222-4-defloc22"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17380222-4-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. the 6th of May, in the 7th Year of his present Majesty, in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-4-victim57" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Millegan 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-4-victim57" type="surname" value="Millegan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-4-victim57" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-4-victim57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-off23 t17380222-4-victim57"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously, &amp;c. did make an Assault, and with a certain Sword made of iron and steal, value 2 s. which he held in his right Hand, him the said Millegan, in and upon the Inside of the right Thigh, did strike and stab, giving him a mortal Wound of the Breadth of half an Inch, and the Depth of 9 Inches, of which mortal Wound he languish'd from the 6th to the 9th of May in the Year aforesaid, and then dy'd.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted on the Statute for Stabbing.</p>
               <p>And a 3d Time on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person58">
                  Mary 
                  Millegan 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person58" type="surname" value="Millegan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person58" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the <rs id="t17380222-4-cd24" type="crimeDate">6th of May 1734</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-off23 t17380222-4-cd24"></join>, my Husband was with the Prisoner at Mr. Langford's a Distiller; I saw them both go from thence, down Windmill-Street. In a little while after this, my Husband was brought Home in a Chair, stabb'd in the Thigh. I asked him who did it? And he told me - that Rogue Hilliard, has stabb'd me, - he has killed me. I know the Prisoner; I saw him in Langford's House. He does not wear a Sword, but had hid one under his Coat, I suppose. The Wound was in the Thigh, very near the Popes Eye; 'twas given on the Monday, and on Thursday, about II o'Clock he dy'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person59">
                  Edward 
                  Langford 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person59" type="surname" value="Langford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person59" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner I believe is the same Person; he came that Day to my House to give me a Note of his Hand, for Money due to me from another Person. He was some Time in the Shop, but seeing somebody in the Street, that he did not like, he desir'd I would suffer him to go up Stairs. When we were above Stairs, he told me he saw Bailiffs in the Street, and he was bewitch'd that he should come out without a Sword. Upon this he call'd a Man up Stairs and sent him for his Sword, which was brought to him, and he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220005"></xptr> aid - 'twas a good Bit of Stuff, and if any Officer attempted to arrest him, it should go through him. After this, the Deceased, Millegan) brought a Man to my House that he had arrested for me, but I would not let him go into the Room, where the Prisoner was, because he was in Wratyh, and had got a Sword I ask'd the Deceas'd if he had any Writ against the Prisoner? He declar'd he had none; then I brought them together, and they were both very friendly. The Prisoner being afraid of an Arrest, the Deceased told him, he would see him safe within the Verge of the Court, and if any Officer attempted to arrest him, he would say, he was his Prisoner already, and would deliver him safe, where he should be out of Danger. Upon these Declarations of the Deceased, they both went out of the House together; I call'd the Deceased back, and would have had him done some other Business for me, but he swore an Oath, and told me he could not, for he was going to arrest the Prisoner. I asked him if he was not afraid of getting some Hurt? He swore he would venture, and would arrest him, - so away they both went. Half an Hour after this, the Deceased was brought back in a Chair wounded, and the Prisoner's Sword was with him. I went to see him, and he told me, Hilliard had stabb'd him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I ask the Deceased if he had any Thing against me? He reply'd, no really Sir, I have not; and Mr. Langford, said, if you have, don't expose the Gentleman, but charge him here, and I will endeavour to make Things easy.</p>
               <p>Langford. I believe I did say so. I said, I would have you both agree, and I told the Deceased, if he had any Thing against him, he must take him to his own House, and must not meddle with him in my House; but the Deceased declared he had nothing against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person60">
                  John 
                  Langford 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person60" type="surname" value="Langford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday May the 6th, 1734, the Prisoner came to my Father's House; he had not been there long, before he desir'd to go up Stairs for fear of an Arrest. When he was in the Room above Stairs, he look'd through the Window into the Street, and said, - he was afraid of the Bailiffs, and wish'd he had a Sword. Presently after this, he call'd a Man up, and sent him to Downing-Street, Westminster, for a Sword, which lay upon his Buroe. The Messenger return'd with the Sword, and the Prisoner took it from him, and bent it, and said, it was a good Bit of Stuff, and would do. Then I went down Stairs and saw no more, till the Deceased and the Prisoner went out of the House together; my Father call'd the Deceased back, and asked him to do some Business for him in Shore ditch; he reply'd, - no, damn it I can't, for I am going to arrest Hilliard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person61">
                  Catherine 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person61" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person61" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person61" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased was my Brother-in-Law; he went out well in the Morning the 6th of May, 1734, and was brought Home wounded in a Chair. I asked him, who gave him the Wound He cry'd, I am a dead Man; the Fellow your Sister saw in Langford's Window,, 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person62">
                  Nat 
                  Hilliard 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person62" type="surname" value="Hilliard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person62" type="given" value="Nat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             has done it. He was lately a Corporal in the first Regiment of Foot-Guards, but was drumm'd out of the Regiment with a Halter about his Neck, for enlisting Soldiers for the Pretender. - The Deceased told us, that he went with the Prisoner as far as the <placeName id="t17380222-4-crimeloc25">Horseshoe Alehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-crimeloc25" type="placeName" value="Horseshoe Alehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-crimeloc25" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-off23 t17380222-4-crimeloc25"></join> and there his Follower gave him the Writ; there it was he tapp'd him on the Shoulder, and told him he had a Writ against him; upon which the Prisoner open'd his Legs, and between his own Legs he thrust him in the Thigh. This was what the Deceased told me; I saw the Wound; the Deceased languished from Monday to Thursday and then died.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person63">
                  Richard 
                  Totterdell 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person63" type="surname" value="Totterdell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person63" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday May 8th, 1734. I went to visit the Deceased; I asked him how the Accident happened? He told me, that he arrested the Prisoner and was going to lay hold of him; but he jump'd from him; the Deceased endeavour'd to leap in with him, to secure him, and the Prisoner open'd his Legs, and jobb'd the Sword into the Deceased's Thigh as he was behind him. I did not see the Thing done, but this was the very Writ, he was then executing upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person64">
                  Isaac 
                  Itorno 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person64" type="surname" value="Itorno"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person64" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About two Hours after the Accident happen'd I went to visit the Deceased, I enquired how he came by the Wound? He told me, that he arrested the Prisoner in the <placeName id="t17380222-4-crimeloc26">Haymarket</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-crimeloc26" type="placeName" value="Haymarket"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-4-crimeloc26" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-off23 t17380222-4-crimeloc26"></join>, and he open'd his Legs and stabb'd him between them, in the Thigh: The Sword is in Court, and is bent; I suppose it ran against the Bone. I told the Deceased, that I apprehended he had not long to live, and I asked him, if he was sure the Prisoner gave him the Stab? I know (says he) that I shall not live, and I am sure he stabb'd me in the Haymarket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person65">
                  Henry 
                  Noble 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person65" type="surname" value="Noble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person65" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by the Deceased when he dy'd, and had hold of his Hand. He declar'd that Hilliard had jobb'd his Sword thro' his Thigh, a little above the Horseshoe, on the right Hand Side of the Way, in the Haymarket.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220006"></xptr>. Surgeon. I was call'd to dress  the Accident happen'd. The Orifice was Length-ways on the Inside of the Thigh, and went upwards a Way; then the Sword pass'd downwards, and came out downwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person66">
                  Richard 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person66" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person66" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was call'd late, and made no great Observation, for I perceiv'd an approaching Mortification, on the downward Part of the Wound.</p>
               <p>A Witness prov'd the Writ, by Vertue of which the Deceased arrested the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>A Witness. The Deceased told me, he had no Writ against the Prisoner, when they were together at Langford's House, but as they went up the Haymarket his Follower put it into his Hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Langford swears, that when we went out of his House, the Deceased told him he was going to arrest me.</p>
               <p>Langford. When he was in my House, he said, he had no Writ against the Prisoner; but as they were going down Windmill-Street, I call'd the Deceased back, and he then told me, he was going to arrest the Prisoner. I asked him if he was not afraid, and bid him not be so unwise, - for the Prisoner would certainly do him a Mischief, D - n him said the Deceased, - I don't fear him.</p>
               <p>The Widow. This is the Writ, - I took it out of my Husband's Pocket, full of Blood.</p>
               <p>A Witness. The Deceased was sworn an Officer on the 27th of July, 1733, and continu'd an Officer to his Death.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. On the 6th of May 1734, I went to Langford's House to perswade him to take my Note, in order to his discharging one Newman whom Langford had arrested. I desir'd to go up Stairs, and while I was above, I saw a Man go by, who was an Officer in the Marshall's Court. I was not much afraid, for I did not owe 5 l. in the World; but I did not care to be expos'd. Millegan came in and told me that I ow'd Money to one Mr. Cable, and that there was a Writ out against me. I desir'd him to go to the Officer and tell him to come the next Day, and he should have a Guinea for not exposing me. He went to the Officer and spoke to him, and when he return'd to me, he told me, the Officer was gone over the Water and would not return in four Hours; and in the mean Time, he would conduct me into the Verge of the Court. I took it kindly of him, and treated him with Punch and Ratafie, promising to be grateful. As we were going out of the House, Langford's Daughter bid Millegan not trust me, for I was a dangerous Fellow; upon which I said to Millegan, - perhaps you have got the Writ your self, if you have, don't expose me, and Mr. Langford said, - no, as the Gentleman has been so civil to you, if you have any Thing against him, do it here. God strike me dead and d - mn'd, said the Deceased, if I have any Thing against him; but as we were walking past the Opera-house, 2 Men came up to him, and while I was asking him who they were, I was knock'd down, stuck in the Back, and my left Thumb almost cut off; then his Followers ran away. Such Treachery and Barbarity no Man was ever used with, and I saw no Writ, - there was none produced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person67">
                  Charles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person67" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person67" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the 3d Regiment of Guards, and was coming from Exercise when this happen'd. I saw the Deceased knock the Prisoner down, but I can't say with what Instrument. His Follower said, - d - md him make sure Work. When the Prisoner got up he stagger'd, and was bloody, and was thrust among the Poles of the Chairs which stood by the Opera house. There was no Sword drawn at that Time, nor did I see the Deceased receive any Wound, or tap the Prisoner on the Shoulder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person68">
                  Thomas 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person68" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person68" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was passing by and saw part of the Fray, I did not stay long, but I saw the Prisoner underneath 2 or 3 Men upon the Ground, how he came down I can't tell; I saw nothing of the Arrest, nor of any Wound given the Deceased.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person69">
                  John 
                  Rayner 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person69" type="surname" value="Rayner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting at a Public House in the Hay-Market, and saw the Prisoner come down the Street, and the Deceased with 2 or 3 Men following him. When they came against the Horshoe Alehouse, the Deceased took hold of the Prisoner and flung him down, over the Chair Poles. I suspected that he (the Prisoner) had received the Hurt, when I saw Blood, and I told the Deceased he had kill'd him, no, said the Deceased, the Villain has murd'red me; I saw no Sword, nor any Wound given to him, but the Prisoner's Head was broke, and he was ill used. I saw the Deceased lay hold of him, but I can't say I saw any Blow; the Prisoner complain'd he was wounded, but he got away from the Crowd, and the Deceased was sent Home in a Chair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ormerod, Surgeon. I believe the Wound could not be given the Deceased in the Fall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person70">
                  Baxter 
                  Polding 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person70" type="surname" value="Polding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person70" type="given" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was riding down the Haymarket on the Shafts of my Dray, and saw a Man strike the Prisoner with something like a Stick. He fell down, and when he recover'd, I saw his Head bloody. I saw nothing of the Arrest, or of the tapping on the Shoulder.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220007"></xptr>The Widow. My Husband had no walking Stick with him, and 'twas after the Prisoner had stabb'd him, that he knock'd him down with his Tiptaff.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person71">
                  Charles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person71" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person71" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the former Witness) When I saw the Sword it was not drawn, nor did I see any Wound given after the Prisoner got up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person72">
                  Joel 
                  Fremoult 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person72" type="surname" value="Fremoult"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person72" type="given" value="Joel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was sent for the 6th of May to the Rose in Shoreditch, to dress the Prisoner. He had a punctur'd Wound on the right Side under the short Ribs, about 3 Inches in Depth. I know nothing of the Scuffle. He had 2 Wounds likewise upon his left Thumb, and 2 Contusions on his Head.</p>
               <p>Langford. The Truth is this, he swore his Sword was a good bit of Stuff, and before he went out, he swore if any Bailift offer'd to arrest him it should go through him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person73">
                  Isaac 
                  Burges 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person73" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person73" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person74">
                  Seth 
                  Cary 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person74" type="surname" value="Cary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person74" type="given" value="Seth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person75">
                  Samuel 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person75" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person75" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person76">
                  George 
                  Sutherland 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person76" type="surname" value="Sutherland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person76" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person77">
                  John 
                  Langley 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person77" type="surname" value="Langley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person77" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person78">
                  George 
                  Gaudy 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person78" type="surname" value="Gaudy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person78" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17380222-4-person79">
                  William 
                  Hamilton 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person79" type="surname" value="Hamilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person79" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , appeared to the Prisoner's Character as a civil Man, and not given to quarrelling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-4-person80">
                  Silvester 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17380222-4-person80" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person80" type="given" value="Silvester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was just now without the Door of the Court, and heard Mr. Warrington perswade a Woman to come in; but she said she would not swear for 20 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Warrington. A Woman at the Door ask'd me if Mr. Hilliard was upon his Trial, I said yes; and if she knew any Thing of the Matter she might come into Court. No, said she, I won't swear any Thing about him, but he's a vile Rogue, and deserves to be hang'd.</p>
               <p>Jury. We would desire to know if the Deceased had any Power to arrest him in the Haymarket !</p>
               <p>A Witness. The Officer had Power to arrest him there. <rs id="t17380222-4-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-4-punish28" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-4-punish28" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-4-defend55 t17380222-4-punish28"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
