<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340710-33">
               <interp inst="t17340710-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-33" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-33" type="date" value="17340710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-33-off129-c183" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-defend247 t17340710-33-off129 t17340710-33-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>39. 
               <persName id="t17340710-33-defend247" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17340710-33-off129" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-off129" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-off129" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               assaulting, ravishing, and against her Will carnally knowing Betteridge the <rs id="t17340710-33-viclabel130" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-victim249 t17340710-33-viclabel130"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17340710-33-person248">
                        John 
                        May 
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person248" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340710-33-person248" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340710-33-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17340710-33-cd131" type="crimeDate">January 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-off129 t17340710-33-cd131"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-victim249" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-victim249" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-off129 t17340710-33-victim249"></join>
                  </persName>
             . On Saturday the 19th of January last, about 5 in the Evening, the Prisoner came to my House - 'tis a Lone-house on <placeName id="t17340710-33-crimeloc132">Enfield-chase</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-33-crimeloc132" type="placeName" value="Enfield-chase"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-33-crimeloc132" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-off129 t17340710-33-crimeloc132"></join> - And ask'd if my Husband<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100018"></xptr> was come home? I said No. He said he wonder'd at that, for he gave him leave to come home sooner than ordinary on Saturdays - The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17340710-33-deflabel133" type="occupation">Master Carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-defend247 t17340710-33-deflabel133"></join>, and belongs to the New-River Works and my Husband is his Man - I kept game Fowls for the Prisoner. He gave Six pence to my Boy, who was 12 Years old, and bid him take care of the Fowls; and Six-pence more to my Child that was sucking at my Breast, and left another Six pence for my other Child who was not at home: Then, says he, your Husband told me he had got fine Pigs, and promised to make me a present of one; but I: will pay him for it. He said they were fine ones, and I am come to look upon them. The Sow and Pigs were in the Stable, and so I took a Candle and went with him thither, we came thro' 2 Doors, which he shut after him, and then came into the Stable.</p>
               <p>Court. How far is the Stable from the House?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. About as far as a cross this Court - I was afraid the Pigs would run out; and so shut the Stable-door</p>
               <p>Council. Did not he lock the Door?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I can't say whether it was lock'd, or only upon the latch - He look'd upon the Sow and Pigs, and said they were fine ones; and then he laid hold of me, beat the Candle out, and threw me down upon a Couple of Faggots, and had to do with me - I cry'd for help, but he put a Hankerchief into my Mouth, and used me so violently that I could make no Noise; but the Sow and Pigs cry'd out, and made a terrible racket.</p>
               <p>Court. Say what he did to you.</p>
               <p>Betteridge. He lay with me with great Violence.</p>
               <p>Council. How?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. He pull'd up my Coats.</p>
               <p>Council. And what then?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. He made use of what he had, and put it into my Body.</p>
               <p>Council. What d'ye call that?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. His Yard.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he do all that was necessary on his part towards getting a Child?</p>
               <p>Betteridge. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Could he possibly do that if you would not comply?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Yes, He did it against my Will.</p>
               <p>Court. I don't find that he made use of any means to terrify you -</p>
               <p>Betteridge No.</p>
               <p>Court. Then would not the least motion of yours have prevented him from doing as you say?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. It was not in my Power.</p>
               <p>Court. The Jury will judge of that - you were but a little way from the House, and if I understood you, the Prisoner did not stop your Mouth till after he had thrown you down. You say you cry'd out before that, but did you cry loud enough for your Boy to hear you?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I believe he might have heard me, if the Pigs had not made such a Noise - When the Prisoner had got his will, he said I should not go out in such a great flurry; and he did all he could to pacify me. I hope says he, you won't tell your Husband; but if you do, I'll turn him out of his Work, and lay him in a Jail for what he owes me. - My Husband ow'd him 7 Guineas and a half, and therefore, tho' my Husband came home that Night, I did not acquaint him with it.</p>
               <p>Court. But if the Prisoner had been convicted of so great an Offence, he must have been hang'd for it; and therefore your Husband would have been out of Danger.</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I know nothing of the Law.</p>
               <p>Council. Did not you prefer an Indictment against the Prisoner at Hicks's-Hall in February last for a Rape?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Yes; but on account of some Objections the Bill was not found.</p>
               <p>Council. And then you indicted him for an Assault with an intent to Ravish?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Yes, but he got off.</p>
               <p>Council. Tho' it was but for an Assault, you gave the same Evidence as now; and swore a compleat Rape - How long was it before you acquainted your Husband with this affair?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Not till the Wednesday<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100019"></xptr> 7 Night after it was done: Tho' I soon found myself very much out of order, and had a violent Pain in my Back - On the 30th of January I apply'd to an Apothecary, and have been under his care ever since.</p>
               <p>Council. How came you to discover it at last?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. My Husband went to Work on the Monday Morning, and that Night the Prisoner came and enquired for me; but I was a bed, and so he went away: But he came again on the Wednesday, and ask'd me if I had told my Husband? I answer'd No, I have not told him yet - I am glad of that, says he, and I hope you won't do it; but I was afraid you had, because he has not come up for his Wages; there is 10s due to him for 5 days Work; and now I'm here I'll pay the Money to you; so he gave me half a Guinea. I told him I could not give him Change; and he said it was no Matter, for I might keep the Six-pence for my self.</p>
               <p>On Thursday I receiv'd a message to meet my Husband the next Day at Mrs. Aylet's, the <placeName id="t17340710-33-crimeloc134">Bird in hand at Waltham-cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-33-crimeloc134" type="placeName" value="Bird in hand at Waltham-cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-33-crimeloc134" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-33-off129 t17340710-33-crimeloc134"></join> . I did not know the meaning of it, but was afraid my Husband had met with another mischance, for once he put his Collar-bone out - So on Friday I went, though I was very ill, and the Woman of the House led me up stairs into a Room, where there was a Fire, but no Company. She said she kept a Fire there to dry Bacon. Presently the Prisoner came up with a Whip in his Hand, and said, by God you are all taken! I ask'd him if my Husband was there. He answer d No, It was I that sent for you; and God Damn it you shall stay Dinner; and if you make any disturbance here, it will be the worse for you; for I have got a pair of Pistols - A Fowl and Bacon was brought; but I had no Stomach, and could not eat any thing. After Dinner, I took my Hat and was going; but he said I should not; and so he laid 2 Pistols on the Table, shut the Door, stuck his Penknife into it, and hung his Great-coat upon it; and then threw me upon the Bed, and used me as he did before in the Stable.</p>
               <p>Court. What did he Ravish you a second Time? - And this in the middle of the Day, and at a Publick-house too?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Yes he did, though I call'd out - as I did before - But nobody came to help me - The Prisoner said, You may tell your Husband of this if you will; for now you come after me: And so I came away.</p>
               <p>Court. Why did not you apprehend the Prisoner then? Was there ne'er a Constable in the Town?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I was so ill, that I could not go to look for a Constable, but went di-directly home.</p>
               <p>Court. Did not you know it was the Prisoner that sent for you to that House.</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Who did you ask for when you came thither?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Nobody I went by the Door, before I enquir'd for the Bird-in-hand; and the Woman of the House was then at the Window, and saw me, and so she came to the Door.</p>
               <p>Court. Did she know you then?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. No, I believe she had never seen me before, but the Prisoner had described my Riding-hood to her.</p>
               <p>Court. Upon your Oath did not you enquire for Mr. - ?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. No, upon my Oath - My Husband came home the next Day, which was Saturday; but I had such a Dread upon my Spirits, that I was afraid to tell him.</p>
               <p>Court. How came you to tell him at last?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I grew so bad, that I knew not how to conceal it any longer.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you send a Pig to the Prisoner on the Sunday Morning?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. No, but my Husband did before I was up; for I was ill a Bed: But when he told me of it, I said, I wish'd he had not done it - There's a Bill against the Prisoner at Hertford for this last Fact - 'Tis for an Assault with an intent to Ravish.</p>
               <p>Court. Why for an Assault only, whereas you swear the Fact was compleated.</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. I did not understand the Law, but I told my Attorney how I was serv'd.</p>
               <p>Attorney. She told me it was only an Assault.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100020"></xptr>Prisoner. On the 19th of January was any Body in your House besides your Children?</p>
               <p>Betteridge May. Not in my House, but in the Next there was a Man and a Woman, and a Girl; and they might hear me cry out, but I believe they thought it was the Pigs.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She let me out afterwards, and bid me good Night - Her Mouth was not stopt then; but she made no complaint to any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-person250">
                  John 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17340710-33-person250" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have work'd for the Prisoner near 9 Years, and indeed he has been a good friend to me. I owed him 7 Guineas and a half. I came home between 9 and 10 on Saturday Night, my Boy told me my Master - had been there, and given him and his Brother Six-pence a piece. My Wife said nothing of this Matter to me; and I had no mistrust of her or the Prisoner, for I knew nothing of their Contrigues. So I went to work again on Monday, and on Thursday the Prisoner came and said, do you go home to Night, John? - if you do, you shall never strike another stroke for me. Why, Sir? says I; where will be the harm as long as I keep my Time?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. But you had neglected your time very much by going home a Nights.</p>
               <p>John May. So I did not go home till Saturday Night, and then my Wife was very ill, and complain'd of a Pain in her Back, and said she believ'd she had got a Fever; and she cry'd - I had promised a Pig to the Prisoner, and so I sent one in the Morning before she was up: and he sent me half a Crown for it - On the Wednesday Night following I was very urgent to do what married Men should do; but she refused: And I insisted upon knowing the meaning of it; and so she was forced to confess, or else she had given it to me. She said that the Prisoner went with her into the Stable to see the Pigs, but did not lock the Door, and then threw her upon the Faggots and lay with her by force; but she said nothing of the second Fact, till after I had got a Warrant for him; and then she told me, and said she did not tell me sooner for fear I should turn her quite out of Doors.</p>
               <p>John May, the Son. I heard a Noise when my Mother and the Prisoner were in the Stable, but I thought it had been the Sow and Pigs; and when my Mother came in she had a high Colour, her Cap was tumbled, and her Hair about her Ears - Before they went into the Stable, the Prisoner sent me to get his Horse out of the Stable for fear he should hurt the Pigs - But Mr. Newman took the Horse out and put into the Wash-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-person251">
                  Rebecca 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17340710-33-person251" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person251" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Our House joins to Mrs May's: I remember the Night the Prisoner was there, and saw them both go into the Stable; they staid there about half an Hour -I heard no squeeling nor crying - But we were spinning and our Wheels made a Noise. He came out of the Stable alone, and in a little Time he mounted his Horse and went away; but did not see her come out - The next Night she complained to me of a Pain in her Back, and a burning within - I ask'd her if it was a Fever? and she said No, I never was so in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-person252">
                  Joseph 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17340710-33-person252" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person252" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I fetch'd the Horse out of the Stable, and put him into the Washhouse; but I don't know who fetch'd him out of the Wash-house when the Prisoner went away, for I did not see him go - On Tuesday Night following between 8 and 9 the Prisoner came to the Door and whistled. I look'd out, and he asked if Mrs. May was within - She is gone to Bed, says I; shall I call her? No, says he, it's no matter.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-person253">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Aylet 
               <interp inst="t17340710-33-person253" type="surname" value="Aylet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person253" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Bird-in-hand at Waltham-cross - On Friday Morning the Prisoner was at my House. About 9 the Prosecutrix knock'd at the Door (tho' the Door was open) and said, Is one Mr. - here? I said, Yes he's in the Kitchen with some Men, will you please to go in? No, said she, if there is Company I had rather you'll call him out.</p>
               <p>Court. She swore that she did not ask for him or any body.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Aylet. She ask'd for him by Name; and so I shew'd her into the Parlour, and told him; but he was smoaking his Pipe, and did not come presently. She complain'd there was no Fire in the Parlour, and so I led her up<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100021"></xptr> stairs - The Prisoner came up and said, So! So! have I catch'd you napping? Then he saluted her, and call'd for a Quartern of Brandy. She drank a little of it, but she chose to have a hot Pot, and so I made one, and after that another; they seem'd to be very friendly, and abundance of pretty Compliments past between them - He said she was an old Acquaintance that he had met on the Road, and would treat her with what the House afforded. I told them I had Bacon an Eggs, - No - Or Salt Fish and Eggs - No - Or a Pullet full of Eggs - Aye, says she, that will do; and he bid me get it ready; and so I did, and she eat part of a Wing - They sat at the Foot of the Bed, and I left them several times together, for I thought no harm.</p>
               <p>Council. Had he any Pistols?</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Aylet. Yes, and he laid them on the Chest of Drawers; for he usually laid them down when he came in.</p>
               <p>Council How came it that he did not lay them down in the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Aylet. Because he was just a-going, but it raining a little, he sat down to smoak a Pipe, and was in the Kitchen about an Hour with 2 other Men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-33-person254">
                  James 
                  Jarvis 
               <interp inst="t17340710-33-person254" type="surname" value="Jarvis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person254" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . John May came several times after me, to desire me to go and make this matter up: I ask'd him how he came to Prosecute so good a Master? He answer'd; he has been a very good Master; and if my Wife had told me the Truth at first, I would have gone another way to work. went to the Prisoner, who said, I know nothing of it; but he owes me a little Money, and I suppose this is some Trick. So I went again to John May, and ask'd him what he meant by beginning such a Prosecution as might take away his Master's Life. He said, No, I don't design that - But that will be the consequence, says I, if the Fact is proved. No, says he again, if it should come to that, I would not appear.</p>
               <p>Council. The Woman don't pretend that the Prisoner made use of any Threats to terrify her, and therefore she had Liberty to call out for help; and she might have cry'd loud enough to have been heard; but it does not appear that any Body heard her.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17340710-33-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-33-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
