<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370114-16">
               <interp inst="t17370114-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-16" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-16" type="date" value="17370114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-16-off78-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend141 t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-verdict82"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-16-off78-c102" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend143 t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-verdict82"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-16-off78-c103" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend145 t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140010"></xptr>20. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-defend141" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Ryan 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend141" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend141" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Garret 
                     Farrel 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend143" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend143" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-defend145" type="defendantName">
                     Hugh 
                     Macmahon 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend145" type="surname" value="Macmahon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend145" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-defend145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17370114-16-off78" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-off78" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-off78" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370114-16-victim147" type="victimName">
                           Edmund 
                           Rowbottom 
                        <interp inst="t17370114-16-victim147" type="surname" value="Rowbottom"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-16-victim147" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-16-victim147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-victim147"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Field near the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from a Hat, value 2 s a Peruke, value 2 s. a Cloth Coat, value 5 s. a Cloth Waistcoat value 5 s. a holland Shirt, value 6 s a Pair of Stockings, value 2 s. a Pair of Buckles, value 1 s a Pair of Shoes, value 18 d. Pair of Buckskin Breeches, value 10 s. and 3 s 6 d. in Money
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17370114-16-cd79" type="crimeDate">Nov. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-cd79"></join>. [The Witnesses were examin'd apart.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-person148">
                  Edward 
                  Rowbottom 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person148" type="surname" value="Rowbottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person148" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I can't say the Prisoners are the Men; but on the 26th of November, between and eight, I was robb'd in the Field, beyond the Half-way-House going to <placeName id="t17370114-16-crimeloc80">Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-16-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-16-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-off78 t17370114-16-crimeloc80"></join>. They took my Hat and Wig, my Coat, Waistcoat, Breeches, Shirt, Shoes, Stockings, and Buckles. Afterwards they bound my Hands behind me, and my left Leg up to my Hands then they ty'd a Handkerchief over my Mouth, and rolled me into a Ditch; they took my Money 3 s. 6 d. as well as my Cloaths, and that was all Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How many was there of them?</p>
               <p>Rowbottom. There was three of them, two led me down the Field, and the third followed me. 'Twas a little Moon-light, but they kept an old Hat over my Face, that I should not see them. Two of them were much of a Size, and one was a little taller.</p>
               <p>Ryan. With humble Submission, - these Thief-catchers have instructed him too, in all Villanies.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-person149">
                  Terence
                   O'Bryan
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person149" type="surname" value="O'Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person149" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Ryan, Farrel, Macmahon, and one Macdonal, went out with Intention to rob on the Highway: We went above the Half-way-House into the Foot-Road. We heard a Man coming up the Path, so Ryan, Farrel, and I went up to him, and brought him down to the Bottom of the Field, farthest from the Road; we took 3 s. 6 d. from him, - half a Crown and two Six-pences This was beyond Mother Redcap's, just at the Back of Kentish Town. When we had got him into the Field, Ryan bid him deliver his Money; then he commanded Farrel and I to bring him to the Ditch. The Man - I don't know who he was, but he told us he was but a poor <rs id="t17370114-16-viclabel81" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-victim147 t17370114-16-viclabel81"></join>; he made no resistance, so we took from him his Hat, Wig, Coat, Waistcoat, Shirt, Breeches, Stockings, Shoes and Buckles. The Stockings were found upon Ryan, which the Man has sworn to.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do next?</p>
               <p>O Bryan. We bound him with a Penny Cord, and turn'd him into the Ditch; both his Hands were ty'd behind him and one of his Legs. Ryan, Farrel and I, were with the Man when he was bound; the others stood in the High Road.</p>
               <p>Ryan. With what intent did they stand there</p>
               <p>O'Bryan. For fear any enterprize should come upon us: When we had done, Macmahon and Macdonald came up to us and join'd us.</p>
               <p>Ryan. Observe how often he convinces ( contradict ) his own Story.</p>
               <p>O Bryan. The Man's Cloaths were brought the same Night to Ryan's Room, and his Wife pawn'd them.</p>
               <p>Ryan. Let his Informations before Col. De-Viel, and the Governor of the Tower be produc'd then we'll stand in our own Defence. I don't alledge in my own Behalf in the least. I have trangress'd; but 'tis a Sin and a Shame the Oath of a Villain should be taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-person150">
                  Owen 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person150" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person150" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I was before Col. Williamson O Bryan told me that Ryan had the Stockings on his Legs, and the Buckles in his Shoes, which they took from Rowbottom. I went to Ryan in Newgate and took them off his Legs, here they are.</p>
               <p>Rowbottom. These are the Stockings and Buckles they took from me.</p>
               <p>Griffith. I bought him another Pair, and took them off.</p>
               <p>Ryan. I pull'd them off, - I was obliged to pull them off, as I might be my Shirt, when these Fellows swear so.</p>
               <p>Col. Williamson. This is O'Bryan's Information; it was read over to him, and he Sign'd it before me.</p>
               <p>The Information of 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person151">
                  Terence
                   O'Bryan
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person151" type="surname" value="O'Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person151" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , taken before Col. Williamson.</p>
               <p>Who saith, That he, with 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person152">
                  James 
                  Ryan 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person152" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person152" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person153">
                  Hugh 
                  Macmahon 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person153" type="surname" value="Macmahon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person153" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person154">
                  Garret 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person154" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person154" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person155">
                  John 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person155" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person155" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were out about a Month since, upon the Road to Hampstead, and that particularly, the latter End of last Month they robb'd a Man who appears to be 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person156">
                  Benjamin 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person156" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person156" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , stripping him and tying him in the Manner he deposed, on the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person157">
                  Gilbert 
                  Fruer 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person157" type="surname" value="Fruer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person157" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and for which Fact at the Old-Bailey the said Fruer was condemned. And he farther saith, the said Fruer was not concerned in the said Robbery, nor doth he know him. He farther saith, that among the Things taken, were a Knife, and a Pair of Buckles, both which were produced by O'Bryan, and sworn by Short to be the Buckles and Knife taken from him. He says that Macdonald was not assisting in this Robbery, but was within Call, if his assistance should be wanted. He farther faith, that 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person158">
                  James 
                  Ryan 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person158" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about two Months ago, robb'd a single Man on the Road between Highgate<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140011"></xptr> and Kentish Town, which Man was stopp'd by Ryan, who with Fitzgerald robb'd him of Money, and stripp'd him to his Skin, ty'd him, and left him in a Ditch; that the Money they took from him was about 9s. as Ryan had told him. That Falconer is a thick Man, about 36 Years old, wears a Wig but often a Cap: Fitzgerald is about 23 Years old a tight Man in a brown Wig.</p>
               <p>Col. Williamson. He made several Depositions, some Robberies he forgot, and he recollected them by piece meal; they came out one after another. Here is another Information. - Terence O'Bryan farther deposeth, that 
               <persName id="t17370114-16-person159">
                  Garret 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person159" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person159" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was concerned in a Robbery at Hampstead, by robbing, stripping, and binding a Man; the said Farrel is a tall, lusty Fellow, full Face, black Hair, wears a red Coat, and is about 28 Years of Age. He farther says, that Dun and Lacey were concerned in the above Robbery, and all the rest, and likewise in enlisting Men for the Service of the French King.</p>
               <p>Farrel. I can bring a Woman to prove that I was elsewhere at the same Time, doing Work for honest Victuals. - Pray from whence did we descend to do this Robbery.</p>
               <p>O'Bryan From one Dive's House four of us went; there were two more than I have mentioned, and they are Lacey and Dun. I don't know the Prosecutor Rowbottom, but at the Robbery the 26th of November, there was Ryan, Farrel, Macmahon, and Macdonald, and my self, and one Lacey, who is gone to France, and that is the Reason he is not mark'd. Lacey went out with us, but he staid a little behind in the Road, waiting till we came back. Dives is a Soldier in the Guards, and keeps a Cook's Shop in Newtoners-Lane. Farrel I have known this 12 Months, he came over to recruit for the King of France.</p>
               <p>Farrel. I serve his Majesty, - God bless him, and that Rogue says, I serve the King of France.</p>
               <p>Ryan. With humble Submission, - this Rogue when he was apprehended, - but I can't rightly tell it you, - he had two Coats of other People's on his Back.</p>
               <p>Col. Williamson. O'Bryan was taken by the Custom-house Officers, on Tower-Hill, on Suspicion of having a Parcel of Tea. This I had from Colonel Deacon, who came to me, and said he had committed a Man the Day before, to the Gaol of the Tower Liberty, on Suspicion of being a naughty Person, for he had found a Pocket Pistol upon him, and he desir'd my Assistance to examine him. There appear'd nothing against him but his having two Coats and a loaded Pistol, made us suspect him to be a naughty Fellow. I threaten'd to commit him, and in an Advertisement to describe him, and the two Coats which were found upon him, if he would not discover his Accomplices He said he was innocent, and would make no Discovery, so we made his Mittimus, but as he was going down Stairs, he desired to be brought back again; then he told us, we had no Proof of any Thing against him, but however he would become a frank Evidence for the King, and then he declared all these Things. I found he had been a Soldier in the French King's Service.</p>
               <p>Farrel. There is nothing against me but this Man, and upon my Shoul, he would hang all the Court for the Sake of the Reward.</p>
               <p>Eliz Dorrel. Farrel came to live at my House the first of November, - the first of October I mean, and he liv'd there till the Time he was taken up, which was the 23d of December. He us'd all the while he abided in my House to go out betimes in a Morning with his Knot and Basket to Market; he always came Home about 10 or 11 o'Clock in the Forenoon, and never stirr'd out an Hour till the next Morning; he never stirr'd out of the House from the first of October to the 23d of December, after he return'd in a Morning from Market.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, if he never in all this Time stirr'd out, neither in the Afternoons nor in the Evenings, how did he spend his Time?</p>
               <p>Dorrel. In cleaning the Knives, or fetching me Water, or playing with the Children. He has never been from the Door in any Evening all this Time.</p>
               <p>Q. On the 15th of November, where was he then?</p>
               <p>Dorrel. At Home, as I am on my Oath, and the Virtue of it, I don't swear he was never out of the House, - I have no Occasion to suspect (inspect) into Days of the Month, but I am sure he was never out of the House to my Knowledge; 'tis true I have been out my self sometimes; but I have left him to take Care of the House.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Week was the 26th of November?</p>
               <p>Dorrel. 'Twas Sunday if I can tell. No, I don't know the Day of the Week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the 26th of November?</p>
               <p>Dorrel. I can't say - but on the Virtue of my Oath, I never miss'd him out the 26th nor the 25th. He was never out of my House; and as for the Man that has sworn against him, he never was in his Company in his Life.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140012"></xptr>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-16-person160">
                  Jane
                   O'Callan
               <interp inst="t17370114-16-person160" type="surname" value="O'Callan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person160" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I us'd to open the Door to him every Morning when he went out to Market; when he came from Market, he would be in the House all the Week; on Sundays he us'd to go out a Shoe blacking. Upon my Life, he us'd always to be at Home, I can't say (no) more. All <rs id="t17370114-16-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370114-16-punish83" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-16-punish83" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend141 t17370114-16-punish83"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend143 t17370114-16-punish83"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-16-defend145 t17370114-16-punish83"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
