<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351015-39">
               <interp inst="t17351015-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-39" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-39" type="date" value="17351015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-39-off164-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-39-defend320 t17351015-39-off164 t17351015-39-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>49. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-39-defend320" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Gibbens 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-39-defend320" type="surname" value="Gibbens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-39-defend320" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-39-defend320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17351015-39-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-39-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-39-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing three Portugal Pieces, Value 5 l. 8 s. and two Guineas, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351015-39-victim322" type="victimName">
                           Michael 
                           Graham 
                        <interp inst="t17351015-39-victim322" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-39-victim322" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-39-victim322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-39-off164 t17351015-39-victim322"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17351015-39-cd165" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-39-off164 t17351015-39-cd165"></join>.</p>
               <p>- Graham. About Eleven at Night the Prisoner came into an House where I was drinking. His Face and Hands were bloody, and he told me that his Landlord had abused him, and turned him out of his Lodging. It may be your Fault, says I, for when I lodged in the same House, the Man was civil to me. In a little Time I got up and went out; the Prisoner followed, and desired me to let him lie with me for one Night. As he was my Countryman, and destitute of a Lodging, I at last consented, tho' I had another Bed-fellow. So we went to my Room together. I undress'd and went to Bed before the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150018"></xptr>My Money was tied fast in the Tail of my Shirt. My other Bed-fellow and I belonging to a Brewhouse three Doors from my Lodging, and being to get up early, I desired the Prisoner to lie on the farther Side, but he would needs lie next to me. In half an Hour my other Bed-fellow got up to go to Work, and after he was gone I am sure my Money was in the Tail of my Shirt, for I had it in my Hand. I went to sleep, and lay above two Hours, and having over-slept myself, I was called up in a Hurry to go to the Brewhouse; upon which I dress'd myself in such haste, that I did not mind whether my Money was safe or not; but in a Quarter of an Hour after I was come to the Brewhouse, I miss'd it. I could not immediately leave the Work I was then about, but in about half an Hour more, I went back and met the Prisoner coming out at the Street-Door. I asked him how he could serve me so as to take my Money, when I had been so civil to him. He answered; What a Noise you make, hold your Tongue, and you'll get your Money again. So we both went up into my Room, and he pulled off his Shoes, and bid me search him. I called to my Landlady, and bid her keep the Door till I fetched a Constable. But I never found my Money. I did not then know the Prisoner's right Name, for he went by the Name of Beau Nash.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was in Liquor, and so was I, and I know no more of the Money than the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351015-39-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-39-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
