<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-30">
               <interp inst="t17390607-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-30" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-30" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-30-off145-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-30-defend235 t17390607-30-off145 t17390607-30-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>367. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-30-defend235" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Cary 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-30-defend235" type="surname" value="Cary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-defend235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-defend235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390607-30-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch, with an out-side Case made of Silver, gilt, val. 6 l. two Gold Pendants for Watches, val. 12 s. two Pair of Chrystal Buttons set in Gold, val. 10 s. two Guineas, and 4 s. in Money; a Gold Ring set with eight Stones, val. 18 s. a Silver Watch Chain, val. 12 d. and a Pair of Cloth Breeches, val. 12 d. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390607-30-victim237" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Elliot 
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim237" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . And a brown Silk Camblet Coat, val. 10 s. a Scarlet Lepelle Waistcoat, val. 4 s. a Pair of brown Silk Camblet Breeches, val. 12 d. and a Pair of Serge ditto, val. 12 d. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390607-30-victim239" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Goodman 
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim239" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim239" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-victim239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17390607-30-person240">
                        George 
                        Lumley 
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person240" type="surname" value="Lumley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-person240" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-30-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17390607-30-cd146" type="crimeDate">Jan. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-30-off145 t17390607-30-cd146"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Elliot. I lodged in Lumley's House in the <placeName id="t17390607-30-crimeloc147">Old Baily</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-30-crimeloc147" type="placeName" value="Old Baily"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-30-crimeloc147" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-30-off145 t17390607-30-crimeloc147"></join>: The Prisoner was recommended to me by Lumley, as an honest Man, so I let him lie with me; and on Friday, the 12th of January last, he stripp'd me of all I had in the World, and did not leave me one Farthing to save my Life. I lost all the Goods and Money mention'd in the Indictment as my Property, and I am sure the Prisoner is the Man who robb'd me; I don't say I saw him take them away, but he was taken with them all upon him. I am sure I never took a Farthing from him but us'd to give him Three-Halfpence every Morning. I won't tell a Lie for the whole Globe. I had all the Things in my Pocket, and was to have gone to Flanders on Monday Morning, if I had not been robb'd I should have been gone gone before, if I had not waited for some Things a Man was making for me to carry with me. I never saw the Prisoner from the Time I was robb'd till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-30-person241">
                  William 
                  Whiteer 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person241" type="surname" value="Whiteer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person241" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (or Whitehead) I lodged in Shoe Lane, at a Woman's House, who us'd to sell a Dram. The Prisoner frequently came there for a Dram, and I have now and then drank a Dram with him. On the 12th of January, between Five and Six in the Morning, he knock'd at the Door, and said he came to pay my Landlady 6 d. or 7 d. which he ow'd her; she let him in, and he asked for me; she told him I was abed, and he bid her call me down to drink a Dram with him, and tell me he had some Shipmates at Brentford, who had appointed him to meet them there, in order to sell some India Goods: I would not go down, so he came up to my Bed-side, with half a Pint of Gin in his Hand, and my Bed-fellow and I drank two Glasses apiece, and he told me he was to meet some Shipmates at Eleven o'Clock, at Brentford, and if I would go with him he would give me a Crown: So I set out with him; and in Piccadilly, as we pass'd a Night-cellar, I said, a Draught of Beer will do us no Harm after our Drams; so we went in and drank. While we were in the Night-cellar, he pull'd out this Watch; I asked him what 'twas o'Clock? He could not tell; so I took it out of his Hand, and found it stood; I wound it up, and set it a-going, then he took it, and put it in his Pocket. At Brentford he shew'd it me again, and told me it cost him 15 l. I guess'd it at 10 l. and imagin'd it was only Pinchbeck's Metal, but he took a Knife, and upon scraping the Edges of the Case, found it to be Silver. After we had eat a Rasher of Bacon, he told me he could not stay, for he was going to Bristol, and from thence to Ireland, and he desired me not to take any Notice where he was gone: So I left him, and came homewards, and being afterwards at the Bull and Garter, by the Ditch-side, I saw an Advertisement, which occasion'd my telling the Landlord that I had been that very Day with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070016"></xptr> Prisoner at Brentford; so we went to Lumley, and he and I hired Horses to pursue him. At Reading, Lumley could go no farther; but I went on to Newbury and seized him, with all the Goods upon him: A Gold Ring set with Stones, a Gold Watch, the out-side of which was Silver, gilt; a Gold Stone Ring; the Gold Buttons, and the Gold Pendants, &amp;c. All which I delivered to Lumley, who had advertised him. I did not search him for Money, but all the rest of the Things were found on him, except the Cloth Breeches. I then charged him with the Robbery, and he owned it, and said he took the Breeches out of the Chair, in Elliot's Room. He had a Silk Camblet Coat, a Scarlet Lepelle Waistcoat, and two Pair of Breeches on; one Pair was Silk Camblet, I don't remember what the other was. The Prisoner own'd he stole all these Things in 
               <persName id="t17390607-30-person242">
                  George 
                  Lumley 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person242" type="surname" value="Lumley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person242" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's House, in the Old Baily, and they were delivered to Lumley.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-30-person243">
                  George 
                  Lumley 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person243" type="surname" value="Lumley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person243" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Goods are all here but the Watch, and I borrowed Money upon that when I came from pursuing the Prisoner, for I had spent Money upon the Road, and Elliot told me, he would pay my Charges. I staid at Reading, and Mr. Whiteer brought the Prisoner to me, and he gave me the Gold Pendants and the Silver Watch-chain, because he owed me Money, 45 s. when he went away; I asked him for Money, but he gave me no more than six or seven Shillings, I borrowed Money at the Elephant and Castle, in Fleet Lane, to go with Whiteer after the Prisoner, who had left all his Things at my House, and had taken Elliot's. There were two Pair of the Breeches, and the Lepelle Waistcoat belong'd to another Lodger, one 
               <persName id="t17390607-30-person244">
                  John 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person244" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that Waistcoat I have now at Home, for Goodwin is gone abroad, and would not take it with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-30-person245">
                  William 
                  Goodhall 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person245" type="surname" value="Goodhall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person245" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Here are the small Things: Lumley brought them to me, and I lent him 10s. upon them. Here's a Ring, and a Pair of Buttons, set in Gold, a Pair of Gold Pendants, and a Watch-chain. Lumley told me he pawned them by the Direction of the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Lumley. The Watch I pawned to a Gentleman in Charterhouse-Lane, - but I don't know his Name. I had laid out 3 l. 9 s. on my Journey, and when I came Home, I had no Money for my Family, so I pawned the Things.</p>
               <p>Elliot. I never had a Word of Discourse with Lumley about pawning the Goods. When he came Home, he told me, he had taken Care of the Chap, (the Prisoner) and had taken fresh Horses at Reading, and so went to Newberry, where he seized the Prisoner, and brought him to Reading. Well, says I, what have you done with my Goods? Your Goods, says he, are in the Justice of Peace's Hands, at Reading. He had no Money when he went after the Prisoner; and when he came Home, I observed he was very flush in Money, but he never said a Word of his having pawned my Goods, 'till six Weeks or two Months after he came back.</p>
               <p>Lumley. I mentioned it to him, about a Fortnight or three Weeks after I had pawned them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I gave Elliot six Ounces of Gold for these Goods.</p>
               <p>Elliot. I never had to the Value of a Pin, or a Pin's Point, from him in my Life, as I am in the Presence of Almighty God.</p>
               <p>Lumley. Whiteer brought all the Things in his Pocket to me at Reading, except the Gold Buttons and Pendants; they were in the Breeches the Prisoner had on, and he told Justice Pottinger he took them instead of his own, and found the Things in them. Whiteer said he would hang the Prisoner, - he would hang him for the Reward of 40 s. which I had promised for taking him.</p>
               <p>Whiteer. I did demand the 40 s. of Lumley, and he abused me in a scandalous Manner, and told me the Man should not be hanged on any Account, and he himself would appear a Witness against me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-30-person246">
                  Roger 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17390607-30-person246" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person246" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has been in my House about five Months ago, and behaved well. I have heard Whiteer say, he would do what he could to hang the Prisoner. He said it was his Due, and he would take Care he should be hang'd, if possible. I can't say I heard any Thing mentioned about the Reward.</p>
               <p>The Court ordered Lumley to produce the Watch, and Restitution to be made of that and the other Goods to Elliot, and the Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17390607-30-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment. <rs id="t17390607-30-punish149" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-30-punish149" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-30-defend235 t17390607-30-punish149"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
