<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-69">
               <interp inst="t17360908-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-69" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-69" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-69-off281-c307" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-69-defend463 t17360908-69-off281 t17360908-69-verdict284"></join>
         
               <p>81. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-69-defend463" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Sanders 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-69-defend463" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-defend463" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-defend463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17360908-69-off281" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-off281" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-off281" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Ring with a Chrystal Stone
            </rs>, from the Person of Priscilla, <rs id="t17360908-69-viclabel282" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-69-victim466 t17360908-69-viclabel282"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17360908-69-person464">
                  Thomas 
                  London 
               <interp inst="t17360908-69-person464" type="surname" value="London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person464" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17360908-69-cd283" type="crimeDate">July 20, 1733</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-69-off281 t17360908-69-cd283"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-69-victim466" type="victimName">
                     Priscilla 
                     London 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-69-victim466" type="surname" value="London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-victim466" type="given" value="Priscilla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-victim466" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-69-off281 t17360908-69-victim466"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . I employed the Prisoner to get in some Debts for me, and in July, I don't well know the Day, he was looking on my Hand in our Kitchen, and says he, you have a very beautiful Ring, let me see it: then he took hold of my Hand, and took it off my Finger; Madam, says he, there is a Noise at your Door, and up he got, and away he ran with it. I met him next Day in the Minories, and he told me I should have it again. I looked after him for half a Year, and then I gave him over.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Madam, don't you remember the Day, you and I were at Well's, the Cooks, in Leadenhall-street, when you and I had Pig for Dinner? I have been a little foolish in loving your Sex too much; but, pray Madam, have not you own'd, you would never have taken me up, if I had not told your Husband, that you gave it me for a Merry Bout you and I had together? Don't you know that Charlesworth was to bring an Action against me for Criminal Conversation with you! Did not you declare, you was obliged to take out a Warrant against me to please your Husband?</p>
               <p>Priscilla London. What I said, was, that you was a good for nothing Man, and when I heard your Wife say, that you and I were gone together, I said to my Husband, now go and take him up for the Ring. You made no Ring but a laugh of me, and bid me kiss your -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not your Husband come to my House and offer to make it up for 6 s.</p>
               <p>Priseilla London. I heard that you offer'd 6 s.? but my Husband would not agree. I did go to the Justices to have it decided, but you had no Money to pay for Stamps, nor general Releases.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you agree afterwards to make it up again for 14 s.</p>
               <p>London. Yes, my Husband had your Note for 14 s but he flung it to you again, at the Justice's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She keeps a Baudy House in Squirrel Alley; I'll prove you gave me the Ring at Wells's a Cook's in Leaden-Hall street, where we din'd together; then I went home with you, and you and I drank 2 or 3 Drams together. Don't you know when you met me in the Minories the next Day, that you said, My dear, do you intend to keep the Ring, or have one made, and I said, my Dear, the Ring is safe enough.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-69-person467">
                  Thomas 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17360908-69-person467" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person467" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I dined with the Prosecutor and Prisoner in Leaden Hall Street, we had Pig, and strong Beer, and a Bottle of Wine for Dinner, up one pair of Stairs. The Ring was on her Finger then, and he said, my Dear, lend me that Ring, she gave it him, and said, there my Dear, there it is.</p>
               <p>London. I never saw this Man in my Life.</p>
               <p>J. Lancashire. I saw Mrs. London and the Prisoner in Wood-street Compter; they were making up the Matter, but he wanted Money, I went home to fetch him Money, but when I came back, I found a fresh Warrant taken out against him, and that he was sent to Newgate. Mrs. London told me she never intended to have let it come to this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-69-person468">
                  John 
                  Philpey 
               <interp inst="t17360908-69-person468" type="surname" value="Philpey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person468" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. London owned before me, that she believed he did not take the Ring with any Design to keep it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-69-person469">
                  Mary 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17360908-69-person469" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person469" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-person469" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. London's Husband said in my hearing, he would make it up for 12 s. <rs id="t17360908-69-verdict284" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-69-verdict284" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
