<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-39">
               <interp inst="t17361208-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-39" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-39" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-39-off220-c249" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-defend354 t17361208-39-off220 t17361208-39-verdict223"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-39-off220-c250" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-defend356 t17361208-39-off220 t17361208-39-verdict223"></join>
         
               <p>55. 56. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-defend354" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Sutton 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend354" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend354" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-defend356" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                      Campbell , otherwise <rs id="t17361208-39-alias-9" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-defend356 t17361208-39-alias-9"></join>Bob the Glazier</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend356" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend356" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-defend356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17361208-39-off220" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-off220" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-off220" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-39-victim358" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-39-victim358" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-39-victim358" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-39-victim358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-off220 t17361208-39-victim358"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Hanger with a Horn Handle, value 20 s. a Silver Watch, value 5 l. a Cornelian Seal set in Gold, value 20 s. and 10 Guineas in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17361208-39-cd221" type="crimeDate">November 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-off220 t17361208-39-cd221"></join>.</p>
               <p>James Smith. About Nine o'Clock on Monday Night, November 8, I was walking along <placeName id="t17361208-39-crimeloc222">Great Russel Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-39-crimeloc222" type="placeName" value="Great Russel Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-39-crimeloc222" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-off220 t17361208-39-crimeloc222"></join>, and was attack'd by two Men under Mountague House, near the Gateway. One of them struck me on the Breast with his Fist, and bid me deliver; the other immediately seiz'd my Hanger, drew it out of the Scaboard, and held the Point of it to my Breast: They bid me make no Noise, if I did, I was a dead Man. I desired them not to use me ill, and told them I would give them what Money I had about me: They made no Answer to this, but one of them took hold of the String of my Watch, and pull'd it out of my Fob. I believe they are the Men, but I cannot take upon me to swear to them. I apprehend that Campbell (the shortest of the Prisoners) was the Man that took my Watch, and the ten Guineas and a Key: He held the Money in his Hand, and by the Light of the Moon, look'd to see how much he had got. I desired them to return me the Key, and they did so: When they had rifled me, they bid me pick up my Cane (which I had dropp'd) and then they went over on the other side of the Way. I look'd in the Face of the Man that struck me; but when the other presented the Hanger's Point to my Breast, I was afraid to give them Offence, by looking earnestly at them. As they were crossing the Way, I ask'd them for my Hanger; they bid me not make a Noise, if I did, they said they would return and murder me.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to swear that the Prisoners, or either of them, are the Men?</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. I cannot; they were very expeditious, in their Work, and I had not time, while they were robbing me, to take particular Notice of them. I went to the Printer of the Daily Advertiser, and described the Watch, promising a Reward of five Guineas for it again; and Notice was brought me from Mr Goddard, who keeps the Crown at St. Giles's, that the Prisoners were taken that Night I went to Mr. Goddard, and he inform'd me that he had found the Goods upon the Prisoners. The next Day we carry'd them before Justice De Veil, and the Hanger, Watch, and Seal, which were found upon them, were produced. I cannot swear to the Prisoners, but I swear that the Hanger, Watch and Seal, are mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Discourse with them then, or afterwards?</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. No; they were brought from the Gatehouse to the Justice's, that I might see them; but I could not swear to them.</p>
               <p>Campbel. Nothing was found upon me but the Money; I desire to know whether the Gentleman will swear to that: I had nothing but the Money upon me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. No, I can't swear to Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-person359">
                  Francis 
                  Waker 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person359" type="surname" value="Waker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person359" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a Warrant from Justice De Viel, against Campbel and another Man, for stealing a Gold Watch, and I took him up on<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080024"></xptr> that Account; I carried him to Mr. Goddard, at the Crown Alehouse, and asked him about the Gold Watch, says he I can help you to two or three Man, for I have just now made a Watch, and have tipp'd 
               <persName id="t17361208-39-person360">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person360" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person360" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Hanger and the Loge. Since I am babbl'd myself, I will babble two or three more, and he nam'd two or three more, and directed us to the Cole Yard. but we found only George Sutton there, though he told us we should find two or more there. When we seiz'd Sutton we searched him, and found the Hanger in his Bosom. Then we brought him to Mr. Goddard's, and put Sutton in one Room, and Campbel in another; says Campbel, search Sutton again, for I am sure he has got the Loge; we searched him again, and found the Watch in his Breeches, under his Ham. Campbel went with us to the Cole yard, and shewed us the House where we found Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the Hanger that was taken from Sutton? (to Waker. )</p>
               <p>Sutton. Yes, yes, - he'll swear it no Doubt.</p>
               <p>Waker. When we felt the Watch in Sutton's Breeches, he said, come, come, I'll give you no more Trouble, - I'll give it you, but it would have served to have kept me in Newgate</p>
               <p>Sutton. You are a for-swearing Rogue.</p>
               <p>C. This Behaviour don't become you, when a Man is swearing in a Court of Justice, what so much affects you.</p>
               <p>Waker I believe this is the Hanger; I did not take so much Notice of the Watch as I did of the Hanger. Mr. Goddard took the Watch out of Sutton's Breeches, and he did not deny the Fact at all, but said, - now since Bob the Glazier has serv'd me, I will serve him; go search him again, for he has got a Lump of Gold about him, and tell him he's a Rogue if he don't send me some to keep me in Newgate. Upon this we search'd Campbel again, and found ten Guineas in the Foot of his Stocking; we took off one Shoe, and he readily let us do it, but when we attempted the other, he fell down on one Knee, and said, No, I will lose my Life before I will be search'd any further; you may hang me or do what you please, you shall not have a Farthing of the Money. We did not know who the Goods belong'd to, till we saw the Advertisement.</p>
               <p>Sutton. That Rogue will swear thro' an Iron Bar.</p>
               <p>Waker. We put the Prisoners into our Round House for that Evening, and next Morning we carried the Watch, the Hanger, and the Money, to Justice De Veil, and took the Prisoners before him; I was one that went with them, and Sutton told me he forgave Bob with all his Heart, and wish'd he could make himself an Evidence, but I believe he cannot, because this is the first Fact I have committed with him since I return'd from Transportation. Mr. Smith was present, and swore to his Goods, though he could not to the Man.</p>
               <p>Campbel. About three Years ago this Fellow stopp'd me in the Street, and cut me in the Face in six or seven Places, and carried me before a Justice, - I carried him before a Justice, and one Attley paid me eight Guineas for the Case. Waker is a common Thief-taker.</p>
               <p>Q. And does he take none but Thieves?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-person361">
                  William 
                  Goddard 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person361" type="surname" value="Goddard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person361" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Waker, and Attley, and one Cook, brought Campbel into my House on Monday Evening November 8, about Ten at Night. I keep the Crown Tavern at St Giles's Pound, they were together a little Time, and then Mr. Waker came out to me, and said, they were going to do Business, - to take some Fellows, and they should be glad of my Assistance; we all went out and Bob the Glazier with us. According to his Directions we went first to Covent Garden, and from thence to the Cole-Yard by Drury Lane; Campbell said, Sutton was at such a House, and pointed at it; we went into the House, and behind a Door, up one Pair of Stairs, there sat Mr. Sutton with his Hand in his Bosom. I put my Hand upon his, and said, George, I have it, - make no Words; and finding the Hanger drawn, I took it from him, it was without a Scabbard, but he had bound his Garter round the Blade. I then search'd his Pockets, and took a Clasp Knife from him. From hence we carried him to my House, and put Sutton in one Room and Campbel in another. Campbel ask'd me, if I had search'd Sutton, and assured me he had got the Watch about him at that Time. I said, - I have search'd him, and surely he cannot have it. He has, said he, and I'll shew you how I robb'd the Man. Upon this he took me by the Breast, and up went his Stick, and he shew'd me very well how it was done. I drew his Hanger, said he, and pull'd his Watch out of his Fob thus - [at the same Time pulling my Watch from my Pocket] this was to shew me in how small a Space of Time, the Fact was done; the Watch and the Hanger he said he had given George Sutton, and the Money he had taken himself. After Campbel had given me this Account, I went into the Kitchen to Sutton, and said to him, George, you have got the Watch, 'tis in vain to make Words, have it I must: he swore he had it not, but I would search him, and in his Breeches, under his Right Ham, I found it; I was going to unbutton his Breeches, he said he would give me no<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080025"></xptr> more Trouble; so he put his Hand into his Breeches, and pull'd it out himself. When I had got it, he desir'd I would let him look at it, for he had never taken any Notice of it since it had been taken; I let him see it, and he said it was a very pretty Thing, and delivered it to me again, and I have had it in my Possession ever since. You can't blame me, said he, for endeavouring to conceal the Watch, for it would have kept me in Newgate; but go and tell Campbel to send me a Guinea or two, for he has got all the Gold.</p>
               <p>Waker. I ask'd Campbel (by way of Pump) whether he had got any Gold for Sutton; and he said, if he had his Hat full of Guineas, he would send him none.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-person362">
                  Owen 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person362" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person362" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Middle Row, St. Giles's. Within three or four Yards of my Door, Mr. Attley and Waker stopp'd Campbel, and I being a Constable, they charg'd me with him. I took him into my Shop and search'd him for Arms. He said he had none, and would go (very civilly) with us any where. I took him to Mr. Goddard's at the Crown, and went into a Room behind the Bar with him. After some few Words had pass'd, he desir'd to speak with Waker by himself; we went out, but presently we were call'd in, and were informed, that Campbel would make a Discovery of Something if we would go with him. Campbel told us all; that Sutton and he had just committed a Robbery by the Dead Well at Bloomsbury, or Great Russel Street, I don't remember which; that he had tipp'd George the Hanger and the Loge, we took the Loge to be a Pistol, but it prov'd to be a Gentleman's Watch.</p>
               <p>We took Mr. Goddard with us to search after Sutton, first at a Place on this Side Covent-Garden, where there us'd to be a Gin-shop; but not finding him there, we went to a private House in the Coal-Yard, where (I think) Campbel knock'd at the Door, a Woman answer'd within, and he spoke to her again; upon which she opened the Door, and he whisper'd to her, and swore an Oath, and told us George was within and behind such a Door. Mr. Goddard, and I, and Waker, rush'd in; Goddard clapp'd his Hand on Sutton's Breast, and cry'd out, I have got it; he pulled it out of his Bosom and I cut the Garter which was bound round the Blade; then I search'd his Pockets, for fear he should have Pistols about him, but I found none. Campbel having talk'd of the Loge, and I imagining the Loge was a Pistol I thought proper to search him narrowly for fear of Mischief. From hence we carried them both to Mr. Goddard's, and Campbel was put into the Back Room, and Sutton into another. Campbel ask'd us what we had taken from Sutton? Some of us said, a Hanger and a Knife. Why, says he, I gave him the Watch which I took from the Gentleman. Upon that Goddard insisted on searching Sutton farther; and when he found we were resolv'd to search him thoroughly, he took the Watch out of his Breeches himself, desiring only to look upon it, for, says he, I have never look'd upon it yet. We shew'd it to him, and he said it was a very pretty Thing, Campbel was a Villain for discovering the Watch, it would have serv'd to have kept me in Newgate, but since he has us'd me thus, go and tell him he had a Handful of Gold from the Gentleman. This occasion'd our searching Campbel again for the Gold: he profess'd he had none, and began to throw his Cloaths about him, but I would pull off his Shoes, and the Right Shoe he let us take off very quietly, but when I endeavour'd to take the Left, he fell down on his Knee, and swore, if he had a Hat full of Guineas, we should not have one of them though we kill'd him; but while the other three Men held him, I pull'd off his Stocking and turn'd ten Guineas out of it upon the Table. Here they are, and these are the very Guineas which I pour'd out on the Table.</p>
               <p>When we found the Money, both the Prisoners seem'd to be positive that there must have been more. Sutton said he thought there had been a Broad-Piece among the Gold, but afterwards he told us, that as he only saw the Money by the Light of the Moon, perhaps he might be mistaken. I told Bob I was surpriz'd how they could do such a Thing in so little a Time, and so early in the Evening. Why, says he, I can do such a Job in half a Minute's Time, and shew'd us the quick Manner in which he did it.</p>
               <p>Campbel. Well, now where's Attley? Is not he a Witness too? Attley! you are not asham'd to shew your Face</p>
               <p>Sutton. I have nothing to say, nor any Body to call.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-39-person363">
                  George 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person363" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person363" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Glazier in Covent Garden, and 
               <persName id="t17361208-39-person364">
                  William 
                  Rextrove 
               <interp inst="t17361208-39-person364" type="surname" value="Rextrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person364" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Cabinet-maker in Thrift Street, Soho-square, appeared in Behalf of Campbel, but neither of them could give any Account of him for these 7 Years last past. Both <rs id="t17361208-39-verdict223" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-verdict223" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17361208-39-punish224" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-39-punish224" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-defend354 t17361208-39-punish224"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-39-defend356 t17361208-39-punish224"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
