<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380113-44">
               <interp inst="t17380113-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-44" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-44" type="date" value="17380113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380113-44-off228-c226" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-44-defend334 t17380113-44-off228 t17380113-44-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>60. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380113-44-defend334" type="defendantName">
                     Garret 
                     Ural 
                  <interp inst="t17380113-44-defend334" type="surname" value="Ural"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-defend334" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-defend334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, &amp;c. for <rs id="t17380113-44-off228" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-off228" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-off228" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               assaulting Sarah his Wife, and with a certain Wooden Handle of a Knife, value 1 d. which he held in his Right Hand, giving her several Mortal Bruises on her Head, Neck, and Stomach, as well by striking her with the said Handle, as by kicking the said Sarah, of which mortal Bruises she instantly died
            </rs>. <rs id="t17380113-44-cd229" type="crimeDate">Dec. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-44-off228 t17380113-44-cd229"></join>.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavannah deposed, that going up Stairs that Night he heard the Prisoner beating his Wife, that she cry'd out, - don't ye, - my Dear, for God's sake don't - and that the Prisoner's Child cry'd out bitterly, and said, don't Daddy, - Daddy don't, that in 4 or 5 Minutes afterwards the Prisoner call'd, - Neighbours! Neighbours ! my Wife is dead! Upon which he went down into the Prisoner's Room, and found the Deceased sitting by the Wall without her Cloaths, and her Head turn'd almost behind her. That the Prisoner had a small Vial in his Hand, and would have gone for some Gin for her, imagining (as he said) that she was in a Faint, if they would have permitted him.</p>
               <p>Other Witnesses deposed to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bell, Surgeon, deposed, that upon his examining the Body of the Deceased, he found several bruises and Wounds upon it, but not of Consequence enough to affect her Life. One Wound was on her Temple, and several in other Places. On examining the Neck, he found all right, and the Contents of the Breast in a natural State; but upon opening the Belly, he found the Abdomen fill'd with Blood; the left Kidney in a very Morbid State; and the large Blood Vessel which supply'd that Kidney was burst, and caused her Death. That upon turning the Body (to look for the Occasion of the Rupture of that diseased Vessel) he saw a large Bruise, which tally'd with the internal Rupture, and was directly over it, but as it was 3 Days after her Death, that he view'd the Body, he could not exactly judge how long it might be since the Blow or Kick, which occasion'd that Bruise, was given, but he believ'd the Deceased might have receiv'd it within 5 Days, and was given with great Violence. <rs id="t17380113-44-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-verdict230" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17380113-44-punish231" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-punish231" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-44-punish231" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-44-defend334 t17380113-44-punish231"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
