<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17371012-4">
               <interp inst="t17371012-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-4" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17371012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-4" type="date" value="17371012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371012-4-off22-c70" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-defend77 t17371012-4-off22 t17371012-4-verdict26"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371012-4-off22-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-defend79 t17371012-4-off22 t17371012-4-verdict25"></join>
         
               <p>6, 7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17371012-4-defend77" type="defendantName">
                     Charlotte 
                     Gregg 
                  <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend77" type="surname" value="Gregg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend77" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , (a little <rs id="t17371012-4-deflabel21" type="occupation">Girl</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-defend77 t17371012-4-deflabel21"></join>) and 
               
                  <persName id="t17371012-4-defend79" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Douglas 
                  <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend79" type="surname" value="Douglas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend79" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-defend79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , (her Mother) were indicted for <rs id="t17371012-4-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a leather Bag, val. 1 d, a thirty-six Shilling piece of Gold, 17 Guineas, 3 half Guineas, and 5 Shillings in Silver, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17371012-4-victim81" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Howell 
                        <interp inst="t17371012-4-victim81" type="surname" value="Howell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-4-victim81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-4-victim81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-off22 t17371012-4-victim81"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in her dwelling House
            </rs>, in the Parish of St. Ann's, Westminster, <rs id="t17371012-4-cd23" type="crimeDate">October 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-off22 t17371012-4-cd23"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-4-person82">
                  Ann 
                  Howell 
               <interp inst="t17371012-4-person82" type="surname" value="Howell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person82" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person82" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners lodged in my House, at the <placeName id="t17371012-4-crimeloc24">Black-Horse, in Earls-Court in Cranbourn-Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-4-crimeloc24" type="placeName" value="Black-Horse, in Earls-Court in Cranbourn-Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-4-crimeloc24" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-off22 t17371012-4-crimeloc24"></join>. The Money mention'd in the Indictment, was lost out of a Desk, in my own Chamber, up one pair of Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Desk lock'd?</p>
               <p>Howell. I turned the Key myself, - I thought it lock'd When my Money was gone I suspected the Prisoners, because they fell out last Saturday Night with another of my Lodgers, and in the Quarrel they taxed one another with pawning my Goods which they used in the Rooms. In the Dispute between them I heard that the Prisoner had pawned my Sheets of their Bed, to pay me for their Lodging. This gave me some Suspicion, and I got a Warrant to search the House of Mrs. Cooper in Castle street, by the Meuse where I knew the Prisoners frequented; there I found a Trunk with my Leather Bag, and 16 Guineas, a 36 Shilling Piece, three Half Guineas, and two Half Crowns in it. - There was only one Guinea wanting.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-4-person83">
                  Margaret 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17371012-4-person83" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person83" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17371012-4-person84">
                  Charlotte 
                  Gregg 
               <interp inst="t17371012-4-person84" type="surname" value="Gregg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person84" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought this Trunk to my House new and empty, and told me that her Landlady was going off, and so she would bring away some odd Things to put into it. I asked her where she got the Money to buy this Trunk, and she told me that a Friend had lent her a Guinea. She came two or three Times and said she had brought some little Things, - as Wristbands and Borders, to put into it: she always lock'd it, and I never saw what was in it. When the Officer came with the Search-Warrant, I saw the Trunk opened, and the Money poured out of this very bag, and 'twas wrapped up in this old Rag. I did not tell the Money over, but I remember I saw the Broad Piece of Gold and the Silver. On Saturday the Mother came to the House to see the Trunk, but I can't say whether she opened it or not; the Daughter was then with her, and I left them together in the Room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-4-person85">
                  Thomas 
                  Pow 
               <interp inst="t17371012-4-person85" type="surname" value="Pow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person85" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. Mrs. Howell brought me two Warrants, one to take the Prisoner, and the other was a Search-Warrant. Mrs. Howell's Maid bid me go and search Cooper's Lodgings, for she had seen them all whispering together. We went, and found this Trunk hid behind the Bed. Mrs. Howell immediately knew the Bag, and the Money (sixteen Guineas, three Half Guineas, a 36 Shilling Piece, and two Half Crowns) were found in it. I should have carried Mrs. Cooper before Mr. Deveil, but I only took the two Prisoners, and Gregg (the little one) owned the Fact before him, but her Mother (she said) knew nothing of the Matter. The Mother said she did not know when her Daughter took the Money, but she knew of it after it was taken, and would have convey'd it into the Place from whence it was taken if it had been possible, but as it was not, she said if she could get 6 d. she would have been let Blood, and then would have bled to Death.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Douglas. I never knew the Child had taken the Money, till the Monday that Mrs. Howell miss'd it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Gregg. Mrs. Howell herself was the first Person that made me think of stealing the Money; for my Mother owing her some Rent, she bid me one Night when I went out, before to bring her some Money, - no Matter how I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120012"></xptr> came by it; telling me if I did not, - I shou'd come in there no more.</p>
               <p>Douglas, the Mother. I am sure I never saw a Farthing of the Money, 'till I saw it before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Howell. The Mother says, she never saw the Money - why she gave me half a Guinea of my own Money to change. I believe it was Part of my own Money, because they had not a Penny to buy them a Role or Cheese, before I lost my Bag; and the Mother told me, she had borrow'd that half Guinea of Mrs. Cooper.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cooper. She borrow'd none of me.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Howell. After they had got my Money, the Mother bought her Girl a new Pair of Stockings and Shoes, and they had a good Loin of Pork for Dinner besides - and that Way went one of my half Guineas.</p>
               <p>Douglas <rs id="t17371012-4-verdict25" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-verdict25" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. Gregg <rs id="t17371012-4-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17371012-4-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-4-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-4-defend77 t17371012-4-punish27"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
