<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-10">
               <interp inst="t17341204-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-10" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-10" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-10-off61-c75" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend94 t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-10-off61-c76" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend96 t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-verdict68"></join>
         
               <p>10. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-defend94" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Casey 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend94" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend94" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Beesly 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend96" type="surname" value="Beesly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend96" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-defend96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17341204-10-defloc60">White-Chappel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-defloc60" type="placeName" value="White-Chappel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-defloc60" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend94 t17341204-10-defloc60"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend96 t17341204-10-defloc60"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17341204-10-off61" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-off61" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-off61" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-10-victim98" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Atkinson 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-10-victim98" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-10-victim98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-10-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-victim98"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in an open Field near the High-way, putting him in fear, and taking from him 31 Yards of Cotton Check, value 27 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17341204-10-cd62" type="crimeDate">Octob. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-cd62"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Witnesses were examin'd apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person99">
                  John 
                  Atkinson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person99" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17341204-10-viclabel63" type="occupation">Weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-victim98 t17341204-10-viclabel63"></join> by Trade. On the 30th of October, near the Evening, I went a-cross <placeName id="t17341204-10-crimeloc64">White-Chappel Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-crimeloc64" type="placeName" value="White-Chappel Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-crimeloc64" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-crimeloc64"></join> to <placeName id="t17341204-10-crimeloc65">King David's Fort in Ratclif Highway</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-crimeloc65" type="placeName" value="King David's Fort in Ratclif Highway"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-10-crimeloc65" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-off61 t17341204-10-crimeloc65"></join>, where I have some who work for me. I staid there till 7, and then came back with a Piece of Cotton Check which one of my Men had made for me. In the middle Field, where there is a Ditch on one side, and Soil on the other. I was attack'd by two young Fellows with Pistols, they damn'd me, and bid me stand, or I was a dead Man. Then one of them collar'd me, struck me over the Face with a Pistol, and swore again, D - ye, stand still ye Dog, or I'll shoot ye. The other searched my Pockets, and finding but nine Pence, he put it in again, and said, D - him, he has got nothing but Half-pence. Then they took my Piece of Check, and so they left me. It was a Moon-light Night, and I had a full view of their Faces; I verily believe that Casey is the Man who collar'd me; and that he who search'd my Pockets was this Man here, Macdonald. I went back to my Men at King David's Fort, and told 'em how I had been robb'd I likewise went to the Constable at the King's Arms in Sun-Tavern Fields, who told me that he should be out upon Duty that Night, and would look after such Fellows as I had describ'd, and then I went home the Street way - Next Morning I went over the same Fields, and called at the Prince of Orange's Head, which joins to the Field were I was rob'd, and left a Description there of the Men who had rob'd me. In about a Fortnight afterwards, some who were acquainted with my Workmen, calling at the Prince of Orange's Head, heard that the Men who rob'd me were apprehended, and that one of them who had made an Information, was in the New-Goal in Southwark. I went thither, and found Macdonald. He asked me if I knew him. I said, yes, I am pretty sure you are one of the Men that rob'd me. He said, it was true enough; for it was he that took the nine Pence, and a Key out of my Pocket, and put them in again; and that he had made his Information before Sir 
               <persName id="t17341204-10-person100">
                  John 
                  Lade 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person100" type="surname" value="Lade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that his Companions were in Custody. I went to Sir John Lade, and he bound me over to prosecute. When Casey's Sister was taken on Macdonald's Information, for receiving the Goods, I went with her to Wood-street<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040009"></xptr> Compter, to see her Brother, and there likewise found Beesly, who pulled off his Hat to me, and said, Sir, I hope you'll be favourable to us - He own'd himself to be acquainted with Macdonald: But I don't remember that ever I saw Beesly before; for I saw but two Men when I was rob'd, and these two I believe were Casey and Macdonald.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person101">
                  John 
                  Bishop 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person101" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be at Justice Lade's when Macdonald made his Information; and coming from thence over the Water, I went to drink with Mr. Atkins at the Bull-head in Bread-street. While we were there, Beesly and 
               <persName id="t17341204-10-person102">
                  John 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person102" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person102" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in together, and were presently follow'd by Casey and two more. They all appear'd to be of one Company. Sutton enquired for Macdonald, and said, he heard he was in some Jail, but he did not know in what Jail. I told them, I believed Mr. Atkins could inform them; I gave Atkins a hint that I fancied these were the Men who were in Macdonald's Information. So we kept them drinking till we got sufficient Assistance, and then we apprehended them all Five. D - my Eyes, says Jack Sutton, here's almost two Load of us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person103">
                  John 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person103" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the two Prisoners about half a Year. On the King's Birth-day, which was the Day after my Lord Mayor's Day, we all went to the House of Mrs. Dick's in the Back Lane in White-Chappel, going towards Stepney Fields; there we staid drinking till past seven at Night, and then to Tom-Turd-Man's Hole in White-Chappel Fields, where we saw the Prosecutor coming along; upon which I said to Beesly, act out of the Path, and watch who comes t'other way, for here is but one Man, and we can deal with him; so Beesly went behind a Bank, about half a Stone's throw off; and then Casey collar'd the Gentleman, and beat him about the Head with a Pistol; and then I searched his Pockets, and took out a Six Pence, and Three Pennyworth of Half-Pence; which being but a Trifle, I bid him take it again. Then I took up the Piece of Check, and ran with it to Beesly, and gave it him to take care of. Casey and I followed the Prosecutor at a little Distance, as far as Mr. Emery's Garden; then we returned, and meeting Beesly, we all went to Aldgate, where we took Coach, and went to an Ale-house in St. Giles's, which was then kept by one Leadbeater; but he is now run away. There we measured the Check, and found there was 31 Yards; we carried it to Casey's Sister in Covent-Garden, and gave it her to pawn for us; and I likewise gave her a Handkerchief of my own. She brought us 17 s. for the Check, and 2 s. for the Handkerchief. We spent all the Money before we parted, in Victuals, Beer, and Gin; except half a Crown which I paid for a Wig - We lived together three or four Days in a Cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person104">
                  Martha 
                  Busby 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person104" type="surname" value="Busby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person104" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Nurse to Mrs. Dicks, who lives in the Back Lane against the Blue-Anchor. About Six o'Clock at Night - I don't remember the Day of the Month; but it was some remarkable Day, for there was a Bonfire before the King's Purveyor's Door - It might be five or six Weeks ago - Macdonald, and he in the Red Coat [pointing to Casey] and I believe the other Prisoner, but I can't be so positive to him, came Mrs. Dicks and went into a back Room, and shut the Door. I think they had half a Pint of Gin, and staid about half an Hour, and then they went away together towards the Fields. Macdonald has drank there several times; I have seen Casey twice with him; but I don't remember any thing of seeing Beesly there before that one Night.</p>
               <p>Casey. Did you never hear my Name mentioned in Macdonald's Company?</p>
               <p>Busby. No.</p>
               <p>Casey. It is very strange that I should be three or four times in his Company, and he should never call me by my Name. I always got my Bread honestly by working as <rs id="t17341204-10-deflabel66" type="occupation">Labourer to Bricklayers, and Plaisterers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend94 t17341204-10-deflabel66"></join>. And one Day, as I was going to fetch a Hod that was left in the City, I happened to meet 
               <persName id="t17341204-10-person105">
                  Jack 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person105" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person105" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , whom I had been to see in Newgate some time before, and spent a little Money to treat him - Not that I had any great Acquaintance with him neither - And so meeting with him in the Street, he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040010"></xptr> told me that he was going to see Jack Macdonald in Prilon, and carry him a Shilling; and he said if I would go with him he'd give me a Pot; upon which we went to the Bull-head in Bread-street, where we were taken, and this is all I know of Macdonald.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person106">
                  Jane 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person106" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person106" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Brother, the Prisoner, has always been a very honest Boy, and work'd hard for his Bread - He commonly earn'd 10 s. a Week in the Winter, and 12 s. in the Summer - He work'd for Mr. Gray, the Builder.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Beesly. I don't so much as know the Place where the Robbery was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person107">
                  Eliz 
                  Savil 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person107" type="surname" value="Savil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person107" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Beesly's Aunt. He always behav'd well - He was Apprentice to a Carver and Gilder; but his Master failing, he turn'd <rs id="t17341204-10-deflabel67" type="occupation">Labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend96 t17341204-10-deflabel67"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person108">
                  John 
                  Buckhold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person108" type="surname" value="Buckhold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person108" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a 
               <persName id="t17341204-10-person109">
                  Builder
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person109" type="given" value="Builder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person109" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Beesly has work'd Labouring-work for me several Years, his Character in general was very honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person110">
                  Sarah 
                  Buckhold 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person110" type="surname" value="Buckhold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person110" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When he has been going to work for my Husband out of Town, he has desired me to let his Mother have 1 s. out of his Wages.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person111">
                  Joseph 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person111" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person111" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bricklayer. He has work'd for me this 12 Months. I have known him 8 or 10 Years, and never knew him guilty of any Dishonesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-10-person112">
                  Thomas 
                  Bryne 
               <interp inst="t17341204-10-person112" type="surname" value="Bryne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person112" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When he lodg'd at my House, he was never out after 8 at Night.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-10-verdict68" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-verdict68" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> Beesly, and found Casey <rs id="t17341204-10-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17341204-10-punish70" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-10-punish70" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-10-defend94 t17341204-10-punish70"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
