<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-40">
               <interp inst="t17361208-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-40" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-40" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-40-off226-c258" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-40-defend366 t17361208-40-off226 t17361208-40-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>57. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-40-defend366" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Butler 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-40-defend366" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-defend366" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-defend366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17361208-40-defloc225">St. Andrew's, Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-40-defloc225" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew's, Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-40-defloc225" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-40-defend366 t17361208-40-defloc225"></join>, was indicted, <rs id="t17361208-40-off226" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-off226" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-off226" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               for that she being big with a certain Female Bastard Child, by the Providence of God she did bring forth the same alive, but not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. on the said Child, so born alive, did, with both her Hands, make an Assault, putting it into a certain Wooden Box, value 2 d. and covering it with a certain Stuff Gown, value 6 d. by Reason of which Putting and Covering, the said Child was choak'd and strangl'd, of which Choaking and Strangling,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080026"></xptr> it instantly dy'd; and so the said Butler, the said Child, did, of her Malice afore-thought, kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder. <rs id="t17361208-40-cd227" type="crimeDate">Oct 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-40-off226 t17361208-40-cd227"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-40-person367">
                  John 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17361208-40-person367" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person367" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was a <rs id="t17361208-40-deflabel228" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-40-defend366 t17361208-40-deflabel228"></join> at my Brother's, the <placeName id="t17361208-40-crimeloc229">Ship, in Gray's-Inn-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-40-crimeloc229" type="placeName" value="Ship, in Gray's-Inn-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-40-crimeloc229" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-40-off226 t17361208-40-crimeloc229"></join>; on Lord Mayor's Day I heard a Disturbance (for I lie in the next Room to where the Prisoner lay) - I heard an Out-cry that she had made away with her Child; the Women desired us all to hunt about for it. I search'd the Vault with a long Stick, but could find nothing; then I went into her Room and broke open her Box; the first Thing I found in it, was a Pint of Gin, then there was a green Stuff Gown, and under this Gown lay the Child; the Box was lock'd, but I broke it open with a Cleaver, such as you chop Meat with. I saw the Child, but I don't know what it was, - Boy or Girl; it was naked, but I was not curious enough to examine it. The Gown covered the Child, and the Gin Bottle lay upon that: I ran down Stairs and told the Women who were examining her; - I don't know what the Prisoner said to the Women for I was not present. But I heard her say when she was before the Justice, that the Child was her's, and she stroak'd it upon the Breast, and said it was born dead about five o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-40-person368">
                  Robert 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17361208-40-person368" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person368" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner liv'd with me as a Servant, and on the 29th of October there was a Disturbance about her having had a Child; my Brother searched for it and found it. She was carried before a Justice, and there she owned it was her Child, and that she was delivered of it dead, about five o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-40-person369">
                  Margaret 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17361208-40-person369" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person369" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There is a Porter who belongs to Gray's-Inn, who lives up two Pair of Stairs, - she lies in the Garret, - and he bid me go up and examine my Maid, for she was not well. When I went up, I found some Disorder, and that she had been deliver'd. She said she was not deliver'd, but that she was then in Labour. I sent for my Midwife, and she examined and found that the Prisoner had been deliver'd. I asked her if she had got any Thing to put the Child in. She told me no; and then she said she had miscarried at a Vault in the Alley; but when the Child was found she owned it was her's, and that she was delivered of it about five in the Morning; it was a Female Child, and there were no Marks of Violence upon it, except a Spot upon one Cheek. She confessed to us that she had made no Preparation for it, but at the Justice's she said, she had got one of a Sort. I thought she looked big when she had been in the House two or three Days, and I asked her if she was married. No, says she, I am not married, I am only Pot-belly'd, all our Family are Pot-belly'd, - and what a Disgrace it is to be Potbelly'd!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-40-person370">
                  Ann 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17361208-40-person370" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person370" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Midwife, and 
               <persName id="t17361208-40-person371">
                  Elizabeth 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17361208-40-person371" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person371" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , confirmed the former Evidences.</p>
               <p>Defence. The Child was dead born, and I being willing to keep it to myself as well as I could, put it into the Box intending to go into the Country again. <rs id="t17361208-40-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-40-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
