<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351015-5">
               <interp inst="t17351015-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-5" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-5" type="date" value="17351015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-5-off16-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-defend44 t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-verdict19"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-5-off16-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-defend46 t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-verdict19"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-5-off16-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-defend48 t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>5, 6, 7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-defend44" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend44" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend44" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend44" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , Widow, 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-defend46" type="defendantName">
                     Rebecca 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend46" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend46" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend46" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-defend48" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend48" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend48" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-defend48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , Spinsters, were indicted for the <rs id="t17351015-5-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351015-5-victim50" type="victimName">
                           Catherine 
                           Hambleton  otherwise <rs id="t17351015-5-alias-1" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-victim50 t17351015-5-alias-1"></join>
                              Elizabeth 
                              Cox
                           </rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17351015-5-alias-2" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-victim50 t17351015-5-alias-2"></join>
                              Ann 
                              Johnson
                           </rs>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-5-victim50" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-5-victim50" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-5-victim50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-victim50"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  : Margaret Hambleton, Widow, by putting both her Hands about the Neck of the said Catherine Hambleton, and thereby choaking and strangling her, of which choaking and strangling she instantly died; and Rebecca and Margaret Hambleton, Spinsters, by being present, aiding, and abetting the said Margaret Hambleton, Widow (their Mother) in the said Murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17351015-5-cd17" type="crimeDate">September 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-cd17"></join>.</p>
               <p>They were a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person51">
                  Sarah 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person51" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person51" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17351015-5-crimeloc18">Denmark Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-5-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Denmark Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-5-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-5-off16 t17351015-5-crimeloc18"></join>. Three Weeks and three Days before the death of the Deceas'd, I lett a Room up two pair of Stairs backwards to Margaret Hambleton, Widow. Her two Daughters (the other two Prisoners) lived with her, and she said she had another Daughter (the Deceased) who lived in a Merchant's Service, and that she seldom had an Opportunity of seeing her above once a Year. And I never saw this Daughter alive. There was one 
               <persName id="t17351015-5-person52">
                  Betty 
                  Camay 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person52" type="surname" value="Camay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person52" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that used to come to see the Prisoners almost every Day. On the seventeenth of September about noon, a Boy came to my House with a Coffin. I told him he mistook the House. He said, No, for Margaret Hambleton, my Lodger, had ordered it to be brought for a Maid who was out of Place and died suddenly. So I went up with the Boy to her Door with a piece of Packthread and a Stick put into the Staple, for there was no Lock; I bounced against it, and forced it open, and behind it the Deceased lay dead on the Floor, covered all but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150003"></xptr> her Face with a piece of an old Flock Bed. There was no living Person there, nor any Furniture, not so much as a Stool or a Chair. I was frighted, and went down with the Boy. He waited for his Money, and by-and-by Margaret the Mother, and Rebecca her eldest Daughter came home. The Mother said to the Boy, I see you are got here before me. I asked her if she had any body dead in her Room. She answered, What's that to you. I told her if it was so, she ought to have acquainted me with it, Truly, says her Daughter, you have a great deal of Impudence to ask if any body's dead in our Room. You don't know nor never shall, for it is none of your business. And so they and the Boy went up I went and told my Neighbours, who sent for the Searchers, and I sent for my Husband, who was upon the Guard at St. James's - I do not know that the Prisoners ever had any Furniture in the Room, for I never saw them bring any in. The Searchers came about Candle-light, and we went up. The Door was then fastened as before. I got it open and we found the Body in the Coffin, and a Pan whelmed on the Lid. The Mother and Daughter were then gone out again, but in a little while they returned, and the other Daughter Peggy, and 
               <persName id="t17351015-5-person53">
                  Betty 
                  Caway 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person53" type="surname" value="Caway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person53" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came with them. Hy! Hy! says the Mother, How came you to have the Impudence to come into my Room? Do you want to rob me of my Goods? The Searchers asked her why she did not tell the Neighbours of the young Woman's being dead. She said it was her own dear Child, her own dear Kitty, and she died of Convulsion Fits. There was a bloody Rag pinned about her Neck. There were black Marks about her Throat, a Bruise on her Temple, another on her Cheek, one on her Shoulder, and one on her Breast, but the rest of her Body was very fair; and the Searchers said, she could not die of Convulsions, because her Nails were white and clear. There was a place on the Floor where the Deceased first lay, that was mopt up and seemed to be bloody.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person54">
                  David 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person54" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person54" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for home, and the Prisoners coming in afterwards, I asked the Mother, Why she did not acquaint us of the young Woman's being dead in the House. She said she died in the Morning, and she did not care to disturb us. I look'd round the Room, and seeing only a Flock Bed no bigger than a Sack, I asked them if there was all their Goods, and what I must have for my Rent. The eldest Daughter said, they never designed to pay me any. Then she wiped the Purging at the Deceas'd's Nose and Mouth, and thereupon she bled fresh Blood, as if a Vein had been opened. I lay on the Ground Floor, and heard no Noise in the Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person55">
                  Jane 
                  Twentyman 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person55" type="surname" value="Twentyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person55" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Searcher. We went first by Candle-light, but the Deceased bled so much at her Mouth and Nose that we could not observe the Marks about her Neck; but next Morning we went again, and found she was bruised much under the right Ear, where the Skin was raised and several Bruises about the Neck and Shoulders, but the rest of her Body was clear, and her Hands and Fingers were white and open. Her Mother said she died of Convulsion Fits, but I think she must have been strangled. For in Convulsion Fits, the Nails and Fingers will be black thus far, and the Bowels will presently turn green - I advised them to send for a Surgeon who had more Skill than I.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person56">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Caway 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person56" type="surname" value="Caway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person56" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners worked at my Mothers at stiching of Stays. About a Fortnight before the Deceased's death, her Mother told me that she was sick with Fits, and was to come home from her Service. I went to see her two or three Days after she came home; she had a violent black Eye, and looked as if she had been beat. I asked her if she had Fits, and she said no. The Saturday before the Deceased died, her Sister Peggy (the Girl there) came to our House crying, and said, her Mother had been beating her Sister Kitty (the Deceased.) I went down to a Chandler's Shop, and there I saw the other Prisoner Beck at the Door. She was crying too, and said to me, You never saw such a barbarous Creature as my Mother, I lifted Kitty off the Bed and set her to lean against the Window, and my Mother knocked her down on the Floor with her Fist, and said, D - ye, it's all along of you! and Kitty<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150004"></xptr> looked up, and asked what that was for? On Sunday Morning I went to see her. She was sitting on the old Flock Bed which my Mother gave them out of Charity, for they had no other Furniture. I asked her if she knew me, and she put her Hand up to her Forehead, and said, O Lord, what must I do? She said no more, and they afterwards told me, that was the last Word she spoke. I went again on Monday (the Day before she died) and then she was dozing, but did not seem to be troubled with any Distemper - They said they had given her two of Ward's Pills, and next Day in the Afternoon I found her lying dead on the Floor. Her Mother said she died in Fits, and wiped her Nose, but the more she wiped, the more clear Blood came. They put her in the Coffin, and mop'd up some blood behind the Door, and then came to my Mothers and drank Tea. I came back with them at Candle-light, and several People were then in their Room. The Mother said, I think here is a hundred People, if I had any Goods I might be robbed. Beck wiped the Deceased's Mouth, and Blood came out of her Mouth and Nose.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person57">
                  Mary 
                  Simmons 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person57" type="surname" value="Simmons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person57" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at Mrs. Edward's up one pair of Stairs backward in the Room under where the Prisoners lay. On Saturday the thirteenth of September between eleven and twelve at Night, I heard a sort of a thump as if some body had been knocked down, and then I heard one Shriek, and after that, a shuffling of Feet as if two or three had been shuffling one from another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person58">
                  Philip 
                  Cadogan 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person58" type="surname" value="Cadogan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person58" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Girl Peggy was examined in Covent Garden Roundhouse, she would make no Confession, but just as we were going to shut the Door, she said, O good God! what would become of my poor Mother if I was to tell the truth?</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilkie, Surgeon. On Saturday after the Deceased's death, at the desire of the Coroner, I viewed the Body in St. Martin's Work house. On each side of her Neck there was a Mark of Fingers; the Skin was quite rubbed off across the Throat, and from one Mark to the other there was part of a black Circle, all which appeared to be made by a violent Pressure on the Gullet, and from thence I judge that she had been strangled. There was a Bruise on her Shoulder, but I did not think that material. As she had been dead so long, I could form no Judgment as to her having had Fits.</p>
               <p>Q. Could she have been strangled without leaving a Mark quite round her Neck?</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilkie. Yes; for by pressing the Gullet the Vessels would be obstructed, and she would be strangled of course.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-5-person59">
                  George 
                  Beckington 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person59" type="surname" value="Beckington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person59" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the same House, and the Sunday Se'nnight before her death she was brought to our House by her eldest Sister, who led her up Stairs. Her Face was half muffled up, and I saw she had a very black Eye.</p>
               <p>Then the Prisoners made their Defence.</p>
               <p>The Mother. My Daughter lived at 
               <persName id="t17351015-5-person60">
                  John 
                  Caldecot 
               <interp inst="t17351015-5-person60" type="surname" value="Caldecot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's in Gray's Inn Lane. She, having two Fits there, would leave her Service and come home. When she came she had a black Eye, and said she was very sick. She had one Fit that Night, and three every Night after. But on Sunday she had Ten, and on Monday Thirteen. I carried her to Dr. Metcalf in Drury Lane, who blooded her, and after that she was blooded by an Apothecary in Princes Street.</p>
               <p>Rebecca. She came home vastly bad, and lay down, and I cover'd her up, and burnt some Gin and gave her, and she had but one Fit that Night. Next Day she sent me to pawn her Stays for two Shillings, which I did, and bought a bit of Mutton, and made her some Broth, but she afterwards grew worse, and at last died in a Fit.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351015-5-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-5-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> them.</p>
            </div1>
