<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-32">
               <interp inst="t17370706-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-32" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-32" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-32-off158-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-32-defend244 t17370706-32-off158 t17370706-32-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>38. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-defend244" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Harvey 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-defend244" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-defend244" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-defend244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370706-32-defloc157">St. Faith's under St. Paul's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-defloc157" type="placeName" value="St. Faith's under St. Paul's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-defloc157" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-32-defend244 t17370706-32-defloc157"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-32-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 38 Guineas, and 2 s. in Money
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-victim246" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Best 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-victim246" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-victim246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-victim246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-32-off158 t17370706-32-victim246"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370706-32-cd159" type="crimeDate">June 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-32-off158 t17370706-32-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person247">
                  Ann 
                  Best 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person247" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person247" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person247" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I live at Silsoe in Bedfordshire. On the 13th of June I pack'd up 40 l under a Lump of Butter, - in the middle of a Flat (of Butter) that was to come to London I saw it loaded in the Waggon, that it could not be come at, unless the Waggon was unloaded. I usually sent up Money to London in that manner, under a Flat of Butter. I put up 38 Guineas and 2 s. and the Basket in which the Flat was put, I ty'd fast with 2 Strings. The Direction was in the Inside of the Lid, that no one should see it, unless the Flat was unty'd. This Butter was directed to my Sister White, and William had the Delivery of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person248">
                  George 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person248" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person248" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I loaded the Waggon, and drove it on the 13th of June to South Mimms, but I knew nothing in particular of this Flat of Butter, or of the Money, - I had 40 Flats (I believe) in the Waggon at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Flat remov'd before you came to London?</p>
               <p>Lee. I drove the Waggon to South Mimms, and it was not mov'd while it was carrying to that Place.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person249" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Waggon came in at South Mimms, it stay'd there about an Hour, and then I drove it to Newgate Market.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you travel all Night?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. Yes; in Company with other Waggons: And nothing was taken out, 'till I came to <placeName id="t17370706-32-crimeloc160">Rose street End</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Rose street End"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-32-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-32-off158 t17370706-32-crimeloc160"></join>; there I stopp'd and unloaded for Newgate Market. I deliver'd the Things my self, to 
               <persName id="t17370706-32-person250">
                  Daniel 
                  Pettit 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person250" type="surname" value="Pettit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person250" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my Master's Porter, and he carry'd them up the Street into the Market. He is a Porter that belongs to the Waggon, and its my Business to deliver these Flats to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person251">
                  Daniel 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person251" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person251" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Salesman in the Market. 
               <persName id="t17370706-32-person252">
                  William 
                  Best 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person252" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is Brother to the Carrier, and marry'd my Sister. I gave him Liberty to open my Letters, and take Care of my Money. On the 14th of June, I came to Market, about 4 o'Clock, and he gave me a Letter, and told me there was 40 l in this Flat, but the Prisoner had got it away: - A Villain! (says I) run after him, and see for the Money. William Best came back, and said the Butter was safe, but the Money was gone. I ran out of the Market to Mrs White's, and said to the Maid, - shew me where this Rascal lives; so the Wench and I, went to the Prisoner's House, and I look'd in an old Chest of Drawers, - if I could have found the greasy Bag, I should have been satisfy'd. But a little Trunk in the Room feeling heavy, I asked the Girl that was there to unlock it; she did so, and in this Trunk there were several Parcels of Money, - several little Parcels of Money, but not such a Parcel as I wanted. - I believe there might be about 40 l in all. What gave me Reason to suspect him, was this, - about 5 Weeks before, I saw him routing among the Goods in my other Shop (where I give a Brother of mine, Leave to pitch his Parcels;) and I said to him, - you Rascal, what Business have you there; for I had a Letter from my Sister, to inform me, she had sent me 328 l. 4 s. in the Goods. He told me at that Time, that he wanted his Mistress's (Mrs White's) Butter. I told him he had a great Assurance to rout over the Goods, when there was no body to deliver them to him; and I charged him never to touch them without Will Best was present; for he is appointed to deliver them, and take the Money, - or Book them. The Prisoner having seen Best take Money out of this Flat, occasio'd me to warn him not to meddle with any of them. He has used the Market many Years: I can't say I ever heard him charged with any such Act before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person253">
                  Anthony 
                  Willcox 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person253" type="surname" value="Willcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person253" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to the Shop about a Quarter after 3 in the Morning, and unty'd the Flat of Butter, and look'd in it; then he ty'd it down again, and carry'd it to Mrs. White's.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060020"></xptr>Council. The Directions are in the Inside: Is it not usual for the Porters to open these Flats, to see where they should be carry'd?</p>
               <p>Willcox. It has been done; but they should not do so, 'till they have Orders. I have known him 20 Years, and never heard that he wrong'd any one all that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whose Flat it was, which he open'd?</p>
               <p>Willcox. No; I saw him take one, but I don't know whose it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person254">
                  Daniel 
                  Pettit 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person254" type="surname" value="Pettit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person254" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a hired Servant to Mr. Best, and when the Waggon is unloaded, I carry the Goods to the Place in the Market where they are always pitch'd, and that Morning as I was carrying a Parcel up the Street from the Waggon, I met the Prisoner coming down, with a Flat of Mrs. White's, upon his Back, going toward her House. This was between 3 and 4 o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person255">
                  Sarah 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person255" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person255" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have order'd the Prisoner to bring my Flats as soon as he could, but I did not do so that Morning, nor do I know that he ever brought any so early. 'Twas brought an Hour sooner than usual; I was a-bed, and my Servant was present at the opening of it. I have indeed, when I have wanted Butter, order'd him to bring me a Parcel, without waiting for Will Best. I have known the Prisoner 7 or 8 Years, and look'd upon him to be an honest Fellow. Our Flats generally come ty'd up; but this had been open'd to look for the Money, tho' I can't say whether it was open when 'twas deliver'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person256">
                  Susan 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person256" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person256" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mrs. White's Servant. I received the Flat that Morning from the Prisoner, and the Clock struck 4 as he went out of the House. I can't tell whether it had been open'd or not, when I receiv'd it, but Pettit a little while after it came in, had open'd it in the Cellar, and when I went down, he said he could find no Money in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-32-person257">
                  William 
                  Best 
               <interp inst="t17370706-32-person257" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person257" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I usually deliver'd Mrs. White's Butter to the Prisoner, but this Flat he took before I came to Market, tho' I had order'd that no Body should meddle with the Goods till I came to Market. I sent Pettit to look in the Flat for the Money before it was missed, but he brought me Word, it was gone. I have charged the Prisoner more than a Month before this, not to meddle with the Goods till I came</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mrs. White has given me general Orders not to stay for Mr. Best's coming, but to bring the Goods as soon as I could.</p>
               <p>Mr. Humphreys, Mr. Philpot, Mr. Pocklington, Mr. Weston, Mr. Doiman, Mr. Fletohen, all gave the Prisoner a very extraordinary good Character <rs id="t17370706-32-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-32-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
