<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370114-30">
               <interp inst="t17370114-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-30" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-30" type="date" value="17370114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-30-off157-c195" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-30-defend271 t17370114-30-off157 t17370114-30-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>38, 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-30-defend271" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-defend271" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-defend271" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-defend271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370114-30-defloc156">St. Mary Whitechappel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-defloc156" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Whitechappel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-defloc156" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-30-defend271 t17370114-30-defloc156"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370114-30-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 2 Chints Bed-Curtains, value 50 s. and a Chints Bed Quilt, value 40 s
            </rs>. the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-30-victim273" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Wroth 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-victim273" type="surname" value="Wroth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-victim273" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-victim273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-30-off157 t17370114-30-victim273"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370114-30-cd158" type="crimeDate">May 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-30-off157 t17370114-30-cd158"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-30-person274">
                  Mary 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17370114-30-person274" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person274" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Lady Wroth's at <placeName id="t17370114-30-crimeloc159">Golden-Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-crimeloc159" type="placeName" value="Golden-Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-30-crimeloc159" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-30-off157 t17370114-30-crimeloc159"></join>. When I went to Bed at Night, I made all the Doors and Windows fast; but in the Morning when I came down, I found a Door open; being surpriz'd, I call'd a Neighbour and went over the House, and found two of the Chints<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140018"></xptr> Curtains, two Quilts, and a red Sattin Mantle gone out of one Room: a little further a Box-lid broke, and the Papers which were in the Box scatter'd about the Room. I can't say any Thing to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Judith Gentry Confirm'd the above Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mary Ward. I saw the Goods in the Room the Day before. There was one Quilt cover'd the Bed, and another was doubled up and lay upon that, and covered that.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Theodorick. The Prisoner brought me two Bed Curtains, and a Quilt last Summer, and offer'd them to sell.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. O Lord! Let her look at me, - swear her again my Lord, - swear her again.</p>
               <p>Theodorick. I agreed with her for three Guineas which she took, and told me they were a Gentlewoman's who was ill and was reduced. They were snipp'd and torn at the Top, but that she said was done by the Rats. These are the very Things.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. O Lord! Lord! I never saw these Thing, 'till this Moment.</p>
               <p>Theodorick. I believe these to be the same, but they have been piec'd and made up again; there was not this Lining in them, and they are thus much lengthen'd, - here they seemed to be gnaw'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She must be a good one, to buy such Things of a Stranger.</p>
               <p>Theodorick. She told me they had lain by a great while, and the Rats had gnaw'd them, but now the Lady would sell them, for she wanted Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. A Lady - and want Money, - O Lord! - a fine Lady!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-30-person275">
                  Robert 
                  Theodorick 
               <interp inst="t17370114-30-person275" type="surname" value="Theodorick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person275" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These Things were advertised; so when I saw the Advertisement, I went to Mr. Sly's, at the Blue Boar in Whitechappel, and took a Friend with me, who happen'd to be in the Shop when my Wife bought the Goods, but this Man is now in Yorkshire . I told Mr. Sly, that my Spouse had happen'd to buy these Things; he desired me to send for them; which I did, and he Paid me the three Guineas my Love had paid for them, and treated us with two bottles of Wine. I promised him to bring the Prisoner as soon as I could light of her, and accordingly I carry'd her to him and she could not disown the Goods, neither at Mr. Sly's, nor before the Justice. She made many Protestations that she bought them in Rag-Fair, but she could not say who she bought them of. I know nothing at all of the Prisoner, nor do I know that ever I had seen her before</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Swear him, whether they ever mention'd Quilt and Curtains to me, before I was carry'd to the Justice?</p>
               <p>Theodorick. No, I believe they were not mention'd till then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She buys of 40 People in a Day, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Theodorick. Yes, I believe I do; and I have bought Things of her once or twice before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes, Shirts and Shifts, and Gowns and Petticoats; we carry our Goods in our Arms publickly. These things are of a great Bulk; did any of her Neighbours see her buy them of me?</p>
               <p>Theodorick. No, There was only one Man in the Shop, and he is in the Country. I take the Prisoner to be the Person that sold them to me: I swear that I believe her to be the Person.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The most Money I ever took of her, was 15 s. for Shirts and Shifts - These Things are beyond my Match to buy.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wroth. These Things are mine; I miss'd them the 11th of May. Since I recover'd them again, I have new lin'd them, and made them up. They are Chints, and not to be match'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I cry old Cloaths, and I buy honestly. I never saw these Things before, - Swear them again, swear them, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-30-person276">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17370114-30-person276" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person276" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17370114-30-person277">
                  Margaret 
                  Ingram 
               <interp inst="t17370114-30-person277" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person277" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest Woman. <rs id="t17370114-30-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-30-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
