<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-7">
               <interp inst="t17360908-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-7" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-7" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-7-off29-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-defend66 t17360908-7-off29 t17360908-7-verdict32"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-7-off29-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-defend68 t17360908-7-off29 t17360908-7-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>12, 13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-7-defend66" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Row 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend66" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend66" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-7-defend68" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hampton 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend68" type="surname" value="Hampton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend68" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-defend68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17360908-7-person69">
                  Alexander 
                  Ratcliff 
               <interp inst="t17360908-7-person69" type="surname" value="Ratcliff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person69" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken) for <rs id="t17360908-7-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360908-7-victim71" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Gibson 
                        <interp inst="t17360908-7-victim71" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-7-victim71" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-7-victim71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-off29 t17360908-7-victim71"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , at <placeName id="t17360908-7-crimeloc30">Islington</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-crimeloc30" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-crimeloc30" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-off29 t17360908-7-crimeloc30"></join>, about the Hour of 2 in the Night, and stealing a silver Watch, value 4 l. a silver Porringer, value 30 s. a silver Cup, value 3 l. a silver Spoon, value 10 s. a pair of silk Stockings, value 10 s. the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17360908-7-person72">
                        Thomas 
                        Gibson 
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person72" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-7-person72" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-7-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-7-cd31" type="crimeDate">March the 26th, 1735</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-off29 t17360908-7-cd31"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Gibson. At the Time mention'd in the Indictment, my Servant and I was at work in the Bake House: I sent my Servant out for a Thing we make use of in out Business, and he was seized in the Yard, and made a great Outcry: I was surpriz'd, and took up a long Pole (with which we rub the Fire about in the Oven,) and went into the Yard, to see what the matter was; but before I had got the length of the Pole, a Pistol was fir'd at me, and wounded me in my Breast and my Arm: A second Pistol wounded me in my Face and beat me backwards: Two of them took me up in their Arms and laid me on the Ground in the Bake-House: Then they brought my Man in, and after they had taken him to several Places to shew them where the Candles were, they brought him to me, with a Handkerchief ty'd before his Eyes, and sat him down by me: Two of them stood over us while the others robbed the House; according to our Information, there was half a Dozen of them, and the Man who gave the first Information, was try'd in this Court, and has been executed. After they had committed this Fact, they all sted to Ireland, but Ward, who made the Information against Row and Hampton. My Servant will swear to Row, and the Evidence that took him, will give an Account of his confessing the Fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-7-person73">
                  Eryan 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17360908-7-person73" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person73" type="given" value="Eryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Servant to Mr. Gibson at the Time he was robb'd, and was at work in the Bake house about 2 o'Clock; I went into the Yard for a Scovel which hung on the Backside of the Oven, facing the Back house, Row and his Companions rushed on me, and I was so surprized, that I could not tell how many there were of them: but they presented Pistols to my Breast, and Row stood with a Sword to guard me, while the rest went into my Master. I heard them discharge a Brace of Pistols at him, and I saw the Flash of the Powder. Row afterwards made me go into the Bake-house, and seeing my Master lie upon the Ground, I thought he was dead: he made me stand with my Face to the Oven's Mouth, and took his own Handkerchief, and bound about my Eyes, while the rest went up to rifle the House, They broke open a strong Door of a Chamber, and a Chest of Drawers, and took Money, and what they thought proper. As to Hampton we took him up on Suspicion before, but we could make nothing of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-7-person74">
                  John 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17360908-7-person74" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Ireland in pursuit of Hall and Dillon: 
               <persName id="t17360908-7-person75">
                  George 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17360908-7-person75" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person75" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (who was executed) I took in Bridgewater. Row I took in Dublin last January, I was sent over, by the Justices of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080004"></xptr> Bridgewater, with a Copy of Ward's Confession. I charged the Prisoner with the Robbery, when I took him; he deny'd it at first, but when I shew'd him; Ward's Confession, he said, if Mr. Gibson would make haste and get him over to England, he would be of Service to the Town; and if his Evidence might be admitted, he would make a fuller Discovery than Ward had done: he said, Mr. Gibson might recollect, that he was more merciful to him, than any of the Rest.</p>
               <p>Bird. My Master is not able to give an Account of that, he was wounded, and in Pain. Row stood as a Guard, and Ward would have kill'd him, but Row was indeed more merciful.</p>
               <p>Gibson. These are the Stockings, which they took out of my House</p>
               <p>White. I bought them of Ward and Row.</p>
               <p>Bird. Ward and Row were together when they were bought; the Prisoner swore that Ward had bought them in Drury-Lane, for a Crown.</p>
               <p>Gibson. I have another Man now in Custody at Dublin, when he is brought over, I don't know how Hampton may appear. Ward put him in his Information. Row <rs id="t17360908-7-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17360908-7-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-7-defend66 t17360908-7-punish33"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Hampton <rs id="t17360908-7-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-7-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
