<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-17">
               <interp inst="t17390607-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-17" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-17" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-17-off85-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-17-defend151 t17390607-17-off85 t17390607-17-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>348. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-17-defend151" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Wint 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-17-defend151" type="surname" value="Wint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-defend151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-defend151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was [the next Day] indicted for <rs id="t17390607-17-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing two Men's Velvet Morning Caps, val. 8 s. a Child's ditto, val. 5 s. two Velvet Hoods, val. 12 s. and twenty-six striped Linnen Handkerchiefs, val. 18 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390607-17-victim153" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Malton 
                        <interp inst="t17390607-17-victim153" type="surname" value="Malton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-17-victim153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-17-victim153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-17-off85 t17390607-17-victim153"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390607-17-cd86" type="crimeDate">Apr. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-17-off85 t17390607-17-cd86"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-17-person154">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Malton 
               <interp inst="t17390607-17-person154" type="surname" value="Malton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person154" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of April, about Eight o'Clock in the Evening, I came into the Shop, and found this Akins with a Piece of Ribbon in his Hand, ( 'twas my Father's Shop) so I seiz'd him with the Ribbon in his Hand, but he got from me, and I pursu'd him quite cross the Street, and got him down upon the Ground; his Hat fell off, and I took it up: This is the Hat. I don't know the Prisoner, but I am positive the Evidence is the Man that was in the Shop. We lost the Things mentioned in the Indictment, among which were a Parcel of Linnen Handkerchiefs, - how many I can't exactly tell, but I am sure there were two Dozen, and we miss'd them, and the other Things, the Minute the Evidence was got out of the Shop; I am sure they were there when he came in. I am positive to the Evidence, for I spoke to him in the Shop, and as I pursu'd him in the Street, a shorter Man than he took hold of my Gown-sleeve, to prevent my following him, and said, - Don't follow him, Child, for you can't catch him, - he is run away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I the Man that laid hold of you?</p>
               <p>Malton. No: 'Twas much such another as Brown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-17-person155">
                  James 
                  Akins 
               <interp inst="t17390607-17-person155" type="surname" value="Akins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person155" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This John Brown and I, and the Prisoner, were going along <placeName id="t17390607-17-crimeloc87">Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-17-crimeloc87" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-17-crimeloc87" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-17-off85 t17390607-17-crimeloc87"></join>, and seeing no body in this Shop, Brown went in, and brought two Caps, -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He'll say any Thing, as he did in the former Trial.</p>
               <p>Akins. It was between Eight and Nine o'Clock at Night, but I can't say what Day it was, but 'twas in April: We were going to see what we could steal, and seeing this Shop, and no body in it, at the Corner of Artillery-Lane, Brown went in, and got hold of a Piece of Ribbon, and this young Woman took hold of me as I was coming out, and asked me what I wanted. We had taken out the Goods they lost before she seiz'd me; there were five Velvet Caps and Hoods, and twenty six Linnen Handkerchiefs: Among the Velvet Things, there were two Mens Caps, and a Child's, with a Button at the Top, and two Hoods, which makes five in all. After Brown had fetch'd out two, I went in, and brought out three, - the Child's Cap, and the two Hoods; - Wint stood in the Middle of the Highway, and what we got, we deliver'd to him: He knew we went into the Shop to steal the Goods. After we had got these Things, I went in again, and laid hold of a Piece of Ribbon, but this young Woman caught me; I ran from her into the Street; she follow'd me, I fell down, and she fell upon me; my Hat fell off in the Scuffle, and I got from her, (without staying to take it up) and ran away down Dunning's-Alley. Brown was at the Door, when I ran out of the Shop, and the Prisoner, (who stood in the Highway) ran away when he saw the Bustle, but when it was over, we met at 
               <persName id="t17390607-17-person156">
                  Moll 
                  Bullinbroke 
               <interp inst="t17390607-17-person156" type="surname" value="Bullinbroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person156" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, in Three-Tun Alley,the Corner of the Rope-walk, (near Rosemary-Lane) and we sold all we had got for a Guinea, and divided 7s. a-piece.</p>
               <p>Wint. Ask him, (on his Oath) whether I had not parted with him that Night, and had not bid him Good-Night? And whether he did not run after me, and say, - Here's a Chance: Whether I did not say, - Where! And whether he did not tell me of this Shop, and when he brought the Caps to me, I did not say, - I would not be concern'd? The young Woman did cry out, Stop Thief! but I was not concern'd with them.</p>
               <p>Akins. 'Tis no such Thing; for we never parted from Twelve o'Clock at Noon, till after the Fact was committed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-17-person157">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17390607-17-person157" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (who was try'd with Wint in the preceding Trial) Wint and Akins call'd me out about Twelve at Noon, and we went into Moorfields, and play'd at Cricket till 'twas dark. Then we came through the Tenter-grounds, and through Sun-street, and bid Akins Good-Night, and he cross'd the Way from us, and went into this Shop. When he had got some of the Things, he call'd after us; and then I went in and got some more: The Prisoner came back, and stood in the Middle of the Highway. I brought out two Mens Caps, and gave them to Akins; - what he did with them I don't know, - but I gave none to the Prisoner. Indeed Akins gave all he got to him, (the Prisoner.) I found he had, when we afterwards met together, for when we met, he had (in his Possession) all that was got by us. 'Twas two Hours before we met together, - because there was a great Uproar in the Street about us.</p>
               <p>Q. On what Intent did you go out together?</p>
               <p>Brown. We did not design to go out with him, (Akins) but only as these Things lay so, ( conveniently ) he call'd us, and then we went with him to rob the Shop. The Prisoner and I were going away from him.</p>
               <p>Q. On your Oath, and as you must answer for the Breach of that Oath to God, did you all go out with an Intent to rob, - or not?</p>
               <p>Brown. Not before this Akins call'd us.</p>
               <p>The Witness was ask'd again in a solemn Manner, (and reminded of his Oath, and the tremenduous Consequences of calling God to help him in an Untruth) whether they did not go out that Night with an Intent to steal?</p>
               <p>Brown. - Yes, - and the Prisoner stood on the other Side the Kennel, over against the Shop, and took the Things from us. And we afterwards met at Bullinbroke's Lodgings, by Rosemary-Lane and sold them to 
               <persName id="t17390607-17-person158">
                  James 
                  Deal 
               <interp inst="t17390607-17-person158" type="surname" value="Deal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lives with her as her Husband, for a Guinea, and the Prisoner had 7 s. of the Money. There were but twenty-one Handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Wint. Brown says there were but twenty-one, and others swear there were twenty-six, - that's five Handkerchiefs Difference.</p>
               <p>Akins. I can't tell whether they were all sold; but I saw twenty-six upon the Bed in Bullinbroke's Lodgings.</p>
               <p>Brown. There were but twenty-one, and they, with the rest of the Things, were sold for a Guinea, and the Prisoner had 7 s. of the Money.</p>
               <p>Wint. Did Akins quit the Handkerchiefs before they were sold?</p>
               <p>Akins. We went down Stairs, and left them upon the Bed, and afterwards had the Money.</p>
               <p>Wint. But did not I come down Stairs with you?</p>
               <p>Akins. I came down first; the Prisoner follow'd: We all came down, one after another.</p>
               <p>Wint. And I am afraid, you'll soon follow me. <rs id="t17390607-17-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390607-17-punish89" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-17-punish89" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-17-defend151 t17390607-17-punish89"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
