<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391205-51">
               <interp inst="t17391205-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-51" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-51" type="date" value="17391205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-51-off241-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-defend342 t17391205-51-off241 t17391205-51-verdict245"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-51-off242-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-defend342 t17391205-51-off242 t17391205-51-verdict245"></join>
         
               <p>56. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     Loglin 
                     Rennells 
                  <interp inst="t17391205-51-defend342" type="surname" value="Rennells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-defend342" type="given" value="Loglin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-defend342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17391205-51-defloc239">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-51-defloc239" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-51-defloc239" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-defend342 t17391205-51-defloc239"></join>, was indicted for that he on the <rs id="t17391205-51-cd240" type="crimeDate">22d of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-off241 t17391205-51-cd240"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-off242 t17391205-51-cd240"></join>, <rs id="t17391205-51-off241" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-off241" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-off241" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seducingAllegiance"></interp>
               with Force and Arms, unlawfully and feloniously procured 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391205-51-victim344" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Jackson 
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim344" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim344" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , (he being a Subject of our Lord the King) to enlist and enter himself, as a Soldier, to serve the King of France, (he being a foreign Prince) without Leave and Licence first had and obtained, under his Majesty's Sign Manual; in Contempt of our Lord the King and his Laws; to the evil Example of others; against the Peace, and against the Form of the Stature in that Case made and provided.
And the Indictment farther charged, that he the said Loglin Rennells, afterwards, viz. on the 22d of October, with Force and Arms, unlawfully and feloniously hired and retained Arthur Jackson, to enlist and enter himself to serve the King of France, (he being a foreign Prince) as a Soldier, without Leave and Licence first had and obtained under his Majesty's Sign Manual. In contempt of our Lord the King, &amp;c. &amp;c. 
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a Second Time indicted (as above) for <rs id="t17391205-51-off242" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-off242" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-off242" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seducingAllegiance"></interp>
               procuring 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391205-51-victim346" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Moore 
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim346" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim346" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-51-victim346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   to enlist and enter himself as a Soldier, to serve the King of France, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>

               <p>And the Indictment farther charged him, with hiring and retaining the said Moore , with Intent to cause him to be enlisted as a Soldier, to serve the King of France, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>First Indictment.</p>
               <p>The Council for the King having opened the Indictment, and the Nature of the Offence, the Witnesses were called; and at the Prisoner's Request, were examined a-part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person347">
                  Arthur 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person347" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person347" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a <rs id="t17391205-51-viclabel243" type="occupation">Centinel in the Second Regiment of Foot-guards</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-victim344 t17391205-51-viclabel243"></join>, and was born at New-castle upon Time . The Day before War with Spain was proclaimed , I was in Bowl-Yard , - you had better let me begin From the First of it.</p>

               <p>Counc. Do so,</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050023"></xptr>Jackson . I happened to be drinking at The Hog in Armour, in Field-Lane, and there was a Man forced his Discourse to me very much, seeing me a Soldier. He did not then tell me who he was, or what he was, but he asked me many Questions about military Affairs, and I resolved him to the best of my Knowledge. He told me he was an Irishman, and had travelled thro' Ireland and France, and asked me where I lived? I told him, at the Sheep's-Head-Shop, facing the Gulley-hole. He took it down, and shewed me his French Pass; but he might as well have shewn it to a Horse, for it was in another Language, and I did not understand it. I asked him his Name? He told me Ryan; I told him I could read that in his Pass, and that was all. He put his Pint of Beer into mine, and we drank together. He was mighty complaisant, and gave a good Account of the military Affairs in France. We had five Pints of Beer together, and he would pay the Reckoning; he would not let me club towards it. After this, in a very complaisant Manner, he made Motions for me to go with him to another Place, and I went with him to Bowl-Yard, in St. Giles's. There he called for Two-penny, and looked upon me very pleasantly; but upon his going out of Doors and whispering other Fellows, I suspected him to be a French Officer. We drank four Pints of Two penny, and he seem'd pleased with me, and told me he would call upon me To-morrow. Accordingly he came the next Day and wrapped at my Door. He was then full of Complaisance: he took off his Hat, and shewed his French Behaviours, and Mr. Jackson (says he) will you please to go drink with me at The Hog in Armour I told him, no: I had Work to do, and should disoblige my Master if I went. Then go and speak for two Pots of Beer, and we'll have them here. No, I told him, I did not chuse to drink; it would get into my Head, and I should neglect my Work: If you have any thing to say to me, sit down and say it. So he sat down, and talked again very much in Behalf of the Character of France; and I told him, I believed he was a French Officer, and was come over here to get Men. Yes, says he; will you go? I did not intend to go, but I told him I would, and that I had an Acquaintance would go with me. He said, if I had, he should be glad to drink with him, and I promis'd to bring him, as soon as I saw him. After this, I went to Lunard Armstrong , and told him, a French Officer had been with me, who wanted Men for the French Service, - for a Company of Fusiliers, which lay at Calais. I said, I did not understand it; therefore I desired him to speak to somebody upon this Affair, and in the mean time I would give the Fellow Encouragement to come to my Room. The next time I saw Armstrong, I asked him if he had enquired about this Business? The Fellow comes, says I, and pays me Visits, - I want to bring him to Justice, and if I bring him to The Old Baily on my own Evidence, he might bring twenty People against me, - yet I don't care to smother such a Thing: Ryan was then out of Town: He went to carry off some Men, and was gone four Days. When he returned, I told Armstrong; so he, and 
               <persName id="t17391205-51-person348">
                  Richard 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person348" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person348" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my Room, to hear farther into the Affair, and I desired Moore to go with me to strengthen my Evidence. Accordingly we all set out for Bowl-Yard; my Wife was unwilling I should go, and she followed us up Holborn, and there I troubled Armstrong to keep her in a Public House, while Moore and I went to Ryan's in <placeName id="t17391205-51-crimeloc244">Bowl-Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-51-crimeloc244" type="placeName" value="Bowl-Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-51-crimeloc244" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-off241 t17391205-51-crimeloc244"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-off242 t17391205-51-crimeloc244"></join>. When we came to the House, I asked the Maid for Mr. Ryan, she said at first, she knew no such Person; but when I told her, I was the Person that had been drinking with him, she knew me, and said she would go and fetch him. When she came back, she said, she had not seen him, but she gave me a Tap on the Shoulder, and bid me come to the Door. I did so; and she there asked me, if the young Man that came with me (Moore) was to go to France too? Yes, says I, he came with me for that Intent and Purpose, if we can see Mr. Ryan. She told us, she would bring a Man to us, who was going off To-morrow: I approved of it, and so she fetched the Prisoner at the Bar into the Passage, and told me that was the Man. The Prisoner shook Hands with me, and said, - Mr. Jackson, I know your Business. I am sure he is the Man that enlisted me; I know him by his Phisiognomy, and the deep Scar in his Forehead. He called me by my Name, and said the Maid had told him my Business, and ask'd me if I was willing to go? I told him, yes; but I came to speak with Ryan. Why, says he, I'll give you as much Encouragement as Ryan, or any body else; and I have as much Power to enlist Men as he has, or any belonging to the King of France's Service. Upon this, I called Moore, and the Prisoner shook Hands with him, and ask'd him, if he was willing to go? Moore said yes, if he liked his Proposals, then he asked us to go up Stairs, and we went up one Pair of Stairs, and sat down at a Table; we drank a Quartern of Gin, and a Pint of Two-penny , and there being<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050024"></xptr> three Beds in the Room, and a Man lying in one of them behind us, I pointed behind me with my Thumb, to let the Prisoner understand, I feared the Man abed would hear us: But he told us, he was one of our Sort, and we might talk what we pleased. While we were talking, another Man came into the Room, and undross'd himself, and went to Bed. The Prisoner knew him too, and told us, he was one of the same. We then told him, we were willing to have gone with Ryan; and the Prisoner said, we might as well go with him, for he would give us as much Encouragement . He talked much in the Character (in Praise) of France, and took Moore to the Back of the Door, and the Maid told us, - that was the Place where the Men were measured. The Prisoner took a Knife out of his Pocket, and having set himself against the Door, he put the Knife (over his Head against it, and he was not so high as the lowest Mark of the Small-coal him-himself. He held the Knife still, and called Moore to stand under it, and Moore was not so high as the Prisoner, by I know not how much, - two Inches I believe. After this, there was another Man came up into the Room, that neither the Prisoner nor we knew, and then he said - I don't care that any body should know my Business, so we went to the Stair-head, from behind the Door. There Moore asked him, what Bounty-Money he gave? Says I, I suppose he'll give us twenty Crowns, for Ryan proposed to give so much. The Prisoner told Moore , he could not give him so much, but he would to me, because I was a sized Man; however he would give him fifteen, tho' he was fit for nothing but a Drummer. Then says Moore , what Pay are we to have, when we come there? - I don't know but the Pay might be talked of, both at the Table in the Room, and at the Scair-head . - The Prisoner told us, our Pay would be Five-pence Half-penny a Day; which, with other Advantages, would be as good as a Serjeant's in a marching Regiment. Why that's a good Place, says I; and Money will go twice as far there, as it will here. I told him, I expected another Soldier every Minute , who was willing to go with us, and asked him; what I must do for Cloaths, for I had no other than what I had on to go in. You'll go, says he, in a Ship, and will not be seen; 'tis as dangerous for me as for you: You may take your Gun and Accoutrements with you, - you'll never be seen.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did he propose to go with you himself?</p>
               <p>Jackson . Yes, he proposed to go off with us the next Day, and was to give us a Note of his Hand for the Money on board of the Ship, which (Note) was to be paid us by the Cornet, when we came to the Regiment. The Money was not to be paid in England, and Moore question'd the Payment of it in France; upon which the Prisoner took two Shillings out of his Pocket, one he gave me, and the other to Moore , and said, - You'll as surely have it as you have this, - by G-d. This is to inlist you to serve the King of France. After this we went in, and sat down, and drank the rest of our Liquor, and he drank the King of France's Health, but I drank no Health at all, nor would I, had he insisted on it, though I gave him his Way as much as I could that Night.</p>

               <p>Counc . How long did you continue together?</p>
               <p>Jackson . We went in a little before Eight at Night, and we continued together till past Eleven. When we came away, we went to Colonel De Veil's to acquaint him with the Affair, but he was gone to Bed. I had inform'd Armstrong of it the second Day I was in Company with Ryan, - (I can't tell: he Day of the Month) - in order to have him apprehended.</p>

               <p>Counc . Did you go to Col. 
               <persName id="t17391205-51-person349">
                  De 
                  Veil 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person349" type="surname" value="Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person349" type="given" value="De"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person349" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next Morning?</p>
               <p>Jackson . I went home to Bed that Night, and toward Morning Armstrong and Moore , with Newbury and Brough , called me out of Bed: I came down to them in a Minute or two, and went with them up Holborn , as far as Hatton-Garden, with my Stockings in my Hand, and there I put them on, and asked Moore if he had got a Warrant for the Prisoner: He said, no, we may take him without. I told them, there was no Occasion for all this Haste, and that if we went before Day-light, 'twould be but beating the Bush, for the Birds would all fly aways so we went to a House in St. Giles's and staid till 'twas Day. Then we got Sticks, for as we had no Arms, and there was so many Beds in the Room, I thought we should stand a Fagg. Moore went first, to see if the Prisoner was in the House; I follow'd in a Minute or two, and he informing me the Prisoner was a bed, I went back to give our Friends Notice , and then I return'd to Moore . He seeing them pass by the Door, went out after them, to se , where they would wait till we wanted their Assistance . But I went up Stairs, and desired the Prisoner to get up and drink with me: He raised himself up, and took his Breeches from under his Head; but the Maid having seen the Soldiers go by the Door, she came to me, and asked me if I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050025"></xptr> knew them; I told her, no, I did not; however she went to the Bed-side, and spoke something to the Prisoner, in another Language, upon which he immediately look'd angry and sulky. Moore was now return'd, and came up Stairs, and the Prisoner lay down again, and said he was sick. Then Moore said he should be glad to get a Rowl and Butter; I told him I would go and get him one, and having given him a Tap on the Shoul der to get him to the Room-door, I bid him not quit the Room till I came back; so away I went to Newbury and Brough, who follow'd me to the House, and when I got up Stairs again, the Maid was in the Room, and shut the Door; but when I saw the Red-coats coming up Stairs, I turn'd the Lock back (being stronger than she) and let them in (Newbury, Brough and Armstrong) and told them, that was the Man who had inned us into French Service, and the Maid having told me, that one of the Men in Bed was to have gone with us, we took him and the Maid too, and carried them all to the Bear Ale-house, till Col. DeVeil was stirring; but she made her Escape, and the Man was discharged. While we were waiting there, a Thought came into my Head, and I bid them take Care the Prisoner dropp'd nothing. We had ty'd his Hands, and he desired they might be loosen'd; after which his Pocket-Book was taken from under the Table. I forgot to tell you, that while the Prisoner was talking with Moore and me at the Stair-head in his Lodging, he told us, we should have new Cloaths, and two Shirts, not so fine indeed as what he had on, but two good strong Shirts.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did not you go with the Prisoner before Col. De Viel?</p>
               <p>Jackson . Yes, we all went, and the Man was committed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if I went by the Name of Macguire .</p>
               <p>Jackson. After we got out of the Coach, when we carry'd him to the Gate-house, there was a Woman who abused us, and called him Macguire . Others call'd him Macguire too.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I name any Regiment in France?</p>
               <p>Jackson. He told us, we were inlisted into the Duke of Berwick's Regiment. I am positive of that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I give you the Shilling above Stairs, or below?</p>
               <p>Jackson. As the Stair-head. Moore had the first Shilling , and I the next, and he told us we should have the rest as sure as we had that, - by God. Lord, I wonder to hear him talk so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I in this Dress at that Time?</p>
               <p>Jackson . I can't be positive to Dress . I am positive he's the Man that inlisted me. He had while Buttons, - metal Buttons, on both Sides of his Waistcoat [The Prisoner had a Waistcoat on him at the Bar, with such Buttons as the Witness described.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person350">
                  Richard 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person350" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person350" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am a Scotsman, - a Shoemaker . I know the Prisoner. I saw him on the 22d and 23d of October last, at a House in Bowlyard, about Eight o'Clock at Night. 'Tis not a publick House, - they sell Gin and Twopenny in a cland stine Manner. Jackson and I went there the first Night, about Eight o'Clock, and Jackson asked for Ryan ; a Woman told us she knew no such Person, but when he told her he had drunk Twopen y and Gin with him there, then she said she knew him, and would go for him. She went out for a little while, then she return'd, and gave Jackson a Tap on the Shoulder to follow her. He went to the Door with her, and came back to me She went out of Doors, and in a short time the Prisoner and she came in together. Then she gave Jackson the second Motion to come to the Door, and he call'd me to him there, where the Prisoner shook Hands with me, and asked me if I was willing to go to France? I know the Prisoner is the Man though I saw him but twice, 'tis impossible I should not remember him, for he has a great Scar in his Face. - I told him I did not know but I might be willing to go Then let's go up Stairs (says he) and drink together. There was a Pint of Twopenny and a Quartern of Gin brought up, and he commended France, telling us how much it exceeded England, and what Encouragement there was to serve the French King. He did not dispute Jackson's Size, but he did mine, and took a Penknife out of his Pocket, and stuck it over his own Head in the Door; then he desired me to come under it; he scrupled my Height, but said I was a likely young Man, and would grow. - I have forgot some Part of my Story. - There was one Man a-bed in the Room, and another came in and undress'd himself, and went to Bed; the Prisoner told us, he was one of the same, and would be no Detriment to us. After I was measured, in came a third Man, and then the Prisoner beckoned us out to the Stair-head, and asked us again, if we were willing to go to France. Says Jackson , Ryan promised to give twenty Crowns, - you'll give no less, to be sure. No, says he, I can't give you so much, (meaning me) - you're not so tall as Jackson; I'll give him twenty, but I can give you but fifteen.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050026"></xptr> and you shall have two new Shirts a-piece, and shall be new cloathed from Top to Toe; you'll have 5 d. Halfpenny a Day, which, with other Advantages, will be as good almost as a Serjeant in a marching Regiment in England. Jackson then told him, he had no other Cloaths to go in, but the Cloaths he had on (Soldiers Cloaths); the Prisoner said, he had a Ship provided to his Mind in the River, and he would not be examin'd , so he might bring his Gun with him, as well as the rest of his Regimentals, because they'd be of Service to him on the other Side of the Water. Jackson told him, he expected another Soldier every Minute, who would inlist likewise, to which the Prisoner reply'd, - So much the better - the more the merrier. I asked him, how we should be sure of the Advance; he said he would give us a Note for it, when we were got on board, and we should receive the Money when we were come to the Regiment. I was scrupulous, and desired the Money before; he told us, he could not do that, but (putting his Hand in his Pocket) he pull'd out two Shillings, one of which he gave first to me, and then the other, - to Jackson. I asked him what the Shilling was for; to inlist you (says he) to serve the King of France, and you are as sure of the rest of the Money when you come there as you are of this. - by God. I think he told us, we were to serve in the Duke of Berwick's Regiment then, - I am sure he told us so before. After this he shook Hands with us, and call'd us Brother-Soldiers. This was on the Stair-head. Then we went into the Room again, and he drank the King of France's Health: I did not drink it, nor do I remember that Jackson did. We drank a little more Gin and Twopenny together, and about Eleven o'Clock we left the Prisoner, and went to inform Col. DeVeil of the Affair, but he being gone to bed, we went and drank a Pet together in Drury Lane ; then Jackson and I parted, and I went and lay at a Friend's House. About Five or Six in the Morning, Armstrong (who knew where I was to lie) came with Newbury and Brough , and knock'd me up: He told me, he had acquainted the Captain of the Tilt-yard-Guard with this Matter, and I must get up, and go with them. We went and knock'd up Jackson, who came out to us with his Stockings in his Hand, and did not put them on till we came upon Holbourn-Hill. I had desired the Prisoner not to lock his Door when I left him over Night, for (I told him) I would only go and fetch my working Tools, and would return to him; but thinking that if the Door should be lock'd, our knocking at it so early would make a Discovery, I propos'd going to drink a Pot of Beer at a House where I was acquainted; but they not being up, we went to another, and asked for Arms, but they could provide us with none but a Mopstick saw'd in two. Then I went to see if the Prisoner's House was open. The Maid (who first brought the Prisoner to us) told me he was above Stairs I had not talked to her above two Minutes, before Jackson came in, and I believe we had a Dram together; and the Persons who were to assist us following Jackson, he made a Motion with his Hand to prevent their coming in, so they pass'd the Door, and I follow'd them, to see where they went in. Before I went after them, the Maid asked me, if I knew those Soldiers? No, really (says I) I don't. But under Pretence of going for a hot Rowl and Butter, I follow'd them, and bid them be easy till I came, or sent for them. When I came back to the House, Jackson was gone up Stairs, and I went up to him. The Prisoner was in Bed, and he seem'd before to be willing to embrace us; but the Maid coming up, and speaking something to him in an unknown Language, (Irish, I suppose) tho' he had his Breeches in his Hand, he put them under his Head, and laid himself down again, seeming much out of Humour, and to be very much startled. After this, I said, I believe the hot Rowls are come from the Bakehouse by this Time, be so good (speaking to Jackson) as to fetch me one. He tapp'd me on the Shoulder (to get me aside) and bid me not quit the Room till he came back. Jackson, under this Pretence, went and told our Men. He return'd in a Minute or two, and the Maid followed him up Stairs, very much surprized; then he peep'd through a Crevice in the Door, and seeing the Soldiers coming up Stairs, she and he struggled together at the Door; but he got it open, and let them all in. They immediately asked us, who gave us the Money to serve the King of France? I told them, - the Man that lay next the Wall: Upon which they bid him get up, for he must go along with them. The Appearance of Soldiers affrighted him, and he got up trembling; and both he and the Man abed with him, were bound with a Cord, - their Hands behind them. After they were pinion'd, I proposed carrying them before Colonel De Viel, and the Maid likewise. Prisoners and Assistants were now Nine in Number, and we all went together to a publick House, to wait for Colonel De Viel's rising: And remembering I had seen Papers in the Prisoner's Window wrote in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050027"></xptr> French, (I am sure they were not in Latin, for I understand something of that) I said - Gentlemen, search him, - may be he has Papers about him, which may strengthen our Evidence. They did not think proper to search him till he came before a Magistrate, so I bid them take Care that he dropp'd nothing; but after Colonel De Viel had sent word he was ready for us, the Prisoner, by some means or other, got his Hands into his Pocket, and dropp'd something like a Book or a Letter-Case. I desired to see what he had dropp'd, and it was pick'd up by Newbury, (I think.) He shew'd it to Brough , and I look'd ever him while he was reading it. 'Twas French; and Brough told us 'twas a French Conge There was a Seal to it, and to the best of my Knowledge, this is the very Paper. I took Notice of the Spelling the Name - Loglin Rennells . I must be very much mistaken, if this is not the ver same . It was produced before Colonel De Viel (I think) by Newbury, and the Colonel asked the Prisoner if his Name was Loglin Rennells? and he told him, Yes. Is this your Pas Yes . What had it you for? To come to England, to see my Friends. Why did you drop in? He said any body might drop a Paper accidentally</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever see me before that Night?</p>
               <p>Moore . Never in the whole Course of my Life, - o my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I go by any other Name?</p>
               <p>Moore . I don't know. The Woman was asked as we went along with them, what his Name was? and she said, Macguire .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know any thing of Ryan?</p>
               <p>Moore . No. From Jackson's Words I expected to have seen Ryan there that Night; but this Prisoner appeared in his stead, and was very fond of the Job: He said he could do as much, or more, for us, than Ryan; that he belonged to a better Regiment, and had better Quarters.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you strip yourself, to shew you had been whipp'd on board a Man of War?</p>
               <p>Moore . Yes, I did. I won't deny a Word. When I was on board a Tender to a Man of War, I got under the Denomination of having been an Informer, and was whipp'd for having the Name of an Informer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person351">
                  Leonard 
                  Armstrong 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person351" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person351" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Jackson having inform'd me, a Man wanted to enlist him into foreign Service, I took an Opportunity to go down with Moore to Jackson's Lodging. Jackson was willing to go with us to the Man, but his Wife made words with him about it, telling him he would bring himself into Trouble. When we went out together, she followed us into Holborn , and then Jackson desired me to go to a publick House with her, and if I could, to leave her there, and come to them in Bowl-Yard. I did so, and between Ten and Eleven at Night I got to the House, and asked the Maid, if there was not a Soldier and a young Man there? She said yes, and I was let in, and saw the Prisoner and the two Witnesses there. I know his Face, and remember that great Scar. His Coat I can't swear to, but he had then on a Waistcoat with whitish Buttons on both Sides. The Prisoner was surprized when I came in; but Jackson told him, he need not be surprized, - this (says he) is the Soldier I spoke of, who is willing to go as well as we: Upon which he seemed content. I can't say there was any Health drank, while I was there. I had not been long in the House, before Jackson's Wife came to the Door; Moore and he went to her, and while they were at the Door with her, the Prisoner said to me - I understand you are willing to go; I have enlisted them, and if you'll go with them you may: I don't know but I may go off Tomorrow . I asked him what Encouragement he'd give? You'll have, ( says he ) Five-pence Half penny a Day, to serve in the Dake of Berwick's Regiment, and other Encouragments . I asked him if he gave the Money down? No; he said, he had been bit before. I could not have any more Talk with him, because Jackson's Wife kept making a Noise at the Door, and I was afraid, the Thing would, by that Means, be blown. So I bid him good Night, and we went to Colonel De Veil's; but he was abed, so we parted, and I went and acquainted Newbury and Brough with what had passed. They insisted on my acquainting the Captain of the Guard; and I went to him, but he did not think proper to send Men from Guard, without an Order from Kensington, so we went ourselves, as soon as it was light, and took him ourselves. He was abed, on the farther Side next the Wall. He behaved civilly , and pretended Innocence.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did not you carry him to a Publick-house , before you went to Colonel De Veil?</p>
               <p>Armstrong . Yes: and there somebody propos'd to search him: One more knowing than we, said, may be he has a Conge about him. The Prisoner complaining he was pinioned too hard, I eased him, and presently Moore (I think it was) cry'd - he has dropped something, and Newbury took up the Letter-case, which was produced before Colonel De Veil .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050028"></xptr>Prisoner. Was Jackson with you, when you first came to me, in the Morning?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. Yes; we called on Jackson, and not he on us. When we were all together, we went to St. Giles's to get Arms, but we could not be supplied. Then we sent Moore and Jackson to the House, who were to give us a Signal, when to come in. When we came there, the Woman seemed to have locked the Door, but Jackson opened it, and we went in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person352">
                  Benjamin 
                  Newbury 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person352" type="surname" value="Newbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person352" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After the Prisoner was taken, we carry'd him to a Publick House, where he was observed by Moore to drop something, after the Proposal was made to search him. We looked under the Table, and I picked up this Letter-case, and gave it to Mr. Brough , who opened it, and took out this Conge; then he put it in again, and gave the Letter-case to me; and I produced it before Colonel DeVeil . Moore never had it in his Possession at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person353">
                  Hagher 
                  Brough 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person353" type="surname" value="Brough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person353" type="given" value="Hagher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was at the taking of the Prisone , and knew him by the Cut in his Forehead. We carry'd him to a Publick-house, and there Moore observing him to drop something, Newbury took up the Pocket-book, and gave it to me unopened. I having once been trapannca in to France in the same Manner, I opened it, to see for his Conge, which I found, and it was left in the Hands of Colonel DeVeil.</p>
               <p>Colonel DeVeil. After these Men had made their Depositions before me, in the Manner they have now done, this Paper was produced to me. I read it, Word for Word to the Prisoner, in French, and he acknowledged it was his Pass. 'Twas produced to me, as a Paper which he had dropped. I asked him, why he dropped it? He said, a Man might drop a Paper by Chance. I asked him, if Loglin Rennells was his Name? and he said it was.</p>
               <p>The Paper was read, in English, as follows.</p>
               <p>BERWICK's Irish Regiment of Foot. Leave of Absence. We who have signed, certify to all whom it may concern, that we have given Leave of Absence, to one named Loglin Rennells , Voluntier in the Company of Hadden, in the Regiment of Berwick , born at Kilshore , in the Province of U ster , aged 23. Five Feet three Inches and a half high: Chesnut Hair; blue Eyes; his Mouth of a midling Bigness: large Face, a little marked with the Small Pox, and a large Cut on the left Side of his Forehead.</p>
               <p>Signed,</p>

               <p>Dated 18 N.S.</p>
               <p>C. 1739.</p>
               <p>7 O. S.</p>
               <p>BARRY, Lieut . Col.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person354">
                  STAPLETON
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person354" type="given" value="STAPLETON"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person354" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Major.</p>
               <p>Colonel DeVeil. I can take my Oath, this is the same Paper which was produced to me.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person355">
                  William 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person355" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person355" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the Man who came in and undressed myself, and went to Bed. I lodge in this House, in Bowl Yard: I came home from Work about Seven o'Clock, and this Soldier, (Jackson) and the Shoe-maker (Moore) there. The Shoe-maker enquired for a Man, but neither of them could tell his Name. The Woman knew who they wanted, by the Description they gave of him, and she told them his Name was Ryan . When the Prisoner came in, the Shoe-maker told a Story about his being whipped on board a Man of War, and said he wanted to be enlisted. Says I, they won't take you, - you are not tall enough. Well, says the Prisoner, what have I to do with it? If you will go, you may; I know nothing of the Matter, - I'll have nothing to do with it; but the Shoemaker was urgent to go, and said if the Prisoner knew any Body that would take him, he should be glad. After they had been some time in the House, they and the Prisoner went up Stairs; and I went up some time after to Bed. The Shoemaker was urgent, above Stairs, to get into the King of France's Service, and the Prisoner said, - If you'll go you may, but I'll not advise you to it.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not you see the Prisoner measure him?</p>
               <p>Barret. No; nor I don't remember his carrying them out of the Room to the Top of the Stairs. They staid in the Room till they all went down together. They had a Dram, I believe, in the Room, but when the Reckoning came to be paid, the Prisoner had no Money, but went o'score for his Dram. They staid in the Room about an Hour, and I was awake all the Time. I had no Curtains to my Bed, nor did I lie with the Prisoner. I am a Carpenter, a labouring Man, and was to rise early the next Morning, but their Talking in the Room kept me awake; - indeed I did not endeavour to compose myself to Sleep, but I was willing to sleep if I could. I lay with my Eyes open all the Time, for I hearkened to their Talk, and could hear them as plain as if I had been nearer them.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you hear any Healths drank?</p>
               <p>Barret. No, none at all, as I heard, - really I did not hear the King of France's health drank. I have lodged six Weeks in the House; there are three Beds in the Room, and I lay in a little one by myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050029"></xptr>Counc. How long had they been above Stairs, before you went up.</p>
               <p>Barret . Not above ten or twelve-Minutes. I went to Bed between Eight and Nine, and they staid in the Room three Quarters of an Hour afterward.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person356">
                  Timothy 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person356" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person356" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am not akin to the Prisoner, but I was at this House, in Bowl-Yard, the 22d. of October, at Night. When Jackson and Moore came in, I was sitting by the Fire: They asked the Landlady for one Ryan; she told them, he was not there then, but if they'd call in the Morning she'd let him know, they had been there. The Witnesses drank a Pint or two, before the Prisoner came in; And then somebody spoke of a Soldier who had been in a Foreign Country, and the Shoemaker (Moore) said he wanted to go abroad; he shewed us his Back, and told us he had been whipped on Board a Man of War; swearing he would go any where to get his Bread, rather than ever go on board again. Then they asked the Prisoner about going to France; but he said he would not encourage them to any such Thing, - they might go if they would. After this, they went up Stairs for half an Hour, or better; what passed there I can't tell, for I was not in their Company above Stairs.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did you lie in the same Room with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. No; I lay up two Pair of Stairs, and he lay up one Pair.</p>
               <p>Counc . When Jackson and Moore came first and enquired for Ryan, did she offer to go and fetch any one else to them?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. No; not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did she go out of Doors after they came in?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I cannot say whether she did or no.</p>
               <p>Counc . How long were they in the House, before the Prisoner came into their Company?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. About a Quarter of an Hour: They had drunk two or three Pints of Two-penny, and some Gin, or Anniseed, or Wormwood-Cordial.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did the Maid and the Prisoner come in together?</p>
               <p>Reynolds . I cannot say, - but during the Time they were waiting for Ryan, she was in the Room, - she remained in the Room till the Prisoner came in, except the Time she was drawing their Liquor. - I can't say whether either of the Witnesses went out with the Prisoner, when he came in, - or not.</p>
               <p>Counc . Did the Prisoner know either of the Witnesses?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. No: But the Shoe-maker was drunk and made a Noise, which I suppose was the Reason the Prisoner took them up Stairs, and the Woman of the House was then sick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-51-person357">
                  James 
                  Sommers 
               <interp inst="t17391205-51-person357" type="surname" value="Sommers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person357" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have made Hay with the Prisoner in July last, (for Want of better Employment) at Mr. Lewis's , in Tyburn-Road. In October he lodged at a Chairman's, - an Acquaintance of mine - in Bowl-Yard, who sold Liquors in his House. We did not make Hay together above a Week, - none in October; but I believe I have drank with him once at this House, - I believe it was in October, - I cannot be positive - I can't tell whether he paid his Reckoning, but he had Credit in the House, if he had no Money. The chief thing that I came here for, was (as he told me) to swear that his Name was Rennells , and not Ryan.</p>
               <p>Counc . Can you tell upon your Oath, where the Prisoner was, between the Time of Hay-making and October?</p>
               <p>Sommers. I can't indeed. He told me in Hay-making-time, that he had been in France to see an Uncle, and that he intended to go there again that Summer.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17391205-51-verdict245" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-verdict245" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17391205-51-punish246" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-punish246" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-defend342 t17391205-51-punish246"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Evidence upon the Second Indictment, was the same, as in the preceeding Trial. And the Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17391205-51-verdict247" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-verdict247" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17391205-51-punish248" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-51-punish248" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-51-defend342 t17391205-51-punish248"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
