<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-5">
               <interp inst="t17361013-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-5" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-5" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-5-off20-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend72 t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-verdict24"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-5-off20-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend73 t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-verdict24"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-5-off20-c64" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend75 t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-verdict24"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-5-off26-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend72 t17361013-5-off26 t17361013-5-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>5, 6, 7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Page 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend72" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend72" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-defend73" type="defendantName">
                  William
                   Orman Rod
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend73" type="surname" value="Orman Rod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend73" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-defend75" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Putrode 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend75" type="surname" value="Putrode"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend75" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-defend75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted, for that <rs id="t17361013-5-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="riot"></interp>
               they being Persons of evil Minds and Dispositions, with divers other Disturbers of the Peace, armed with Clubs, Sticks, Stones, &amp;c. and unlawfully devising and contriving, to vex, molest and injure one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-5-victim77" type="victimName">
                           Graves 
                           Atkin 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim77" type="surname" value="Atkin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim77" type="given" value="Graves"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim77" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17361013-5-cd21" type="crimeDate">30th of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-cd21"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off26 t17361013-5-cd21"></join>, about a 11 at Night. before the house of the said Graves Atkin, in <placeName id="t17361013-5-crimeloc22">Lemon Street, in the Parish of St. Mary Whitechappel</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Lemon Street, in the Parish of St. Mary Whitechappel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-crimeloc22"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off26 t17361013-5-crimeloc22"></join>, did unlawfully and riotously gather and assemble, with divers others unknown, to the number of one hundred Persons and upwards, and the said Graves Atkin's Wife and Family being then in the said House, and being so assembled as aforesaid, they, the said 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-person78">
                        Robert 
                        Page 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person78" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person78" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-person79">
                        William Orman 
                        Rod 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person79" type="surname" value="Rod"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person79" type="given" value="William Orman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-person80">
                        Thomas 
                        Putrode 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person80" type="surname" value="Putrode"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person80" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said dwelling House, unlawfully, riotously and violently did attack and with divers other Persons unknown, the Windows and Window Shutters of the said House, with Clubs, Sticks, Stones, &amp;c. did break to pieces and destroy; by reason and means whereof the said Graves Atkin's Wife and Family were greatly affrighted, and put in fear and danger of their Lives, and in apprehension of receiving great Hurt, Damage, and injury; and the said Graves Atkin was obliged, in order to avoid the Rage and Fury of the said Page. Orman Rod, and Putrode, to absent himself from his House and Family, and Shelter himself in places unknown to the said Page, &amp;c. for the space of one Hour; and other Mischiefs and Damage bringing on the said Graves Atkin, &amp;c in contempt of the Laws, &amp;c. and with an intent to break the Peace of our Sovereign Lord the King, being then and there so assembled as aforesaid, they, with divers others unknown, did raise a great Disturbance, and a Riot made, and caused to be made, and for the space of one Hour they, the said Page, &amp;c. &amp;c. then and there did unlawfully continue, hollowing and behaving themselves to the terror of the Subjects of our Lord the King, in contempt of the Laws, and to the evil Example of others in like Cases offending, and against the Peace of our Sovereign Lord the King, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>The Counsel for the King having very judiciously opened the Nature of the Offence, and shewn the dangerous Consequence of such Outrages, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person81">
                  Richard 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person81" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person81" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Night, July 30 between 9 and 10, I was at the End of Red Lion Street, and I saw the Mob coming down Bell Yard, with Sticks and lighted Links. One of them made a sort of a speech directing the rest to go down Church Lane, to the Gentleman and Porter: My Master serving Mr. Allen who keeps the House with Drink, I ran down to inform him that his Sign was mentioned. There was about 50 or 60 of them then, and they had 2 or 3 Links with them. One read from a Paper the Signs of the Gentleman and Porter, the Bull and Butcher, and the Tavern in Well Street I did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130008"></xptr> not hear them make any Declaration what was to be done, but I went directly to Allen's to inform him they had great Sticks, like Stakes out of Bakers Bavins. While I was standing at Allen's Door, the Mob came down; I told them the House had been mine for a Fortnight, and that the Man who kept it before was gone. One of them was called Captain Tom the Barber, and was in a striped Banjan. I would have taken notice of him, but he turned away and would not let me see his Face. I desired him to use me favourably, and told him it was my House. They said they knew I was not Irish by my Tongue, and I should not be hurt. I made them set up Candles in the Windows, and pacify'd the Mob seemingly well, but a Woman telling them it was a sham, and that I was only the Brewer's Cooper, the Sticks flew immediately and beat the Candle out of my Hand, as I stood at the Door; but Justice Phillips coming down, and the Captain with his Soldiers, they took some of them, and the rest made off immediately, and were gone as suddenly, as if a Hole had been ready dug in the bottom of the Street, and they had all dropped into it at once.</p>
               <p>The Prisoners all declared they never saw this Evidence before.</p>
               <p>Justice Phillips. On Friday, July 30, about 10 at Night, some Neighbours came knocking at my Door in a great hurry, and told me the Mob were come out of Spittle Fields, and were pulling down some Houses; they desired my Assistance, and I told them my Assistance would be of little service, without support; reading the Proclamation will signify nothing; if you will go to the Tower, and give my service to the Governor, and desire his Assistance, I will venture my Person. They went, and the Governor, or the commanding Officer, sent 30 Men to my Door, and the Captain told me, they had Orders to go with me, and follow my Directions. I desired him that his Men might march quietly, without beat of Drum, and in the dark, and did not doubt, but with such brave Fellows, we should drive them, tho' they were a greater Number. When we came to the End of the Street, the Houses were all illuminated, and we heard a great Noise, as if they were knocking the Houses to pieces. I said to Captain Hudson, now Sir, I submit to you; if you please, command your Men into such a Disposition, as may be most proper for the securing as many of the Mob as we can. There was several hundreds attacking a House; and just over the way, there was a Baker's Shop; I apprehend they broke open this Baker's Celler, and armed themselves out of the Bavins. The Street was very light, and I could see (at a distance) the Mob beating against the Shutters with their Clubs, and could hear the Glass fly: so I said to the Captain, - now let us be upon them at once; I drew my Sword and ran to the House they were attacking, and, that Prisoner Page, I took him with his Club breaking the Windows: I could not tell whether he might not make use of it upon me, therefore I told him, if you don't surrender, I'll run you thro'. The Soldiers at the word of Command had stretched themselves into a Line, and then enclosed as many of them as they could; among the rest, the Prisoners; and the Serjeant seized them. The Prisoner Page I took my self, driving furiously at the Windows; every Pannel of the Shutters was broke but one, and all the Glass. Some were poking in with their Sticks to clear the inside, (I suppose) that they might get in. When the Soldiers had taken some of them Prisoners, the rest ran away, some one way, some another; those we had taken, were carry'd to the Watch-House, and that I might be more sure of the Prisoners, I called them over at the Watch-House, and took down their Names; then we posted 12 Soldiers with their Bayonets on their Muskets round the Watch-House, because we were apprehensive the Mob would rescue the Prisoners. After we had patroled 'till Morning, the Captain and I refresh'd ourselves at my House, and I ordered something for the Men at my Door. I am positive that the Prisoners were among the Mob, and Page I took myself in the Fact, the rest of them might be as near the House, as 'tis from hence to the Leads (before the Court.)</p>
               <p>Capt. 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person82">
                  Joseph 
                  Hudson 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person82" type="surname" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person82" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of July, I was sent for from the Tower, by a Message from Justice Phillips: The Governor ordered between 30 or 40 Men to suppress the Assembly, under the Directions of Mr. Phillips. I went with my Men to his House; he came out with us, and in our way to the place where the Riot was, we called upon another Magistrate. When we came to Lemon Street, we found a vast Number of People assembled together, and I believe there was about 8 or 10 of them were beating with Clubs against the front of the House of one Aikin: I cannot say I heard any particular cries; the Prisoner Page I am positive was one, but I cannot be so sure, with regard to either of the other. As they were beating against the front of the House, Mr. Phillips and I, at the front of our Men, with our Swords drawn, struck at one or two of them, and two or three of those who were attacking the House we seized immediately.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130009"></xptr> Mr. Phillips and I were close to one another, and when we had struck among them, our Men instantly follow'd; I cannot be positive to the Faces of any but Page, tho' we made 8 or 9 Prisoners in the Watch House. I went with Mr. Phillips to the Watch House, but I can't take upon Me to say positively the other Prisoners are the Men. After this, we went and clear'd the Street, and left a Corporal and 10 or 12 Men to guard the Watch House till the next Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person83">
                  Andrew 
                  Oakes 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person83" type="surname" value="Oakes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person83" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I went with my Captain, July 30 at Night to Lemon street, from the Tower: We march'd softly. and in the dark: When we got there, we found the Mob beating against the Windows of the House, the Man's Name that keeps it, I cannot remember, nor can I swear to the Faces of the Men who were attacking it. The Prisoner Orman Rod. I took in the middle of the Street; he had receiv'd a Cut from some of the Officer I believe it was from Justice Phillips, but he had nothing in his Hand when I took him, nor did I see him do any thing. He told me he was a <rs id="t17361013-5-deflabel23" type="occupation">Blacksmith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend73 t17361013-5-deflabel23"></join>, and desired me to let him go; I told him I could not, so he went along very good humour'd. I don't remember I heard any Cries, but I heard the Noise they made with their Sticks against the Window Shutters, and against the Glass.</p>
               <p>Mr. Phillips. I heard the Hollowing at my House. and the Cry in the Street was, down with the Irish, down with the Irish.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person84">
                  Daniel 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person84" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person84" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present in Lemon-street, and I heard the Noise of their beating against the Windows, tho' I saw but little of the Mischief 'till the Mob had done; then I saw the Shutters of the Windows were broke to pieces: I was as near as the rest, under the Command, and was going along the middle of the Street. I did see several striking against the Windows.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any Cries and Noise made?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I cannot remember particular Persons nor Words: I was indeed at the taking of Orman Rod; he was cut in the Head, and was then very much disguised with his own Blood. I saw him again after I came to the Tower, but I cannot now be sure whether the Prisoner is the same Person. I, and the last Man examined, brought him to the Watch House, and Mr. Justice Phillips was there when we delivered him in, and he saw him and all the rest of the Men that we took Prisoners, but I cannot swear to their Faces. I remember I took Orman Rod out of the Mob, and that either my Captain or Mr. Phillips cut him over the Head: he was within 4 or 5 Yards of the Door, but I did not see him strike, nor did I see any thing in his Hand; he desired us to let him go, and we told him we could not. He endeavoured to run away when the Captain and Mr. Phillips came upon him, but we layed hold of him and brought him back.</p>
               <p>Capt. Hudson. I cannot charge my Memory with the Man's Person.</p>
               <p>Justice Phillips. I saw Barnes seize the Prisoner Orman Rod, but I cannot say whether he struck at the Windows or not; I am positive he is the Man that was taken. This Soldier is unwilling to declare the Truth, because one of the Prisoner's is a Brother Soldier</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person85">
                  William 
                  Fairclough 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person85" type="surname" value="Fairclough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person85" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was under the Command of Capt. Hudson at that time; we went from the Tower to Mr. Phillips's House, from thence to the End of Lemon Street. I heard no Cry, but there was about 40 or 50 People in the Mob.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear no Cry at all?</p>
               <p>Fairclough. Only down with them - down with them, this was all I heard. They had Clubs in their Hands, and were demolishing the Windows, I seized the Prisoner Putrode, he was with them who were crying down with them - down with them, about half a dozen Yards from the House, and had a Stick in his Hand about the length of a common Walking-stick; but when I seized him, he dropped it, and begged for God's sake I would let him go. I told him I did not come for that End from the Tower; if my Captain and the Justice will let you go they may. We carried this Man to the Watch House, and Mr. Phillips, and Capt Hudson, and Capt, Littleer were there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take this Man? Fairclough. Between the End of Lemon Street and White Lyon Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you suppose he dropped his Stick by Design?</p>
               <p>Fairlough. He seemed surprised at my seizing him as I did.</p>
               <p>Justice Phillipss I saw Putrode seized by that Man; we ran upon them, and I cried out seize them, seize them; I laid hold of Page; and the Soldiers seiz'd Putrode.</p>
               <p>Graves Aikin. I live in Lemon Street; July 30, at Night, I was at a Neighbour's House; my Child came to me about 10 o'Clock, and told me there was a great Mob gone by. I went home, and a Lodger told me the great Cry was, put up your Lights. I imagined this was to distinguish Houses, so I sent for Candles and li't them up. Sometime after this, I heard they were coming back to my House; my Wife was very much<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130010"></xptr> frighted, and begged me to get out. I told her I would stay, but she insisting upon my leaving the House, I went out, and heard the Mob at Mr. Allens; I went thither, and heard them cry, Down with the Irish - down with the Irish; I saw them breaking Allen's Windows, and raking in the Kennel, I suppose for Stones, but I cannot say I saw them take any up. Then I heard them enquire for my House, a Woman directed them to it, and they fell immediately upon it. I believe there might be above a hundred People; they broke my Windows and Shutters with their great Clubs, but Capt. Hudson and Justice Phillips came in a very little time to my relief, and I was afraid to get in among them, lest some body should shew me to the Mob, as they had done my House.</p>
               <p>Page's Defence, My Sister being at my Fathers that Night, I went to see her home; we met the Mob, and while I stood looking on I was taken hold of.</p>
               <p>Alice Corner. I know nothing of this matter, nor where he was that Night; but I have known him from a Child, and never heard or saw any harm of him.</p>
               <p>- Brown. I saw Page that Night standing in Mill Yard looking on; there was a great Noise, and I said, Bob, what do you do here? he told me he was going home presently; this was a quarter past 11 at Night, and in a quarter of an Hour afterwards, I heard he was taken up. I have known him from a Child, he is a very honest Lad as ever I knew in my Days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person86">
                  Mary 
                  Hutton 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person86" type="surname" value="Hutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person86" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner a good Character.</p>
               <p>Orman Rod's Defence. I was at work that Night at Rotherhith 'till 8 o'Clock; then I went to Horse-lye-down, and came home to supper; but hearing the Soldiers were come, I went out to see the Sight, and was taken. I live in Rag Fair the Corner of Church Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person87">
                  John 
                  Grice 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person87" type="surname" value="Grice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person87" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and another Witness appear'd to this Prisoner's Character; but as they had both been Bail, for his Appearance at this Sessions, their Evidence was not taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person88">
                  Leonard 
                  Kell 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person88" type="surname" value="Kell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person88" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person89">
                  Richard 
                  Dobbins 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person89" type="surname" value="Dobbins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person89" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person90">
                  Thomas 
                  Herring 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person90" type="surname" value="Herring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person90" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person91">
                  Roger 
                  Whityate 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person91" type="surname" value="Whityate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person91" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and others appear'd, and gave this Prisoner a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person92">
                  Thomas 
                  Putrode 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person92" type="surname" value="Putrode"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person92" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence My Wife deals in Rag Fair, and sells old Cloaths: She was not at home that Night, I went out to see for her; the Mob came past me, and the Soldiers took me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person93">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person93" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person93" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person94">
                  Michael 
                  Seawell 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person94" type="surname" value="Seawell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person94" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17361013-5-person95">
                  Ann 
                  Bradford 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person95" type="surname" value="Bradford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person95" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest quiet Man. The Jury found them all <rs id="t17361013-5-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person96">
                  Robert 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person96" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person96" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was a second Time indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17361013-5-cd25" type="crimeDate">30th of July</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-cd25"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off26 t17361013-5-cd25"></join>, <rs id="t17361013-5-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assault"></interp>
               with divers other Malefactors, to the Number of one hundred Persons, arm'd with Clubs, Sticks, &amp;c. the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-5-victim98" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Farrel 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim98" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim98" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in Rose and Crown Alley, did assault, and several of the Glass Windows, and Shutters belonging to the said Windows, did break and destroy, the said 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-person99">
                        James 
                        Farrel 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person99" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person99" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and his Family being in the House; by reason of which the said Farrel for the preservation of his Life, was oblig'd to absent himself from his Family for the space of an Hour And for that he, the said 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-person100">
                        Robert 
                        Page 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person100" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person100" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , a certain piece of Board did cast and throw into the said House, which struck 
                     <persName id="t17361013-5-victim101" type="victimName">
                        Catherine, the <rs id="t17361013-5-viclabel27" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-victim101 t17361013-5-viclabel27"></join> of James Farrel<interp inst="t17361013-5-victim101" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-5-victim101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the left Thigh
            </rs>, to the great Damage of the said James Farrel and Catherine his Wife, and to the evil Example of others offending, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-5-person102">
                  James 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17361013-5-person102" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person102" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17361013-5-crimeloc28">Rose and Crown Alley in Church Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-5-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Rose and Crown Alley in Church Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-5-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off20 t17361013-5-crimeloc28"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-off26 t17361013-5-crimeloc28"></join>. On the 30th of July I was at home; my Wife was gone to bed with my Godchild, and I was undrest and in my Shirt when the Noise came down the Alley. I open'd my Window and look'd out, and heard them knocking at the next House. Hall and Kelly cry'd out, d - n ye that is not the House, and then they came to my House; I had a Candle in my Hand, and saw that Page and Kelley were the first that attack'd my Windows with their Clubs: Kelly's Wife open'd her Door, gave them a Candle, and cry'd d - n them, have their Heart's Blood. I was at the Window with a Candle in my Hand, and saw the Prisoner break my Windows, and the middle Pannel of the Door. When the Door was broke, I thought it high time to get away; so I open'd a back Casement, and got out in my Shirt from the first Story. I said to my Wife, you can't get out, you must be at their Mercy. I had no sooner spoke, but a Board was thrown in, which hit her on the Thigh, I jump'd out of the Window into the Hog Yard, and heard the Mob crying d - n it, which are Irish Houses? A Farrier let me thro' the Yard, and I went down in my Shirt towards Sullivan's: Fearing I should be known, I came back to the Farrier's, and got to my back Window, and my Wife threw me out something to cover me. While Page was beating against the House, I heard him cry out, d - n it, - more Help, more Help; and they did not leave me one whole Pane of Glass in my Windows, tho' I call'd out to Page - pray young Man forbear, - I ask your Pardon - I don't hurt any Body. <rs id="t17361013-5-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-5-punish30" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-punish30" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend72 t17361013-5-punish30"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend73 t17361013-5-punish30"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend75 t17361013-5-punish30"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-5-punish31" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-punish31" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-5-punish31" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend72 t17361013-5-punish31"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend73 t17361013-5-punish31"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-5-defend75 t17361013-5-punish31"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
