<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390117-19">
               <interp inst="t17390117-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-19" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-19" type="date" value="17390117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-19-off88-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-defend154 t17390117-19-off88 t17390117-19-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>89. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-19-defend154" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Easter 
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-defend154" type="surname" value="Easter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-defend154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-defend154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390117-19-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-19-victim156" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Mills 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim156" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim156" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-19-victim158" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hill 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim158" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-19-victim158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway , putting them in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from the said Mills, half a Guinea, and 10 s. in Silver, and 15 s. from the said Hill
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390117-19-cd89" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-off88 t17390117-19-cd89"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mills. In the Month of June (last) Mr. Hill and I took a Ride out for the Air, about Six in the Evening: To avoid the Dust, we went up a Lane call'd the <placeName id="t17390117-19-crimeloc90">Devil's Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc90" type="placeName" value="Devil's Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc90" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-off88 t17390117-19-crimeloc90"></join>, in the Way from <placeName id="t17390117-19-crimeloc91">Lower Holloway</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc91" type="placeName" value="Lower Holloway"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc91" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-off88 t17390117-19-crimeloc91"></join> to <placeName id="t17390117-19-crimeloc92">Crouch-End</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc92" type="placeName" value="Crouch-End"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-19-crimeloc92" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-off88 t17390117-19-crimeloc92"></join>; upon the Turn of an Elbow in the Lane, the Prisoner presented himself, and at a little Distance, saluted us with a Volley of Oaths, commanding us to stand: We thought proper to obey; so he came up to me first, swore again, and demanded my Money, holding<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170013"></xptr> his Hat in his left Hand, and his Bridle and Pistol in the right; I gave him what Silver I had, but he told me, he must have more, so I gave him Half a Guinea, and told him I had no more; then he demanded my Watch, and upon my assuring him I had none, he left me, and went to Mr. Hill; I saw Mr. Hill give him some Silver and a Key, the Key he desired the Prisoner to return. I know him perfectly well; his Usage made an Impression upon me: D - mn your Blood, - you're a dead Man, - I'll shoot you through the Head, &amp;c was the Language he made use of. He had another Wig on when I saw him in New Prison, yet I pick'd him out from all the People who were there. He had on when he robb'd us, a light natural Wig, and his Countenance made an Impression on my Mind.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hill. On the 30th of June, I believe it was half an Hour after Six, Mr. Mills and I were riding out for the Air, and, to avoid the Dust, we turn'd into a back Lane, called the Devil's Lane, we had not got above ten Poles into the Lane, but I saw the Prisoner, and said to Mr. Mills, - That Man looks like a Rogue; he laugh'd at me: But when he came up, he presented a Pistol: 'twas bigger than a common Pistol, but not so big as a Horse-pistol. Mr. Mills was robb'd first, and I next: When he had got his Money, he demanded mine, and I gave him what Money I had, and a Key, and a Pocket-piece; I asked him to give me the Key again, he d - mned me, and gave it me; when he had got my Money, he demanded my Watch, but I had pluck'd the String of it into my Breeches, and told him I had none; so I did not lose that. When I saw him in New Prison, I knew him perfectly well, and so did Mr. Mills.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Sort of a Horse did I ride?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hill. I think it was a bay Horse. He had no Neck-cloth on, and his Coat was unbutton'd, which shew'd his red Waistcoat. When he came up to us, he pull'd his Pistol out of his Leather Breeches. He had grey Stockings on, and a light natural Wig, - no Curl at all in it, - such an one as People of his Profession (generally) wear. He was two Minutes in robbing Mr. Mills; I look'd him full in the Face, and the Sun shone bright, all the Time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I think it hard to take People's Lives away, when they are innocent of the Matter. <rs id="t17390117-19-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390117-19-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-19-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-19-defend154 t17390117-19-punish94"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
