<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350116-29">
               <interp inst="t17350116-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-29" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350116-29" type="date" value="17350116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350116-29-off131-c152" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-defend217 t17350116-29-off131 t17350116-29-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350116-29-defend217" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Owen , otherwise <rs id="t17350116-29-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-defend217 t17350116-29-alias-3"></join>Gardener</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-defend217" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-defend217" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-defend217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17350116-29-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Camblet Cloak, value 8 s. a Callico Work'd Night Gown, value 4 l. a Quilted Petticoat lined with Blue Sattin, value 12 s. a Pair of Stays, value 8 s. four Petticoats, value 20 s. four Shirts, value 40 s. a rich Laced-handkerchief, value 5 l. six Suits of Laced Pinners, value 4 l. a double Laced Hankerchief, value 20s. three Silver Spoons, value 10 s. a Mother of Pearl Snuff Box, six Silk Aprons, twelve Cambrick Hankerchiefs, and a Pair of Shoes and Clogs, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350116-29-victim219" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Chilton 
                        <interp inst="t17350116-29-victim219" type="surname" value="Chilton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-29-victim219" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350116-29-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-off131 t17350116-29-victim219"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350116-29-cd132" type="crimeDate">May 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-off131 t17350116-29-cd132"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-29-person220">
                  William 
                  Chilton 
               <interp inst="t17350116-29-person220" type="surname" value="Chilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person220" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17350116-29-crimeloc133">Hen and Chickens in Cloth-Fair</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-29-crimeloc133" type="placeName" value="Hen and Chickens in Cloth-Fair"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350116-29-crimeloc133" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-off131 t17350116-29-crimeloc133"></join>. The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17350116-29-deflabel134" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-defend217 t17350116-29-deflabel134"></join> and lived with me a Month. I had a Son about seventeen. He was very lame of the Palsly, and quite helpless. On Sunday the twelfth of last May, I and my Wife went out about ten in the Morning, and left only my Son and the Prisoner at home. We returned at six, and knock'd at the Door. My Son look'd out of Window and told us that the Maid went out about four o'Clock and took the Key with her, so that he could not let us in. We went to a Neighbour's House where we staid; and the Prisoner not coming by nine o'Clock, I borrowed a Ladder,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173501160011"></xptr> and so got into the Window. My Son told me that the Prisoner went up Stairs and made a great Busling: That he called to her several times, and asked her what she was doing, and at last he heard her come down and go out. We searched, and soon found that she had rob'd us, at which we were much surprised, for we had a very good Character of her from Mrs. Richardson, a Milliner in Paternoster-Row. I advertised the Goods. and enquired after the Prisoner; at last I received a Letter from a Friend at Gloucester informing me that she was there, and married to one Gardner a Chimney-Sweeper. I went thither, but she and her Husband were then gone about the Country sweeping Chimneys. I got a Warrant to take her, and left Patterns of some of the Goods, and so came to London; and she was afterwards taken by Mr. Hemmings, the Keeper of Gloucester Goal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-29-person221">
                  Matthew 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17350116-29-person221" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person221" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Having a Warrant from Mr. Lythe, the Arch Deacon of Gloucester, I took the Prisoner at her Lodging at Little-worth - I found this Cloak there, which matches with the Pattern that was left with my Master by the Prosecutor. I carried her to the Green Dragon, and leaving her there with another Man, I went to call my Master - She confest that she had sold the two Silver Spoons at Gloucester, and the Callico Gown to a Servant Maid: And I found the Gown accordingly, but the Maid had taken it to Pieces to clean it, for the Prisoner had made it very black by wearing it when she went to sweet Chimneys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-29-person222">
                  Joseph 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17350116-29-person222" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person222" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw this Cloak and Quilted Petticoat lined with blue Sattin taken from the Prisoner at the Green Dragon by Mr. Hemmings. The Cloak was first found at her Lodgings, but she desired Mr. James to let her put it on when she was going to the Dragon, and he gave her leave. She own'd that the Cloak and Quilted Coat were her Mistress Chilton's Goods.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Mistress gave me the Cloak and Gown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350116-29-person223">
                  John 
                  Wilks 
               <interp inst="t17350116-29-person223" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner from a Child, she was born at Shresbury, and I never heard an ill Character of her beafore.</p>
               <p>The Jury found her <rs id="t17350116-29-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17350116-29-punish136" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-punish136" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350116-29-punish136" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350116-29-defend217 t17350116-29-punish136"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
