<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391017-42m">
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m" type="date" value="17391017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391017-42m-off172-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-42m-defend296 t17391017-42m-off172 t17391017-42m-verdict174"></join>
         
               <p>536. 
               
                  <persName id="t17391017-42m-defend296" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Drinkwater 
                  <interp inst="t17391017-42m-defend296" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-defend296" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-defend296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17391017-42m-defloc171">St. Sepulchre's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-42m-defloc171" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-42m-defloc171" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-42m-defend296 t17391017-42m-defloc171"></join>  was indicted, for <rs id="t17391017-42m-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               that 
                     <persName id="t17391017-42m-person297">
                        Catherine 
                        Kaylock, otherwise <rs id="t17391017-42m-alias-8" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-42m-person297 t17391017-42m-alias-8"></join>Harrison</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person297" type="surname" value="Kaylock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person297" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the 10th of December, in the 12th Year of his Majesty, in the Parish of St. Bride's, a Repeating Watch, with the Outside and Inside Cases, made of Gold, val. 20 l. the Goods of the Right Honourable 
                     <persName id="t17391017-42m-victim298" type="victimName">
                        Sackville 
                        <rs id="t17391017-42m-viclabel173" type="occupation">Earl</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-42m-victim298 t17391017-42m-viclabel173"></join> of Thanet<interp inst="t17391017-42m-victim298" type="given" value="Sackville"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-victim298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Privately from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391017-42m-victim300" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Lorton 
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-victim300" type="surname" value="Lorton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-victim300" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-victim300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did steal, &amp;c. and afterwards, on the 18th of December, in the said Parish, he, the said Drinkwater, on account of helping 
                     <persName id="t17391017-42m-person301">
                        Nathaniel 
                        Delander 
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person301" type="surname" value="Delander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person301" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   to the said Watch, feloniously did receive and have from the said Delander the Sum of 8 l. 8 s. as a Reward for helping him to the said Watch; the said 
                     <persName id="t17391017-42m-person302">
                        Catherine 
                        Kaylock 
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person302" type="surname" value="Kaylock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person302" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the Felon, not being apprehended, nor did the said Drinkwater apprehend, or cause the said Catherine to be apprehended and brought to Trial, nor did he give Evidence against her; contrary to the Statute, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution set forth, That the Offence charg'd upon the Prisoner was Felony by the Act 4 Geo. c. 7. 1. 4. '' To prevent Persons '' acquainted with Thieves from following the '' pernicious Practice of procuring stolen Goods '' from the principal Felons, and making them '' over to the right Owners for a Sum of Money, '' without discovering the Felon''; and offer'd to prove it in the following Manner, viz. That the noble Lord above-mentioned having sent a fine Gold Repeating Watch to Mr. Delander to be mended, Delander delivered it into the Custody of a Workman of his one Lorton. As Lorton was going home with the Watch, he fell into the Company of Catherine Kaylock, and she pick'd his Pocket of it. The Defendant hearing of Mr. Delander's Loss, and that one Pope and Kaylock, (the Husband of Catherine Kaylock) were in the Computer on this account, he apply'd to one 
               <persName id="t17391017-42m-person303">
                  Lydia 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person303" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person303" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person303" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (who is acquainted with many of this Sort of People) and told her if she would go to the Computer with him, and be instrumental in getting the Watch, it might be a good many Pieces both to her and him. Accordingly, she went, and the Defendant got the Watch into his Possession; but he being pretty well aware of the Penalty of the Act, it made him cautions in what Manner to restore it to Mr. Delander; for he did not do it openly, and with his own Hands, but it was to be left at a Tavern, in a Room, under an old Almanack. The Money was first to be put there, and when the Money was taken from thence, the Watch was to be left. And that the Prisoner actually had the Watch in his Custody, they offer'd to prove in this manner, viz. That<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173910170017"></xptr> he came home one Night in a very great Passion with his Wife, and cry'd, D - n, you, why don't you turn out? But she not being dispos'd to go out that Night, he was angry, and said, - then these two innocent People in the Compter shall not suffer; fetch me the Watch down Stairs, - I will give it to Mr. Delander again; upon this she went up and brought it down; and deliver'd it into the Prisoner's Hands, soon after which it was restor'd to Mr. Delander.</p>
               <p>But before the Witnesses were sworn, the Defendant's Council beg'd a Point of Law might be spoke to, by Way of Objection to the Prosecution of this Indictment: And the Council for the Prosecution having admitted, that Catherine Kaylock (the principal Offender) was dead, and had not been convicted; the Defendant's Council urg'd, that the Act directs the Pains, Penalties and Judgment [that is, the same Pains, &amp;c.] shall be inflicted on, and given against the Person that receives Money for restoring stolen Goods, &amp;c. as should have been given against the principal Offender for stealing them, and that he shall be guilty in the same Manner, and shall suffer as for the same Crime the principal Offender had been guilty of: That the Crime charged in the Indictment was for privately picking a Pocket, which is a capital Offence; but upon the Trial of the Principal (Kaylock) it might have came out only a single Felony; the Evidence might not have been sufficient to have convicted her of picking the Pocket, but yet it might have been sufficient to have caused the Jury to have convicted her of a single Felony: And if, upon Conviction of the Principal, it had come out a single Felony, then the Defendant must not have been indicted for a capital Felony, &amp;c. therefore it was impossible to know what Punishment to inflict on the Defendant, unless the Principal had been convicted. That the Act expressly requires the same Judgement in this Case, as should be given against the first Offender; but as the first Offender had not been convicted non constat, whether the Crime was single Felony, petty Larceny, or Capital.</p>
               <p>It was farther observ'd for the Defendant, That this Case tallied with that of Principal and Accessary: That receiving stolen Goods was not a Felony at Common Law, it was only a Misdemeanor, but it was made Felony by a particular Act, and yet it was never known that an Accessary was convicted of Felony, till the Principal had been convicted, and when the Principal could not be found, the Accessary could not be indicted for a Felony, but only for a Misdemeanor, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Substance of the Reply to these Objections was, That if they were to prevail, the Act would be eluded, and the Subject frustrated of all the Benefit intended by it: That if the Principal had been taken, and a Bill found against her, and she had dy'd, or broke Goal before Trial, it would be hard that the Act should be eluded, when the Fact mentioned in it could be prov'd by sufficient Witnesses; and as to the Comparison of this Case to that of Principal and Accessary, it is laid down in Hale's, that tho' the Principal does not appear, the Accessary may be put to Answer in a Way of Defence; and Serjeant Hawkins says, that tho' by ancient Authorities, the Party is not to be compell'd to answer before the Principal has answer'd, yet the contrary Opinion (he says) he takes to be settled at this Time. It was farther urg'd, that the present Case was a different Case, and the Fact charg'd on the Prisoner was an independant Fact: That the Gentlemen had mistaken the Words of the Act, which were, That the Party ( supposing him Guilty) shall suffer according to the Nature of the Felony committed (which was to be prov'd by the Circumstances of the Case): That the Act does not say he shall suffer as a Principal; but, if he is guilty, he shall suffer Pains and Penalties, according to the Nature of the Felony committed, and it does not mention a Word of the Principal's being first convicted.</p>
               <p>It was likewise observ'd, That in the Case of Jonathan Wild, the Principal Felon was not convicted when Wild suffer'd: And if the whole of the Charge against the Prisoner was but a Pretence, yet he was under the Cognisance of the Act, (for the Words of every Act must be suppos'd significant) and this Act says, If any Person, under Pretence of restoring, &amp;c. shall receive Money, &amp;c. he shall suffer, &amp;c. and if it was a meet Pretence, he must answer, tho' he must be convicted before he can suffer.</p>
               <p>It was farther observ'd by the Counsel for the Prosecution, That they were ready to prove, that Part of the Indictment that affected Catherine Kaylock, and tho' it was not to be prov'd by Record, but by Witnesses viva voce; yet, if that was prov'd, it was hop'd they should be allowed to proceed to the Proof of the other Part which affected the Prisoner; and if both Parts of the Indictment were prov'd, then the Court would be under no Difficulty to know what Judgment the Prisoner ought to receive; because the Act says he ought to receive the same Judgment as if he had pick'd Lorton's Pocket himself. It was again urged, that this Construction would be an absolute Repeal of the Act, and directly contrary to the Meaning of it, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>To which it was answered, That it was now impossible to convict a dead Body; That there was many a Case that might be called casus omissus; That the Party might die, and a Man might be disabled from doing what he intended to have done for his Country; That the other Side knew the Principal, and if they had taken her, and the Defendant had refused to give Evidence, then they would have come with a good Grace before the Court; That the Act relating to Principal and Accessary plainly chalks out the Method<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173910170018"></xptr> of Proceeding in such Cases; which is, that the Court should give such Judgment against him, as against the Principal Felon, and it was impossible in the present Case to know what that Judgment must be, because it would have been in the Breast of the Jury to have found it either a Transportable, or a Capital Felony; That it was incumbent upon them to shew what kind of Judgment was to be awarded against the Principal, but as the Act of God had put it out of their Power, it was now impossible.</p>
               <p>That the Observation that had been made of a Man's taking Money under a meer Pretence of restoring stolen Goods, being within the Act, is not sufficient, because the Act lays it down, that the Goods must be stole, though it be not expressed therein totidem verbis, yet it says, such Offender shall be punished as if he had stole such Goods, and in such a Manner, and with such Circumstances, as if the Offender had stole them; and the particular Kind of Stealing must be proved, and the Manner of it, before Judgment can be given in such a Case as this.</p>
               <p>That as to the Citations from Hale and Hawkins, though they say the Accessary may be put to answer, yet his Tryal was never proceeded on, till the Principal was try'd: And an Instance was mentioned, where a notorious Receiver of stolen Goods was taken, and nothing could be done against her till they had got the Principal; who being taken, was try'd, and burned in the Hand immediately, that he might then be a Witness against the Accessary.</p>
               <p>That as to 
               <persName id="t17391017-42m-person304">
                  Jonathan 
                  Wild 
               <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person304" type="surname" value="Wild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person304" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Case, the Exceptions were not then made. And as to the Objections being a Repeal of the Stature, it was otherwise, for the Man that helps another to stolen Goods for Money may be laid hold of, and then for his own Security he will discover the Principal, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Upon the whole no Evidence was given. <rs id="t17391017-42m-verdict174" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-42m-verdict174" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
