<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-11">
               <interp inst="t17360721-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-11" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-11" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-11-off60-c79" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-defend107 t17360721-11-off60 t17360721-11-verdict67"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-11-off63-c79" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-defend107 t17360721-11-off63 t17360721-11-verdict67"></join>
         
               <p>13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-11-defend107" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     English 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-11-defend107" type="surname" value="English"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-defend107" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-defend107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-11-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a pair of Shag Breeches, and a Cloth Frock without Sleeves, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-11-victim109" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Seymour 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim109" type="surname" value="Seymour"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim109" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 4 Pieces of Cloth cut out for a Coat, 4 pieces cut out for a Waistcoat, and other Things, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-11-victim111" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Gordon 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim111" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim111" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . <rs id="t17360721-11-viclabel61" type="occupation">Gent</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-victim111 t17360721-11-viclabel61"></join>. in the House of William Seymour
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-11-cd62" type="crimeDate">June 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-off60 t17360721-11-cd62"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-off63 t17360721-11-cd62"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted, for <rs id="t17360721-11-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Cloth Coat, a Woolen Stuff Waistcoat, a silk Waistcoat, a Dimitty Waistcoat and Breeches, a Suit of Sagathy Cloaths, the Goods of Persons unknown. Six Shirts, two pair of Worsted Stockings, six Handkerchiefs, two silk Gowns, two linnen Gowns, and other Things, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-11-victim113" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Wilson 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim113" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim113" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-victim113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17360721-11-person114">
                        Rebecca 
                        Burton 
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person114" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-person114" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-11-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-11-cd64" type="crimeDate">June 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-off60 t17360721-11-cd64"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-off63 t17360721-11-cd64"></join>.</p>
               <p>First Indictment.</p>
               <p>William Seymour. I am a <rs id="t17360721-11-viclabel65" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-victim109 t17360721-11-viclabel65"></join>; and the Prisoner was my <rs id="t17360721-11-deflabel66" type="occupation">Journey-man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-11-defend107 t17360721-11-deflabel66"></join>. The Things mentioned in the Indictment, I lost on the 26th of June. I had cut out a Suit for Mr. Gordon, and delivered it to the Prisoner to finish, and went out about some Business, and when I came Home again, English was gone out; I went to look for him, that my Work might be finish'd in Time, but could not find him. I returned Home, and my Wife told me my Man was come to work again. I went up Stairs into my Work Room, and my other Man told me that English had carried out the Cloaths he was about. On Saturday Morning he sent me Word where the Goods were pawn'd: I got a Search-Warrant, and found all the Things at Mr. Yarp's in Hounsditch; and took the Prisoner at Globe-Stairs by Ratcliffe-Cross, and carried him before Justice Priestly, where he owned he took the Things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-11-person115">
                  Robert 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17360721-11-person115" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person115" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner owned he took the Things when he was before the Justice; he said the Prosecutor ow'd him 20 s. and he pawn'd them to pay himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-11-person116">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17360721-11-person116" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person116" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with a Search-Warrant to the House where Wilson said I might find the Prisoner, and there we found a Chest which he and another Man had brought, but they were gone to the other side of the Water: Wilson's Wife was with them, and they were all going to New-England together. We went over the Water and took them; and before the Justice he owned he took the Goods for Money that the Prosecutor owed him, and the Justice committed him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Master owed me 20 s. for Wages, and I could not get the Money; I thought it hard as I was going to Boston, to leave so much Money behind me, so I pawn'd these Things and sent him Word next Day where they were. I have not any Witnesses, for I gave all my Money to one Mac - something, a Newgate Solicitor, to manage my Cause, and he is run away with the Money and has done nothing.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-11-person117">
                  Edward 
                  Costecan 
               <interp inst="t17360721-11-person117" type="surname" value="Costecan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person117" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had employed and entrusted the Prisoner, and took him to be an honest Man. <rs id="t17360721-11-verdict67" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-verdict67" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Second Indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-11-person118">
                  Robert 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17360721-11-person118" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person118" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 24th of June I had been out, and when I returned I found Seymour standing at my Door; he told me he was robb'd by these Irish Villains, and bid me see if I had not been robb'd too. I went up Stairs and found my Door fast, but he perswaded me to break it open, (for my Wife had carried away the Key) and we did so, and found the Things all gone, and my Wife too The Things mentioned in the Indictment, were in a Chest, and were brought some Time before, as a Pledge for four Guineas which my Wife had made me lend the Prisoner. We had heard of their Design of running away together to New England, so we went to the New England Coffee-House and got Intelligence where to take them there we found the Chest, but they were gone over the Water: We got a Waterman who said he'd give us leave to crop him if he did not take them; we followed his Advice, and took them, but the Justice let two of them go. He own'd the Chest was in his Custody, but he said he did not take it out of my Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That very Day, he had sold his Wife at the George on Tower Hill, for a Pot of Beer, to the Man she ran away with, and I was present. He half starved her, and turned her out of Doors, so we agreed to go to New England, and she took her Cloaths with her, and this Chest of mine that was at their House; for the Man she ran away with, was a Friend of mine. He swore the Robbery against his Wife.</p>
               <p>Wilson. I did not. The Lord above knows where my Wife is: I'm sure I don't; she is run away with t'other Irishman. <rs id="t17360721-11-verdict68" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-11-verdict68" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
