<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340911-47">
               <interp inst="t17340911-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-47" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-47" type="date" value="17340911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340911-47-off219-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-defend339 t17340911-47-off219 t17340911-47-verdict223"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340911-47-off219-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-defend341 t17340911-47-off219 t17340911-47-verdict222"></join>
         
               <p>55, 56. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340911-47-defend339" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Cook 
                  <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend339" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend339" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend339" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17340911-47-defend341" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Bartlet 
                  <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend341" type="surname" value="Bartlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend341" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-defend341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17340911-47-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver Watch, value 30 s. 2 half Guineas, and 30 s. the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340911-47-victim343" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Mason 
                        <interp inst="t17340911-47-victim343" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-47-victim343" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-47-victim343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-off219 t17340911-47-victim343"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17340911-47-person344">
                        Thomas 
                        Gale 
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-person344" type="surname" value="Gale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-47-person344" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-47-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17340911-47-cd220" type="crimeDate">Aug. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-off219 t17340911-47-cd220"></join>.</p>
               <p>Edward Mason. On the 5th of August, between 2 and 3 in the Morning, I happen'd to be in Liquor, and as I was going along Fleet-street, I was pick'd up by what we may call - not a Woman, I suppose - but - a Mistress of the Town, and I was taken into Sword and Hanging-Alley, or Hanging and Sword Alley, or some such a cramp sort of a Place.</p>
               <p>Court. What happen'd after you were carry'd into this Alley?</p>
               <p>Mason. Carry'd? - No, have a care of that, I was not so drunk as that came to neither - I was not carried - I walk'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110019"></xptr> or as a Body may say, I was conducted, by this Woman, as I took her to be; but I can't be positive what she was, Because I did not examine her, and I would not swear to a Thing that I was not sure of.</p>
               <p>Court. Was it either of the Prisoners?</p>
               <p>Mason. No; no, it was none of the Prisoners - But I was conducted up into a Room where I found the Prisoners. We had 2 or 3 Quarterns of Cherry-brandy, and other Liquors to the Quantity of 2 or 3 Shillings. Then they persuaded me to go to Bed, because they saw me in Liquor; and so I began to strip, and in the first Place the Shoes - Aye, I suppose the Shoes must come off first; and then to be sure the Breeches must come next, and the Breeches I laid upon the Table, and then -</p>
               <p>Court. You went to Bed?</p>
               <p>Mason. No; I don't suppose I went to Bed - But I was making Preparations to go to Bed, and so far is right. And when I had laid my Breeches upon the Table, the Prisoner, Betty Cook, snatches them up, and runs down Stairs with them. I cry'd out, Stop Thief ! my Breeches! my Breeches! she has got my Breeches, and all that I have - And indeed it was all that I had at that time.</p>
               <p>Court. All that you had?</p>
               <p>Mason. That is, all that I had in my Breeches, when my Breeches were off - Take me right - I don't say t'other and all - No, no - that was all safe.</p>
               <p>Court. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Mason. My Watch, and two half Guineas, and 30 s. may I believe I could swear to a Guinea more, for I had 4 or 5 l. not long before I met the Woman, and I had been in no other Company that Night.</p>
               <p>Court. Where did you get fuddled?</p>
               <p>Mason. At the Tavern along with some Friends.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you were in Company?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes; in Company with Men, but with none of the other female Sex, that was what I meant, for I was not so drunk as not to know one from t'other - I left my Friends at a Tavern upon Fleet-street-hill, and at several other Places, and I had my Money and Watch then, and that was not much above half an Hour before I lost my Breeches</p>
               <p>Court. Did you follow the Prisoner Cook when she went away with your Breeches?</p>
               <p>Mason. No; the other Prisoner Bartlett bolted the Door, and would not let me run after my Breeches.</p>
               <p>Court. Was the Bolt within side the Room where you were?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. And could not you open it then?</p>
               <p>Mason. I might have done to, but if I had where should I have found my Breeches?</p>
               <p>Court. Did you ever get your Breeches again?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes? a Man brought them to me afterwards, but there was nothing in them except this Rule.</p>
               <p>Court. When you were so drunk as you say, could you take so much notice of Cook as to know her again, and especially as you had been such a little while in her Company?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes; for I'll tell you what - It's just like as when a Man was frighted, his Senses strike quicker than ordinary at such a Time.</p>
               <p>Court. That's a new Piece of Philosophy.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Cook. Did I bring you into the, House?</p>
               <p>Mason. No; but you took my Breeche that I'll swear, and I was not over and above drunk neither, for I remember that you were brought out of the Bed, and had no Stockings on, because as I have heard since, you were famous for slight of Hand - And I found you again, about a 11 a Clock, the same Morning, with the Watch upon you - No, that's a Mistake, for you were upon the Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-47-person345">
                  Francis 
                  Skelborn 
               <interp inst="t17340911-47-person345" type="surname" value="Skelborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-person345" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable of St. Brides. The Prosecutor told me, that he had lost his Breeches in Gale's House, in <placeName id="t17340911-47-crimeloc221">Hanging-Sword-Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340911-47-crimeloc221" type="placeName" value="Hanging-Sword-Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340911-47-crimeloc221" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-off219 t17340911-47-crimeloc221"></join>, upon which I took up the Landlady, and Bartlett, the Girl, and carry'd them before Alderman Brocas, and soon afterwards I heard that Cook was at another House in the same Alley. I went and thither and found her upon a Bed. As soon as we came in, I perceived her take something<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110020"></xptr> off the Bed, and put it in a Chair, and then she sat down upon it. She desired us to go out a little, because she wanted to make some necessary Occasion. You Saucy Toad, says I, get up! and then we found the Prosecutor's Watch under her. I carry'd her to the Bull-Head, and there she was so outrageous, that she swore, and damn'd, and broke all the Windows, and we were forced to send for a pair of Handcuffs from the Compter, before we could manage her - At last she offered the Prosecutor 18 s. to make the Matter up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-47-person346">
                  Robert 
                  Misset 
               <interp inst="t17340911-47-person346" type="surname" value="Misset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-person346" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the Prosecutor and Constable to Cook's Room. The Prosecutor said, That's the Woman. She got into the Chair, and said she wanted to make Water - I swear to the Words Verbatim, and I took the Watch from the left side of her Buttock - Yes, I say, her Buttock, for I think that is a proper Word.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Cook. She that carry'd the Prosecutor into the House, was more likely to rob him than I.</p>
               <p>Court. But how came the Watch in your Possession?</p>
               <p>Cook. The Woman that pick'd him up, was a little Woman big with Child, and her Husband brought the Watch to me, and desired me to Pledge it for him.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17340911-47-verdict222" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-verdict222" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> Mary Bartlett, and found Elizabeth Cook, <rs id="t17340911-47-verdict223" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-verdict223" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-verdict223" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               guilty to the Value of 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17340911-47-punish224" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-47-punish224" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-47-defend339 t17340911-47-punish224"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
