<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-3">
               <interp inst="t17380222-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-3" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-3" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-3-off17-c42" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-defend48 t17380222-3-off17 t17380222-3-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>3. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-3-defend48" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Gittings 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-3-defend48" type="surname" value="Gittings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-defend48" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-defend48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380222-3-defloc16">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-3-defloc16" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-3-defloc16" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-defend48 t17380222-3-defloc16"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-3-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a silver Watch, value 10 s. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380222-3-victim50" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hanquets 
                        <interp inst="t17380222-3-victim50" type="surname" value="Hanquets"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-3-victim50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380222-3-victim50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-off17 t17380222-3-victim50"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17380222-3-cd18" type="crimeDate">Jan. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-off17 t17380222-3-cd18"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220004"></xptr>Mr. Hanquets. On the 24th of January I was at <placeName id="t17380222-3-crimeloc19">St. James's House</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-3-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="St. James's House"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380222-3-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-off17 t17380222-3-crimeloc19"></join> to see his Majesty return from the Parliament House; after the King was come by, I attempted to get into the Park, through the narrow Passage, by the King's Kitchen, but I was surrounded with a Croud of People, and being apprehensive of Pickpockets, I clapp'd my Hand upon my Breeches where my Watch was Presently I felt something stirring under my Hand, and looking over my Shoulder, I saw the Prisoner very near me; at that Instant I felt something slip out from the Side of my Pocket, and the Prisoner turn'd about, and made off as fast as he could. I cry'd out stop Thief! And some Men who were near, pursu'd him; I follow'd as fast as I could, but he fled into a Barber's Entry, where these two Men took him, with my Watch upon him. I came up while they were searching him in the Entry, and he deny'd he had any Watch about him, but I saw them draw it out between the Cloth and the Lining, from the Bottom of his Coat. This is the very Watch, which I lost at that Time, and which I saw taken out of the Skirts of his Coat. He was carry'd before a Justice, and there he said, he found it upon the Ground. I am very positive to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did say before the Justice, that he could not tell who took the Watch from him?</p>
               <p>Hanquets. No, I said no such Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-3-person51">
                  William 
                  Capps 
               <interp inst="t17380222-3-person51" type="surname" value="Capps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person51" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of January I saw the Prisoner and Prosecutor in the midst of a Croud, and observ'd both of them scuffling to get out of it. The Prisoner made his Way through first; the Prosecutor follow'd, and cry'd stop Thief ! I pursu'd him into the Priory, and he was never out of my Sight; when I took him, he told me he had no Watch about him; but the Prosecutor being positive to him, I felt in his Pockets, on that Side next me, and found nothing; but another Person gathered up his Cloaths on the other Side, and feeling something, he cry'd out, - here's the Watch, and pull'd it out of the Skirts of his Coat, from between the Lining and the Outside. The Pocket was broke, and it had slipp'd down between the Cloth and the Lining.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-3-person52">
                  William 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17380222-3-person52" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd the above Witness, and declar'd that he drew the Watch from the Bottom of the Prisoner's Coat, and that Mr. Hanquets own'd it immediately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-3-person53">
                  James 
                  Wallington 
               <interp inst="t17380222-3-person53" type="surname" value="Wallington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person53" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry'd the Prisoner before Mr. De Veil, who ordered the Watch into my Custody, and I have kept it ever since.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was coming through St. James's Court that Day, and kick'd the Watch before me the Ground; when I took it up, it was dirty.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wallington. The Soldier (Jones) told me Yesterday, that he saw some Dirt upon the Watch, when he took it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Capps. The Prisoner's Friends were all Yesterday, treating with the Soldier about a favourable Evidence from him, and they promis'd him, he should be rewarded.</p>
               <p>Jones. They did promise to reward me, if I would be favourable in my Evidence.</p>
               <p>Capps. I never lost Sight of him, 'till I took him in the Barber's Entry. <rs id="t17380222-3-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17380222-3-punish21" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-3-punish21" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-3-defend48 t17380222-3-punish21"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
