<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390221-31">
               <interp inst="t17390221-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-31" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390221"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-31" type="date" value="17390221"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390221-31-off150-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-defend241 t17390221-31-off150 t17390221-31-verdict156"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390221-31-off152-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-defend245 t17390221-31-off152 t17390221-31-verdict156"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390221-31-off152-c168" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-defend247 t17390221-31-off152 t17390221-31-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>182. 183. 184. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-defend241" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Haggis 
                  <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend241" type="surname" value="Haggis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend241" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of St. Mary Whitechapel , was indicted for that <rs id="t17390221-31-off150" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-off150" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-off150" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               he, not having GOD before his Eyes, &amp;c on the <rs id="t17390221-31-cd151" type="crimeDate">12th of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-off150 t17390221-31-cd151"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-off152 t17390221-31-cd151"></join>, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390221-31-victim243" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Main 
                        <interp inst="t17390221-31-victim243" type="surname" value="Main"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-31-victim243" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-31-victim243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, did make an Assault, and her unlawfully, feloniously, and against her Will, did carnally know, and abuse, against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c
            </rs>. And 
               
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-defend245" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Keeble 
                  <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend245" type="surname" value="Keeble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend245" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was a fifth time indicted, with 
               
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-defend247" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Gibbons 
                  <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend247" type="surname" value="Gibbons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , for that <rs id="t17390221-31-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               they feloniously were present helping, comforting, and assisting him the said Haggis, the aforesaid Rape to commit, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person248">
                  Sarah 
                  Main 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person248" type="surname" value="Main"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person248" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodg'd in the <placeName id="t17390221-31-crimeloc153">New 'Change, in Rag-fair</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-31-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="New 'Change, in Rag-fair"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-31-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-off150 t17390221-31-crimeloc153"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-off152 t17390221-31-crimeloc153"></join>, with a single Woman, - a poor Woman; she blacks Shoes. I gave her 6 d. a Week for my Lodging, and there was two others lodged there, who gave her 6 d. a Week a-piece. About three Weeks ago, I went out for a Pipe, between Eleven and Twelve o'Clock at Night, to the Cheshire Cheese, and to beg a little Bit of Tobacco; and there I saw George Haggis [the <rs id="t17390221-31-deflabel154" type="occupation">Butcher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-defend241 t17390221-31-deflabel154"></join>,] Keeble and Gibbons; there were Seven of them in all. Haggis told me, (at the Cheshire Cheese ) that I was his Wife; and you B - ch, (said he) you ran away from me the Day before: I ran out of the House from him as fast as I could, [in order] to get home, but he ran after me into the New 'Change. The New 'Change is a Place like a Square, where the People bring old Cloaths, and lay them down for Sale. He overtook me by the Pump in the New 'Change, and tore my Gown out of the Gathers, and beat me with a Stick; then he wanted to be impudent with me there. [The Witness here gave a particular Account of the beastly Behaviour of Haggis in this Place.] But somebody looking out of a Window, and calling to him, he desisted, and let me go. I ran away again, but he ran after me, and got hold of the Tail of my Gown, and though I was got to my Landlady's Door, yet I could not get in, and shut the Door upon him, but he came in after me. My Landlady<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173902210016"></xptr> and a Woman big with Child, and a Boy was in the Room, - 'twas a Ground Room, where the Woman, the Boy, and I used to lie, for a Penny a Night. When Haggis was got into the Room, six other Fellows follow'd him, and came in, among whom were the Prisoners, Keeble, Gibbons (the <rs id="t17390221-31-deflabel155" type="occupation">Barber</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-31-defend247 t17390221-31-deflabel155"></join>), and a Fidler. They were no sooner in the Room, but they turn'd the two Women out; and the Boy was order'd out, but he hid himself in a little Closet by the Door. When the Door was shut, and lock'd, and the Key taken out, Keeble threw me down; (he was the first Man who abused me in the House.) Then they blew the Candle out, and blow'd it in again; this they did two or three times: [The Witness express'd herself here in Terms necessary to prove the Fact, and gave such an unparallel'd Account of the Abuse, and of Gibbons's Behaviour, as would be shocking to every chaste Ear.] I cry'd out Murder but Haggis said, if I made a Noise he would run his Knife into me; and tho' I did all that I could to prevent it, yet he abused me three times in the Space of half an Hour. I cry'd out, Murder! but the other Men laughed, and cry'd, - beat the B - ch, beat the B - ch, make her be still, and Gibbons laid hold of me, while Haggis was abusing me; and then Gibbons himself, and Keeble, - and all of them, &amp;c. I was left in such a Condition, &amp;c. that had it not been for Gibbons, I should have been burnt to Death. The Fidler they brought in with them, was present all the time, and play'd several Tunes. After this they unlock'd the Door, and went away; and my Landlady came in as soon as they were gone. I cry'd, and made my Complaint to her; she told me, she was afraid to come in, for Fear of having her Brains dash'd out. I complain'd likewise to the People at next Door: and they told me, that when the Men left me; they came in there for each of them a Glass of Maxim, [ Geneva,] but they could not tell any of their Names. I live alone, - I have had no Friends these three Years, so I give this Woman 6 d. a Week to let me lie there: Her Name is Pegey. The Prisoners came sometime afterwards to the House, and said, if the People who were in the House had not gone out, they would have served them the same Sauce.</p>
               <p>Haggis. Did not I give you Money?</p>
               <p>Main. No.</p>
               <p>Haggis. Did not you say, if Gibbons would give you half a Crown, you would not prosecute? Did not you receive Money?</p>
               <p>Main. No; they would have given me a Halfpenny a-piece, but I would not take any of their Money, but made an Information against them, before Justice Riccards, the next Day after the Abuse was committed; I can't tell directly the time, but 'twas on a Monday Night, about a Fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>Gibbons. It was not on the next Day (Tuesday) that she made her Information, for she was with me the next Day to make it up.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Riccards. I took the Girl's Information on the 14th Instant, but I can't be sure whether it was Tuesday or Wednesday. She swore the Fact was committed on Monday the 12th.</p>
               <p>Gibbons. Was not you with me at the The Three Tobacco Pipes, and drank with me after this?</p>
               <p>Main. I was there with a Woman and her Husband, and the Woman's Husband said, - let's send for Gibbons, and he came, and owned the Fact, and desired me to make it up. This was on Tuesday between Three and Four o'Clock. He said he would cloath me, if I would make it up, and he offered to pay me ten Pounds, but I told him if I cleared one, I must clear the rest; and he said, - no, you Fool, there's no Occasion for that. I did not accept of his Offer, but came away without his Notice, and left him drinking with the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person249">
                  Sarah 
                  Liley 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person249" type="surname" value="Liley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person249" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (nicknamed Pogey) gave an Account, That on Monday Night, at almost Twelve, Haggis came to her Door, and asked for a Quartern of Maxim; and tho' the Door was locked, he pushed it open; a little Push; she said, would open it, and then Haggis came in; he had not been long in the Room, before Main went to beg a Pipe of Tobacco for the Woman with Child, and Haggis followed her out. While Main was out, she heard her call out, - Pogey ! - Pogey! but she was afraid to go out to her. When Main returned, the Men all came in in a Quarter of a Minute after her, and Haggis struck Main a Slap in the Face, &amp;c. [She here gave an Account of Haggis's obscene Behaviour, before she was turned out] And that one of them cry'd, - turn the Bitches out, which was done accordingly. That she went to the Watch House twice, and asked for the Constable, telling the Watchman Mischief she apprehended would be done; that at last she found the Constable in the Watch-House, but he would not stir out of his Chair, nor any of the Men. That before she went to call the Constable, she heard the Girl cry out dread-fully<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173902210017"></xptr> - Murder! Murder! And when she came back, she saw Three Men come out of her Door first, and Four others after them, but that she could not swear to any of them but Gibbons.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person250">
                  Edward 
                  Saw 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person250" type="surname" value="Saw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person250" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the Boy) gave an Account, That he stood in a Closet by the Door, and saw Haggis's Nakedness, &amp;c. And, that she screamed out, and the Fidler play'd all the Time. His Evidence confirmed Main's and Pogey's in several Circumstances. He added, That he staid in the Closet 'till he was frighted and terrify'd (lest they should find him, and abuse him, &amp;c.) then he got away.</p>
               <p>Gibbons the Prisoner said the Boy had a bad Character; and the Boy owned he had been disobedient to his Father, and had been Guilty of something he was ashamed to speak of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Riccards informed the Court, That Gibbons, when he was before him, named Haggis, and Keeble (a notorious Thief) as concerned in the Fact; he would not allow a Rape had been committed; but he said, they had used the Girl very ill, and if it had not been for him, she must have been burned to Death.</p>
               <p>Haggis, in his Defence, gave an Account of some lewd Discourse that pass'd between him and the Girl, when she came for the Pipe of Tobacco, and said she was a notorious Whore, and the Boy a Pick-pocket.</p>
               <p>Gibbons said, He was out that Night with others, in Pursuit of Keeble, who was a Thief, and had he been in the Way, they should rather have taken him, than assisted him.</p>
               <p>Keeble. Gibbons is a Thief-Taker, and was then in Pursuit of me, to take me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person251">
                  John 
                  Frederick 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person251" type="surname" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he was in Pogey's House during these Transactions, and that the three Prisoners came in with a Fidler and three other Men, and the Girl ran in before them. He mentioned some Circumstances in Haggis's Behaviour, which corresponded with the Girl's Account, and that of 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person252">
                  Edward 
                  Saw 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person252" type="surname" value="Saw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person252" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (the Boy) but he added one Instance of Indecency in the Girl, before the Commission of the Fact. He said, the Girl did cry out, and said, - O Lord! let me alone. But as he was sent out for a Pint of Gin, he did not see all that passed. In answer to a Question that Gibbons put to the Witness, he said he lodged one Night with Main about a Year and a half ago, and likewise that very Night the Fact was committed, after the Prisoners and their Companions were gone; and that Keeble was not one of the Company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person253">
                  Mary 
                  Barnet 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person253" type="surname" value="Barnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person253" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Midwife, said, she went to see the Girl in White-Chappel Work-house, on the Saturday following; she examined her, and found her Body Scabby, and Symptoms of the Itch upon her, but not the least Sign of her having been thus abused.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person254">
                  John 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person254" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon, examined her a Week after the Fact, and found no Disorder, but he could not tell whether there might not have been an Amendment in a Week's time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person255">
                  Mary 
                  Carnes 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person255" type="surname" value="Carnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person255" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account, that she saw the Men go in a little after Ten, and that they came out again a little before Twelve. That she saw the Boy at the Door, and he told her - the Men were a-going to send for Liquor, and to give the Girl a Penny a-piece. That the Boy was several Times at the Door to listen, and she heard a Noise, but could not tell which of them made it: That Pogey came to and fro, and went to call the Watch: That she had heard some People give the Girl a bad Character, but Pogey's, in General, was that of an idle Person. And tho' Pogey kept a Room for Lodgers, yet there was no Bed in it, nor any Thing but a Tub, a Salmon-Kitt, and two Stones in the Chimney to make a Fire between.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person256">
                  Jane 
                  Gilstrup 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person256" type="surname" value="Gilstrup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person256" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same Effect, adding, That when the Men were gone, she saw Pogey-and the Girl go out together for a Dram, and that the Girl told her, they had not much injured her, only her Cheeks and her Hands were sore with their beating her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person257">
                  Cath.
                   Chappel
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person257" type="surname" value="Chappel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person257" type="given" value="Cath."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             saw the Prisoners come out of the House; her Evidence was to the same Effect with Gilstrup's and Carnes's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person258">
                  Richard 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person258" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person258" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Boy's (Saw's) Father-in-law, deposed, That the Boy would lie about in the Streets, and he could not speak in his Behalf.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person259">
                  Mary 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person259" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person259" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore she heard Pogey say, (the Day before the Trial) that she had not appeared against the Prisoners, if they had given her the new Cloaths they had promised her; and that both she and the Girl had very bad Characters.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person260" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he had seen the Fellows that lurk about the Glass House pulling and halling both Pogey and the Girl, and he thought they seemed willing to be so pulled and halled about.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person261">
                  Thomas 
                  Godding 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person261" type="surname" value="Godding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person262">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person262" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person262" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person263">
                  Patrick 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person263" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person263" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person264">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gofton 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person264" type="surname" value="Gofton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person264" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person265">
                  George 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person265" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person265" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person266">
                  Ellen 
                  Newport 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person266" type="surname" value="Newport"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person266" type="given" value="Ellen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person267">
                  Robert 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person267" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person267" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person268">
                  Robert 
                  Kisby 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person268" type="surname" value="Kisby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person268" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person269">
                  Samuel 
                  Gibbons 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person269" type="surname" value="Gibbons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person269" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person270">
                  Thomas 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person270" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person270" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person271">
                  Sarah 
                  Pomfret 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person271" type="surname" value="Pomfret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person271" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person272">
                  Thomas 
                  Barnet 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person272" type="surname" value="Barnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person272" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person273">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person273" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person273" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person274">
                  Hannah
                   Hare
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173902210018"></xptr>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person274" type="surname" value="Hare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person274" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-31-person275">
                  William 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person275" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person275" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390221-31-person276">
                  Henry 
                  Teat 
               <interp inst="t17390221-31-person276" type="surname" value="Teat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person276" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , appeared for the Prisoners, and gave them good Characters; some of those who appeared for Gibbons, declared they never heard his Character impeached, but on Account of being a Thief Taker, and that he lived agreeably with his Wife, and was fond of his Children. Those for Haggis declared, they took him to be an honest Man. Several of these Witnesses gave Pogey, and the Girl an ill Character. All <rs id="t17390221-31-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-31-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
