<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-41">
               <interp inst="t17370907-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-41" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-41" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-41-off212-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-41-defend295 t17370907-41-off212 t17370907-41-verdict214"></join>
         
               <p>44 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-41-defend295" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hickman 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-41-defend295" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-defend295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-defend295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370907-41-defloc211">St Leonard Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-41-defloc211" type="placeName" value="St Leonard Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-41-defloc211" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-41-defend295 t17370907-41-defloc211"></join>, was Indicted for <rs id="t17370907-41-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously making and causing to be made a certain false, forged, and counterfeit promissory Note, for the Sum of 56 l. &amp;c. and for uttering and publishing the same, knowing it to be false, forged and counterfeit 
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370907-41-cd213" type="crimeDate">July 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-41-off212 t17370907-41-cd213"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution having open'd the Charge, the Witnesses were call'd.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-41-victim297" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Sturk 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-41-victim297" type="surname" value="Sturk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-victim297" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-victim297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-41-off212 t17370907-41-victim297"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . The Prisoner is the Man. My acquaintance with him began, by his coming to Drink at my House, for at that Time, I kept a publick House. What he call'd for, he paid for, and spent his Money pretty liberally, never insisting on Credit, nor ever borrowing Money of me. But hearing I was a Widow, he told me he had a Chest with a great many good Things in it coming Home in the Fleet with Sir 
               <persName id="t17370907-41-person298">
                  John 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17370907-41-person298" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he would bring it to me. He told me likewise, that he had got a Note upon Mr. Jasper of Tower-Hill, payable 2 Months after Date for 56 l. and if I would consent to Marry him, he would leave that with me. I refused him, but after many Persuasions, he left the Note with me, tho' I told him, I had no Inclination to Marriage. He said, if I had any Occasion for Money, he would endorse the Note, and then I might make'use of it. I told him I should not want it, for I was supported other Ways, and if I went to Holland, as I believe I should, - I should have enough. Some Time after I resolved to go to Holland, so I left the Note with Mr. Peacock to take Care of it for him, but Mr. Peacock told me the Bill was a bad one, and if I did not produce the Man I had it of, I should come into Trouble. The Prisoner was then at Portsmouth, Mr. Peacock desiring to know how a Letter might be directed to him, we went to the House where he had lodged and enquired. The Woman told us, he was going a two Years Voyage, and we apprehended it would be very difficult to find him. But I set a Man to watch for him in the Neighbourhood, and he saw him come by that Evening; he was going to make his Escape, and the Woman was following him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he taken then?</p>
               <p>Sturk. Yes; and this is the Note I received of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give it you as a real, true Note?</p>
               <p>Sturk. Yes; and he said if, I wanted Money, I might make use of it; he told me, it was a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070031"></xptr> Debt due to him from Squire Jasper; but I refused to make use of it.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads the Note.</p>
               <p>At, or on the twienth Day of June, I promise to pay 
               <persName id="t17370907-41-person299">
                  Jon 
                  Hickman 
               <interp inst="t17370907-41-person299" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person299" type="given" value="Jon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Sum of Fifty-six Pounds Ster. for Value received, Witness my Hand.</p>
               <p>May 27 Tower-Hill. 56 l. 
               <persName id="t17370907-41-person300">
                  Edwd 
                  Jasper 
               <interp inst="t17370907-41-person300" type="surname" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person300" type="given" value="Edwd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Tower-Hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-41-person301">
                  Thomas 
                  Chorley 
               <interp inst="t17370907-41-person301" type="surname" value="Chorley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person301" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Jasper's Clerk, and am very well acquainted with his Hand writing. This Note I am sure is none of his Writing, it bears not the least Resemblance to any Writing of his, that ever I saw. Here is a Paper of Mr. Jasper's Writing, this I know to be his Hand, and this forged Note is not at all like it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you liv'd with Mr. Jasper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Chorley. Seven Years.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was this forged Note brought to your Master?</p>
               <p>Mr. Chorley. It was brought to his Office about the 25th of July last. A Lad brought it, and gave it into my Hand; he asked me whether it was a good one, - whether it was Mr. Jasper's? I took no Notice that 'twas bad, but only asked him, who he had it of. The Boy said it had been left by Mrs. Sturk, with his Father, (Mr. Peacock) and she desired to know if it was a good one. I told the Lad Mr. Jasper was out of Town, but that he was expected Home next Day; so I desired him to leave it, and call again for my Master's own Answer. I don't know that the Boy called again, but next Evening a Man came to let us know that the Prisoner was apprehended.</p>
               <p>Sturk. I was at the taking of the Prisoner, and when I charged him, with this forged Note, the Constable bid him charge me, he did so, and we were both carried to Prison together. So I got much, by endeavouring to clear up this Matter, - I was sent to Jail with him. When the Prisoner was before the Justice, he did not deny his giving me the Note, and he could not say that Mr. Jasper owed him any Money. The Justice asked him, how he came by that Note? He told him he did not know.</p>
               <p>The Justice. When he was before me, he own'd the Note was in his Custody, but he could not give any Account how he came by it. I can't say he own'd the Delivery of it to the Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-41-person302">
                  Alexander 
                  Chorley 
               <interp inst="t17370907-41-person302" type="surname" value="Chorley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person302" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd with Mr. Jasper about 3 Years, but have been gone from him about 3 Months. I know his Hand-writing, - I have seen him write an hundred Times; I am satisfied this Note is not his Writing; the other that has been compared with it, I do believe to be his own Writing.</p>
               <p>The Justice. Upon Recollection, he did own he left it with the Woman, and justify'd himself, by saying he had not paid it away.</p>
               <p>Q. So the Prisoner made Application to you, by way of Marriage?</p>
               <p>Sturk. Yes, and I told him I had no Inclination to marriage.</p>
               <p>C. 'Twas well you was not enclin'd to marriage at this Time, - you had a good Escape.</p>
               <p>Defence. I know nothing of it. I am a Stranger in Town, and by this Charge, have lost my Voyage, - I was never in London before. Please to enquire into this Woman's Character.</p>
               <p>C. 'Twould stand you in more stead, to give a good Account of your own.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord I have no Witnesses. <rs id="t17370907-41-verdict214" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-verdict214" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370907-41-punish215" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-41-punish215" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-41-defend295 t17370907-41-punish215"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
