<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341016-22">
               <interp inst="t17341016-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-22" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341016-22" type="date" value="17341016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341016-22-off107-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-22-defend190 t17341016-22-off107 t17341016-22-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>23. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341016-22-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Linch 
                  <interp inst="t17341016-22-defend190" type="surname" value="Linch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-defend190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17341016-22-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 7 Guineas and a Half, the Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341016-22-victim192" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Ansell 
                        <interp inst="t17341016-22-victim192" type="surname" value="Ansell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-22-victim192" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-22-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-22-off107 t17341016-22-victim192"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17341016-22-person193">
                        Lewis 
                        Eslip 
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person193" type="surname" value="Eslip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-22-person193" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341016-22-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17341016-22-cd108" type="crimeDate">Sept. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-22-off107 t17341016-22-cd108"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-22-person194">
                  George 
                  Ansell 
               <interp inst="t17341016-22-person194" type="surname" value="Ansell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person194" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17341016-22-viclabel109" type="occupation">keep a Fruit Cellar</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-22-victim192 t17341016-22-viclabel109"></join> in Mr. Eslip's House, at the Corner of <placeName id="t17341016-22-crimeloc110">Albermarle-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-22-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="Albermarle-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341016-22-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341016-22-off107 t17341016-22-crimeloc110"></join>. When I went out in the Morning, on the 12th of September, I left 7 Guineas in my Trunk, which stood in the Cellar Window, and my Wife had half a Guinea in her Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-22-person195">
                  Sarah 
                  Ansell 
               <interp inst="t17341016-22-person195" type="surname" value="Ansell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person195" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sat at my Cellar Window to sell my Goods, and the Prisoner came and sat down by me as he us'd to do. I gave him a Basket, and desir'd him to step down, and fetch me up some Walnuts, I being busy with a Customer He staying much longer than was necessary, I call'd him, and he said he was coming, and so he came up, with about half a hundred of Walnuts, tho' he might have brought half a Bushell in less time. Presently after I had taken them from him, he held up his Hand, as if somebody had call'd him, but no Body did, as far as I could hear; and so he went away. In about ten Minutes afterwards, I had occasion to change a Guinea, and so went to my Trunk, and miss'd all my Money; which was kept Guineas and a Half, for I had put a half Guinea in, but a Quarter of an Hour before the Prisoner came; and from that time, to the time I miss'd the Money, no Body went down the Cellar but he. The next Day, about 11 in the Morning he was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-22-person196">
                  Nathan 
                  Crumpton 
               <interp inst="t17341016-22-person196" type="surname" value="Crumpton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person196" type="given" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Victualling-Cellar, by the King's Meuse. On the 13th of September about 7 in the Morning, the Prisoner came down and called for a hot pint. He said he had fell in a Ditch, and so he pull'd off his wet Stockings, and put on a new Pair. One Macdonald and Will. Robins came down, and they and the Prisoner drank together and fell into Discourse, and the Prisoner said he had lodg'd 6 Guineas over the Water. He spent 16 d. Half-penny in Hot-pots, and went away about ten a Clock that Morning.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173410160013"></xptr>- Macdonald. I am a Carpenter, and went to do a job in 
               <persName id="t17341016-22-person197">
                  Nathan 
                  Crompton 
               <interp inst="t17341016-22-person197" type="surname" value="Crompton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person197" type="given" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Cellar. I found the Prisoner there, and he drank to me, and said, he had lost a Crown by his Goods in the Market - for he drove a Wheel-barrow with Fruit - Then, says I, you are broke. No, says he, for I have planted 6 Guineas over the Water, and if you will go with me we'll take them up - But I refus'd, for I was to go to White-hall to receive my pay - He pull'd off his old Stockings, and threw them away, and put on a new Pair.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I told him I had lost 6 Guineas over the Water, and if I had them again, I should be a rich Man.</p>
               <p>Macdonald. No; he said planted.</p>
               <p>Will. Robins. I am a Taylor, and went down Crompton's Cellar to roast my Goose, and there was the Prisoner. He said he had lain in a Ditch almost all Night and had planted 6 Guineas at the Black-horse over the Water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341016-22-person198">
                  Arthur 
                  Raven 
               <interp inst="t17341016-22-person198" type="surname" value="Raven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person198" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the Prisoner in the Gatehouse, and ask'd him how he got Money to buy the new Stockings? Why, says he, I have been at Southwark-Fair, and there was a Man, that won a good deal of Money by tossing up with a Halfpenny that had got a Head on both Sides; and I knowing the Secret, he gave me half a Crown not to discover it - But before Justice Lambert, he said he won the Money at Nine</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I had brought up Wal-nuts, I staid to shell some of them, but a Gentleman's Servant, of my Acquaintance, going down the Street, I called to him, and went with him. And there is a Back-door in the Cellar, and People may come in that way.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There is a Back-door that goes into the Yard, and there's a pair of back Stairs that comes from the House into that Yard. The People of the House come down that way to fetch Water, and when I want Water my self, I go out at my back Door, but it is never open at any other Time, and I know it was bolted within side when I lost my Money. The Jury <rs id="t17341016-22-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341016-22-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
