<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-27">
               <interp inst="t17361013-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-27" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-27" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-27-off129-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-27-defend220 t17361013-27-off129 t17361013-27-verdict133"></join>
         
               <p>35. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Chapman 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-27-defend220" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-defend220" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-defend220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-27-off129" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-off129" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-off129" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               willful and corrupt Perjury, in swearing at <placeName id="t17361013-27-crimeloc130">Guild Hall</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-crimeloc130" type="placeName" value="Guild Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-crimeloc130" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-27-off129 t17361013-27-crimeloc130"></join>, <rs id="t17361013-27-cd131" type="crimeDate">February 14, 1733</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-27-off129 t17361013-27-cd131"></join>. that 
                     <persName id="t17361013-27-person221">
                        John 
                        Tyson 
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person221" type="surname" value="Tyson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-27-person221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-27-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   on the 25th of December 1722, was at his House in the Tower of London, and that he ordered himself to be denied to one 
                     <persName id="t17361013-27-victim222" type="victimName">
                        Myat
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-victim222" type="given" value="Myat"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-27-victim222" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-27-off129 t17361013-27-victim222"></join>
                     </persName>
                   a <rs id="t17361013-27-viclabel132" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-27-victim222 t17361013-27-viclabel132"></join>, to whom<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130015"></xptr> he was indebted in the Sum of 25 l. - or there abouts; whereas in Truth and in Fact, the said Tyson was not at his House in the Tower, but was on the 25th of December 1722, at his Seat, called Woolvaston Hall in Suffolk - &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person223">
                  George Rignal 
                  Chadwick 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person223" type="surname" value="Chadwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person223" type="given" value="George Rignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was at that time Clerk to Mr. Goostrey, and I remember the Prisoner was called as a Witness of Collet and Brown, Assignees of Mr. Tyson; he swore that on the 25 of December 1722, Mr. Tyson ordered himself to be denied, and that he was denied to one Myat a Taylor, and that he was indebted at that time in the Sum of 25 l. or there abouts to the said Myat. I remember there was none of the Witnesses fixed the time but the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Willmore 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person224" type="surname" value="Willmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at this Trial in Hillary Term, between the Assignees of Mr. Tyson, and those of Mr. Ward, and I heard Chapman swear that 
               <persName id="t17361013-27-person225">
                  John 
                  Tyson 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person225" type="surname" value="Tyson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the 25th of December was at his House in the Tower of London at nine o'Clock in the Morning; that he ordered himself to be denied to one Myat a Taylor, who came to dun him for Money. This Trial was on the 23d of January, I think, I am not sure.</p>
               <p>- Metcalf. This Trial was at Guild Hall, February 23d, 1733. The Prisoner was sworn and examined for Collet and Brown; he swore Mr. Tyson ordered himself to be denied the 25th of December 1722, to Myat a Taylor, and that he was then at his House in the Tower, and owed Myat 25 l. -</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person226">
                  Thomas 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person226" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person226" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Year 1722 Servant to Mr. Tyson; on Christmass Eve he came down to Woolvaston Hall in Suffolk, and Christmass Day several Farmers dined with him, and on the next Day he went out a hunting; and I remember Sir Casar Child was there that Christmass; Lady Child went down before, but her Coach broke down on the Road, and Mr. Tyson when he came, took her into his Coach, and brought her to Woolvaston Hall. Sir Caesar Child I believe might be there the Day before. Last February I happened to see Chapman and we fell into Discourse about this Affair, and he told me he believed he was wrong in what he swore at the Trial at Guild Hall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person227">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person227" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person227" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember Mr. Tyson was at Woolvaston Hall the 25th of December 1722, because on that Day he gave out Bread and Beef, and no such thing was done before, or has been done since. I am sure he never was in the Country but that Christmass, nor no Man else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person228">
                  Thomas 
                  Death 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person228" type="surname" value="Death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person228" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Fourteen Years ago next Christmass Eve, I carried some of Mr. Tyson's People and their Goods to Woolvaston Hall, that very Night that he went himself, there were two Coaches together and one of them broke down, so they revoked that Coach and got into the other, and I carried the Luggage and Servants in my Waggon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-27-person229">
                  Joseph 
                  Burges 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person229" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person229" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day after Christmass Day 1722, I met Mr. Tyson going a hunting, and I never remembered him keep Christmass there but that time,</p>
               <p>- Harrison. I live at the King's Head at Colchester; I knew Tyson very well, he was at my House the 22d and 23d of December (I have forgot the Year) and he went away the 24th to Woolvaston Hall, but my Bill has never been paid yet.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17361013-27-person230">
                  Cesar 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17361013-27-person230" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person230" type="given" value="Cesar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was at this Tryal at Guildhall, and remember Chapman's being a Witness there: He swore it was Christmas 1722. I never heard either Christmas Day, or the twenty fifth of December mention'd; but only Christmass 22. I know Mr. Tyson did abscond, and did commit Acts of Bankruptcy: I have heard him order Chapman to deny him to his Creditors, many Times before this Christmass, and several Times before my Face. I have been at his House when People have enquired for him, and he has deny'd him; and I have gone through them all, and found him above Stairs. I know he did not care to trust any body to deny him, but Chapman. As to Myat's Name, which they have sworn to, I don't remember I heard it once mention'd: There was Hopegood and How I think I remember mention'd upon the Tryal. I have known Chapman from a Boy, he was always a very honest just Servant; he liv'd with Captain Cleland, and since that he has been a Tenant under me, and I believe he would no more forswear himself, than I would</p>
               <p>Mr. Cotton. I was at the Tryal, and remember what Chapman swore; it was, about Christmass 1722 he had such Orders from Tyson. I don't remember Myat's Name was ever mention'd. I had a List of Tyson's Creditors, and I think there was no such Name among them.</p>
               <p>Mr. How. I know Mr. Tyson, - I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130016"></xptr> reason to know him, he owes me 95 l. upon Bond. About Christmass 22, I was many Times to see after my Money Chapman used to deny him, but I have staid after that, and have seen him go out in Disguise.</p>
               <p>Mr. Linton. I was at Tyson's at Christmass, 1722, for Money, Chapman has deny'd him, and I have afterwards seen him go out.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilkinson. Mr. Chapman on the Trial mention'd no particular Day. he only said about Christmass 1722. I believe him to be as honest a Man as lives, and that he would not forswear himself for the Universe.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fleming. I went down that very Christmass to Woolvaston Hall with Mr. Tyson; I cannot be sure whether it was Christmas Day or the Day after; but it could not be before Christmass, because I remember all the Shops were shut up. I waited two Hours at the Man in the Moon at White-chappel for him: At last he came, in a mighty Hurry, We whipt into a higher Chariot, and away we went, no Creature with us. I have known Chapman sixteen Years, an honest Man, and don't believe he'd forswear himself.</p>
               <p>Sir Caesar Child: Mr. Tyson that Christmass was to have call'd upon us, at Woodford Bridge, and we were all to have gone into Suffolk together; but he sent us Word we must set out before him, and he would meet us at the King's Head at Colchester, but he did not come, and we went down to Woolvaston, and Tyson came down a Day or two after, and this Gentleman was with him. <rs id="t17361013-27-verdict133" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-27-verdict133" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
