<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-2">
               <interp inst="t17381206-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-2" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-2" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-2-off7-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-defend33 t17381206-2-off7 t17381206-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-defend33" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Gardiner 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-2-defend33" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-defend33" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-defend33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17381206-2-defloc6">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-2-defloc6" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-2-defloc6" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-defend33 t17381206-2-defloc6"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17381206-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch and Steel Seal, value 13l. 13s. a Gold Ring, set with seven Diamonds, value 8l. a Gold Ring, set with three Diamonds, value 3l. a Hanger, with a Horn Handle, value 3 s. ten Holland Shirts ruffled, value 10 l. a Cloth Coat, value 20s. and a Pair of Shoes, value 4s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-2-victim35" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Waldron 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-2-victim35" type="surname" value="Waldron"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-2-victim35" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-2-victim35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-off7 t17381206-2-victim35"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17381206-2-person36">
                        William 
                        Murray 
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person36" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-2-person36" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-2-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17381206-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">Oct. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-off7 t17381206-2-cd8"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. On the 30th of October last, I intended to go to Court, and therefore I asked the Prisoner (who was my <rs id="t17381206-2-deflabel9" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-defend33 t17381206-2-deflabel9"></join>) for a particular Shirt? He told me 'twas above Stairs, and accordingly he went up into my Bed chamber, and after he had taken the Goods, he went quite away, and never came into my Service any more. I lost a Gold Watch, and a Steel Seal which hung upon a Hook, at my Bed's Head, and two Diamond Rings; ten Holland Shirts, a Hanger with a Horn Handle, a Cloth Coat double buttoned, with Gold Buttons, a Dimity Waistcoat, a Pair of Breeches, and a Pair of Shoes. I advertised the Goods, and the Advertisement came out the next Day with a Reward of ten Guineas, to any who would inform me of them. On the Sunday following, the Prisoner came to the Green Dragon Ale-house in Church-Court, where he was stopped with some of my Goods upon him, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060003"></xptr> about two Hours after he was taken, I saw him at Justice Frazier's, and he fell down upon his Knees, and begged Mercy. He had delivered the Rings to Mr. Frazier before I came, and had confessed they were not his own, but he insisted on it, that he was entrusted with them, though I never intrusted him with them at all. He deny'd his Knowledge of the Watch; but that was brought to me (after the Advertisement came out) by one Smithson, who told me he bought it (the same Day I was robbed) at an Alehouse in Aldermanbury. This Smithson is a Broker in Holbourn. When he was before Mr. Frazier, I asked him, how he came by these Things? He said, they were delivered to him in Trust, without mentioning by whom.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with taking the rest of the Goods.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. Yes, and he had two Shirts on his Back, which he acknowledged were mine, and pulled them off, and delivered them to the Constable. The Waistcoat and Breeches, I believe, he has upon him at this Time; I know he had them on Yesterday. He told me; that three of the Shirts were at the Pawnbrokers, and directed me to them. The Hanger likewise was found upon him, but it was taken from him at the Alehouse before I saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been with you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. He came to me on the 18th of Sept. last, and robbed me on the 30th of October.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would ask Mr. Waldron, whether he did not intrust me with these Things?</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. No; not with the Watch nor Rings. He took in my Linnen from the Washerwoman, and when I called for any of it, he brought it me. He had a Key of the Place where it was kept, and I had a Key, that I might look over it, at any Time. He was so far from being entrusted with any Thing else, that when I went down into Devonshire, I put all my Jewels, my Watch, Rings, and Snuff Box, into Mr. Murray's Custody, who is the Master of the House where I lodge.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Frazier. The Prisoner was brought to my House the 9th of November last. I ordered him to be searched; and after some Difficulty, there two Rings, and this Seal were found in one of his Breeches Pockets, before Mr. Waldron came. The Prisoner told me, he had no Property in them, and that I might keep them if I pleased. When Mr. Waldron came, he owned them, and swore they were the same he lost. They have been in my Custody ever since.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. This Seal hung to my Watch: these Rings are likewise mine.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frazier. When I ask'd him how he came by these Things, he hesitated and paus'd, and would give no Account: but, says he, I have no Property in them; if you please, you may take them yourself. He owned they were his Master's, before Mr. Waldron, and to the best of my Remembrance he told me, he was not obliged to make any Confession.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person37">
                  Thomas 
                  Hawksworth 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person37" type="surname" value="Hawksworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person37" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Pawnbroker in St. Martin's Court; and receiving an Advertisement from Goldsmith's Hall, relating to this Robbery. I remembered the Mark upon a Shirt which the Prisoner had pawned at my Shop in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17381206-2-person38">
                  James 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person38" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person38" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . So I sent my Daughter up Stairs to look over the Goods, and she found four Shirts, which the Prisoner had pawned, at different Times, in the same Name. These are the four Shirts, which I carry'd to Mr. Waldron, and he owned them directly. He pawned them for six Shillings a-piece, and they have been till now, in my Custody.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. These are mine.</p>
               <p>Hawksworth. The Prisoner pawned a Coat (which I have since seen at Mr. Waldron's) 'twas a brownish Cloth with Gold Buttons, and a Waistcoat and Breeches; but these Things he redeem'd the Night before. The Waist-coat was taken in by my Servant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person39">
                  Thomas 
                  Bridgewater 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person39" type="surname" value="Bridgewater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person39" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought an Olive-colour'd Coat, and an old red Coat of the Prisoner, on the 31 st of October. The red Coat, it seems, was his own. I carry'd them into Monmouth-street, to sell them again, and there I was informed, the Olive-coloured Coat was stole, and being directed to Mr. Waldron, in <placeName id="t17381206-2-crimeloc10">Henrietta street, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-2-crimeloc10" type="placeName" value="Henrietta street, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-2-crimeloc10" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-off7 t17381206-2-crimeloc10"></join>, I carried it to him, and he claimed it. The red Coat was old, the other was but an indifferent Cloth, and had an old Lining in it; the Gold Buttons were papered over. I paid him 25 s. for them. I went afterwards to see him in the Gatehouse; and asked him if he did not know me? He said he could not call me to Mind, - but he shook his Head, and had the Breeches belonging to the Coat upon him at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person40">
                  Terence 
                  Eavers 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person40" type="surname" value="Eavers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person40" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Sunday after the King's Birth-day, I took the Prisoner: He had pawned a Shirt with me for 3 s. I keep a publick House by St. Martin's Church in the Fields, the Sign of the Green Dragon, in Church Court: Mr. Waldron had said he carry'd the Hanger and a long cutteau knife about him, but I found only the Hanger upon him, which I took from him in my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060004"></xptr> House, to disarm him: This is the Shirt; I have bad it ever since.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. This Hanger, and this Shirt, are mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person41">
                  Robert 
                  Bushell 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person41" type="surname" value="Bushell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person41" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. On Sunday Night, about a Month ago, I was sent for to the Green Dragon, to take a Man who had robb'd his Master. I went, but the Prisoner was taken in Custody, before I got there. I searched his Pocket slightly for Weapons, but found none. He was searched again, before Mr. Frazier; and I took two Diamond Rings out of his Pocket. He had two of Mr. Waldron's Shirts upon his Back, which he pulled off; then he pulled his own Shirt out of his Pocket, and put it on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person42">
                  Anthony 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person42" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person42" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Journeyman to Mr. Carmoult, a Pawnbroker, at the Corner of Russel Court.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. This Carmoult kept the Shirts he took in Pawn, a Week after they were advertised. Mr. Frazier sent for this Man, and his Master, but neither of them would come.</p>

               <p>Barnes. I have brought but one of the Shirts now, for my Master said, one would be enough to produce to the Court. They are all of the same Sort. I had them from the Prisoner at the Bar, I think about the Beginning of October, they were pawned for 6 s. a-piece, in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17381206-2-person43">
                  James 
                  Waldron 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person43" type="surname" value="Waldron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person43" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took two of them in my self, but I won't say positively I had them from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Waldron. They were desired to go and see the Prisoner in the Gatehouse, but they refused to go.</p>
               <p>Barnes. I don't know but Mr. Waldron might desire my Master to go, but I am not my own Master; if Mr. Carmoult had ordered me to have gone, I should have gone.</p>
               <p>The Court reprimanded Barnes, and expressed their Displeasure at Carmoult's Behaviour; at the same time ordering an Officer to go with Barnes, and demand the Shirts which were detained, and they were accordingly brought into Court.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bathurst. Last September was Twelve month, the Prisoner was recommended to me as a Footman, with an honest Character. He served me eleven Months, or better; and left me with a fair Character. Mr. Waldron wanted a Servant, and he told me he had an Opportunity to better himself, by going into his Service. This was one Reason of his going from me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-2-person44">
                  William 
                  Drysdell 
               <interp inst="t17381206-2-person44" type="surname" value="Drysdell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person44" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep an Alehouse in the Hop Garden, Bedford-bury, and have known the Prisoner ten or twelve Months. He used to come to meet some Countrymen of his, at our House, and I always took him to be a civil, sober Man. The Jury found him <rs id="t17381206-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17381206-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-2-defend33 t17381206-2-punish12"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
