<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-58">
               <interp inst="t17370216-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-58" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-58" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-58-off255-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-58-defend361 t17370216-58-off255 t17370216-58-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>65. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-defend361" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Holland 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-58-defend361" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-defend361" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-defend361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370216-58-off255" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-off255" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-off255" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               willful and corrupt Perjury, in a Trial at common Bench, in Trinity-Term, between 
                     <persName id="t17370216-58-person362">
                        James 
                        Jackson 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person362" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person362" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Fishmonger, 
                     <persName id="t17370216-58-person363">
                        Richard 
                        Ealey 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person363" type="surname" value="Ealey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person363" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Butcher, Defendants, and 
                     <persName id="t17370216-58-person364">
                        Henry 
                        Nown 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person364" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person364" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Plantiff: At which Trial the said Holland Swore; that the Defendants did not Assault, &amp;c. 
                     <persName id="t17370216-58-person365">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Nown 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person365" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person365" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-58-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  : whereas in Truth and in Fact, he did Assault, &amp;c. and the said Holland was not present, when the said Assault was made, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person366">
                  Richard 
                  Leaf 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person366" type="surname" value="Leaf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person366" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at this Trial of 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person367">
                  James 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person367" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person368">
                  Richard 
                  Ealey 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person368" type="surname" value="Ealey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person368" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I did not see Holland sworn.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salt. Holland was sworn upon the Holy Gospel, to speak the Truth, the whole Truth, and nothing but the Truth.</p>
               <p>Leaf. Holland's Evidence (to the best of my Knowledge) was this, that he was in Company with James Jackson and Richard Ealey, the 3d of May, that he went with them into the House or Shop of 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person369">
                  Henry 
                  Nown 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person369" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person369" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before mentioned; that he was at the Top of the Stairs (the One Pair of Stairs I think it was) and that there was no<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160019"></xptr> Assault committed on Elizabeth the Daughter of Henry Nown, or something to that Effect.</p>
               <p>Councel How came you to attend there? Are you an Attorney?</p>
               <p>Leaf. No, I attend my Master's Messages.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you within the Bar or without?</p>
               <p>Leaf. Without.</p>
               <p>Councel. How come you to remember this?</p>
               <p>Leaf. Because this Man gave the last Evidence.</p>
               <p>Councel. And do you swear that because he gave his Evidence last, therefore you remember it?</p>
               <p>Leaf. No</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you take Notes at that Trial?</p>
               <p>Leaf. No.</p>
               <p>C. Are you sure that he swore he was there all the while?</p>
               <p>Leaf. To the best of my Knowledge he did. - I had rather speak to the best of my Knowledge, - that will be Truth.</p>
               <p>C. Did he say positively that there was no Assault committed, or did he only say, he saw none committed?</p>
               <p>Leaf. I won't take upon me to say which.</p>
               <p>Councel. Have you never declared that the Prosecutrix attempted to hire you to rap, as they term it?</p>
               <p>Leaf. I don't know that ever I did.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salt. I reduced the Words into Writing: they were, - That he was in Company with Jackson and Ealey the 3d of May, at the dwelling House of 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person370">
                  Richard 
                  Nown 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person370" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person370" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; that he went with them to the Top of the first pair of Stairs, and that James Jackson did not make any Assault on the Person of 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person371">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Nown 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person371" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person371" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Councel. Was this reduced into writing the same Day or the next.</p>
               <p>Mr. Salt. I can't tell that. It was not done in Court.</p>
               <p>Councel. I would ask you, whither he did not say, that he saw no Assault?</p>
               <p>Mr. Salt. I take it that he said there was no Assault.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person372">
                  Sarah 
                  Goode 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person372" type="surname" value="Goode"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person372" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Company with Mr. Jackson and Mr. Ealey, at Mr. Nown's House: They came to distrain for 20 s. for Nown's selling Liquors, I was there from the beginning to the ending of the Business. There were Mr. Jackson and Mr. Ealey, and Mrs. Nown and her Daughter. I was up Stairs with them, and I did not see Holland at all. I went up Stairs behind them, and came down behind them. There was Jackson and Ealey, and 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person373">
                  Betty 
                  Nowns 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person373" type="surname" value="Nowns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person373" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and my Self. The first Time I saw Holland was the 3d of May.</p>
               <p>Councel. What did not you see Holland at all?</p>
               <p>Goode. I saw him at the Door; I did not see him 'till he fetch'd away the Baskets. I am certain he was not above Stairs when the Skirmish was. I am certain he was not there.</p>

               <p>Q. Were they out of your Sight, while they were in the House?</p>
               <p>Goode. No, Sir,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person374">
                  Mary 
                  Nown 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person374" type="surname" value="Nown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person374" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3d of May, Jackson came into my House and said he had a Warrant of Distress for 20 s. and you Bitch, says he, I will send you to Newgate and your Husband to Jayl: he was pretty hot, and been warming himself before he came in; my Child said, for Christ's Sake, don't send them to Newgate, - send me instead of them. Holland (upon the Trial of this Assault,) said he was in my House, in Company with Jackson and Ealey, that he went up Stairs with them into a dark Entry, and that they never touch'd the Door, nor my Daughter neither: and that they were not there two Minutes, if he had had a Watch. I desired Sarah Goode to go up Stairs and see what they were doing, and she followed them up immediately. I never saw Holland 'till Ealey call'd - Porter - Basket, and he carried the Baskets away. He never was in the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person375">
                  Hen.
                   Briggs
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person375" type="surname" value="Briggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person375" type="given" value="Hen."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was not there all the Time; Jackson, was in the Shop when I came; and Ealey was at the Door; I did not see Holland in the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person376">
                  Hannah 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person376" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person376" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Door when the Distress was made. I saw the Gentleman take the Baskets. - I dont know Holland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person377">
                  Simon 
                  Gabb 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person377" type="surname" value="Gabb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person377" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Holland was at the Door, when they called Basket: he was at the Door, when I came there.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Nown. The 3d of May, Jackson and Ealey came and said they would go up Stairs, and take what they could find: Jackson went up first, and Ealey followed him, and the other Woman followed them. Jackson used me ill, - by ill Language, and the Kitchen Door being shut, he said I had got the Keys, and he took me by the right Side of the Petticoat and tore it. Holland was neither in the House nor up Stairs there was no Man up the Stairs save Jackson and Ealey.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jackson. In May last, I was Church-Warden of St. Mary-Hall. I received this Warrant from the late Mayor, to levy a Fine of 20 s. on them for retailing Liquors. I desir'd her not to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160020"></xptr> oblige me to seize, she would not pay, but bid me do as I pleas'd. She told me I might go up Stairs, and call'd her Daughter to go up before us. I bid my Servant 
               <persName id="t17370216-58-person378">
                  Arthur 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person378" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person378" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,call a <rs id="t17370216-58-deflabel256" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-58-defend361 t17370216-58-deflabel256"></join>, and he call'd Holland, who went with me and the Beadle into the House. Holland follow'd me up Stairs, and the Beadle follow'd him. I never saw that Oyster Woman (the Evidence) there.</p>
               <p>C. Did you strike or assault her above Stairs?</p>
               <p>Mr. Jackson. On my Oath I did not. I should not care to come so near her; I never touched her, but the Doors being lock'd I came down again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-58-person379">
                  Arthur 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17370216-58-person379" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person379" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When my Master went to Nowns's House, I call'd Holland, and bid him follow my Master.</p>
               <p>Richard Ealey's Evidence confirm'd Mr. Jackson's.</p>
               <p>A great number of credible Persons appear'd to Holland's Character. <rs id="t17370216-58-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-58-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
