<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-45">
               <interp inst="t17370420-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-45" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-45" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-45-off243-c284" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-45-defend393 t17370420-45-off243 t17370420-45-verdict246"></join>
         
               <p>55. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-45-defend393" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Irons , otherwise <rs id="t17370420-45-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-45-defend393 t17370420-45-alias-6"></join>Thompson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-defend393" type="surname" value="Irons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-defend393" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-defend393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17370420-45-off243" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-off243" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-off243" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. dut devising and intending, our Lord 
                     <persName id="t17370420-45-victim394" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17370420-45-victim394" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-45-off243 t17370420-45-victim394"></join>
                     </persName>
                   to deceive and defraud, on the <rs id="t17370420-45-cd244" type="crimeDate">22d of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-45-off243 t17370420-45-cd244"></join>, 40 Pieces of false and counterfeit Money, of base Metal, in the Likeness of the lawful and current Money of this Realm, called Shillings, and 10 Pieces, &amp;c. to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200031"></xptr> the Likeness of Six-pences, did feloniously and traiterously forge and counterfeit
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-45-person395">
                  Samuel 
                  Goodyere 
               <interp inst="t17370420-45-person395" type="surname" value="Goodyere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-person395" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner, I believe a dozen Years. He once <rs id="t17370420-45-deflabel245" type="occupation">kept a Cook's Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-45-defend393 t17370420-45-deflabel245"></join>, then he went beyond Sea, and about the latter end of October, or the beginning of November, he return'd to England, and I came over with him in the same Ship. When we first arriv'd here, we got a Lodging at Mrs. Worral's in Swallow-street; while we liv'd there, we us'd to get King Charles's Farthings, and file the Woman side, and the Edges to make them of the size and thickness of a Six-pence; then we used to white them over with quicksilver taken from the back of a Looking-glass, and sometimes we put them into an Onyon, then we used to bend them and pass them off. This Practice we continued a Month, if not longer; but we had bad Luck in putting them off: Some we disposed of to Apple-Women, and People in the Street: But one Day when we were out upon this Business, I thought an opportunity offer'd for putting some of them off, and I bid the Prisoner give me some; (for he always carried them in his Pocket, and I generally put them off,) he felt in his Pocket, and said he had left them at Home; so return'd Home for them. While we were out, our Landlady Mrs. Worral had been up in our Room to clean it, and she found the Paper they were in upon the Table with some Quicksilver in it; she gave it him, when we came Home, but told us we should be there no more. Then we went and liv'd in a Place by Long-Acre, (I have forgot the Name) over-against a Brewhouse, and there he told me he had learn'd of a Woman in Virginia, (whose Mother was burnt here for Coining) how to make Shillings and Six-pences, and Half-Crowns. This Womans Name was Knight, she had instructed him in the Art of making Money, he said: So he went to his Brother-in-law Powl in Brick-lane, and got a Mold made, - thus long, and thus wide. The inside of the Mold was square and hollow, which he fill'd up with Chalk, finely scraped, then he made the Impression of a Shilling, and cast one; the first did not do well; the 2d, was better, so he made several Shillings, and the more he made, the better they prov'd. The Metal was always melted in a Tobacco-Pipe, and pour'd into the Mold. (If I had the Things here I could show you how we made them.) When the Pieces were taken out of the Molds, he pared off the Metal that ran from the Edges, and then nick'd them with a clean Tile, to make the Milling; then he used to scower them with Sand to make them look bright, and the last Thing was to put them into a Pot of Water and boil them with a Powder call'd Argol, to make them look white and like Silver. Some were in the Form of South Sea Shillings, other with the Feathers and the Roses on the Backs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner do this?</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes; and 'twas my Business to put them off; that's some of the Metal that lies there; they call it Soder; we bought it at the Pewterers, and gave 10 d. a Pound for it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Watson. This Samuel Goodyere came to my House to buy a Sheep's Tongue, and he gave me this very Shilling to change for it. I am sure I had it of Goodyere.</p>
               <p>Goodyere. 'Tis true, I remember paying this to Mr. Watson, but I had this Shilling from one Davis, who is not taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that Shilling made by the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Goodyere. 'Tis one of the same Sort that the Prisoner used to make and deliver to me. I have had a great many of them from him, - a great many more than 20. - I can very well swear to 20. I can't swear to Sixpences made in this Manner, but I can swear to copper Sixpences.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you put them off.</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Councel. And were those 20 Shillings you swear to, made in the Manner you have mention'd?</p>
               <p>Goodyere. I can't swear they were made of the same sort of Metal with this Shilling, but they were made of such Soder as that which lies in Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-45-person396">
                  Francis 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17370420-45-person396" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-person396" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found this Piece of Soder in a House which the Prisoner at the Bar calls his; 'twas in a Closet lock'd up. When I took up the Prisoner, he asked me, if I had been at his House; I told him, Yes, and that I had found a Piece of Metal and some Argol; he said he us'd them in his Business.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Closet where you found the Things, joining to the Lodging-Room?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. Yes. He calls all the House his, I thought it had been an empty House, but when we forced the Door open, we found a Soldier in it, who said he had Leave to come there to wash his Shirt. When we had the Prisoner before Justice Frazier, he own'd the Metal was there, but he said he never knew how to make Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own the Argol?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I am not positive whether that was mention'd to him or not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you find any thing else?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200032"></xptr>Mitchel. No. The Files were found in Border's Lodging.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Worral. The Prisoner Lodged with me about a Month, and Goodyere was with him: Whenever they went out, I made them leave the Key of the Room, that I might see if my Sheets and Things were there. One Day when they were out, I went up into the Room, and found a Paper twisted up, upon the Table; I brought it down Stairs and look'd into it; there were 10 Six-pences in it, some Mill'd, and some not Mill'd, they had all-of them Heads on one Side, and some of them had Cross-Bars on the other; the Prisoner came back and asked me if I had been in the Room; yes says I, and I have brought 10 pieces down, I have told them, and see that you have them all again; to-morrow your Week will be up, and you must provide your selves with another Lodging. I had heard them at Work, and a Fileing, and seeing these Pieces, made me resolve they should not stay. Goodyere and he liv'd together in Friendship then, and said they were Buckle-makers.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen any Files there?</p>
               <p>Worral. Yes, and small Dust, small Fileings too, which I did not know what to make of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any Powder there?</p>
               <p>Worral. Yes, the Six pences lay in a Paper of Powder, I believe 'twas much such Stuff as this (here a Paper of Argol was shewn her) it look'd like rotten Stone, Powder'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know those Pieces in the Paper were Naught?</p>
               <p>Worral. They did not found so well as others, but a crooked Six pence will not found so well as another.</p>
               <p>Councel. You said you thought they were not Good, and that was the Reason you gave them Warning. Do you think it was good Money or Bad?</p>
               <p>Worral. I cannot say it was right Good.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever see any Metal or Molds?</p>
               <p>Worral. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No; I don't know how you should; for I never Coin'd a Shilling, or a Six-pence in my Life.</p>
               <p>Worral. I believe they did not Coin in my House, for they never had but half a Peck of Coals at a Time, and they generally served them a Week.</p>
               <p>Councel. You can't tell what they did at their Fire, always.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was there any Lock, to Lock any thing up?</p>
               <p>Worral. No; and I had always the Key of the Door when they went out.</p>
               <p>Goodyere. The Money and Things we always put up on the Tester of the Bed, when we went out. The Money, the Files, and the Quicksilver we always hid there.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. This Powder is call'd Argol, 'tis used in whitening Plate. The counterfeit Money as it came out of the Molds, would be a little dirty, but boiling it with this, it takes of all the Soil, and makes it look white. This Shilling is a counterfeit Shilling, and was never Coin'd at the Tower, 'tis made of Pewter, I believe.</p>
               <p>Defence. I left Goodyere once (when I was abroad) to look after the House, and while I was gone, I heard he had had one Davis with him, (the Man he had that Shilling from,) but he was not there when I came Home. Goodyere cannot tell one Place where he put off a bad Shilling, but only this One.</p>
               <p>Goodyere. I put off one that you made, at an Oylshop in Maiden-lane, and to several Apple People and Ginger-bread Women, and such Folks.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire to know if he ever saw me use any of that sort of Metal.</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes; I have seen him use that sort of Metal to make the Money, and then he put it into an earthen pot, with some of that Argol and boil it over the Fire.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Since I have been in the Gatehouse, a Man bid me hold my Tongue about that Block Tin, 'till I heard what the Evidence should say; then says he, tell my Lord, that, that Metal when 'tis Melted will not hold together, but will run all in little Pieces, - little Lumps; there's no such Thing as Casting any Thing with it.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. I am not enough acquainted with that sort of Metal, to know whether 'twill hold together or not: I believe 'tis proper to use some other sort with it, by way of Alloy.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the Impression on that Shilling was made by Casting or Stamping?</p>
               <p>Mr. North. This is Cast; tho' they scrape the Chalk ever so fine, yet there will be Sand-holes in the Piece they Cast; if it had been struck with a Dye, the Metal would have been a great deal closer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make use of any other Metal with this Soder by Way of Alloy? (To Goodyere.)</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes, sometimes we melted Pewter Spoons with it, - those mark'd with X, because they were the best sort; sometimes we made them without Pewter, and sometimes with.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you use to buy Pewter Spoons?</p>
               <p>Goodyere. No, they were the Pewter Spoons that we had in our Lodging, or the Spoons we used to make.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200033"></xptr>Councel. Make! why, did you use to steal them?</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I got that Sodor to mend a Mould which I bought to make Candles in; and the Metal lay about the Kitchen a Fortnight or 3 Weeks, - I did not mind it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner get this Metal to mend his Moulds, or to make Money? (To Goodyere)</p>
               <p>Goodyere. To make Money, his Moulds wanted no mending, and he was too lazy to make Candles.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Lord have Mercy upon me! did you ever see such Metal in my House, Samuel Goodyere!</p>
               <p>Goodyere. Yes, and you us'd to give 10 d a Pound for it.</p>
               <p>Spencer Burges. I am a Tin-man, and I use that metal in my Business. I know 'tis brittle, but I believe it will hold together to make a Shilling or a Six-pence; 10 d. also is the common Price. I give so much for it my self. <rs id="t17370420-45-verdict246" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-45-verdict246" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
