<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-16">
               <interp inst="t17380628-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-16" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-16" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-16-off79-c121" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-defend155 t17380628-16-off79 t17380628-16-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>18. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-defend155" type="defendantName">
                     Godfrey 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-16-defend155" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-defend155" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-defend155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380628-16-defloc78">St. Luke's Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-16-defloc78" type="placeName" value="St. Luke's Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-16-defloc78" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-defend155 t17380628-16-defloc78"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17380628-16-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17380628-16-cd80" type="crimeDate">25th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-off79 t17380628-16-cd80"></join>, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-16-victim157" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Pike 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-16-victim157" type="surname" value="Pike"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-16-victim157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-16-victim157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-off79 t17380628-16-victim157"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously did make an Assault, and with a certain Hatchet made of Steel, value 6 d. and which he held in both his Hands, on the fore Part of the Head, of the said Pike, feloniously did strike, giving him a mortal Wound and Bruise, of which from the said 25th of May, to the 11th of June, he languished, and languishing liv'd and then dy'd
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time charged by Vertue of the Coroner's Inquest, for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>- Birkenhead. I had a Warrant from Justice Wroth, to execute upon the Prisoner, and Mr. Pike (the Deceased) being <rs id="t17380628-16-viclabel81" type="occupation">Headborough</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-victim157 t17380628-16-viclabel81"></join>, I carry'd it to him, - I got this Warrant for him because he would have stabb'd me in the Back with his Bayonet, - there, - there he stands, - let him deny it if he can; - d - mn you, says he, I will kill you, - aye, that, - that's the Man, - there he stands, - that's the Man that would have kill'd me. And so I got a Warrant for him, and gave it Mr. Pike, and when we went to the Prisoner's House, - there he stands, - that's the Man, - he said G - d d - n you, I will murder the first Man that comes in. The Door stood a little o'jar, and I saw him within, and said to Mr. Pike, - there's your Prisoner; I was got into the House; Mr. Pike was just behind me; and he (the Prisoner) cry'd out, G - d d - n your Bl - d I will murder you both, by G - d; then he made a Motion with his Hand, - I suppose he had the Axe in it, but I did not see it, and Mr. Pyke said, - he has done my Business. God forbid, says I, and I was so surprized, that I could not take Notice of what he had in his Hand, and the poor Man bled prodigiously. I only saw the Prisoner make a Motion, - Truth is Truth.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was any body near you, when the Thing was done?</p>
               <p>Birkenhead. I can't say, - the Mob came so fast upon us: I can't really say, - the Street-Door was open, but the Prisoner's Shop was shut, 'twas between 9 and 10 o'Clock. After Mr. Pike was hurt, we came to my House, and there the Wound was wash'd with Vinegar and Loaf-Sugar; from thence we went to the Cock, and Justice Worth was there, and Doctor Godman, and he dress'd the Man's Head.</p>
               <p>Councel. Whereabout was the Wound, and how did it appear?</p>
               <p>Brickenhead. I can't say where it was; I did not look upon it, - I don't love to look upon Wounds, but I clean'd his Wig. And I am sure the Door was open, when we went in, - as sure as that God made the World.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did the Deceased tell the Prisoner when he went in, that he had a Warrant?</p>
               <p>Brickenhead. I can't say I heard that. I heard him say something, but I can't say he told him that. I saw the Deceased several Times before he died, and he always complain'd of a Dizziness in his Head.</p>
               <p>The Warrant was read.</p>
               <p>Birkenhead. Pike was a Headborough in St. Luke's and this happen'd in that Parish.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person158">
                  Ann 
                  Desborough 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person158" type="surname" value="Desborough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person158" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the Out-cry of the People, that the Constable was coming to take the Prisoner, so I ran to bid him shut the Door; but I found Birkenhead with his Back against the Door,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280011"></xptr> and making Room for the Deceased to get in. As soon as he entered; he spoke to the Prisoner, I saw him put his Hand toward the Window, and strike the Deceased with something large, but I can't tell what, for 'twas dark, and tho' there was a Candle, yet it gave but glimmering Light. I observ'd the Stroke to fall upon his Head, and he said, he had done his Business, and flung the Blood out of his Neck with his Hands.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you hear the Prisoner say any Thing?</p>
               <p>Desborough. No, I was so frighted, that as soon as ever I got away I swooned.</p>

               <p>Prisoner to Birkenhead. Did not Mr. Pike agree to make it up for a Guinea?</p>
               <p>Birkenhead. I told Mr. Pike that the Prisoner wanted to make it up, and asked him how he found himself? He said, he had a great Dizziness in his Head. I advised him to make it up, if he was nothing detrimented, and the Prisoner came to me about it, but the Deceased said neither off, nor on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person159">
                  Geo 
                  Pike 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person159" type="surname" value="Pike"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person159" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased was my Brother. He had not been out of his House above half an Hour, but News was brought Home that he was murder'd: He came in all over Blood, which came from his Head, and said he was hurt worse than we imagin'd, and that he was afraid it would be his Death. He had a large Cut upon his Head, but I can't say upon what Part, for I was busy to and fro in the House.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did he say who gave him the Wound?</p>
               <p>Pike. I did not hear him that Night, but I remember he said it was the Prisoner, on the 7th of June; and that the Blow would be the Occasion of his Death. He died on the 11th, he was very well in Health before this happen'd, and nothing ail'd him no more than ails me now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person160">
                  Richard 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person160" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person160" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About two Nights after the Accident, the Deceased told me, the Blow which the Prisoner gave him when he went to serve the Warrant on him, he believed would be his Death, for (says he) my Head is all on Fire.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did he tell you with what Instrument the Wound was given?</p>
               <p>Sims. He said the Prisoner took up an Axe, or a Hatchet, and threw at him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person161">
                  Eliz 
                  Loveit 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person161" type="surname" value="Loveit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person161" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The same Night the Murder was committed, I stood at my Door near the Prisoner's. My Door is No 2. and he lives at No. 3. I saw him come to the Door with a Hatchet in his Hand about 10 o'Clock, and he stamp'd with his Foot, and said, this Night I am bent to do Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person162">
                  Francis 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person162" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person162" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Surgeon and an Apothecary, and serv'd my Time in the Country with a Practitioner in both Ways. The Night the Coroner's Inquest sat upon the Body of the Deceased, I went in and call'd for half a Pint of Two-penny. Hearing the Jury had brought in their Verdict-Natural Death, I desir'd to see the Body, and upon searching the Head, I found a Wound, and a Caedes on the left Side of the Sagittal Suture. There was a Caedes, a simple Fracture, the Skull was broke; and there was the Print of the Weapon just upon the Cranium. I pointed to the Place, and said, I believ'd that Blow was the Cause of the Man's Death. The Cranium was not crack'd, 'twas not a Fissure, but the Skull was dented inwards. I improperly call'd it that Night a Fissure, but it was more properly a Caedes, and the Periostium must be broke to be sure, and this will occasion an Inflammation, and St. Anthony's Fire, if proper Care be not taken. I believe he died of the Blow. The Body was all mortify'd and black, when I saw it, and the Man had been dead 3 Days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person163">
                  Ann 
                  Longdon 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person163" type="surname" value="Longdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person163" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, she heard the Deceased say, on the 25th of May, that the Prisoner had struck him with an Axe, that she saw a great quantity of Blood about his Head, and that she heard him declare the Blow would be his Death.</p>
               <p>- Holdwright was in the Entry of the Prisoner's House when the Fact was done, and he deposed, that the Deceased had not been 3 Minutes in the House before he cry'd out Murder; when he came out he said, he believed the Prisoner had given him his Death's Wound.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Chidsdell. I nursed him when he kept his Room, he always complained of his Head, and would say, that Night's Work would be his Death. He was not sick, but cry'd out only his Head, his Head, and Lord have Mercy upon me, my Head is distracted. We have moved his Pillows 20 Times in a Night. He took his Bed the 2d of June, and died the 11th. The Wound was heal'd up before I came to him, but I think he died of the Disorder in his Head, for his Head and Face were swell'd to a very violent Degree with the St. Anthony's Fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person164">
                  Tho 
                  Godman 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person164" type="surname" value="Godman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person164" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On the 25th of May, the Deceased came to me, and I examin'd the Wound. I remov'd the Blood, and the Hair, and found a superficial Wound, I applied a Tonsil of Lint, and put on a common Plaister. I saw no more of him till Saturday se'ennight, or fortnight after; I was then sent for by Order of Dr. Hall to bleed him. When I bled him, he had a violent<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280012"></xptr> St. Anthony's-Fire upon him, and after I had blooded him, I look'd at the Wound, and it was well. The next Day I was sent for to bleed him again, and found the Tumor on his Head and Face began to subside; but then he began to complain of a Difficulty in Breathing: I took my Leave of him, and the next Day he died. After his Death, I laid the Skull bare, in the Presence of Mr. Hicks of Hatton-Garden, and we found no Injury done to the Skull. As to the Gentleman's Remarks on a Caedes, I don't know what he means; a Caedes is when a Print of the Weapon is left. We never had any Symptom of a Fracture of the Cranium, nor of a Concussion upon the Brain.</p>
               <p>Councel. You never open'd the Cranium, to see if the Brain was injur'd. Cannot the Brain receive an Injury, without any outward Appearance of Hurt?</p>
               <p>Mr. Godman. Yes; but then there will be the Symptoms of that Injury, Vomiting, Drowsiness, &amp;c. I can't take upon me to say the Blow was the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>Councel. You can't say it was not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hicks. I inspected the Skull, when 'twas laid bare, but I saw nothing of any Fracture or Depression. The Skull was not laid open, because it is judg'd to be unnecessary where there has been no Bleeding at the Nose, or Ears, no Comus, nor any of the Symptoms of a fractur'd Skull. I never saw the Man alive, but upon Enquiry, I could not find he had had any such Symptoms. I can't say the Wound was the Occasion of his Death; it might bring on sooner the Symptoms of the St. Anthony's Fire.</p>
               <p>Mr. Snowd was of the same Opinion, and he imagined Mr. Robinson might mistake a Suture in the Cranium for the Caedes, which he said he saw. And tho' it was not impossible for a Blow on that Place to cause Death, yet in such a Case the Symptoms must have come on sooner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person165">
                  John 
                  Burrows 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person165" type="surname" value="Burrows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday, after the Wound was given, I was sent for to the Deceased, and found him in a violent Fever, and an Inflammation was begun on the lower Part of his Face, Jaws, and Cheeks; and he had all the Symptoms of a St. Anthony's Fire. I gave him proper Remedies, but the next Day the Swelling was increas'd, to so violent a Degree, that he could not see out of his Eyes, and his Face was as big as two Mens. His Fever was decreas'd, because the Humours were flown outward. On the Wednesday he could not be persuaded to keep his Bed, but went out of one Room into another; and that might throw in again the Humour, which should have perspir'd off. So his Fever increasing again the next Day, Doctor Hall was call'd in, and he order'd Bleeding and Blistering. The Wound was cur'd before I attended him. He complain'd of a violent pricking Pain, and a shooting in his Head; and said, he had had a Blow from the Prisoner, but I did not hear him say that was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-16-person166">
                  Thomas 
                  Hayward 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person166" type="surname" value="Hayward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person166" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17380628-16-person167">
                  Anthony 
                  Dod 
               <interp inst="t17380628-16-person167" type="surname" value="Dod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person167" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Serjeants, gave the Prisoner the Character of as quiet a Fellow as any they had in the Regiment. <rs id="t17380628-16-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-16-punish83" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-16-punish83" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-16-defend155 t17380628-16-punish83"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
