<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-41">
               <interp inst="t17390607-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-41" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-41" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-41-off193-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-41-defend315 t17390607-41-off193 t17390607-41-verdict196"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-41-off193-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-41-defend317 t17390607-41-off193 t17390607-41-verdict196"></join>
         
               <p>378, 379. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-defend315" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Bird 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend315" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend315" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-defend317" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend317" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend317" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-defend317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17390607-41-off193" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-off193" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-off193" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390607-41-victim319" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Edwards 
                        <interp inst="t17390607-41-victim319" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-41-victim319" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-41-victim319" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-41-off193 t17390607-41-victim319"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; Bird, for feloniously, violently, and against her Will, ravishing and carnally knowing the said Edwards, and Clark for being present, aiding, comforting, &amp;c. him the said Bird, the said Felony to commit, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-person320">
                  Mary 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person320" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person320" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person320" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             depos'd, she was 14 Years old, and lived at the Bell Ale-house, in <placeName id="t17390607-41-crimeloc194">George-Alley, near Fleet-ditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-41-crimeloc194" type="placeName" value="George-Alley, near Fleet-ditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390607-41-crimeloc194" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-41-off193 t17390607-41-crimeloc194"></join>. That on a Thursday or Friday, (three or four Days before the Prisoners were taken up) a Woman, whose Name was Nanny, bid her carry a Pot of Beer to Clark's Room, up one Pair of Stairs, over against the Ale house in which she liv'd. That as she went up Stairs with the Beer, Bird met her upon the Stairs, took the Drink from her, and pull'd her into the Room. That he set the Beer down on a Table, and threw her down on the Bed, Clark and Nanny being both in the Room at the same Time. That Clark shut the Door, and then sat down by the Fire, while Bird kiss'd her, &amp;c. (the Witness express'd herself in Terms necessary to prove a Charge of this Nature) She said, Clark swore at her for crying out; and Nanny went down Stairs, and told another Woman what had been done, and this Woman told her Grandfather. This Usage happen'd to her, (she said) between Three and Four o'Clock, and Clark open'd the Door after the Witness had been in the Room about a Quarter of an Hour, and she went home directly, but nothing was mention'd of the Affair, till Sunday Noon. That her Grandfather then scolded at Clark, and talk'd to the Witness about it, but she did not tell him a Word of what had happen'd till Night. That on Monday Night Bird and Clark came to their House to ragg (scold) her Grandfather for what he had talk'd of, concerning them; and there being a Talk about sending for a Constable, Bird said he would stay till an Officer came, and after he had sat a good while, he complain'd that he could not stay all Night for the Constable; but her Grandfather perswaded him to be easy, and he would get one, which at last he did, and the Constable took Charge of the Prisoners. She added, that the Prisoner was a <rs id="t17390607-41-deflabel195" type="occupation">Shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-41-defend315 t17390607-41-deflabel195"></join> by Trade, but pretended to be skilful in Surgery, and came to Clark's House to cure her of the foul Disease. And at the Time she was ill used, there were several Lodgers in the House, but none on the same Floor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-person321">
                  John 
                  Bradford 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person321" type="surname" value="Bradford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person321" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd some Part of the Girl's Evidence.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17390607-41-person322">
                  John 
                  Stonehouse 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person322" type="surname" value="Stonehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person322" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Surgeon) was called.</p>
               <p>The Surgeon. I am the same Gentleman belonging to Sir 
               <persName id="t17390607-41-person323">
                  George 
                  Stonehouse 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person323" type="surname" value="Stonehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person323" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bart. by his Title, I am so, being all the Sons he had. I know nothing of the Prisoners directly nor indirectly; but Mr. Bradford belonging to the Child, he sent for me three or four Days after the Thing was done, to search the Girl, to inspect or look into - She was a little tumified, - tumify'd comes from the Word tumeo, and tumor, tumoris, to puff up and swell. There was some small Damage, but not a great deal. I gave her some Things accordingly, for Fear, (as I understood the Man was a vile Fellow ) there should be some Foulness.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-person324">
                  Alice 
                  Mace 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person324" type="surname" value="Mace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person324" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account that she was in Clark's Room all the while, and that Nanny was not there at all. That the Girl brought the Beer into the Room herself, and set it down on the Table; that she then sat herself down on the Bed, and Bird sat down by her. The Witness mention'd some Acts of Immodesty in the Prisoner, but nothing that amounted to a Proof of the Charge, and said, the Girl talked very impudently, and told the Prisoner he should not lie with her. She added, that there was not the least Noise, and that the Girl went away very well, and free from Passion.</p>
               <p>- Close deposed, That he lodged in the same House, and but a few Steps above the Prisoner's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070020"></xptr> Room; that he was at home at that Time, and heard no Noise, though if any had been made, he must have heard it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-41-person325">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wolford 
               <interp inst="t17390607-41-person325" type="surname" value="Wolford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person325" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That the Girl's Grandmother told her there were no Signs of ill Usage upon the Girl's Linnen.</p>
               <p>A Witness gave Bird the Character of an inoffensive Man.</p>
               <p>Another gave the Girl the Character of being very pert, and said, he had taken Notice of her being very fond of the Doctor's (the Prisoner's) Company; but he never saw them together. Both <rs id="t17390607-41-verdict196" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-41-verdict196" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
