<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390117-62">
               <interp inst="t17390117-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-62" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-62" type="date" value="17390117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-62-off268-c287" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-62-defend433 t17390117-62-off268 t17390117-62-verdict269"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170024"></xptr>141. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-62-defend433" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hanna 
                  <interp inst="t17390117-62-defend433" type="surname" value="Hanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-defend433" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-defend433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390117-62-off268" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-off268" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-off268" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and and corrupt Perjury in his Evidence given (at the last Sessions of Admiralty) against 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-62-victim435" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Longdon 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim435" type="surname" value="Longdon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim435" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-62-victim437" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Grant 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim437" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim437" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-62-victim437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17390117-62-person438">
                  Samuel 
                  Farrant 
               <interp inst="t17390117-62-person438" type="surname" value="Farrant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person438" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was called, who deposed, that the Prisoner on that Trial gave in Evidence as follows, viz. * That he was on board the Happy Entrance, whereof 
               <persName id="t17390117-62-person439">
                  John 
                  Longdon 
               <interp inst="t17390117-62-person439" type="surname" value="Longdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person439" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was Master. That he was at the Helm, steering the Ship on the Holderness Coast, Jan. 5th about eight in the Evening, and seeing a Ship in the Way of his Steerage at Anchor, he asked Longdon, whether he might go to the Leeward. Longdon ordered him to go to the Windward. He said, if he went to the Windward, he should run her down, and Longdon replied he would knock him down if he did not go to the Windward, and that the People belonging to the Vessel, called out to them to keep clear. And that one 
               <persName id="t17390117-62-person440">
                  John 
                  Wiley 
               <interp inst="t17390117-62-person440" type="surname" value="Wiley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person440" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Mate ordered the Sails aback; Longdon said he would knock them down if they put their Sails aback, for they might cut their Cable; and they ran on Board her, and made a Hole in her Larboard Bow, by which in three Minutes she sunk. (That) the People on Board her, cry'd out to save them; Longdon told them, if there was a hundred they should all die. He said, there was a tall Man, with short black Hair attempted to save himself by climbing up the Side of Longdon's vessel on the Gunnel, and he begged on Longdon, as he had run them down, yet (that) he would save their Lives, and told him that the Vessel belonged to Horselydown; Longdon said no, if there was a hundred of them they should all die, and called to Grant to help him; saying, That there should not one of them come on Board the Ship. Grant on that, took the Man by the Shoulders, and held him; and Longdon took a Knife out of his Pocket, and ripped him up, on the right Side, and then they shoved him into the Sea, between the Bows of the Ships; (And that) they saw no other Ship but that which they run down.</p>
               <p>* See the Trial, printed for J. Roberts in Warwick Lane.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17390117-62-verdict269" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-verdict269" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-62-verdict269" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               Mr. Farrant produced a Paper of Minutes, which he said, was a true Copy of the original Minutes, taken by him in Court upon Longdon's Trial. But there appearing several Variations between Mr. Farrant's Account of the Prisoner's Evidence, and that assigned in the Indictment, the Prisoner was acquitted
            </rs>. The Councel moved for Leave to bring another Indictment against him next Sessions, which was granted.</p>
            </div1>
