<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-57">
               <interp inst="t17370216-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-57" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-57" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-57-off251-c223" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-57-defend353 t17370216-57-off251 t17370216-57-verdict254"></join>
         
               <p>64 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-57-defend353" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Drinkwater 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-57-defend353" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-defend353" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-defend353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370216-57-off251" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-off251" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-off251" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt Perjury, on a Trial between 
                     <persName id="t17370216-57-person354">
                        Eliz 
                        Sayer 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person354" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-57-person354" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-57-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17370216-57-person355">
                        John 
                        Warwick 
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person355" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-57-person355" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-57-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , at <placeName id="t17370216-57-crimeloc252">Justice-Hall in the Old Baily</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-crimeloc252" type="placeName" value="Justice-Hall in the Old Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-crimeloc252" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-57-off251 t17370216-57-crimeloc252"></join>
               
                  </rs>, in <rs id="t17370216-57-cd253" type="crimeDate">Sept</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-57-off251 t17370216-57-cd253"></join>. last,</p>
               <p>^ John Warwick. In September Sessions I was tried here for two Robberies, on a Woman I was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160018"></xptr> acquainted with, and Drinkwater was a Witness at the Trial.</p>
               <p>^ Vide Sessions-Paper, Numb. 7. p. 180. 1736.</p>
               <p>Drinkwater. This Warwick was found guilty of conspiring against my Life, last Sessions, and for the same stood in the Pillory, - a little while.</p>
               <p>Warwick. On my Trial for these Robberies in September, I desired my Councel to ask Drinkwater, whether he had not declar'd he would hang me. I saw him sworn; and when the Question was ask'd him, he made Answer, - no, I only said, I would bring him to Justice. After he had given Evidence he was sent to Newgate -</p>
               <p>Drinkwater. What was it for?</p>
               <p>Warwick. I call'd Mr. Cook to prove he had said the Words, and he was order'd into Custody, and was taken into the Baledock, and there he bawl'd out, - my Lord! my Lord! - Pray my Lord! pray my Lord!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-57-person356">
                  Joseph 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17370216-57-person356" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person356" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About Midsummer last I saw Drinkwater, and he asked me when I saw 
               <persName id="t17370216-57-person357">
                  Jack 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17370216-57-person357" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person357" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I told him I had not seen him a pretty while, he's in the Country, says I; I have been in Jail, says he, eleven Months, and my Head and Pen have been at work; if I can find him, I will hang him; if I can't hang him, I'll transport him; if I don't do neither of them, I'll imprison the Dog for Life. I believe I might say, - what's the Occasion of your being in Goal? And he said, - no Matter, I have it all in my Book.</p>
               <p>C. Was you acquainted with Warwick?</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes, I have been acquainted with him about three or four Years. I took a Lease of some Ground from the Countess of Southampton, and Warwick had a Mind to a Bit of this Ground to build upon, and he appearing well I let him a Bit of Ground.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-57-person358">
                  George 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17370216-57-person358" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person358" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner Drinkwater was at my House in Spaw-Fields last Summer, and Mr. Cook was looking over his Pales into my Yard, and he asked Cook when he saw his Friend Warwick. Cook told him that Warwick and he had fallen out, and that he was gone into the Country. I wish I could find him, says Drinkwater, I have been barbarously used by him in Jail, and if I can catch him, I will either hang him, or transport him, or keep him in Jail for Life.</p>
               <p>Councel. I desire Warwick's Indictment, with the short Minutes on it, may be read; what the Issue was, and the Verdict.</p>
               <p>Then the Record of Warwick's Conviction and Judgment against him was read.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-57-person359">
                  John 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17370216-57-person359" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person359" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Warwick tried on that Bill of Indictment, he was upon Trial convicted and ordered to be set in the Pillory.</p>
               <p>Councel. We can shew this by more Witnesses, but I believe nobody doubts it.</p>
               <p>C. Now the Evidence that Warwick has given, is to be of no Weight; no more Regard is to be paid to it, than if he had given no Evidence at all.</p>
               <p>Warwick. If I have been proved a Villain, he has been ten times as big.</p>
               <p>Councel. Aye ! but you are the Largest Man.</p>
               <p>Warwick. He is as bad a Rogue as myself, though I have stood in the Pillory.</p>
               <p>Drinkwater. He did not stand Half his Time.</p>
               <p>Warwick. I was forced to jump out to save my Life, that Bull-fac'd Fellow there had got a Mob, and they threw Stones and Brickbats. I have a Hole in my Leg you may turn your Fingers in, made with a Brickbat; and my Arm has since been laid open.</p>
               <p>C. Offenders are to suffer the Judgment of the Law, and their Punishment is not to be extended farther; whoever is concerned in Outrages of this Nature, are liable to the Censure of this Court.</p>
               <p>No other Evidence appearing to support the Charge, the Prisoner was <rs id="t17370216-57-verdict254" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-57-verdict254" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
