<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-7">
               <interp inst="t17341204-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-7" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-7" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-7-off40-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-7-defend71 t17341204-7-off40 t17341204-7-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-defend71" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Atkins 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-7-defend71" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-defend71" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-defend71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of St. Martin in the Fields, was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-7-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               privately stealing 3 Silver Knee-Buckles, value 10 s. 4 Silver Stock-Buckles, value 16 s. 2 Silver Shoe-Buckles, value 12 s. 1 Silver Girdle-Buckle, value 2 s. and 1 Pair of Silver Sleeve-Buttons value 2 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-7-victim73" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Liger 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-7-victim73" type="surname" value="Liger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-7-victim73" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-7-victim73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-7-off40 t17341204-7-victim73"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17341204-7-cd41" type="crimeDate">October 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-7-off40 t17341204-7-cd41"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Liger. On Sunday the 13th of October I miss'd some Buckles out of my Shew-Glass; I thought my Man might have lent 'em: But next Morning my Man told me some Buckles were gone he could not tell how. On the 31st of October Mr. White, the Prisoner's Master came over to me and asked me if I had miss'd any Thing. I said, Yes. Then he shew'd me some Buckles, and asked me if I knew them. I answer'd Yes, very well, these are mine. He told me that he had been robb'd too, and was afraid there was Confederacy between his Servant and mine. Upon this I examined the Prisoner, who confessed that between 11 and 12 at Night, when I was in Bed, he came to my Shop and desired my Man, who is near-sighted, to shew him some Buckles; upon which my Man opening the Shew-Glass, he (the Prisoner) at twice took out several Buckles, and put them into his Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-person74">
                  Stephen 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17341204-7-person74" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person74" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prosecutor's Apprentice. The Prisoner said he had a Letter from a Cousin in the Country, ordering him to send her some Buckles, and therefore he desired me to shew him some; and if they would do, he would pay me for them.</p>
               <p>Mr White. The Prisoner is my <rs id="t17341204-7-deflabel42" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-7-defend71 t17341204-7-deflabel42"></join>. I observ'd he had several Silver Things, and examin'd him how he came by them. He said he met a Man in the Street who gave him a Guinea. I thought this was a villainous Story, and what encreased my Suspicion of him was, that a Man at a Brewers told me the Prisoner had presented their Maid with a Diamond Ring worth 20 Guineas. - The Prisoner was carry'd before Mr. Justice Deveil, where he confess'd that he took the Goods out of the Prosecutor's Shew-Glass.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't deny that I had the Goods, but they were given me by the Prosecutor's Wife. My first Acquaintance with her was when he and my Master went out of Town together. Her Apprentice being gone out, she desired me to shut up her Shop for her, which I did. And then she said, Ned, what do you want? I said, A Buckle for my Hat, and one for my Stock She bid me take 'em. I asked her what they came to, she said she would not take any Thing of me. After this, I was at her House Thirteen Nights in Fourteen, while they were in Gloucestershire.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ivell. Six or Seven Weeks ago the Prisoner sold me some old broken Silver Buckles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-person75">
                  Ruben 
                  Bowler 
               <interp inst="t17341204-7-person75" type="surname" value="Bowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person75" type="given" value="Ruben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the Prisoner's Fellow-'Prentice, and never heard that he wronged any body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-person76">
                  Abraham 
                  Burrier 
               <interp inst="t17341204-7-person76" type="surname" value="Burrier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person76" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day the Prisoner was taken up his Master was sitting by me, when the Prosecutor came in and brought a Buckle, and said it was not quite the same as one of those that were found upon the Prisoner: And he said besides, that he had got his Number, and above his Number.</p>
               <p>Court. Above his Number: That's a little strange!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-person77">
                  James 
                  Needham 
               <interp inst="t17341204-7-person77" type="surname" value="Needham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person77" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Mr. White's, when he was out of Town, and his 2 Boys were over the Way at the Prosecutor's House - I have heard that they and the Prosecutor's Wife have drank 14 Gallons of Brandy together.</p>
               <p>Mr. White. They have invented a great many Stories about junketting together, and sometimes they have run it up to 46 Gallons.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-7-person78">
                  Mary 
                  Garman 
               <interp inst="t17341204-7-person78" type="surname" value="Garman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person78" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to this Gentleman, and said, Consider this young Youth - Good God! - I never was afore a Justice my Lordship in my Life before - My Lordship should consider a young Youth - I never knew no harm of him before.</p>
               <p>Three or Four Witnesses deposed that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040007"></xptr> they had known the Prisoner several Years, that they had never heard any Ill of him, and believed he was a civil honest young Man.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17341204-7-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17341204-7-punish44" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-7-punish44" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-7-defend71 t17341204-7-punish44"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
