<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-26">
               <interp inst="t17381206-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-26" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-26" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-26-off118-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-26-defend188 t17381206-26-off118 t17381206-26-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-defend188" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Lyon 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-26-defend188" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-defend188" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-defend188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that he on the 10th of August, in the 5th Year of his present Majesty, in the Parish of St. George the Martyr, <rs id="t17381206-26-off118" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-off118" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-off118" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               did marry and to <rs id="t17381206-26-viclabel119" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-26-victim190 t17381206-26-viclabel119"></join> take, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-26-victim190" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Williams 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim190" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim190" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Widow; and afterwards, on the <rs id="t17381206-26-cd120" type="crimeDate">19th of July, in the 11th Year of his Majesty</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-26-off118 t17381206-26-cd120"></join>, with Force and Arms, in the Parish of St. Mary Magdalen, Old Fish-street, feloniously married, and to Wife took, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-26-victim192" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Allen 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim192" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim192" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-victim192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Widow, and to her then and there was married; his first Wife, 
                     <persName id="t17381206-26-person193">
                        Mary 
                        Williams 
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person193" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-person193" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-26-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , being then living, and in full Life
            </rs>, &amp;c. and afterterwards that he the said 
               <persName id="t17381206-26-person194">
                  John 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person194" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 27th of November, in the 12th Year of the King, in the Parish of St. Martin in the Fields, for the Felony aforesaid, was arrested and taken.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution having taken notice that the Indictment was grounded on an Act made in the 1st Year of King James I. c. z. proceeded to open the Charge, and the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-person195">
                  Henry 
                  Mackworth 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person195" type="surname" value="Mackworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person195" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Apothecary in Bloomsbury: I know the Prisoner James Lyon: He came to my House, August 31, with my Sister Mary Williams, (after they had been taking a Walk in the Fields) and said they had agreed to be married, - I remember it was in Tottenham-Court Fair Time, and they were both willing to to be married that Day. I had my Sister consider what she was about; but she, having a Notion<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060014"></xptr> that the Prisoner was worth Money, and that twould be a good Match, desired to be married then. The Prisoner and she din'd at my House, and after Dinner she went home to her Lodging, to dress herself, and we sent for two or three different Roman Priests to perform the Ceremony; but they were not at home. At last we went to one Johnson's in Eagle-Street, ('tis a private House) and there we found a Priest, one Mr. Vane, and by the Consent of each other, - by asking the Consent of each other, that is, - whether you'll take me, - and I will take you, they were marry'd. 'Twas not the Ceremony of the Church of England which was read, but that of the Church of Rome.</p>
               <p>Q. Was a Ring made use of in the Ceremony?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. I can't say that: - but 'twas according to the Ceremony of the Romish Church, because my Sister was a Roman. When the Ceremony was over, they came to my House, and after supper they went to bed together. Next Morning he went about his Business, and she went to her Lodging. At Michaelmas following he took a House in King-street, St. Giles's, where he <rs id="t17381206-26-deflabel121" type="occupation">kept a Pawnbroker's Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-26-defend188 t17381206-26-deflabel121"></join>. Here they liv'd a Year and a Half, and she went by his Name, and appear'd as his Wife in all manner of Shapes and Respects. Indeed since Christmas last I have not seen her; we have been to enquire after her, but can't hear whether she is dead or alive.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was there any Courtship preceded the Marriage?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. He had been with her two or three times, and the thing was talk'd of; she inform'd us of the Offer he had made to her - I never heard it suspected she was his Housekeeper, but she went for his Wife with every one.</p>
               <p>Counc. In what Manner was the Ceremony performed?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. 'Tis taking such a one for my Wife; - and she says; she takes such a one for her Husband, To Have, and To Hold for Life.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Person produce a Book?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. Yes, - Latin and English; but I did not look into it.</p>
               <p>Counc. Then it might be a Play-Book, for aught you know?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. I did not look into it, sure enough.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was there any Latin read at that Time?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. I can't say that particularly; but I remember the Consent of the Parties, very well. I never attended a Marriage by a Popish Priest, but this and my own, and that was fourteen Years ago.</p>
               <p>Counc. Are you a Roman?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. Yes, - but the Prisoner is a Protestant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Q. Have not you, (on your Oath) said she pass'd for a Housekeeper, and not for my Wife?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. No; nor have I ever heard any such thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Q. Had not she a Husband then living?</p>
               <p>Mackworth. She had not, he died abroad - Long before this I received an Account of his Death by Letter, and his Relations went into Mourning for him. I have lost the Letter, for I had no Notion of these Difficulties coming up.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mackworth gave much the same Account with Mr. Mackworth: adding, that she was a Roman Catholick, and that the Prisoner and her Sister were married in the same Manner that she and Mr. Mackworth were married; that she could not remember all the Words, only these: - I take thee for my wedded Wife, and endow thee with all my worldly Chattels: that the Prayers were in Latin; but that the Priest gave them a deal of good Advice in English; that there was a Ring made use of; that after the Marriage, they were visited and received Visits as Man and Wife; that during the Year and Half they liv'd in Kingstreet, they were not one Night asunder; and that the Marriage Ceremony was performed by a Priest, in a Room up one Pair of Stairs, about Nine o'clock at Night; she and her Husband, the Bride, Bridegroom, and the Priest, being only in Company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-person196">
                  James 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person196" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person196" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about 6 Years come Christmas next. He married Mr. Mackworth's Sister, and I remember their living as Man and Wife together in King-street, Bloomsbury. Her Name was Williams before he married her. I took the House they liv'd in of the Prisoner, and they liv'd with me in it Half a Year afterwards, and all that Time she went by his Name, and they liv'd and lay together. She has dined several times at my House since last Christmas Day. I don't know what's become of her now, - but I believe I saw her last February.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-person197">
                  Catherine 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person197" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person197" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have not known the Prisoner till lately: I have heard my Husband speak to him; but I was not married then. I have known him about a Twelvemonth, and have seen Mrs. Williams (poor Woman!) several time since Christmas. I believe she was his Wife - else<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060015"></xptr> she would not have taken the Usage she had from him.</p>
               <p>Counc. The Question now is, Concerning a Marriage De Jure and De Facto; Whether a Marriage by a Popish Priest is a Marriage De Jure? She is a Wife De Facto - she has liv'd with him as such, and he has acknowledged her for his Wife; but, I must own, I am not prepared to produce particular Cases to this Purpose.</p>
               <p>But as I have been often told upon the Circuits, that I must shew some Ceremony to have been performed, I was willing to shew the Truth of the Case. I apprehend the Prisoner would be liable to pay his first Wife's Debts, and if he should, then this poor Woman's Substance, who has been deceived by him, is to be taken from her, and she can claim no Dower out of his Effects. Call Mrs. Allen.</p>
               <p>The Council on the other Side objected to her being sworn, and observed that as all Acts constituting Felonies are to be construed strictly, so a Marriage, strictly and according to the Laws, must be a Marriage according to the Ceremony of the Church of England, and it appearing that there had not been such a Marriage, but one by a Popish Priest, it was submitted, that they had not incontestibly established the first Marriage, nor had they so established it, as to be intituled to produce the second Wife.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Allen. I was married to the Prisoner the 19th of July was twelve Months at <placeName id="t17381206-26-crimeloc122">St. Mary Magdalen's Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-26-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Magdalen's Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-26-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-26-off118 t17381206-26-crimeloc122"></join>, by Licence from Doctors-Commons, and the Certificate is here. He then passed for a Widower, and I lived with him 'till I took him up, except a little Time he was in Ireland. I found it out in June, and told him of it; he deny'd it utterly, but I called upon Mr. Mackworth, and he confirmed it, and said he was present at his first Marriage, and told me all that he has said here. This was the Reason I indicted him for marrying me. I am a Protestant, and have brought this Prosecution against him, by my own Resentment. I sent for a Marshall's Man, and was present when he was brought before Mr. De Veil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-person198">
                  Carter 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person198" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person198" type="given" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when he was arrested, 'twas in Spring-Gardens, near Charing-Cross. I am a Servant to Mr. Mackenzie, who lodges at No. 2. in Spring-Gardens, 'twas there he was apprehended for having two Wives, as I was informed, but I did not see the Warrant.</p>
               <p>Mr. De Veil. The Constable always keeps the Warrant for his Justification. He was brought before me, and committed by me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-26-person199">
                  Ann 
                  Roe 
               <interp inst="t17381206-26-person199" type="surname" value="Roe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person199" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the Prisoner married Mrs. Allen, at St. Mary Magdalen's Church.</p>
               <p>Council. I apprehend, 'tis necessary (in order to shew the Court has a Jurisdiction to try him in Middlesex) that they should produce the Warrant by which he was taken. The Rule of Law is, - that the best Evidence is to be given in such Cases, and the Warrant will speak for itself: That being produced, it will appear for what Offence the Man was committed, and in this Case 'tis mentioned in the Indictment.</p>
               <p>Council. I imagine it never was required, or ever was expected, that the Warrant should be produced, and that the Objection with Regard to Jurisdiction is easily answered; for if he had been taken up in another Country, he had not come here but by Habeas Corpus. But as he is here, he is to be taken Prima Facie, as he is before the Court. And Mr. De Veil says he was brought before him, and committed by him; therefore he can easily shew, if 'twas for any other Offence.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Mackworth. Were all the Words necessary to make a Popish Marriage repeated on this Occasion?</p>
               <p>Mr Mackworth. Yes: I never read the Words of a Popish Matrimony in my Life, yet I believe he was married according to this Form. The Priest was in a Secular Habit, but he put on a little Thing, which we call a Stole. 'Tis a Thing that comes round their Shoulders; a Bit of Silk about four or five Inches broad, and hangs down a little Way. He had no surplice on; but he was one whom I had seen officiate as a Priest; and no Seculars wear the Stole, tho' they may do some Office. <rs id="t17381206-26-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-26-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
