<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391017-6">
               <interp inst="t17391017-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-6" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391017-6" type="date" value="17391017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391017-6-off27-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-6-defend76 t17391017-6-off27 t17391017-6-verdict30"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391017-6-off27-c66" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-6-defend78 t17391017-6-off27 t17391017-6-verdict31"></join>
         
               <p>494, 495. 
               
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-defend76" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Green 
                  <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend76" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend76" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-defend78" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Leeson 
                  <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend78" type="surname" value="Leeson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend78" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-defend78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17391017-6-off27" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-off27" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-off27" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               ripping and stealing 80 C. wt. of Lead, val. 4 l. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17391017-6-victim79" type="victimName">
                        Ferdinando
                         John Paris
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-victim79" type="surname" value="John Paris"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-6-victim79" type="given" value="Ferdinando"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391017-6-victim79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-6-off27 t17391017-6-victim79"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , fix'd to his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17391017-6-cd28" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-6-off27 t17391017-6-cd28"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person80">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person80" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person80" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Paris's in <placeName id="t17391017-6-crimeloc29">Strand-Lane, Surrey-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-6-crimeloc29" type="placeName" value="Strand-Lane, Surrey-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391017-6-crimeloc29" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391017-6-off27 t17391017-6-crimeloc29"></join>. On Sunday Morning, the 16th of September, about One o'Clock, I open'd a Sash that looks over a Parlour, (which is lower than the rest of the House, and was cover'd with Lead) to see whether it rain'd or not: The Leads at that Time were very wet, but upon putting my Hand out of the Window, I found it did not rain.</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. This House is mine; and the Parlour that has been mentioned, was cover'd with near 40 C. wt. of Lead. On Saturday Night, between Ten and Eleven o'Clock, as I was going to Bed, I look'd out of a Window that looks over these Leads, toward Somerset Gardens, to see<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173910170009"></xptr> what Weather it was, (according to my usual Custom) and I then saw the Lead safe; but at Six o'Clock on Sunday Morning, Sept. 16. as I came down Stairs, I saw two great Strips cut off to the Joinings where the Lead is doubled over. Upon this I went down Strand-Lane, and enquired of several People if they had seen any Lead carrying off? One of them told me, that William Green of Maypole-Alley had a good Job To-night, and that a great deal of Stuff had gone into his House. Hearing this, I went to Maypole-Alley, and enquired after Green; before I could get a Word of an Answer, the People said, - What, Sir, have you been robb'd To-night? I had a wretched Character of him, and therefore I apply'd to a Magistrate for a Search Warrant, but could not get one on Sunday. However, I planted my own Servants, and five or six others, about the House: In short, I beset it all Sunday and Sunday Night, and went myself every Half Hour, or Three-quarters, to see that my Watch did Duty. About One o'Clock on Monday Morning, my Servant sent me Word, he had seiz'd a Man with some Lead; I went to him, and found Hesketh with a large Quantity, which I thought was mine; so I carry'd him before a Justice, and upon his Information I search'd Leeson's House, and in a little private Hole under the Stair-Case, I found another Quantity press'd as flat as possible. I examin'd it, and found some of it still wet; I took as much of it as I thought was mine, and sent it to be flatted, and upon laying it to the Place, I found it tallied exactly in all the Notches and Indentures. I am very positive all the Lead I found in Leeson's House was mine; but when I had it laid on the Place from whence it was taken, there was not enough, there was still some wanting: So I went to search Green's House; there I saw some small old Iron, but a huge large Pair of Scales, and at last I found my Lead, and pick'd it out of a great Quantity which he had in his House, and upon laying it to the Places where it had wanting, it tallied in the most exact Manner; in one Place they were forced to cut round a Nail, and the Cut in the Lead fitted the Nail. Upon this I took Green, and carry'd him before a Justice, where he own'd that he himself carry'd Part of my Lead to Leeson's House, (which is exactly opposite to his own in Maypole-Alley) at Three o'Clock on Sunday Morning. The Lead that my Man stopp'd upon Hesketh, that likewise was mine, and I left it in the Constable's Hands; that was cut very irregularly, and tally'd exactly. I lost above 8 C. Wt. I think there was 9, but I won't swear to a Pound or two.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person81">
                  Edward 
                  Oak 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person81" type="surname" value="Oak"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person81" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know the Prisoners; but on Sunday Evening, I saw two Men carry something like Lead under the Flaps of their Coats to Hesketh's, at the Corner of Maypole Alley. One of the Men had a Set-to Coat on, with a Cape; he was very much like the Prisoner, and the Coat like what Green has on now: I saw them carry it into Hesketh's Cellar. I saw no more of them that Evening, but on Monday Morning, between Six and Seven o'Clock, Hesketh brought something in a Basket out of his Cellar; and to me, it appeared, as two Bunches of Turneps. He called a Man to give him a Lift-up with the Basket; which I saw, and was surprized that two Bunches of Turneps should be so heavy; so I followed him from his Cellar to Clare-Market, and there he pitched the Basket upon a Bulk. Then I went up to him, and asked him if those Turneps were to be sold? No, says he, there's nothing to be sold. I insisted on looking into the Basket, and found a Parcel of mill'd Lead under the Turneps; so I sent for my Master, and we took Hesketh before Mr. Justice Frazier, who granted us Search-Warrants, by virtue of which, we found great Quantities in Leeson's and Green's House, all which, (with that, which we took from Hesketh,) fitted exactly to the Places, from whence they were taken. When Green was before the Justice, he said, he had been out that Saturday Night till Twelve o'Clock, that he then came home in Liquor and went to Bed, but his Wife called him up about Three o'Clock, and told him, some Lead was brought to the House, which his Cousin took in, and he was uneasy about it, and said, it must be removed. He told us, that his Wife informed him, the Lead was brought in by 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person82">
                  Thomas 
                  Asser 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person82" type="surname" value="Asser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person82" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he himself carried Part of it to Leeson's House, telling him, he was not afraid himself, nor need he (Leeson) fear coming into any Trouble about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person83">
                  Thomas 
                  Hesketh 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person83" type="surname" value="Hesketh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person83" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the Porter, and the Lead found was in my Basket. On the 16th of September, at Night, the Prisoner Leeson called to me, and asked me where Green was? I asked him if any thing was the Matter, more than ordinary? He said, yes; he had a great deal of Lead in his (Leeson's) House, which was brought in that Morning. Leeson wanted to move it to my Cellar, but I advised him to stay till Green came; but he swore a great Oath, and said he would throw it down the Vault. After this I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173910170010"></xptr> went to get a Pint of Beer, and while I was gone, I found two Pieces had been brought into my Cellar. I saw Green presently after; he told me he was not afraid of any thing, and bid me carry the Lead from my Cellar to Waldron, the Plummer, in Holborn. Accordingly, the next Morning, between 7 and 8 I put the Lead in a Basket, and covered it with a Bunch of Turneps, because I was afraid 'twas not honestly come by, and I was stopped with it in Clare-Market, as I was carrying it to Waldron. This is one of the Peices that was then taken from me: I put my Name upon it, and here it is now.</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. This is a Piece of what I lost.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frazier. Green being brought before me, owned that such Lead as Mr. Paris had lost was in his House, but he could not give any Account how he came by it: He said it came in, while he was from home. Leeson was not brought before me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. Green told Mr. Frazier, that 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person84">
                  Thomas 
                  Asser 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person84" type="surname" value="Asser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person84" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (his Cousin) brought it into his (Green's) House, I asked him who this Asser was, and told him I would send a Horse and Man fifty Miles to find him, but he said he did not know where to find him, tho' (he owned) he was his Nephew, and and lived in the House with him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frazier. I do remember he mentioned Asser's Name.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Leeson. Green knocked me up on Sunday Morning, and told me he had a Parcel of Lead in his House, which his Kinsman had taken in, and as he had been in Trouble before, (on such Accounts) he desired me to let him put it in my House, 'till the People who brought it should come for the Money, and then he should know (he said) who it came from.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person85">
                  Mary 
                  Meddall 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person85" type="surname" value="Meddall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person85" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Midwife. I live in Russel-Court, by Covent-Garden. On that Saturday Night I was sent for to Green's Wife; she was ill, and I thought it would be her Labour, so I staid with her till between Four and Five o'Clock on Sunday Morning. Pretty near Twelve, Green came home very much in Liquor, and his Wife and I went up, and saw him safe upon a Bed up two Pair of Stairs in his Cloaths. This was about 12 o'Clock; - I am sure it was not past One. After his Spouse and I had seen him safe, we came down Stairs and had a Dish of Tea. About Two o'Clock, somebody knocked very hard at the Door, and Mrs. Green called to a Relation to see who it was. She went down two or three Steps herself, and I (being a little curious) listned myself; and I heard three or four People say, - where's Green? We have got some Lead to dispose of. Mrs. Green told them he was a-bed, fuddled; and that 'twas a wrong time o'Night to bring Lead to sell. Why then (says the Men) we'll leave it till we can speak to your Husband; and I heard a heavy Load fall on the Ground. I have known Green six or seven Years; he buys and sells old and new Brass, and Lead and Iron: I never heard any thing in this Respect before. He has the Character of a sober Man in his Neighbourhood. Indeed I have heard he has been in Trouble before, but he was Acquitted by the Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person86">
                  Anthony 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person86" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person86" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (Green's Landlord) 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person87">
                  Charles 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person87" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person87" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a Chandler) 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person88">
                  John 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person88" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person88" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a Picture Frame-maker, and Keeper of a Stuff Shop) gave the Prisoner Green a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person89">
                  Thomas 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person89" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person89" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Stanhope street, the Corner of Maypole-alley, and 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person90">
                  Richard 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person90" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person90" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had known Green about nine Years, and gave Green the Character of a bad Man, and said he was a reputed Buyer of stolen Goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person91">
                  John 
                  Lamb 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person91" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person92">
                  William 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person92" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person92" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person93">
                  William 
                  Henning 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person93" type="surname" value="Henning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person93" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person94">
                  John 
                  Logan 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person94" type="surname" value="Logan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person94" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person95">
                  John 
                  Baily 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person95" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person96">
                  Susan 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person96" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person96" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person97">
                  Richard 
                  Smallwood 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person97" type="surname" value="Smallwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person97" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person98">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person98" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person98" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17391017-6-person99">
                  Francis 
                  Rimer 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person99" type="surname" value="Rimer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person99" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave Leeson a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391017-6-person100">
                  John 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17391017-6-person100" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore he knew Leeson when his Mother was with Child of him, and that he always had behaved well. Green <rs id="t17391017-6-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>; Leeson <rs id="t17391017-6-verdict31" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391017-6-verdict31" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
