<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17371012-26">
               <interp inst="t17371012-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-26" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17371012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371012-26" type="date" value="17371012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371012-26-off113-c144" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-defend197 t17371012-26-off113 t17371012-26-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>31. 
               
                  <persName id="t17371012-26-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Lyford 
                  <interp inst="t17371012-26-defend197" type="surname" value="Lyford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-defend197" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-defend197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17371012-26-defloc112">St. Andrews Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-26-defloc112" type="placeName" value="St. Andrews Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17371012-26-defloc112" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-defend197 t17371012-26-defloc112"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17371012-26-off113" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-off113" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-off113" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               he on the 8th of July in the 10th Year of his Majesty's Reign, in the Parish of Acton, took to <rs id="t17371012-26-viclabel114" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-victim199 t17371012-26-viclabel114"></join> 
                  
                     
                        <persName id="t17371012-26-victim199" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Wynne 
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim199" type="surname" value="Wynne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim199" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and to her was then and there married, and afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17371012-26-cd115" type="crimeDate">24th of June</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-off113 t17371012-26-cd115"></join> last in the Parish of <placeName id="t17371012-26-crimeloc116">Paddington</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-crimeloc116" type="placeName" value="Paddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-crimeloc116" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-off113 t17371012-26-crimeloc116"></join>, feloniously; took to Wife 
                     
                        <persName id="t17371012-26-victim201" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Hinton 
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim201" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim201" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371012-26-victim201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, his former Wife being then in full Life
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution set forth, that the Prisoner had marry'd one Wynne, a Widow, on the 8th of July 1736, and while she was alive, it happen'd that Miss Hinton and her Mother took Lodgings, in his House. That the Defendant got into young Mrs. Hinton's Acquaintance, and knowing that she was entituled to Money, he inveigled her to marry him. That he never asked the Consent of her Trustees, but prevailed upon her to marry him without it; after which the Trustees hearing something of the first Marriage, they satisfied themselves of the Truth of it, and then tax'd him with it. He denied it, but they told him they could produce not only the Certificates both of his first and second Marriage, but the very Affiadavit he made of his being a Batchelor when he took out the Licence in order to marry the second Wife, and tho' the Prisoner had pleaded not Guilty, yet they should bring such clear Evidence of both Marriages, as would plainly prove him to be Guilty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-26-person202">
                  Thomas 
                  Knowles 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person202" type="surname" value="Knowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person202" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the Prisoner's Wedding at Acton Church; he was there marry'd to Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17371012-26-person203">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wynne 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person203" type="surname" value="Wynne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person203" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in July 1736, and I saw her alive within these 2 Months.</p>
               <p>Councel. Are you not positive you have seen her within these 6 Weeks?</p>
               <p>Knowles. I won't say that; but I'll swear I have seen her within these 2 Months, at the House where I lodge, in Kings Head Court, by the King's-Head-Tavern in Holborn.</p>
               <p>Councel. And what Name did she then go by?</p>
               <p>Knowles. By the Prisoner's Name - Lyford.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did they live together as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Knowles. Yes; for near a Twelvemonth.</p>
               <p>The Reverend Mr. Brook Saunders. I marry'd 
               <persName id="t17371012-26-person204">
                  Henry 
                  Lyford 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person204" type="surname" value="Lyford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person204" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17371012-26-person205">
                  Mary 
                  Hinton 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person205" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person205" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Paddington, the 24th of June last. I believe the Prisoner is the Man. They were marry'd by the Names of Henry Lyford, Batchelor, and Mary Hinton, Spinster. Here is the Register-Book.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. As the second Wife is by Law admitted to be a Witness, she is the best Evidence, whether there was a second Marriage or not. For them to prove it only by Circumstances, and not produce the Woman, is against the Course of the Law. Says the Doctor - I believe the Prisoner is the Man, and why, - because I suppose him to be so. The Law in Penal Cases requires the best Evidence, and I believe the Gentlemen on the other side, can't shew that ever there was a second Marriage prov'd, without the Evidence of the 2d Wife.</p>
               <p>Councel's Prosecutor. I believe this is the first Time that the second Wife's Testimony was ever call'd the best Evidence. In this Case, the young Woman has thought fit to chuse the Prisoner for a Husband; the Fear of losing him might exasperate her, but these Persons which we call, must be allow'd to be unbias'd, and to be indifferent Witnesses.</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. I believe the Prisoner is the Man I marry'd to Mary Hinton, at Paddington, by Licence. I have the Licence here, and this is my Hand-writing; I always back the Licences myself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. Are you sure it was Mrs. Hinton that you marry'd?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. Yes; and I should know her again if I was to see her.</p>
               <p>C. Have you seen either of the Parties before?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. Yes: I believe I have; but not to know them before I recollect the Prisoner's Person, now.</p>
               <p>Councel You never make any Entries here of Marriages, but what are real?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads.</p>
               <p>Marriages and Burials. June the 24th, 1737. Henry Lyford, of St. Andrew's Holborn, Middlesex, Bachelor, and Mary Hinton, of the same Parish, Spinster. Per Licence.</p>
               <p>By the Reverend Mr. Saunders</p>
               <p>Counc. Who made that Entry?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. The Parish Clark; but I inspect the Register myself.</p>
               <p>Counc. And have you any other Reason to assert this Marriage, but from this Licence?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. Seeing the Prisoner, I can recollect his Person. I told the Attorney, that I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120018"></xptr> had marry'd a Person of that Name, by the Archbishop's Licence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. Suppose now you had not seen this Book, should you have remember'd you marry'd such a Person?</p>
               <p>Mr. Saunders. Yes to be sure; and the Woman I should have known particularly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-26-person206">
                  Thomas 
                  Abingdon 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person206" type="surname" value="Abingdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person206" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am Clark of Paddington Parish, and I believe the Prisoner is the Person that was marry'd the 24th of June last to 
               <persName id="t17371012-26-person207">
                  Mary 
                  Hinton 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person207" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person207" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe he is the very Man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any other Marriage that Day?</p>
               <p>Abingdon. No. They were marry'd by this Gentleman - Mr. Saunders: And I made the Entry of this particular Marriage, within a Day or two after.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. Do you know Mrs Hinton?</p>
               <p>Abingdon. No; I never saw her before, nor since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371012-26-person208">
                  Christopher 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17371012-26-person208" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person208" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I went to spend an Evening, some Time since, at Mr. Ross's, and there I saw Mr. Adams and Mr. Latewood: They pull'd out the Certificates of these two Marriages, and I read them. Mr. Lyford and Mrs. Hinton were sent for, and he declar'd he was marry'd to her. I charged him with being marry'd to Mrs. Wynne; he said, he had no other Wife but Miss Hinton, and she was present the same Time. A Constable was sent for, in Order to his being charged with the Prisoner; but he deny'd the first Marriage, and when we read the Certificates to him, he said, he did not Care a Farthing for them; we might bring twenty of them, if we pleased. He deny'd the first Marriage, but the second, he always acknowledged, and said to Mrs. Hinton - my Dear, I have no other Wife in the World but you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. Pray was you before a Magistrate, that had any Authority to ask these Questions, or was it only among yourselves?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gibson. 'Twas among ourselves.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hinton, Widow. I know that Man at the Bar, to be Henry Lyford. On the 24th of June last, my Daughter was up sooner than ordinary, and went out. She did not come Home all Night - not 'till the next Night at Eight o'Clock. Then she came up Stairs to my Bed-side, and fell on her Knees. I asked her where she had been all Night? She told me, at Islington - to take a Lodging. What have you to do, said I, to take a Lodging? She then said - why, Madam, to be plain with you, I am marry'd Marry'd! says I - to whom! to Mr. Lyford, Madam, said she. And presently the Prisoner came up, and he fell on his knees, to ask my Blessing. I shut the Door against him, and immediately did up my Things, and went out of the House.</p>
               <p>Q. Has your Daughter ever come Home to you since?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hinton. No.</p>
               <p>Mr. Adams About the Beginning of July last, Mr. Lyford sent a Person to my House, to ask my Consent for his marrying this Girl: And afterwards he came himself. I told the Man, and him too, that I would not give it. I asked Lyford (when he came himself) whether he was not marry'd to Miss Hinton already? He said, yes, he was marry'd to her. Then, says I, what signifies my Consent, if you are marry'd already. I heard him own this second Marriage, at Mr. Ross's; and we had a Suit in Chancery, relating to some Part of Miss Hinton's Fortune; and when it was over, Lyford came and demanded the Writings in Right of his Wife. After this, we heard he was marry'd to another Woman, and we got Certificates from the Ministers of the Churches, where he had been marry'd: Upon which we sent to Miss Hinton, to desire her to come to us alone, for we had something to communicate to her, at Mr. Ross's House; but her Husband and she came together, and Mr. Gibson happen'd to come in just before them. When the Prisoner and his Wife came in, we desired her to walk into another Room, and there we shew'd her the Certificates; then we called him in, and Miss Hinton charg'd him with being marry'd to another Woman; he deny'd it; and upon that, we shew'd him the Certificates - why, says he, what are they to me? You may bring twenty of them, if you please. She fell a Crying, and call'd him Names, and he said - what signifies it? I have no other Wife in the World but you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Councel. I apprehend, that this Evidence is not to be received; and that in a Case of Felony, so penal, and ignominious as this is, the best Proof ought to be brought to support the Charge. I have been concern'd in many Prosecutions on this Statute, and I submit it to the Court, whether the second Wife is not the most competent Witness, and whether she was not always call'd, to prove the second Marriage And the Reason of it is - that when there happens to be any Dispute about the Identity of a Marriage, the Jury may be fully convinced, that the Person accused, is the very same Person who did the Prejudice, nor justifiable by Law. And because the second Wife is not a legal Wife, she is always admitted an Evidence. The second Wife, in this Case, can't be mistaken; if they had produced her, she might have said - This was the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173710120019"></xptr> Man that actually married me at Paddington, and then this corroborating Evidence would have come in well. I apprehend a Man's Calling a Woman - his Love, - and his Dear, - and his Honey, are Circumstances not to be depended upon; and that on this Penal Statute, if there is a Possibility of having positive Evidence, no circumstantial and bare presumptive Evidence ought to be admitted; for it may happen, that two People may go and be married in the Names of two other Persons, and take ten or twelve People to be present, and it may happen that these very Persons may be call'd upon to prove a Marriage upon the People whose Names had been made use of; they can come and say, - I believe such Persons were married, and at such a Place, because I was present, and heard two Persons of such Names married. In this Case the Prosecutors have it in their Power to produce the second Wife, and I submit it, whether a second Marriage has ever been proved without the Evidence of the second Wife.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pros. My Brother has no Evidence to give in Behalf of his Client, and so he has only a mind to give him a Speech. <rs id="t17371012-26-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17371012-26-punish118" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-punish118" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371012-26-punish118" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371012-26-defend197 t17371012-26-punish118"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
