<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17371207-3">
               <interp inst="t17371207-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371207-3" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371207-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17371207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17371207-3" type="date" value="17371207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17371207-3-off14-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-defend38 t17371207-3-off14 t17371207-3-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>5. 
               <persName id="t17371207-3-defend38" type="defendantName">
                  John
                   otherwise 
                  <rs id="t17371207-3-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-defend38 t17371207-3-alias-1"></join>Samuel</rs> Bugden<interp inst="t17371207-3-defend38" type="surname" value="otherwise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-defend38" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17371207-3-defloc13">Allhallows Barkin</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17371207-3-defloc13" type="placeName" value="Allhallows Barkin"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17371207-3-defloc13" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-defend38 t17371207-3-defloc13"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17371207-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Watch, value 3 l a gold Ring with 2 small diamonds, value 20 s. a gold enamelled Ring, value 10 s. a Shirt, value 10 s. a Guinea, two half Guineas, 2 Portugal Pieces, value 36 s. each, a quarter Moidore, a French Crown, value 4 s. and 23 Shillings in Money, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17371207-3-victim40" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Brooks 
                        <interp inst="t17371207-3-victim40" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371207-3-victim40" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17371207-3-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-off14 t17371207-3-victim40"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17371207-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">Nov. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-off14 t17371207-3-cd15"></join>.</p>
               <p>Francis Brooks. My Lord, and Gentlemen of the Jury! I live in <placeName id="t17371207-3-crimeloc16">Thames-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17371207-3-crimeloc16" type="placeName" value="Thames-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17371207-3-crimeloc16" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-off14 t17371207-3-crimeloc16"></join> against the Custom-house, and <rs id="t17371207-3-viclabel17" type="occupation">keep a publick House</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-victim40 t17371207-3-viclabel17"></join>. The Prisoner came to my House the 1st of Nov. in the Morning, before I came down from my Chamber, he asked for me as readily as if he had known me. When I came to him, he bid me - Good-Morrow, and asked me if I knew him? I told him no. I know you, says he, and the last Time I was with you, I drank half a pint of Wine with you. I said, I did not remember it, and I went away<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173712070003"></xptr> from him, but he followed me, and requested I would drink half a pint with him now. I told him I was not well, and Wine was like Physic to me; but he insisted upon my drinking with him, and called for half a pint of mulled Wine and a Toast, telling me it would do me no Harm. While we were drinking, he told me that one Hall, who belongs to the Custom-house, brought him acquainted with me. We sent for Mr. Hall, and he came to us, and the Prisoner told him he was Master of a Yarmouth Vessel now; that he had had the Misfortune to have been concerned in the Smuggling Way, but thro' the Interest of a Gentleman he got off, and now he was to live honestly. Then he told me he had run from Yarmouth to the Pool with his Vessel in 30 Hours, (which was an extraordinary Run) and that he was a little drowsy, and he wished I would let him lie down upon a Bed, and if my Cabbin-Coy comes to ask for me, bid him stay. The Prisoner being well drest, I call'd my Maid Patience, and bid her go up Stairs, and lock my Door, and the Lodger's Doors, and then lay such a Bed straight for the Master of the Ship to lie down. When she had done as I ordered, and had given me the Keys, I sent John Burges to shew the Prisoner the Bed on which he was to lie down, 'twas up 3 pair of Stairs, but the Goods that I lost were in a Cupboard in my Chamber up 2 pair of Stairs. He staid but a very little while above, not a quarter of an hour, when he came down he told me he had been restless, and I believe that was true enough, for he had been at Work all the Time. I missed the Things in about a quarter of an Hour after he was gone, and found the Cupboard in my Chamber broke. I had put Money in it while he was in the House, but it was taken away, and a Silver Watch, and 2 mourning Rings, one of which had 2 Sparks on each side of the Cypher. He took likewise three Notes of Hand for about 25 l. these he owned he flung away. The Money I lost amounts to much about 9 l. I no sooner found I was robb'd but I requested my Customers to go some one Way, and some another, to search bad Houses for the Prisoner, and in 2 Hours and a half he was taken. I charged him with the Robbery, and he fell down on his knees and begg'd Mercy. He owned he had open'd two Doors with a Knife, and the Cupboard Door with a pair of Scissars. We carried him before Sir William Billers, and there my Shirt was taken from his Back, and all the Money was found upon him within 30 s. I did not make use of any Promises of Favour to get this Confession from him, - 'twas all his own, and done generously.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17371207-3-person41">
                  Patience 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17371207-3-person41" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-person41" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-person41" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Master (on the Day this happen'd) order'd me to go up and lock the Lodger's Doors, and the Door of his Chamber, where the Cupboard was. I did so, and push'd the Door with my Knee to see if they were fast: Then I laid the Bedcloths smooth in Mr. Bennet's Room, and came down and put the Keys in the Bar. Then the Prisoner went up to sleep, and staid above Stairs about three quarters of an Hour. I did not know what was in the Cupboard, but I took Notice it was lock'd before I shut the Chamber Door.</p>
               <p>Samuel Wall, Constable. I was charged with the Prisoner on the 1st of November at Wapping Wall, and I brought him with a Pair of Oars to the Prosecutor's House. The Goods were taken from him in the Boat, and I have them here to produce. Burges taxed him with robbing Mr. Brooks and he own'd it directly, and gave us the Money and Rings. The Watch was in his Pocket, and the Rings upon his Finger which he return'd with 7 l. 3 s. 9 d. in Money, all which he said he had taken from Mr. Brooks.</p>
               <p>Brooks. This is my Watch: I have had it these 20 Years, and these are my Rings: One of them was made for my Wife's Mourning, and the other for my Son's. This French Crown, I brought from France. These are the Things I lost.</p>
               <p>Constable. Here's a Shirt I took off his Back before Sir 
               <persName id="t17371207-3-person42">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17371207-3-person42" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-person42" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Brooks. I believe it to be mine, - 'twas made abroad. I have the Fellow to it, now upon my Back</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am a <rs id="t17371207-3-deflabel18" type="occupation">Sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-defend38 t17371207-3-deflabel18"></join>, and have not been at Brooks's House since last Summer. I am a perfect Stranger to all this.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17371207-3-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17371207-3-punish20" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17371207-3-punish20" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17371207-3-defend38 t17371207-3-punish20"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
