<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380518-31">
               <interp inst="t17380518-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-31" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-31" type="date" value="17380518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-31-off152-c168" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-defend240 t17380518-31-off152 t17380518-31-verdict156"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-31-off152-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-defend242 t17380518-31-off152 t17380518-31-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>35, 36. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Arthur
                      O'Hara
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend240" type="surname" value="O'Hara"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend240" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Tobin 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend242" type="surname" value="Tobin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17380518-31-defloc151">St. George's Hannover-Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-defloc151" type="placeName" value="St. George's Hannover-Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-defloc151" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-defend240 t17380518-31-defloc151"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-defend242 t17380518-31-defloc151"></join>, were indicted with 
               <persName id="t17380518-31-person243">
                  Rose 
                  Plunkett 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person243" type="surname" value="Plunkett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person243" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (not taken) for <rs id="t17380518-31-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380518-31-victim245" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Claridge 
                        <interp inst="t17380518-31-victim245" type="surname" value="Claridge"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-31-victim245" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380518-31-victim245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-off152 t17380518-31-victim245"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him, a Silver Watch,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180018"></xptr> two brass Seals, and a brass Key, value 5 l. a silk Handkerchief, value 6 d. and five Shillings in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380518-31-cd153" type="crimeDate">April 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-off152 t17380518-31-cd153"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Claridge. I was going to my Master's Stables, on the 28th of April, about 10 at Night, and under the Duke of Devorshire's Wall, I was attack'd by two Men and a Woman One of the Men put a Knife to my Breast, and said, If I offer'd to disturb them, they would stab me. Then the Woman came up while they held me, and took my Watch, 5 s. and a Handkerchief. When she had robb'd me, one of the Men still held me, while his Companion and Woman got off, I scuffled with him, but he got away from me, and ran away. To the best of my Knowledge, the Prisoners are the Men, but I can't swear positively to them. I advertised the Watch, and it was brought me again by Mr. Seddon, the Man that made it. This is my Watch.</p>
               <p>Mr. Seddon One 
               <persName id="t17380518-31-person246">
                  Harry 
                  Grubb 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person246" type="surname" value="Grubb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person246" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought this Watch to me, the 1st of May; it was advertised to be left with me.</p>
               <p>Grubb, Pawnbroker. On Saturday the 29th of April, the two Prisoners came to me with the Watch, and wanted to borrow 40 s. upon it; (I live in St. James's-Market) O Hara is a <rs id="t17380518-31-deflabel154" type="occupation">Chairman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-defend240 t17380518-31-deflabel154"></join>, and plies there; I asked him who was the Owner of the Watch? He told me it was Tobin's, who then appear'd like a Sailor. I asked Tobin where he bought it? He said, he bought it of a Mate of a Ship at Wapping. Then I asked him who it was made by? And O Hara immediately answer'd, - by Seddon, at St. James's, who was his particular Friend. Upon this I lent 40 s. upon it. This was on Saturday the 29th of April, and on Monday Morning, seeing the Watch advertised, I carry'd it to Mr. Seddon, and he said it was the same Watch which had been lost. He offer'd me the three Guineas that was was offer'd as the Reward in the Advertisement; but I took no more than what I had lent upon it, and told him, I could help him to one of the Men that brought it to me. It was pawn'd in Tobin's Name, and O Hara averr'd it was his (Tobin's) Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-person247">
                  Samuel 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person247" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person247" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Pawnbroker's Man, confirm'd his Master's Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-person248">
                  Judith 
                  Dalton 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person248" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person248" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday, the 28th of April, I went to Peter Street, to see Tobin and his Wife; O Hara and one Brooks was there, and we all din'd upon Mutton and Broth. Between 7 and 8 at Night, O Hara, and his Wife, Tobin, and his Wife, and I, went out to take a Walk. When we came near Piccadilly, 
               <persName id="t17380518-31-person249">
                  Rose 
                  Tobin 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person249" type="surname" value="Tobin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person249" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the Wife) pick'd up a Gentleman and carry'd him into a House; O Hara and Tobin follow'd them in, but I staid at the Door till they came out; and Rose said, she had got half a Crown. Then we all went on, and met this Man (Claridge) in a velvet Cap; Tobin's Wife and I, and the two Prisoners went after him; and when we came up to him, O Hara took hold of him, and held him, while I took the Watch out of his Pocket. I saw no Money; I can't tell who took that.</p>
               <p>Claridge. I had a Cap on that Night I was robb'd.</p>
               <p>Dalton. When I had got the Watch, one of them held him, while Tobin's Wife and I ran away to Clancey's House; and we had no sooner got in, but the Prisoners came in likewise; we sat down, and I gave Tobin the Watch, and Clancey open'd it, that Tobin might look at it. I did not mind it much myself; so I can't be positive whether this is the Watch or not.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Please to ask her where this Watch was taken?</p>
               <p>Dalton. Just by a big Door, within some Rails, in <placeName id="t17380518-31-crimeloc155">Piccadilly</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Piccadilly"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-31-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-31-off152 t17380518-31-crimeloc155"></join>; but I am a Stranger to the Place.</p>
               <p>Tobin's Wife stood at a little Distance, when I robb'd him.</p>
               <p>Claridge. I was surpriz'd, and so saw but one Woman.</p>
               <p>- Clancey. I keep the two Blue Posts in Compton Street, St. Ann's. On the 28th of April, at Night, Dalton (the Evidence) and the two Prisoners were at my House, with their Wives, pretty late. After they had drank about 1 s. or 14 d. in Liquor, O Hara and his Wife went away, but Tobin and Dalton. About half an Hour after the Prisoner (O Hara) and his Wife were gone, Dalton pull'd out the Watch, and I open'd it. I ask'd her whose it was, and she told me 'twas her Husband's.</p>
               <p>Dalton. I did not produce the Watch till they were gone, because O Hara was not willing his Wife should know what was taken that Night. Tobin felt the Watch in my Hand, immediately after I had taken it; and O Hara knew I had got it when we were all together at Clancey's. The next Morning, Tobin and O Hara went to pawn the Watch; when they return'd, they told me they had got but a Guinea and a half upon it. Please to ask Clancey if Tobin did not deliver him a Knife?</p>
               <p>Clancey. He deliver'd me this Knife, about a Week ago, last Tuesday. (A very long sharp pointed Clasp Knife) This is the Knife.</p>
               <p>Claridge. Twas was just such a Knife as this, one of them held to my Breast.</p>
               <p>Dalton. Some Time after this, we all quarrel'd, and I went before a Justice and made a Discovery.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180019"></xptr>Mr. Blackerby. 
               <persName id="t17380518-31-person250">
                  Judith 
                  Dalton 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person250" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person250" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came one Morning before me; and upon her Evidence, I issu'd Warrants against the Prisoners. She gave an Account of the Fact perfectly consistent with that she gives now. That very Morning Tobin came to me, to let me know that he receiv'd the Watch from her, and upon hearing the whole, I thought it my Duty to commit him, and his Companion.</p>
               <p>Tobin's Defence. Dalton gave me the Watch, and desired me to pawn it for her.</p>
               <p>O Hara. Tobin told me Dalton had got him to pawn a Watch for her, and I only went along with him to the Pawnbroker's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-person251">
                  Lawrence 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person251" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person251" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I come for Tobin. He desired me to find out where Dalton lodged, for he said his Life depended upon it. I knew where she lodged, for I met her once in Peter Street, and she was enquiring her Way to her Lodgings in Holborn, I have no more to say, - only as I was going Home with her, I met Tobin and O Hara in the Street, and one Luttwych was with them. 'Tis not every one that is endowed with Sense; if I had, I should have left Dalton with O Hara and Tobin, and not have gone Home with her to her Lodgings. This I think was at Night, the 29th of April, when Dalton met with her Acquaintance, we all went together to an Alehouse, next Door to Justice Marget's, in Castle Street. - I can't tell the Sign, but I know by their own Expressions, that Tobin's Wife was there, and I left them all there, and went Home with Dalton to her Lodging. I am not so ignorant, but I know this was the 29th of April.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-person252">
                  Darby 
                  Mac Connor 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person252" type="surname" value="Mac Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person252" type="given" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday the 28th of May, - April I mean, between 7 and 8 o'Clock, I was at Clancey's, and saw the two Prisoners come in between 8 and 9. They drank about 4 Quarts of Beer, and had a Penn'orth of Bread and Cheese, and a Ha'p'orth of Onions. I saw no Body with them. I came in with Mr. Dod, and ask'd them to drink with me.</p>
               <p>Clancey. I remember this Man came in that Night, but I can't tell whether the Prisoner came in about that Hour, - we have vast Business, - I can't tell whether they drank with Connor or not, but I am sure O Hara's Wife was with him</p>
               <p>Connor I kept Company with the two Prisoners 'till between 11 and 12 o'Clock and then the Witness Dalton and Tobin's Wife came in.</p>
               <p>Clancey. The Prisoners Wives were both in their Company.</p>
               <p>- Anticker. Connor was in Company with the two Prisoners and their Wives. They came in about 9 o'Clock, and staid till past 11.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-31-person253">
                  Richard 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17380518-31-person253" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person253" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with Connor that Night at Clancey's; the Prisoners came in and eat and drank with us till the Watchman went Eleven, and then Dalton came in with O Hara's and Tobin's Wife. Dalton called for Liquor, and made the Prisoners come into their Company; they sat some Time, and then O Hara, and his Wife, and Tobin's Wife, went away, and Tobin himself was going along with us, but Dalton called him back and made him stay, so we went out and saw no more of them.</p>
               <p>- Sample, one who keeps a Publick House at Charing-Cross, and one Lewsly, never heard O Hara charged with Dishonesty before. Two others said the same of Tobin. Both <rs id="t17380518-31-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-31-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
