<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-77">
               <interp inst="t17341204-77" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-77" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-77" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-77" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-77-off373-c399" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-77-defend569 t17341204-77-off373 t17341204-77-verdict376"></join>
         
               <p>74. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-77-defend569" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Campion 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-77-defend569" type="surname" value="Campion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-defend569" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-defend569" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-77-off373" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-off373" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-off373" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing a Pair of Pattins, an Apron, and a Handkerchief
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-77-victim571" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Nutsford 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-77-victim571" type="surname" value="Nutsford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-victim571" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-victim571" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-77-off373 t17341204-77-victim571"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17341204-77-cd374" type="crimeDate">Aug. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-77-off373 t17341204-77-cd374"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-77-person572">
                  Abigal 
                  Nutsford 
               <interp inst="t17341204-77-person572" type="surname" value="Nutsford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-person572" type="given" value="Abigal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-person572" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a poor Woman, and sell a few Greens; and I selling a few Greens; and such a matter, and a little small Beer and a Dram, and the like; says my Husband one Day - for my Husband you must know is a <rs id="t17341204-77-viclabel375" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-77-victim571 t17341204-77-viclabel375"></join>, and he was going out - and says he to me, Tab, says he, If my Master should come, save a Jobb for me; and this Creature, Mary Campion owing me three Pence, she said as how she would clean my Room for it, or else she would never pay me. Whereof I thought I might as well let her do it; and so I goes out, and leaves her to clean this Room: and while I was gone, she pulls open my Drawers, and takes my things, and breaks me as much Crockery as comes to 3 or 4 Shillings - And when I came home, she was gone, and my Child said; Mammy, she has put your Apron in her Pocket,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040039"></xptr> and so set a good while there was no such thing as finding her, high nor low; but at last, I meets with her a going along the Street, and she had got my Pattins on - I can safely swear it, and I have but three Weeks to go. - And having these Pattins on; Mistress, says I, these are my Pattins. Well, says she, and what then? Why then pray give them me, says I: No, says she, I'll give ye none of them - Nap my Cuckold for 'em - And now she pretends truly, that I had lent her the Pattins: but if I had, why did not she bring them home again? Pray tell me that: and then I desire to know what Satisfaction I must have for my Crockery-Ware that she broke; and more than that, she proffer'd this Man Mr. Shaw, to give him a Dram out of my Bottle.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Why don't you pay me for washing your Smock? - You know that while I was a washing it, you was forced to stand without one.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Well, and a good Shift too.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Aye, so it was, for them that can make a Shift, without a Shift.</p>
               <p>Pros. You made a Shift to walk off with my Pattins - Pray what did you keep out of the way for? If I did not know myself to be a Thief, what occasion had I to keep out of the way?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She lent me the Pattins to clean her Room, and as I was cleaning it, I happen'd to throw down her Crockery-Ware: and for that she stopt my Broom and my Child's Frock which I had left behind me. And so when she met me afterwards, and asked me for her Pattins, I told her, if she'd give me my Broom and my Frock, I'd give her the Pattins.</p>
               <p>Pros. It's no such Thing; she said nothing, but, Nap my Cuckold! Nap my Cuckold! But howsomever, when her Cuckold came the next Day, and asked for her Things, I let him have 'em.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-77-verdict376" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-77-verdict376" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
