<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-5">
               <interp inst="t17380628-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-5" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-5" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-5-off26-c59" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-defend70 t17380628-5-off26 t17380628-5-verdict30"></join>
         
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-5-defend70" type="defendantName">
                     Isaac 
                     George 
                  <interp inst="t17380628-5-defend70" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-defend70" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-defend70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            (a Blackamoor) was indicted for <rs id="t17380628-5-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-5-victim72" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Gravener 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-5-victim72" type="surname" value="Gravener"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-5-victim72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-5-victim72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-off26 t17380628-5-victim72"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Pair of Silver-bow'd Scissars, value 5 s. a Silver Spatula, value 4 s. a Silver Probe, value 6 d. a Steel crooked Needle, value 1 d a Fish skin Case with Silver Hinges and Clasps, value 10 s. 6 d. three Lancers, with Tortoiseshell Scales, value 3 s. a Gum Lancet, value 1 s. a black Shagreen Case, value 5 s. a Silver Seal, value 2 s. 6 d. and 7 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-5-cd27" type="crimeDate">April 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-off26 t17380628-5-cd27"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gravener. As I return'd from <placeName id="t17380628-5-crimeloc28">Endfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-5-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Endfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-5-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-off26 t17380628-5-crimeloc28"></join>, on Sunday Night, the 30th of April, the Prisoner and another Man attack'd me in the Highway. They struck at me with their Clubs, and my Horse threw me. I got up, and ran away from them, about 150 or 200 Yards towards <placeName id="t17380628-5-crimeloc29">Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-5-crimeloc29" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-5-crimeloc29" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-off26 t17380628-5-crimeloc29"></join> Town, but happening to fall in a Cart-rut, the Prisoner and his Accomplice overtook me, and robb'd me of the Things mention'd in the Indictment, they likewise took from me 6 d. and some Half-pence. The Prisoner was the Man that seiz'd me first, and he and his Comrade rifled me. When I fell from my Horse I lost my Hat, so after I had been rifled, I desired them to let me have my Hat; they said, they did not desire that, and I went back with them, to the Place where I fell, and found it, the two Men guarding me all the Time. The Reason of my desiring to go back was, that I thought some Body might come by, as we were going up the Road, and then I would have endeavour'd to have taken them. I am sure the Prisoner is one of the Men that robb'd me, - he is a Black, and 'twas he that walk'd on my right Hand, when I went back to look for my Hat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing of this Affair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gravener. When I first saw the Prisoner in Bridewell, I asked him if he knew me? He said, - No, he never saw me (to his Knowledge) before in his Life. I asked him if he could give any Account how he had spent his Time last Monday? Yes, says he, I have been a Month in the Hospital, and was discharged from thence about a Fortnight ago, and the People of the Hospital can be Witnesses for me. <rs id="t17380628-5-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17380628-5-punish31" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-5-punish31" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-5-defend70 t17380628-5-punish31"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
