<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-25">
               <interp inst="t17360721-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-25" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-25" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-25-off123-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-defend197 t17360721-25-off123 t17360721-25-verdict128"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-25-off125-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-defend197 t17360721-25-off125 t17360721-25-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>27. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-25-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Kelsey 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-25-defend197" type="surname" value="Kelsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-defend197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-defend197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-25-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-25-victim199" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Winston 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim199" type="surname" value="Winston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him one Guinea
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-25-cd124" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off123 t17360721-25-cd124"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off125 t17360721-25-cd124"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted, for <rs id="t17360721-25-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-25-victim201" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hussey 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim201" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim201" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-25-victim201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's High-way, &amp;c. and taking from him a Guinea
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-25-cd126" type="crimeDate">June the 30th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off123 t17360721-25-cd126"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off125 t17360721-25-cd126"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Winston. I was coming yesterday was three Weeks from Gloucestershire to London, in the Cirencester Coach, and about <placeName id="t17360721-25-crimeloc127">Knights-bridge, near Hyde Park Corner</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-25-crimeloc127" type="placeName" value="Knights-bridge, near Hyde Park Corner"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-25-crimeloc127" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off123 t17360721-25-crimeloc127"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-off125 t17360721-25-crimeloc127"></join>, three Fellows stopped the Coach and demanded our Money, Watches and Buckles; I gave the Fellow that put his Hand into the Coach a Guinea; another Gentleman gave them a Guinea and some Silver, and a third Person gave them more Silver. After this, they talked of taking us out of the Coach, I said they had got all we had, and away they went. I told the Watch and the Neighbourhood we had been robbed, and they pursued them, and that Man at the Bar was taken. Next Morning he was carried before the Lord Carpenter and Justice Ray, at Hanover-Square, and they bound him over. I can't take on me to say he was one of the three, for it was past 11 o'Clock at Night. He was taken by the Description we gave of the Robbers, that they were little Fellows, young, and unused to that Way. They were very civil, no Oaths nor Swearing, but, Gentlemen if you don't deliver, we must take you out of the Coach.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210010"></xptr>Mr. Hussey. I can give but the same Account that Mr. Winston has given. We were attack'd by three Foot pads, one held a Pistol to my Breast and demanded my Money; I gave him a Guinea and some Silver, I cannot be positive how much, nor can I swear to the Prisoner. He who took the Money from us, went a little Distance and made a Speech, telling us, as they had not done us an Injury, and a Necessity obliged them to do what they did, he hoped we would not pursue them: but his Companions call'd him away, and bid the Coachman drive on. By the Description we gave to the Watchmen, the Prisoner was taken, and carried next Morning before the Lord Carpenter, at the Vestry-Room, in Hanover Square, and sent from thence to Prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-25-person202">
                  George 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17360721-25-person202" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person202" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going past 11 o'Clock, and a Gentleman came up, and sud, he was afraid of being robbed, there were three Foot-pads had stopped a Coach in the Road. He said one of them had on a Checquer'd Shirt, dark brown Cloaths, and a flapped Hat. I ordered the other Watchman to put out his Light, thinking if they saw our Lights, they would not come near us. In about a quarter of an Hour they came down the Road, I stooped down, that they might not see me; so, says I, they are coming, to my Companion, and as soon as the Prisoner came up to us, I seized him fast by the Breast; but while we were attacking him, the other two got off. We went up to the Turn-pike to see what Coach it was that had been robbed, and we found it was the Sissiter ( Cirencester ) Coach, so we went to the Bell-Savage Inn, and found out Mr. Hussey. I did not see the Coach attack'd, for it was not near the Houses, but so much as it was described upon him ( according to the Description) he must be the Man. He had these Surgeon's Instruments about him, and this Stock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-25-person203">
                  William 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17360721-25-person203" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman. We had an Account of this Coach being robbed by three Foot Pads; two of them were described very plainly, by a Man who jumped down from behind it, when the Fact was committed; so we stopped the Prisoner at the Bar, and the others ran away. He was searched at the Lodge at the Park Gate; we found some Money upon him, but not much, and two or three Shagreen Cases to hold Lancers, and this Stock, but I did not see any Gold about him. The Robbery was committed about half a Mile beyond my Stand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-25-person204">
                  John 
                  Stokes 
               <interp inst="t17360721-25-person204" type="surname" value="Stokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable that Night the Prisoner was brought to the Watch house; the next Morning I carried him before the Lord Carpenter, and Mr. Justice Ray, and he confessed the Fact in my hearing, and the Confession was taken in writing, and was signed by the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Parry I saw this Confession taken, and the Prisoner signed it, after it had been read over to him: He gave an Account where those, who were concerned with him in this Robbery might be taken, but they have not yet been found</p>
               <p>The Examination.</p>
               <p>Middlesex. The Examination of John Kelsey taken before us, two of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace for the said County, and Liberty of Westminster, July the 1st, 1736.</p>
               <p>Who being charged with stealing two Guineas from Mrs. Winston and Hussey, and putting them in fear, near Knight's Bridge, confesseth and saith, that he met with Rigby and Cooper at the Fountain Ale-house, and that he staid there with them 'till about three o'Clock: then they went to the Angel near Queen's Square, and drank a Pint of Beer, and from thence to a Cook's Shop, and having agreed to rob the first Coach they should meet, saith, that about eleven o'Clock at Night they stopped this Coach, that Rigby demanded the Money, Watches, and Buckles of the Passengers, and this Examinant put his Hat into the Coach, and received two Guineas, five Shillings in Silver, and two Pence Half-penny; that he gave Rigby the Money, and they went into the Fields and divided it; he saith, they then returned into the Road again, were pursued, and he this Examinant was taken by the Watchmen He farther saith, that last Saturday they robbed the Salisbury Coach near Kensington, and took from the Passengers 18 s. That he was concerned with Rigby and Cooper<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210011"></xptr> in robbing the Bury Coach, in Stratford Road, and that he this Examinant had 9 s. for his Share.</p>
               <p>Signed 
               <persName id="t17360721-25-person205">
                  John 
                  Kelsey 
               <interp inst="t17360721-25-person205" type="surname" value="Kelsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not in my right Senses when I made that Confession, and was frighted into it.</p>
               <p>Several Persons appeared to the Prisoner's Character, most of whom, had known him from his Cradle; and all of them swore they never heard ill of him before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-25-person206">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Kelsy 
               <interp inst="t17360721-25-person206" type="surname" value="Kelsy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person206" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, the Prisoner at the Bar is my Child, and has always behaved well, and been a dutiful Child, and has lived very regularly. I cannot speak, my Lord, as to particular Company, I am at this time a distressed Widow; I know not Rigby, nor Cooper, - have Mercy upon my Child. <rs id="t17360721-25-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17360721-25-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-25-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-25-defend197 t17360721-25-punish129"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
