<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360225-13">
               <interp inst="t17360225-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-13" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-13" type="date" value="17360225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360225-13-off85-c84" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-defend109 t17360225-13-off85 t17360225-13-verdict90"></join>
         
               <p>17. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-defend109" type="defendantName">
                     Michael 
                     Hughes 
                  <interp inst="t17360225-13-defend109" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-defend109" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-defend109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17360225-13-defloc84">St. George Hanover Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-13-defloc84" type="placeName" value="St. George Hanover Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-13-defloc84" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-defend109 t17360225-13-defloc84"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360225-13-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360225-13-victim111" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Pearce 
                        <interp inst="t17360225-13-victim111" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-13-victim111" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-13-victim111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-off85 t17360225-13-victim111"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in <placeName id="t17360225-13-crimeloc86">St. James's Park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-crimeloc86" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-crimeloc86" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-off85 t17360225-13-crimeloc86"></join>, putting him in Fear, and taking from him one Cloth Coat, a Wastcoat a pair of Breeches, a Handkerchief, a pair of Buckles, 2 Knives, and one Brass Seal
            </rs>, the <rs id="t17360225-13-cd87" type="crimeDate">16th of this Instant</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-off85 t17360225-13-cd87"></join>.</p>
               <p>George Pearce. I was going Home to Knights bridge on Monday Se'nnight, about 7 or 8 o'Clock, and upon Constitution-hill, I met 2 Men, who took the Things mention'd in the Indictment from me: They were wrapp'd up in a Handkerchief, and were my own. Mr. Grimes hit me with an Oaken Stick, made two of my Teeth loose, and cut my Gum: The Moon shone upon the Snow, and made it very light: Grimes was before me, and his Companion behind me. Grimes led me about 100 Yards out of the way, took my Things, rifled me, and then ty'd my Hands and my Legs together with my own Garters: They left me sitting within a Yard and a half of the Pond, by the Wilderness, and told me, they would either release me in a Quarter of an Hour, or bring me more Company. When they were gone, I got up with some Difficulty, and jumped along to the Keeper's House, where I was unty'd. I don't know how the Discovery was made of the Prisoner: I suppose the Robbery being put in the Papers occasion'd it: They sent for me when Grimes and the Prisoner were before the Justice, and I was order'd to prosecute the Prisoner. I can't swear to the Prisoner; he kept always behind me.</p>
               <p>Grimes. otherwise Graham. The Prisoner had been a <rs id="t17360225-13-deflabel88" type="occupation">Gentleman's Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-defend109 t17360225-13-deflabel88"></join>; my Circumstances he knew were low, and therefore he from Time to Time endeavoured to seduce me to these Courses: He perswaded me to go out with him 3 or 4 nights together, but we had no manner of Success in our Way. Thursday, Friday, Saturday, and Sunday we took nothing but on Monday Night we went round Hyde-Park Corner, and met nothing that would do: Come, says he, let us go down Constitution-Hill, perhaps we may make something there. I went with him, and there we met this young Man, and took from him the Things mentioned, ty'd up in a Handkerchief, and ty'd his Hands and Feet: The Seals, I believe, were lost; the Buckles I know nothing of; but as to the Knives, one of them is in Court, the other is at the Justice's. It was I who took hold of the Prosecutor; the Prisoner had a Pistol. I had only a Stick; he kept behind in order I suppose, to conceal himself. He bid me attack the Man; I did, and giving him a Stroke in the Mouth with my Stick, for fear he should be Rusty, I made him come out of the Road towards the Pond.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-person112">
                  George 
                  Stringer 
               <interp inst="t17360225-13-person112" type="surname" value="Stringer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person112" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Accomplice Grimes told me, it was the Prisoner who was at the Door, when another Man brought the Coat and Wastcoat to me to pawn. I lent 4 s. upon them, about 9 o'Clock at Night, the 16th of February. I can't swear to the Prisoner; but it was such a sort of a Man, and about his Size.</p>
               <p>Grimes The Prisoner carry'd them to pawn the very Night we took them: Upon my Oath he was the Man, and I had 2 Shillings of the Money.</p>
               <p>Constable. Last Friday Grimes came to my House, and told me, he desired to go before a Justice, to make himself an Evidence; but stay a little, says he, and the Man will come whom you are to take. Accordingly the Prisoner came and enquired for Grimes; he immediately charged me with him, and before Justice Mitford, he made his Information of this Robbery. When Grimes charged me with him, he seem'd surpriz'd; and cry'd O Mr. Grimes. I did not think you would have serv'd me so! we search'd the Prisoner, and found some Things upon him, which are at the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173602250010"></xptr> Justices, and this Knife was taken out of his Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-person113">
                  Robert 
                  Fish 
               <interp inst="t17360225-13-person113" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person113" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when this Knife and some Gun Powder and some Flints were taken out of his Pockets; he desired us to let him go, and cry'd, O Mr. Grimes! have you brought me to this at last!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-person114">
                  Alexander 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17360225-13-person114" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person114" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can only prove the Prisoner and Grimes to have been acquainted; they lay together 3 Nights, about a Fortnight ago. I keep a Publick Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. You sell a Dram, I suppose.</p>
               <p>Graham. Yes, my Lord, I sell a Dram of Gin, and the like.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I would ask, whether Grimes has not been supplied with Money in New-Prison; and whether he has not had Money given him to swear my Life away?</p>
               <p>Constable. Grimes told me in New-Prison he was starving, and I lent him 2 s. that's all the Matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-person115">
                  Mary 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17360225-13-person115" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person115" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Laundress. and live by Golden-square; I came here on the Prisoner's behalf On last Monday Se'nnight I got the Prisoner to write me out a Bill for Washing, he did, and I desired him to come to Supper with me: He came about 6 o'Clock that Night, and staid with me till almost 10.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know it was Monday Se'nnight?</p>
               <p>Morgan. I know it was that Day, because I wanted the Bill to be wrote out.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose Bill was that?</p>
               <p>Morgan. One Mr Sale's.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a Date to that Bill?</p>
               <p>Morgan. Yes, the Day of the Month was to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you produce that Bill?</p>
               <p>Morgan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. 'Tis a little unlucky; because if Mr. Sale had been a Person of Reputation, this Circumstance would have been of Weight. - Pray where do you live?</p>
               <p>Morgan. At Mr. Humphrey's, a Cheesemonger, in the Garret, as high as I can go.</p>
               <p>Q. So the Prisoner was with you in the Garret from 6 to 10. Pray does any of Mr. Humphrey's People know any Thing of his being there?</p>
               <p>Morgan. I don't know that; there is an Entry, when the Shop is shut up for the Lodgers to go in and out through: When a House is full of Lodgers, they seldom take notice who comes to and fro.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Humphreys here?</p>
               <p>Morgan. No, if he was here, he could not but give me a very good Character. I washed the Prisoner's Linnen, when he served the Lord Southwell; and we went over to Holland, when his Lady went with the Princess of Orange; but as the Place did not agree with his Constitution, he came back to England.</p>
               <p>Another Woman. I am with Child, and speak nothing but Truth: This young Man at the Bar, was in this Gentlewoman's Room from 6 to 10. I lived with her, and know it was that Monday Night; I provided the Supper, and I am sure of it. I am with Child at this Instant of time.</p>
               <p>- Anderson. I lived with my Lord Southwell, when the Prisoner was my Fellow <rs id="t17360225-13-deflabel89" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-13-defend109 t17360225-13-deflabel89"></join>. He behaved very honestly, and when he returned from Holland, my Lord gave him a Character to two Places.</p>
               <p>Luttwich. I happened to be at Goodhall's (the Constable) at Dinner, when Grimes came in: He said he would go into a Back Room, and smoke a Pipe: In a very little time the Prisoner came and enquired for him, and Graimes called him out into the Entry.</p>
               <p>Grimes. I was in Mr. Goodhall's Parlour; when one came and told me the Prisoner enquir'd for me: I went to him and wink'd at the Person that call'd me, to go back and call Mr. Good-hall, that I might charge him: Then I went into a Room, and left the Prisoner in another; he followed me, but I took up my Pint and my Glass, and went into another, and I never went out to him afterwards.</p>
               <p>Constable. Grimes was called out of the Room, when the Prisoner came to ask for him; then they went into another Back Room, and presently Grimes sent for me, and charged me with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-13-person116">
                  Robert 
                  Fish 
               <interp inst="t17360225-13-person116" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person116" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Luttwich said to the Prisoner, you Rascal, have not I told you often, not to frequent such Company; and he desired him not to mention the Powder nor Flints. You Villain, says he to the Prisoner, have not I desired you to go with me to Chapel and hear Mass, and warned you against such Company?</p>
               <p>Luttwich. I did meet the Prisoner about a Fortnight ago, and would have had him gone with me to serve God, and not have gone to a Beer-house. I don't know, whether he said any Thing about the Flints and the Powder.</p>
               <p>One of the Jury Men desired Mr. Morgan and the other Woman might be asked a Question or two apart; one of them was ordered to withdraw.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173602250011"></xptr>Q. T, Morpan. What had you for Supper that Night the Prisoner was at your House?</p>
               <p>Morg. Breast of Mutton, Turnips, and Broth.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was Supper ready?</p>
               <p>Morg. About 9 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you doing till 9 o'Clock?</p>
               <p>Morg. I had been out, and the other Woman too; I came in about 6, and she likewise.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you drink?</p>
               <p>Morg. We drank small Beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you nothing but small Beer from 6 to 9?</p>
               <p>Morg. Nothing but one Bottle of small Beer all the Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Before, at, and after Supper, you had nothing but one Bottle of small Beer?</p>
               <p>Morg. Nothing more than one Bottle of small Beer; we did not drink any Thing till we went to Supper. She was ordered to withdraw, and the other called into Court.</p>
               <p>2d Woman. What Time o'Night was it you came home, last Monday Se'nnight?</p>
               <p>Woman. I was not out at all; I was at Home all Day, and all Night; my Partner was out some part of the Day, but she came Home about 4 o'Clock in the Afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time did the Prisoner come in?</p>
               <p>Woman. About 6, and went away at 10.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you pass the Time?</p>
               <p>Woman In a very good Manner; I was at my Plain Work, and he was reading a good Book.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink any Thing?</p>
               <p>Woman. We had a Pot of strong Beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Whence did you fetch it?</p>
               <p>Woman. From a Publick House at the next Door.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you fetch it?</p>
               <p>Woman. Not till we went to Supper; we had Breast of Mutton, Turnips, and Broth for Supper between 8 and 9 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you nothing else to drink all this Time?</p>
               <p>Woman. No.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you drink of this Strong Beer?</p>
               <p>Woman. Yes, I tasted it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Small Beer?</p>
               <p>Woman. No, none at all; we keep none in the House. <rs id="t17360225-13-verdict90" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-13-verdict90" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
