<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-6">
               <interp inst="t17370706-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-6" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-6" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-6-off28-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-defend63 t17370706-6-off28 t17370706-6-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-defend63" type="defendantName">
                     Martin 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-6-defend63" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-defend63" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-defend63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370706-6-defloc27">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-6-defloc27" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-6-defloc27" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-defend63 t17370706-6-defloc27"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-6-off28" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-off28" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-off28" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing eight Guineas, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-6-victim65" type="victimName">
                           Roger 
                           Applegarth 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-6-victim65" type="surname" value="Applegarth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-6-victim65" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-6-victim65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-off28 t17370706-6-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370706-6-cd29" type="crimeDate">June 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-off28 t17370706-6-cd29"></join>.</p>
               <p>Roger Applegarth. On the 28th of May last, I went into the Country, and left my <rs id="t17370706-6-deflabel30" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-defend63 t17370706-6-deflabel30"></join> (
               <persName id="t17370706-6-person66">
                  Martin 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person66" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person66" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) in my Chambers in <placeName id="t17370706-6-crimeloc31">New-Inn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="New-Inn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-off28 t17370706-6-crimeloc31"></join>. I had lock'd-up eight Guineas in my Scrutore, before I went from Home, and when I return'd, the Prisoner met me at the Door, and said, the Back of the Scrutore had been broke open. I asked him how it came: He told me he did not know; but in the Afternoon, when I examined him again, before two Gentlemen who are here, he confess'd he did it himself; that he broke it open the Night I left the Town, and took out three Guineas at that Time: On the Thursday following, he took out the other five. I asked him what he had done with the Money? He told me, he had laid out some of it in Cloaths; some of it he had spent, and thirty Shillings of it he had left in one Mrs. Wilkinson's Hands. I went next Morning to Mr.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060005"></xptr> Wilkinson's, and he said, he knew nothing of the Matter, but he would inquire of his Wife about it; and the next Day he brought me 22 s. 6 d. and told me, his Wife had laid out the rest of the Money for the Prisoner's Use.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask my Master if he found any thing upon me?</p>
               <p>C. He does not say he did: He says, you own'd the Fact.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If I did own it, it was unknown to me: They threaten'd my Life, and gave me Money to own it.</p>
               <p>A Witness I was at Mr. Applegarth's Chambers on Saturday the 4th of June, and he accused his Footboy of breaking his Scrutore, and taking out eight Guineas. After he had been examined, he confess'd, that he broke the Scrutore on the Saturday before, and took out three Guineas, and on the Friday following, he took out the other five He was asked, what he broke it open with: And he told us, he did it with the Pin that fasten'd the Window shutters The greatest Part of the Money, he said, he had spent; thirty Shillings he had laid out in Cloths; half a Guinea he had spent that Day Se'snight in Drink, and in treating his Companions, and a Guinea, he said, he had lodged in the Hands of Mr. Wilkinson. I asked him if there was any more there? And I think he said, there was some little Matter more there He was as fresh and sober, when he gave this Account, as he is now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They will take my Life away, if it be possible, tho' I know nothing at all of it. The 30 s. that Mrs Wilkinson had, was Money I had sav'd-up, and had given her to keep for me.</p>
               <p>A Witness. He fell on his Knees, and asked Pardon: He said, if his Master would forgive him, he would never do so any more, but would be a very faithful Servant for the future.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-person67">
                  Mary 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person67" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person67" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner gave me the Money to keep for him, 'till I had Opportunity to lay it out in Linnen for Shirts. He did not tell me how he came by it; he only desired me to keep it for him, lest he should spend it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he leave this Money with you?</p>
               <p>Mary Wilkinson. 'Twas the 1st of June, as near as I can guess; I never heard any Thing ill of him in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-person68">
                  Matthew 
                  Sloper 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person68" type="surname" value="Sloper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person68" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the Bar was my Servant and Mr. Applegarth's. On the 28th of May, Mr. Applegarth went into the Country, and I went out to spend the Evening. When I came Home, I found his Scrutore was removed, about a Foot from the Wainscot, and the Back of it was broke open. I look'd about the Room, to see if any Thing was missing; I saw nothing gone, unless 'twas any Thing out of the Bureau. When Mr. Applegarth return'd, I told him his Bureau had been broke, and he tax'd the Prisoner with it, and he confess'd he took the Money. He said, he broke open the Bureau, and took out three Guineas, the Saturday his Master went out of Town; and on the Thursday following, he took out five more. He own'd he did it with the Pin of the Window, and he fell upon his Knees and begg'd Pardon; he said, it was the first Fact that he was ever guilty off, and if he would forgive him, he would serve us honesty and faithfull for the future. I am in Chambers with Mrs. Applegarth, and the Prisoner was our Servant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-person69">
                  Thomas 
                  Eames 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person69" type="surname" value="Eames"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person69" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep an Academy by Red-lion-Square, and am Vestry-Clark of St. George the Maryr. I employed the Prisoner before he came to these Gentlemen, and since he had been with them likewise. I have left him to take Care of my House, with a great Charge; I have entrusted him for some Years, and within these two Months, but never miss'd any Thing: I have known him from a Child, and that was the Reason I confided in him in this Manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-person70">
                  John 
                  Shorey 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person70" type="surname" value="Shorey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person70" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my Kinsman: I have known him from his Infancy: He is as honest a Lad as any can be. He never wronged Man, Woman or Child of a Farthing in the World, to my Knowledge. Others were in the Chambers, and had the Keys, and I believe him Innocent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-6-person71">
                  Thomas 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17370706-6-person71" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person71" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner between two and three Years: He always behaved in a sober, civil Manner. I never saw him Master of above a Shilling in my Life. <rs id="t17370706-6-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370706-6-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-6-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-6-defend63 t17370706-6-punish33"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
