<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-37">
               <interp inst="t17360908-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-37" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-37" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-37-off156-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-defend236 t17360908-37-off156 t17360908-37-verdict161"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-37-off158-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-defend236 t17360908-37-off158 t17360908-37-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>44. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-defend236" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Warwick 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-37-defend236" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-defend236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-defend236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360908-37-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360908-37-victim238" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Sayer 
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim238" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim238" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of two in the Afternoon, and stealing a Bureau, value 40 s. 11 Chairs, value 35 s. a Stove Grate, value 30 s. 2 Pewter Dishes, value 2 s. 18 Pewter Plates, a Culender, 2 feather<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080012"></xptr> Beds, 3 Bolsters, 3 pair of Sheets, a Table Cloth, 6 Napkins, a Stew Pan, 2 Pictures, a Clock, and 2 Tables, the Goods of Thomas Sayer
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-37-cd157" type="crimeDate">April 25, 1734</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off156 t17360908-37-cd157"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off158 t17360908-37-cd157"></join>. </p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17360908-37-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch, value 16 l. a Diamond Ring, and 5 Holland Shirts, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360908-37-victim240" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Miller 
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim240" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim240" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-victim240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17360908-37-person241">
                        Thomas 
                        Sayer 
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person241" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-person241" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-37-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17360908-37-cd159" type="crimeDate">April 20, 1734</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off156 t17360908-37-cd159"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off158 t17360908-37-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-person242">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sayer 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person242" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person242" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of December, 1734. the Prisoner came to my House in <placeName id="t17360908-37-crimeloc160">St. Clements's Church Yard, in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-37-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="St. Clements's Church Yard, in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360908-37-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off156 t17360908-37-crimeloc160"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-37-off158 t17360908-37-crimeloc160"></join>; (where I had liv'd 19 Years) and took a Lodging, to put his Goods in, which he expected would be seized by the Sheriff, on Account of some Recognizances: on the 20th of April. (Sunday Morning) he knock'd at the Door; I had no body in the House then, but 2 Children about 8 or 9 Years old; he was let in, and he went directly to my Bureau, call'd me Bitch, and said if I took the Law of him, he would cut my Throat, or get 50 People to swear my Life away; he then took away the Gold Watch, and the Diamond Ring, and a Bank Note of 40 l and 5 Shirts of the Orphans.</p>
               <p>Q. What Pretence did he make for this?</p>
               <p>Sayer. None at all; he took them violently. And on the 24th of April, he arrested me in an Action of 140 l. tho' I never had seen a Farthing of his; and while I was at the spunging House in Grocer's Alley, my House was broke open, and all he Things mention'd in the Indictment, were taken away. I could not prosecute him sooner, because I have been in Custody; and when I had my Liberty, I heard he was gone to Holland.</p>
               <p>Councel. Pray did not you keep a publick Coffee House; and did not the Prisoner, and you live together as Man and Wife? did not you both receive Money of your Customers?</p>
               <p>Sayer. No: he was only my Lodger; I kept the House in my own Name.</p>
               <p>Councel. At whose Expence was the Coffee House fitted up? Did not he pay the Money?</p>
               <p>Sayer. He did pay a Man in the Name, and for the Use of Elizabeth Sayer. I always gave him the Money, he never paid any Money of his own for me.</p>
               <p>Councel. I ask you if he did not pass for your Husband?</p>
               <p>Sayer. No, never. He had a Wife in Sheer Lane.</p>
               <p>Councel. Why did he lodge at your House then?</p>
               <p>Sayer. He took a Room to screen his Goods, and he would lodge there himself, as it was his own Lodging.</p>
               <p>Councel. I ask whether this Quarrel did not arise from his reprimanding you about your Daughter's keeping Company?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She sold her Daughter's Maiden-head to one Major Lewis of Deptford for 100 l. he is since a Bankrupt, and she got none of the Money. She pawn'd a silver Spoon of mine to buy a pair of Sheets, she pawn'd even her own Looking Glasses. She says she did not know where to find me before; but my Lord, she was on the back of a Bill last Sessions as a Witnes against me for a Conspiracy against one Drinkwater, and this Drinkwater has charged my Wife (while she was attending on me here) with a Robbery, and she is taken into Custody by one Hicks an Officer.</p>
               <p>Drinkwater. In the Year 1734, I was Servant for about 6 Months to the Prisoner as a Drawer. - Hicks the Constable was call'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you the Warrant to take this Woman into Custody, while she was attending her Husband.</p>
               <p>Hicks. This Man was one: There was 2 Men and 2 Women with him.</p>
               <p>Warwick's Wife. I saw Drinkwater give it the Constable, and then he took hold of my Arm.</p>
               <p>Drinkwater. I was Drawer at Warwick's House in Sheer Lane; he kept a very Disorderly House. Sayer came to him to advise with him about her Administring, and he advised her to make a forged Will, and asked me if I had a Will of any bodies, to make it by: but I would not be concerned. Afterwards he said, one Day, G - d d - n this silly Bitch, she has got Money, I must contrive to get it from her; I will get a Lodging in her House, make her drunk, and so get it from her; Good by Molly, says he to his Wife, I must go from you for 6 Months, to get the tall Man's Effects from the Bitch. What will you do with the Children say'd she: I'll send them to Sea, says he, so the Prisoner and his Wife parted, that he might rob the Woman.</p>
               <p>(The Court order'd Drinkwater into Custody, for taking his Wife while she was attending her Husband's Business in the Court; and the Constable was reprimanded.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-person243">
                  James 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person243" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person243" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When my Mother was out, Joyce and Warwick came to the Door Joyce open'd the Cellar Door and got into the House, and let Warwick in; then they got Porters and carry'd off all the Goods, in Baskets and Sheets.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask the Boy if he has not seen me in bed with this Woman?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, Sir. He had Goods of his own in the House once; but they had been seized and were gone before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-person244">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person244" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person244" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Warwick packing up the Goods, and taking off the Lock from Sayer's Street Door; I can't tell how they liv'd together; nor have I ever heard they were Man and Wife.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080013"></xptr>Q. He had a Wife else where, but he lodged at her House. 'Tis a very scandalous Story. Pray what Pretence had you to take the Watch, the Ring, and the Shirts of 
               <persName id="t17360908-37-person245">
                  Alexander 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person245" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person245" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's?</p>
               <p>Warwick. I can produce the Man that made the Diamond Ring, and all the Rings she had: the other Goods were my own: the Sheriff seized them on an Extent; a Man bought them afterwards of the Sheriff. Here is the Bill of Sale, and I bought them again of him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. I heard Drinkwater say, his Head and Pen were at work to get 
               <persName id="t17360908-37-person246">
                  Jack 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person246" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person246" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             hanged or transported. I know he and Sayer liv'd together as Man and Wife. He call'd her my Dear, and she call'd him so: nay, she has shewn me the bed, that her Johnny and she lay in. I saw some Diamonds they had to sell, and says she to him, Johnny as we can't sell them, you shall have a Ring, and I'll have a Ring, and the Girl shall have a Ring; it was he alter'd the House, and paid several Workmen.</p>
               <p>Mr. Martin. I was told that Warwick had Goods in this House, and that the Sheriff's Officers had seiz'd them, as his. I found it was so, and I bought them again of the Sheriff's Officers for my self; but Warwick applying to me for them, I sold them to him again for the same Money I had paid, so the Goods were never carry'd away.</p>
               <p>Warwick. Ask if I did not pay 3 Guineas for the Ring?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-person247">
                  William 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person247" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person247" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a Stranger to Warwick before he brought the Action against this Woman. I took her then to be an honest, industrious Woman; however, she has order'd it since. When she was in the spunging House, she sent for me; I told her I would see Warwick. and know his Demands. He told me he had disbursed Money on her Account, and would release her, if she would pay some Debts on Account of the House, which amounted to 11 or 12 l. She offer'd me the Lease of her House for Security, if I would pay this Money; I paid the Money, and had the Key of the House to take Possession; she desired me to take care of her Goods, and I went accordingly to the House, supposing I should find it lock'd up, but I found Warwick there, and he told me he got in at the Cellar Window; the Goods were taken down; some were carry'd away before I came, and some, while I was in the House. Warwick told me then, he had the Woman's Authority for what he did, and that he was to take care of the Goods. There were some Things in the House, not proper to be broke down; he would do it, and rather than I would dispute with a Man of his Reputation. I paid him 48 s. to prevent it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-37-person248">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17360908-37-person248" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person248" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry'd Warwick and Sayer by Water, to see a Horse he had at Grass: after they were got home, they sent to know if a Case of a Watch was not left in the Boat; I searched, and sent word I could not find it, after this, her Daughter came to me, and said, Mr. Warwick was very kind to her Mother, and bid her not fret about it, for she should wear her's (the Daughter's) 'till he gave her another.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. I was at Warwick's House in St. Clement's Church Yard, 2 Years ago about altering a Watch, and the Woman said, when it was done, it would make her Jackey a good Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any one will give you a good Character: you give your self a very bad one?</p>
               <p>- Sidley. I have dealt with Warwick, and he paid me for what he had. I never knew he was a Thief before. <rs id="t17360908-37-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-37-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
