<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350911-52">
               <interp inst="t17350911-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-52" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-52" type="date" value="17350911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350911-52-off233-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-defend341 t17350911-52-off233 t17350911-52-verdict237"></join>
         
               <p>59. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350911-52-defend341" type="defendantName">
                     Lawrence 
                     Pickup 
                  <interp inst="t17350911-52-defend341" type="surname" value="Pickup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-defend341" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-defend341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17350911-52-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17350911-52-victim342" type="victimName">
                        Rachel, the <rs id="t17350911-52-viclabel234" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-victim342 t17350911-52-viclabel234"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-person343 t17350911-52-viclabel234"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17350911-52-person343" type="victimName">
                              John 
                              Fletcher 
                           <interp inst="t17350911-52-person343" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17350911-52-person343" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17350911-52-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-off233 t17350911-52-person343"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17350911-52-victim342" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-52-victim342" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350911-52-victim342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-off233 t17350911-52-victim342"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , by assaulting and fixing both his Arms and Hands about her Waste and squeezing and pressing her divers times on the Back, Loins and Sides, and thereby giving her several mortal Bruises, <rs id="t17350911-52-cd235" type="crimeDate">June 28</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-off233 t17350911-52-cd235"></join>. of which she languished till August 2. and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil. This Deposition on Oath, I took from the Mouth of the Deceased as she lay in her Bed at Kensington Gravel Pits, on the twenty eighth of July last, and she died on the second of August following.</p>
               <p>The Information was read, to the following purpose.</p>
               <p>That one Pickup a <rs id="t17350911-52-deflabel236" type="occupation">Brewer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-52-defend341 t17350911-52-deflabel236"></join>, came to her House, at the Time the Races were at Hounslow, being about three Weeks ago, and finding her alone, he went into her back Parlour, and proposed to lye with her, which she refusing, he seized her about the Waste, and struggled with her so long, that by his Violence in attempting to ravish her, she apprehended he broke something within her, and bruised her Kidneys which she immediately felt. That he did attempt to ravish her, and by force took up her Coats, and that she has not been able for a Fortnight after to make Water, and that she believes it will be the Cause of her Death.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deveil, further deposed. That he found her in a bad Condition, and that in his Judgment, she was a dying Woman, in great Pain and Misery, that she gave rational Answers, and seemed to speak with all imaginable Veracity.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-52-person344">
                  John 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17350911-52-person344" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person344" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that on the twenty eighth of June, he went to the Hounslow Races between one and two in the Afternoon, and returned about seven in the Evening, when he found his Wife crying, and asking her the reason, she said she would not be left alone any more: That next Morning she said she was very bad, and shewed him her Water, which war bloody; but he thought it no more than usual, she having been troubled with the Stone and Gravel, but he had heard no Complaint of that nature for a Month before, and that he left her well when he went from Home. That nine or ten Days afterwards, she told him that Pickup the Brewer had been there, and finding her alone, went into the back Parlour, and called for a Pint of Wine: And when she carried it to him, he locked the Door, threw his Arms round her Waste, and threw her down, and put his Hands up her Coats, and attempted to ravish her, that she got up again, and threw up the Sash, and got half out, but he pulled her back, and offered her a Cellar full of Beer to lye with her. That he went to the Prisoner's House, to know why he had abused his Wife, but he was not in Town. That a Week after this, the Prisoner sent him some Two-penny, which the Evidence returned, whereupon the Prisoner came with Mr. Mosely, and huffed the Evidence, and asked why he sent back the Drink, to which he answered: You Villain how dare you come to my House, and abuse my Wife. That his Wife hearing the Prisoner's Voice, called out and said, That Villain at the Door has been the Death of me.</p>
               <p>Being asked if his Wife might not have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173509110019"></xptr> been heard, if she had cryed out when the Prisoner assaulted her; he answered, that she did not cry out, for he struggled with her half an Hour, and she was out of breath: He added that she was attended in her Ilness by Dr. Beaufort, Dr. Bloxham and others, and being cross-examined, he said he believed his Wife did not tell the Doctors how her Disorder began; that he did not ask them what they thought was the cause of it, nor did they tell him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-52-person345">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sheham 
               <interp inst="t17350911-52-person345" type="surname" value="Sheham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person345" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person345" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, that the Deceased sent for her seventeen Days before her Death, she complained of a violent Fit of the Cholick, and said she had been ill two Days before, and believed she had got it by eating Beans and Bacon, but this Evidence thought it was the Gravel.</p>
               <p>Dr. Beaufort About the nineteenth of July, the Deceased sent for me, and said she had been ill three or four Days, was in great Pain, and under a total suppression of Urine. I believe it proceeded from the Stone, and directed as for a suppression of Urine. I visited her three or four times, but she would take nothing, and so I went no more. She never complained of receiving any Bruises, or any Disorder about her Kidneys.</p>
               <p>Being asked if taking a Woman round the Waste, and struggling with her, could bruise her Kidneys, so as to be felt. He said he did not think that so doing could have such an Effect. Being farther asked, if a Stone in the Kidneys might not by Violence be removed, and so cause that suppression of Urine, he replied that it was not to be done by any Violence that could be used in hugging and squeezing.</p>
               <p>Dr. Bloxham deposed, that he attended the Deceased in March or April, she had severe Vomiting, and all the Symptoms of the Stone, for which he directed. That he saw her three Days after his Direction, and she had voided a little Stone. That about the end of July she told him she had had a suppression of Urine for seven Days, which he took to be the Stone, and ordered a Warm Bath. That neither she nor her Husband ever told him that she received any Bruise. Being asked, if Squeezing and Struggling could bruise her Kidneys, so as to be immediately felt. He answered he did not apprehend any such thing could happen; but perhaps it was possible that a violent Wrench or sudden Distortion of the Body might dislodge a Stone and throw it into the Ureter.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17350911-52-person346">
                  Richard 
                  Manningham 
               <interp inst="t17350911-52-person346" type="surname" value="Manningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person346" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that on the thirtieth of July, he was sent for to meet Dr. Burton, at the Plough at Kensington, from whence they went to the Deceas'd's House. The Deceased said she had been abused, and had not made Water for a Fortnight. He told her that was a long time indeed, and (letting her know his Profession) he laid his Hand on her Belly, and found a Tension. He pulled out his Catherer, but a Woman who was present cried out, No, We will have no Experiments - she has been prob'd already. He then let them know he had no farther business there. The Woman told him he had frighted the Deceas'd to death, and she might lay her Death to him. He said, they might do as they would, provided they did not swear he had ravished her. And so he stept down to Dr. Burton, and told him it was well if there was no Trick - They both went up, and were met by one who said they might search now - He did examine, and found no Water in the Bladder. They pretended she was bruised, and that the Child was killed within her. He offered to take the Child away, but upon searching, there was neither Child nor Bruise to be found.</p>
               <p>That he saw the Deceased in half a quarter of an Hour after she was dissected, and could perceive no sign of any Bruises, or of her being with Child; that her Kidneys were emaciated by a settling of Gravel. That the Surgeon shewed him two Stones, and told him that the biggest had been fixt in the ureter going out of the kidney, and the other at the insertion of the ureter into the Bladder, and that he believed her Death was owing to those Stones only.</p>
               <p>Being asked if he thought those Stones had been there for some time, or had been removed thither by some sudden Violence. He answered, the Kidneys were so well guarded that no Struggle could remove those Stones.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173509110020"></xptr>Mr. Chovet, a Surgeon, deposed. that he opened the Body and found a large Stone in the right Kidney at the Exit of the Pelvis, that he found no inward or outward Bruises; that from the Conformation of the Parts, the Water arising like the Swan-neck of an Alembic, or the Letter S, he thought it evident that the Stones could not fall into the places where they were found by means of any struggling.</p>
               <p>The Court having summed up the Evidence, the Jury <rs id="t17350911-52-verdict237" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-52-verdict237" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
