<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351015-31">
               <interp inst="t17351015-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-31" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351015-31" type="date" value="17351015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351015-31-off131-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-31-defend279 t17351015-31-off131 t17351015-31-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>39 
               
                  <persName id="t17351015-31-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Ingram 
                  <interp inst="t17351015-31-defend279" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-defend279" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-defend279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17351015-31-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing seven Guineas, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351015-31-victim281" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Howorth 
                        <interp inst="t17351015-31-victim281" type="surname" value="Howorth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-31-victim281" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351015-31-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-31-off131 t17351015-31-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17351015-31-cd132" type="crimeDate">January 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-31-off131 t17351015-31-cd132"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-31-person282">
                  John 
                  Howorth 
               <interp inst="t17351015-31-person282" type="surname" value="Howorth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-person282" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had received forty Pound. I had a Bank Note for half of it, and the rest was in Gold. About nine at Night, I went to drink at the Red Lyon Ale-house in Peter Street, Soho, and there was this Prisoner. When I went away, she followed, and asked me to give her a Pint - We went to an Ale-house the corner of <placeName id="t17351015-31-crimeloc133">Church Lane in St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-31-crimeloc133" type="placeName" value="Church Lane in St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351015-31-crimeloc133" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351015-31-off131 t17351015-31-crimeloc133"></join>, where we drank Ale and Brandy, and it growing late we concluded that one Bed should serve us both, and so giving the Landlady a Shilling for the use of her Lodging, she locked us both in, and we went to bed. Next Morning, when I awaked, I found my self disordered in a strange place, and she was sitting up in the Bed with her Clothes half on. She desired me not to stop her because she was going to her Days Work, which was Washing. I looked into my Bag, and seeing some Guineas there, I thought all was safe, and so I knocked, and my Landlady opened the Door. But when I came home I mist seven Guineas. I went to the House where I first saw the Prisoner, and by enquiring, I found her at a Ginshop; she confest she had the Money, but pretended that I gave it her upon that same Account. So I sent for a Constable, but the Mob rescued her; and indeed. I being a Man in Business, did not much care to take her up; and I had not done it now, but that she came into my Neighbourhood and degraded me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351015-31-person283">
                  William 
                  Whitesides 
               <interp inst="t17351015-31-person283" type="surname" value="Whitesides"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-person283" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the Prisoner confess that she took seven Guineas from the Prosecutor. Upon which, I told her, if it was in my Power I would prosecute her for her Assurance in divulging it. She said if it was to do again she would do it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He asked me to drink, I told him I hoped he would do me no harm, and he said he would not, but he made me drunk and put me to bed, and when I awaked and found my self locked in, I was frighted - And next Day he charged me with seven Guineas. I have seen him several times since,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173510150017"></xptr> and he wanted me to go with him, but I would not, and therefore he has brought on this Prosecution.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351015-31-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351015-31-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
