<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340710-24">
               <interp inst="t17340710-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-24" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-24" type="date" value="17340710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-24-off99-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-defend179 t17340710-24-off99 t17340710-24-verdict102"></join>
         
               <p>29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-defend179" type="defendantName">
                     Humphry 
                     Remmington 
                  <interp inst="t17340710-24-defend179" type="surname" value="Remmington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-defend179" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-defend179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17340710-24-defloc98">Finchly</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-24-defloc98" type="placeName" value="Finchly"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-24-defloc98" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-defend179 t17340710-24-defloc98"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17340710-24-off99" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-off99" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-off99" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340710-24-victim181" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Wells 
                        <interp inst="t17340710-24-victim181" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340710-24-victim181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340710-24-victim181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-off99 t17340710-24-victim181"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him, on the Right side of the Head with a Dung-fork, one mortal Wound and Bruise, <rs id="t17340710-24-cd100" type="crimeDate">June 8</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-off99 t17340710-24-cd100"></join>, of which he dy'd the same Day
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>The Witnesses were examin'd a-part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person182">
                  Richard 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person182" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person182" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceas'd, and 
               <persName id="t17340710-24-person183">
                  William 
                  Kirby 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person183" type="surname" value="Kirby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person183" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, were going to water our Horses at a Pond before the Prisoner's door, on <placeName id="t17340710-24-crimeloc101">Finchly-Common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-24-crimeloc101" type="placeName" value="Finchly-Common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-24-crimeloc101" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-off99 t17340710-24-crimeloc101"></join>. The Prisoner came out, hit my Fore-horse on the Head, and took me a good Knock; but for all that, I went to lead my Horse to the Pond, upon which the Prisoner took me by the Hair, and dragg'd me to his Door, and beat and abused me. Kirby said, don't abuse the Lad; but if he has done any thing contrary to Law, take the Law of him. And the Deceas'd (who was then unreining his Horses) said, If you want to fight, don't fight with a Lad, but with a Man; and so begun to unbutton his Coat. Upon that the Prisoner went in, and fetch'd out a three tined Dung-fork. Sure, says Kirby, you won't be such a Villain as to knock the Man down? The Deceas'd made no offer to fight; but the Prisoner struck him on the Head with the edge of the Dung-fork, and he dropt down immediately - We help him up, and set him against the Sign-post, and in less than a Quarter of an Hour got him upon his Horse; the Prisoner in the mean time was damning and swearing that no Body should come to Water at his Pond.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100012"></xptr> The Deceas'd rode about a Mile, but dopt his Head like a drunken Man; but then he could ride no farther, Lord have mercy upon me, says he, he has almost kill'd me. So we put him into his Master's Dung-cart, and he lean'd his Head over the Side of it, and vomited a little Blood, and so he was carry'd to Hadley Windmill, where his Mother-in-Law lives. We felt on the Right-side of his Head, and felt it was broke: He was put to Bed, and, as I heard, dy'd in two Hours - Here is the Fork - the Prisoner held this, and struck the Deceas'd on the Head with this side of the Iron Tines - I live at Hadley. We were coming from London, and went to Water our Horses at this Pond, which lies in the Highway, and is a common Watering-place.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Is not the Pond rail'd in?</p>
               <p>Roberts. It is rail'd; but not quite round, there is a Cartway left for People to drive Carts and Waggons in.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not deny your going in with your Horses; but I told you, that you should not draw your Cart in.</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, you did not speak one Word, but struck my Fore-horse; and when I took the Fore-horse to lead him in, you fell upon me - The Deceas'd had unreined his Horses, in order to Water them, but had not water'd them when you knock'd him down; for he came after you to speak to you for beating me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How far is the Pond from my House?</p>
               <p>Roberts. 4 or 5 Pole.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not 3 Men strip and follow me 30 Yards quite to my own Door?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, there was not a Soul stript. The Deceas'd had only begun to strip.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person184">
                  William 
                  Kirby 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person184" type="surname" value="Kirby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person184" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner beat the Lad, and I said, don't beat the Boy, but if he had done any thing against Law, take another Course with him. The Deceas'd was then standing by the Highway 2 or 3 Pole from the House, and said to the Prisoner, don't beat the Boy, beat a Man. Upon which the Prisoner ran in and brought out a Dung-fork. His Wife follow'd him and said, What! have you a mind to be hang'd? And says I, sure you don't design to be such a Villain as to kill the Man? The Deceas'd never lifted up his Hand against the Prisoner, but was standing thus with his Coat unbutton'd, and just turn'd back over his Shoulder, when the Prisoner struck him on the Head with the Prong of the Fork edgeways, and down he fell. The Boy and I help'd him up. He loll'd his Head against the Horse block, but in a little time he something recover'd himself, and then we put him upon his Horse, and afterwards into the Dung-cart, where he spit Blood; and so was carried to his Father-in-law: He had a Bruise on the right side of his Head. We sent for a Surgeon, and then left him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you stript to fight me?</p>
               <p>Kirby. No, Nobody was stript.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you follow me to my own Door? And why?</p>
               <p>Kirby. No, no farther than your Sign Post that stands out in the Road, and there the Deceas'd was knock'd down - 'Tis the sign of the Windmill, a quarter of a Mile from Whetstone.</p>
               <p>Council. How came you on the Prisoner's Ground?</p>
               <p>Kirby. His Ground? I thought it had been the King's Ground - The Pond has been a common watering Place ever since the oldest Man in the Parish can remember.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person185">
                  Joseph 
                  Hughs 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person185" type="surname" value="Hughs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person185" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came up with my Teem 2 Minutes before the blow was struck. The Deceas'd was then going to strip, and the Prisoner came out with the Fork and knock'd him down, while his Clothes were half stript over his Shoulders. He was help'd upon his Nag, and told the Prisoner he would make an example of him for striking him with such a Weapon. Then the Deceas'd took his Teem and rode, sometimes sitting and sometimes lying upon his Nag for about half a Mile, and then they put him upon his Load of Dung, and carried him to his Father-in-law, 
               <persName id="t17340710-24-person186">
                  Thomas 
                  Perry 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person186" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person186" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Hadley.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Were not you stript?</p>
               <p>Hughs. No, nor Nobody else.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not the Deceas'd threaten to fight me?</p>
               <p>Hughs. No, he only said, don't set your<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100013"></xptr> wit to a Boy but to a Man - The Deceas'd was about 35 Years old.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person187">
                  Wright 
                  Faulkner 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person187" type="surname" value="Faulkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person187" type="given" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On Saturday, June 8. I was sent for to Mr. Perry's at Hadley, where I found the Deceas'd extremely ill and speechless. He had received a violent Blow on the Head I let him Blood, he sigh'd once, and dy'd in a quarter of an Hour - On the Thursday following the Coroner sent for me. I open'd the Head of the Deceas'd, and found a large Contusion and a Fracture of 4 inches on the Temple-bone, a little above the Ear. A Piece of Bone as big as a Hazel-nut was broke quite round. I raised it up, and put a Spatula under it - I believe the Wound was the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The beginning of the Story was this. The Boy came up to the Pond, and I said, You shan't draw your Cart thro' the Pond, but take your Horses off, water them and welcome. Upon that, he struck me on the Head with his Whip, and the Deceas'd and 2 or 3 more stript, and said, God Damn him, let's knock him on the Head. And then the Deceas'd struck me with his Whip, and I knock'd him down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person188">
                  Edward 
                  Bolton 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person188" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person188" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was 20 Yards from the Pond. The Prisoner was going from the Pond, and 3 Men follow'd him; 2 of them were stript. He look'd back, and pacing they got Ground of him; he run to his House, and somewhere in the Stable he took up this unfortunate Weapon, and then coming to his own Door, he said, Gentlemen stand off! for I'll stand in my own Defence. But they made upto him, and he struck the Deceas'd; and then one of them struck the Prisoner in the Face.</p>
               <p>Court. Did the Deceas'd strike the Prisoner first?</p>
               <p>Bolton. I did not see that, but when the Deceas'd fell, the Prisoner flung down the Dung-fork and went to his own House, but one of them stript, follow'd him, and several blows past between them.</p>
               <p>Coroner. How far were you from them when the blow was given?</p>
               <p>Bolton. About threescore Yards.</p>
               <p>Court. And could you hear what was said at that Distance?</p>
               <p>Bolton Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Who else was near when the blow was struck?</p>
               <p>Bolton Thomas Scot was one, and several Carters stopt their Carts.</p>
               <p>Court. Was Scot before or behind you?</p>
               <p>Bolton. Before me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-24-person189">
                  Thomas 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17340710-24-person189" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person189" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were 4 Carters following the Prisoner as he was making towards his own Door.</p>
               <p>Court What Carters?</p>
               <p>Scot. These 3 Gentlemen here, and the Deceas'd, they follow'd him to his own Door - and he turn'd his Head - And as he was going to his own Door - He met me with this Weapon.</p>
               <p>Court. Met me with it? Where?</p>
               <p>Scot. Some where or other.</p>
               <p>Court. At the Door, or within the Door?</p>
               <p>Scot. I can't say as to that; but as he was coming along with this unlawful Weapon, he said, Gentlemen, take care, I stand upon my own Defence, and then the Gentlemen -</p>
               <p>Court. What Gentlemen?</p>
               <p>Scot. The Deceas'd made up to him, and the Prisoner struck him with the Pitch-fork, and then threw it down, and then the Boy struck the Prisoner - The Deceas'd lay 2 or 3 Minutes, and then got upon his Horse and went to his Team.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he get up himself?</p>
               <p>Scot. He got up, or was hold up.</p>
               <p>Court. Who was stript?</p>
               <p>Scot. Two of the Carters that follow'd the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Court. Was the Deceas'd stript?</p>
               <p>Scot. Yes, he was - No he was not - But the Boy was.</p>
               <p>Court. How did the Deceas'd stand when he receiv'd the blow?</p>
               <p>Scot. Upon his Legs - He was unbutton'd and Rioting with the rest, but he gave no blow.</p>
               <p>Court. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Scot. I had been a Haymaking for Mr. Milbourn, and was going home about 4 in the Afternoon; for we left off Work because it rain'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100014"></xptr>Court. How far was you off when the blow was given?</p>
               <p>Scot. 100 Yards.</p>
               <p>Court. Could you hear what was said at that Distance?</p>
               <p>Scot. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Where was Bolton?</p>
               <p>Scot. He was with me; we had both been at work at the same Place, and were going together.</p>
               <p>Court. Was he behind or before you?</p>
               <p>Scot. Behind me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had no Malice against the Deceas'd, for I never spoke to him before, and little thought of killing him when I gave him that blow.</p>
               <p>Several Witnesses gave the Prisoner the Character of a very sober, honest, civil Man, and not subject to be quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17340710-24-verdict102" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-verdict102" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17340710-24-punish103" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-24-punish103" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-24-defend179 t17340710-24-punish103"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
