<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380113-28">
               <interp inst="t17380113-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-28" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-28" type="date" value="17380113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380113-28-off157-c183" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-28-defend256 t17380113-28-off157 t17380113-28-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>** 41. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-defend256" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Harbin 
                  <interp inst="t17380113-28-defend256" type="surname" value="Harbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-defend256" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-defend256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17380113-28-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver Candlestick, val. 39 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-victim258" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17380113-28-victim258" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-victim258" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-victim258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-28-off157 t17380113-28-victim258"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17380113-28-viclabel158" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-28-victim258 t17380113-28-viclabel158"></join>; <rs id="t17380113-28-cd159" type="crimeDate">Jan. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-28-off157 t17380113-28-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <p>** Harbin was an Evidence Last Sessions in the Trial of Cook and Carter, for robbing the Fountain-Tavern at Stock-Market; he having receiv'd from Cook, Part of the Goods stole, and dispos'd of them for him. See Sessions Book, No. 1. P. 6</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-person259">
                  William 
                  Maycook 
               <interp inst="t17380113-28-person259" type="surname" value="Maycook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person259" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr. Clark, in <placeName id="t17380113-28-crimeloc160">New North-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-28-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="New North-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-28-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-28-off157 t17380113-28-crimeloc160"></join>. On the 4th Instant I clean'd my Plate, and set it in the usual Place; then I was sent out of an Errand; while I was Abroad, 2 Fellows came dress'd like Dustmen (as the Maids told me) and pretended they came for the Dust: When they had taken it away, they came again and begg'd small Beer. We had a new Servant, who was not acquainted with our Dustmen, but having no Suspicion of the Men, she went and drew them some Beer. When I came Home, I miss'd the Candlestick, and the Maid telling me who had been there, I went to the Master of the Dustmen, and found that they were none of his Men. I (being to pay for the Candlestick) carry'd the Fellow of it to Mr. Page in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173712130019"></xptr> Orange-Street, to know what it came to, and told him the Story; but I had not been come home again above an Hour, before he brought the Prisoner's Wife, and Part of the Candlestick, to our House. We took her before a Justice, and at first she said she found it in Gray's-Inn Walks; and as she was carrying from New-Prison to be re-examined, her Husband begged of her to hold out in the same Story; and when we came to the Justice's Door, he ran away, but we pursued him, and took him near Saffron-Hill, and brought him to the Justice's, when they were both re-examined, she said her Husband gave it her to sell for him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Were not the Servants call'd to see if they knew me again?</p>
               <p>Maycock. Yes, and they said they could not safely swear to you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Lovet 
               <interp inst="t17380113-28-person260" type="surname" value="Lovet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Headborough. A Neighbour of mine appeared in the Prisoner's Wife's Behalf, and gave her the Character of a very honest Woman; at first she said she found it, but afterwards she owned she had it from her Husband. The House where he lives is a Den of Thieves, and it is a Place contrived for their Conveniency: He had the Impudence to go with his Wife to the Justice's Door, but then he ran away, and I cry'd stop Thief, and took him. Every earthly Thing upon this Occasion has been mov'd out of his House, except two old Bedsteads. When he fled from me, I asked him what made him run? He told me I look'd as if I had a Warrant against him, and he did not like my Face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-person261">
                  William 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17380113-28-person261" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person261" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             saw a Piece of Candlestick in the the Prisoner's Wife's Possession, and she told him she had it from the Prisoner to sell for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-28-person262">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harbin 
               <interp inst="t17380113-28-person262" type="surname" value="Harbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person262" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner's Wife, deposed, That she had the Silver from her Husband at an Alehouse, and that he insisted on her selling it for him; - but as soon as the Court understood she was the Prisoner's Wife, they would not admit her Evidence. <rs id="t17380113-28-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-28-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
