<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390502-30">
               <interp inst="t17390502-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-30" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390502-30" type="date" value="17390502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390502-30-off144-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-defend221 t17390502-30-off144 t17390502-30-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>268. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-defend221" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Trotter 
                  <interp inst="t17390502-30-defend221" type="surname" value="Trotter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-defend221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-defend221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17390502-30-defloc143">St. Mary Le Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-30-defloc143" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Le Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390502-30-defloc143" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-defend221 t17390502-30-defloc143"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17390502-30-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 40 Ells of Holland, value 30s. 22 Pieces of Buckram, value 10 l. 15 Gross of Braid for Stays, value 7 l, 15 Gross of Galloons, value 8 l. 3 Pieces of white Buckram, value 18 s. 15 Pieces of Canvas, value 15 s. 3 Pieces of brown Buckram, value 3 s. and 6 Pieces of Ticken, value 2 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390502-30-victim223" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Doughty 
                        <interp inst="t17390502-30-victim223" type="surname" value="Doughty"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-30-victim223" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390502-30-victim223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-off144 t17390502-30-victim223"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390502-30-cd145" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-off144 t17390502-30-cd145"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Hitchins 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person224" type="surname" value="Hitchins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I searched the Prisoner's Lodgings in Vine street, near Round Court in the Strand, in the Presence of Mr. Doughty, and one or two more. These are the Goods we seized, some were produced before Justice Fraser, the rest were in a Cart near the Justice's Door. I sealed the Bags up into which they were put; the Goods in them are what we found in the Prisoner's Lodging, and they have been in my Possession ever since, without any Alteration at all.</p>
               <p>Mr. Doughty. These are my Goods; they were in my Shop, and were stole from thence. This is a Piece of my Buckram, and I know it by my Stamp at each Corner; and I was present when this and the rest of the Goods were taken at the Prisoner's Lodgings. Here is another Piece of Buckram; and this is my Silesia Holland, I bought of this Gentleman: He and his Clerk are here to vouch they are my Goods. About nine Weeks ago I had the Misfortune to have an Iron Bar fall on my Leg, by which Accident I was confin'd for seven Weeks to my Chamber. The Prisoner went away from me two or three Days before the Accident happen'd; so I had not Time to examine my Shop till I was recover'd; and then several of my Customers told me, they could buy Goods cheaper of the Prisoner than they could of me: I thought that was strange, and suspecting they might be my Goods, I cast up my Shop, and found by my Bills of Parcels, that I had lost 150 l. Worth of Goods.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Quantity of Goods did you find at his Lodgings?</p>
               <p>Doughty. Here are several Parcels which I cannot swear to. I can be positive to these two Pieces of Buckram, and three Pieces of Silesia Holland, and these three Pieces of White; here's my Stamp on them. There are more Buckrams, but we have not produced them all.</p>
               <p>Counc. How many Pieces can you be positive to?</p>

               <p>Doughty. About ten Pieces, - all mark'd with my Mark. Here's seven Pieces of White, which I am positive to; they are stamp'd at each Corner, and here's the Man who made this Stamp for me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020013"></xptr>Counc. How long had the Prisoner been gone from you when you miss'd the Goods?</p>
               <p>Doughty. About a Month, or better.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was not you arrested for Wages due to me, before I was charged with this Robbery?</p>
               <p>Doughty. Yes; and I had a Suspicion of him then, but I had not Time to examine my Books: I remember I said to the Officer, - There's something extraordinary in this Man, for he us'd to go like a Nobleman. I paid him 10 l. a Year, Wages, and sent to him in Order to pay him before I was arrested. He was my <rs id="t17390502-30-deflabel146" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-defend221 t17390502-30-deflabel146"></join>, and I trusted him to sell in the Shop; but these Goods which we found in his Lodgings, could not be sold in my Shop, by my Directions, I am sure they were not: I miss'd to the Number of 50 Pieces of Goods.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long before you miss'd these Goods, had you seen them in your Shop?</p>
               <p>Doughty. I can't tell certainly; because I have a great Quantity of them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Might not those Goods be sold out of the Shop with the Mark on them?</p>
               <p>Doughty. As he was trusted to sell Goods in the Shop, he must sell them with the Mark on them. It was his Business to sell in the Shop, and to keep my Books.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you settle Accounts with me, and cast up the Books, before you parted with me.</p>
               <p>Doughty. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person225">
                  John 
                  Doughty 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person225" type="surname" value="Doughty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , junior. I went with my Father and the Constable to the Prisoner's Lodging, where these Goods were found. I have been conversant with my Father's Shop and Business ever since last March was Twelvemonth, and know these Goods are my Father's: I believe they might have been in the Shop about three or four Months before they were miss'd. I attended in the Shop while my Father's illness lasted, (which was near seven Weeks) for the Prisoner had been gone about two Days before; and no body did Business in the Shop, while my Father was ill, but myself.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you miss any Quantity of Buckrams out of the Shop, before your Father came down into the Shop?</p>
               <p>Doughty junior. No. But when he came down, he was sensible (upon searching the Shop) that a great many Pieces were wanting.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Can you say these Goods were not sold out of the Shop?</p>
               <p>Doughty junior. Yes. If they were sold, they were never enter'd in the Books, nor did we ever receive a Farthing for them.</p>
               <p>Counc. What is the Value of the Goods that lye before you?</p>
               <p>Doughty junior. About 10 l. and the Value of the Buckrams that we can swear to is about 5 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person226">
                  James 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person226" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person226" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I stiffen'd these Pieces of Buckram for Mr. Doughty; I believe these have been stiffen'd about a Quarter of a Year: I know they are his Goods, and were done at my House; for we always stamp every Persons Goods with their own Mark. We have a Penny a Yard for Stiffening them. I have look'd over about a Dozen Pieces, and can't say whether this Piece may not have been stiffen'd a Twelvemonth ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person227">
                  David 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person227" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person227" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I know the Prisoner, and went to his Lodging the 28th of last Month, to look on some Buckrams that he had to dispose of; and I bought these two Pieces, at 6 d. a Yard, of the Prisoner at the Bar, which is cheaper than the Market Price by 2 d. a Yard. I am a Taylor, and the usual Price is 8 d. I bought these two Pieces by Mr. Doughty's Direction, that he might see whether they were his Goods. I believe this Buckram was never bought unstiffen'd under 6 d. a Yard.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE. Prisoner. I sold these Buckrams in Mr. Doughty's Shop, to a Gentleman that was going Abroad, with many other Goods; the Money for them was received and book'd, and I can prove when the Goods were delivered: But the Person not going the Voyage that he expected, he told me the Goods would be of no Use to him, so I bought them again of him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fraser. When the Prisoner was brought before me, I asked him how he came by so large a Quantity of Goods? He told me they had been Mr. Doughty's Goods, but he bought them of a Surgeon, who had paid Mr. Doughty for them, and was now gone Abroad.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Gentleman who bought them of Mr. Doughty did not go the Voyage he expected, so I took the Goods off his Hands, and paid him 18 Guineas for them. This was in the Month of November, and they were lodg'd at a Friend's House, till I left my Master, then I took them to my Lodging. As to the Galloons, I buy my Goods of the Makers and Hawkers, and they must sell to more People than Mr. Doughty. The Day after I left him, I went to him for my Wages, and he used me very civilly, but did not pay me then; and three or four Days after that he heard<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173905020014"></xptr> I was ill, he sent and offer'd me my Money; however, I was not paid, and I brought a Writ against him for it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Doughty, senior. The Prisoner came to me the latter End of December, and went away in February last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person228">
                  David 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person228" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person228" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In November last the Prisoner brought some Buckrams to my House, while he was in his Master's Service, and he took them away about eight or ten Days after he had left him: They came either by a Porter, or a Cart, and were after wards carry'd to his Lodging; he told me he had them of one Mr. Brown. I can't tell whether these are the same Pieces that were at our House, but they were the same Sort of Goods; and the Prisoner himself desired me to let him leave them at my House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person229">
                  Robert 
                  Skinner 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person229" type="surname" value="Skinner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person229" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have dealt with the Prisoner lately: I sold him 11 Pieces of white Linnen on the 17th or 18th of last Month, and he paid me for them; but these Goods that are now produced are none of them which I sold him. He bought no other Goods of me but what are mentioned in this Bill of Parcels. I have known him five Years; and never knew of his being given to pilfering, nor ever knew him suspected before.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hyde. I know the Prisoner: I have sold him brown Irish Linnen, but there are none of them among the Goods now produced.</p>
               <p>Mr. Clavey. I have sold the Prisoner two small Parcels of Irish Buckrams, at 10 1/2 d. (I think) a Yard, for the Use of Stay-makers: These that are produced are of another Sort; these are for Taylors, they are Scotch Buckrams, and are not what I sold him.</p>
               <p>Col. Sinclair. About two Years ago the Prisoner came out of the Country, and brought me a Letter of Recommendation from my Sister, the Lady Beard, wherein she desired me to get him into some Shop-keeper's Service, and told me therein, that he had an honest Character, and could keep Books, and that she should take it as a Favour if I could get him recommended as a Book-keeper; and I accordingly spoke to some People, in order to get him into Business: He has an Uncle at Edinburgh, who is a Shop-keeper, and a Man of a fair Character. I never heard the Prisoner was addicted to Pilfering.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lindsay. The Prisoner I know serv'd his Apprenticeship with one Mr. Stewart, at Edinburgh, and had a good Character while he was there. His Uncle is a considerable Dealer at Edinburgh, but I can't say I know any Thing of the Prisoner's Character since he came here.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. I have known the Prisoner ever since he came to Mr. Doughty. I took him to be an honest Man, and have heard Mr. Doughty say he believ'd him to be so; and that the Prisoner gave such Satisfaction to his Customers, that they chose to be serv'd by him, and by none but him. I never heard any Thing laid to his Charge, or that he was addicted to Pilfering before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390502-30-person230">
                  James 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17390502-30-person230" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person230" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner had lodged in my House when he was taken up, eight Weeks and two Days; he behaved soberly, liv'd moderately, and I never heard him swear in my Life. He used to bring in Goods in the Day-time, and People used to come to him to buy them.</p>
               <p>- Warren. I have known him a Year last November; he bore a universal good Character. I am a Hair-cutter; and he used to come to my Shop to have his Hair done up: I was once drinking with him and Mr. Doughty's Son, and I would have had another Tankard, but he would go home, because it was about Ten o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fryer. I have known him about eight Years, and never knew any Thing amiss of him in my Life. <rs id="t17390502-30-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390502-30-verdict147" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, <rs id="t17390502-30-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17390502-30-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390502-30-defend221 t17390502-30-punish148"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>.The Jury recommended the Prisoner to his Majesty's Clemency
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
