<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361208-74">
               <interp inst="t17361208-74" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-74" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-74" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361208-74" type="date" value="17361208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off362-c350" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend527 t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off362-c351" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend529 t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off362-c352" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend531 t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off362-c353" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend533 t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off365-c350" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend527 t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off365-c351" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend529 t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off365-c352" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend531 t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361208-74-off365-c353" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend533 t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-verdict370"></join>
         
               <p>93, 94, 95, 96. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-defend527" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Anthill 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend527" type="surname" value="Anthill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend527" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-defend529" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Waters 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend529" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend529" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend529" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-defend531" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Maccartey 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend531" type="surname" value="Maccartey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend531" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend531" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-defend533" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend533" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend533" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-defend533" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17361208-74-off362" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-off362" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-off362" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-74-victim535" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Innys 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim535" type="surname" value="Innys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim535" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim535" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17361208-74-person536">
                        Joseph 
                        Anthill 
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person536" type="surname" value="Anthill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person536" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person536" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , for giving the said Innys a mortal Bruise on the Crown of his Head with a wooden Stick, of which mortal Bruise he instantly died, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17361208-74-crimeloc363">St. Sepulchres's</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc363" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchres's"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc363" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-crimeloc363"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-crimeloc363"></join>, <rs id="t17361208-74-cd364" type="crimeDate">Sept. 19</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-cd364"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-cd364"></join>, and 
                     <persName id="t17361208-74-person537">
                        Thomas 
                        Waters 
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person537" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person537" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person537" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17361208-74-person538">
                        Daniel 
                        Maccartey 
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person538" type="surname" value="Maccartey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person538" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person538" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17361208-74-person539">
                        Philip 
                        Brown 
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person539" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person539" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person539" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , for aiding, abetting, assisting and comforting the said Anthill in the said Murder
            </rs>, as aforesaid.</p>
               <p>They were a second time indicted for <rs id="t17361208-74-off365" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-off365" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-off365" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17361208-74-person540">
                        Alexander 
                        Innys 
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person540" type="surname" value="Innys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person540" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-person540" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Cane, value 2 s. 6 d. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361208-74-victim542" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Oakley 
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim542" type="surname" value="Oakley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim542" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361208-74-victim542" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , a Silver Hilted Sword, value 20 s. and a Silver Shoe Buckle, value 2 s. 6 d.
            </rs> Sept. 19. The Counsel for the Prosecution having open'd the Charge, and the Evidence against the Prisoners, they proceeded to call the Witnesses.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fewterel. I live at the Thistle and Crown in Church-Court, against Hungerford-Market. On Sunday, Sept. 19. Capt. Innys was at my House in the Evening, and went from thence about Half an Hour after Nine, in good Health. He went towards Wine-Licence-Court in Fleet-street. I would have perswaded him to have said all Night, or have taken a Coach, because he was a little fuddled; but he would not. There was a Gentleman in his Company, but he did not go home with him. I lighted him to the End of the Court, and saw him walk very well, with a Cane in his Hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person543">
                  Thomas 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person543" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person543" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person543" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Rainbow Coffee-House the Corner of <placeName id="t17361208-74-crimeloc366">Ludgate-Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc366" type="placeName" value="Ludgate-Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc366" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-crimeloc366"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-crimeloc366"></join>. On this Sunday Night I saw Capt. Innys, and two Men with him; who they were I did not know at that time: He had a Linkman with him, and was going towards St. Paul's. The Captain insisted upon being lighted home, the Linkman refused to go any farther, and would have a Shilling then: The Gentleman said, if he would not light him home he would give him nothing; then the Fellows said to the Linkman, D - n him, take his Cane, or something to that Purpose; then the Linkman turn'd round and snatch'd the Cane out of the Captain's Hand, and they all stood arguing a little; but they seeing me and other People coming up, he li't him up a little farther than Mr. Ashley's Coffee-House, then he put out his Link and ran away with the Cane, towards Temple-Bar. After this, I saw the Captain much in Liquor, - he seem'd to stagger, and those two Fellows kept with him: I did not like them, and had a Curiosity to see what they would do to him. I observed the least of them on one Side of his Pocket; but they taking Notice of me, one of them was a coming up to me, but I was afraid of them, and went away. I took Notice of the Man that was coming up to me, he had a sort of a whitish Face, and a brown Coat: I pick'd the Man afterwards out of a Room full of People. I won't swear positively that is the Man, but I think in my Heart he is the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the Man with a white Face?</p>
               <p>Walker. I don't know where he is now; but I pick'd him out of a Room full of People.</p>
               <p>Q. Look about you, do you see the Man?</p>
               <p>Walker. That's the Man.</p>
               <p>[The Witnesses went directly to the Bar and took Anthill by the Hand] This is the Man. - That Man stood by the Captain, and that was the Man that came over the Kennel to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the Link put out?</p>
               <p>Walker. Yes; but I saw the Man's Face that came over to me, while the Linkman was with them: He was one that bid the Linkman take his Cane; - I can't swear positively that he is the Man. When that Man came up to me, I was afraid, and so I went directly home: This was about Ten o'Clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person544">
                  Jane 
                  Tyrrel 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person544" type="surname" value="Tyrrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person544" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person544" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the three Prisoners, Anthill, Waters and Brown: I know nothing of the old Man. I remember the Night that Capt. Innys was found murdered, by their own Words; it was the 19th of Dec. I was a hired Servant to Anthill, at 6 l. a Year. That Sunday we had baked Pork for Dinner, and it was not done enough.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080035"></xptr>Q. What Business does he follow?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. He keeps a House in Black and White-Court in the Old Bailey; - about Six or Seven o'Clock that Sunday Night, 
               <persName id="t17361208-74-person545">
                  Tom 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person545" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person545" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in to Anthill's House, and this 
               <persName id="t17361208-74-person546">
                  Phil 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person546" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person546" type="given" value="Phil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person546" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in; they drank two half Quarters of Gin together, and Tom Waters paid Anthill 2 d. for the Geneva When they had drank the Gin, they Three went out together, between Six and Seven o'Clock. Between Nine and Ten Anthill came in again by himself, and flung his Hat down upon the Table, and said, G - d D - n it, what have we done! - we have taken his Hat and left his Money! I had a Stake of Pork broiling on the Fire, and while I was turning it, in came Tom Waters, and he cry'd G - d D - n my Eyes, we have taken his Sword, and left the Scabbard and Money behind. I did not see Brown 'till the Wednesday following. Then says Anthill to Waters, G - d D - n it, what have you done with the Blade?</p>
               <p>Q. What had Anthill in his Hand when he went out?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. He took out a Stick with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Waters any Thing in his Hand?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. God forbid I should say any Thing but of a Stick. Neither of them had any Sword. Waters had a Stick when he went out, and a Stick when he came in again. Then an't please you, Anthill said, what have you done with the Blade of the Sword? Waters said, he had broke it into four Pieces; then G - d D - n it says Anthill, it will serve for nothing but Files: what they meant I could not tell, I was not a Judge of their material Way of thinking. After this had pass'd, they both went out of Doors, and came in again; then Anthill went out and call'd Tom. Waters out to him, and in about two Minutes I heard Tom bid Anthill Good Night, telling him, he was going Home. When Anthill came in again, he said, - G - d D - n it! I gave him but one Blow! Have you been Fighting says I; can one Blow kill a Man? (not knowing any Thing of the Matter then) Yes, says he, - just here; putting his Hand under his Wig, this was about Ten o'Clock. Then he sat down by the Fire, and trembled, and could not eat a Bit. About Eleven o'Clock, when the Watchman came about, I took the Candle off the Table and hid it in the Closet, that he might not see the Light. I could not imagine what made him tremble so, I thought he might be in Liquor; for I did not know any Thing of the Murder 'till Monday Morning Seven o'Clock, and then at a Chandler's Shop, I heard one say of me, that Woman lives in <placeName id="t17361208-74-crimeloc367">Black and White-Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc367" type="placeName" value="Black and White-Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361208-74-crimeloc367" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off362 t17361208-74-crimeloc367"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-off365 t17361208-74-crimeloc367"></join> where the Man was kill'd: this made me have a Thought; so I stept Home, and went to Anthill's Bedside, and said, Joe, what do you think! I don't know what to think said he, and cry'd - I gave him but one Blow; what need you to be frighted, my Dear, says he to me! I gave him but one Blow.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first discover these Expressions and this Behaviour?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. About Five Weeks and odd Days ago; to one Mr. Gordon at his House; and when Anthill was taken up, he could not disown one Word.</p>
               <p>Q. How come you to conceal a Thing of this Importance so long?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. If I must expose my self, I must, - I was under Confinement Nine Days or a Fortnight, - and when People have seen me crying, and ask'd me the Reason, I have said, I am sorry that I should keep Company with such People, for because I am a Woman of the Town, the People would say, I did it out of Spite, if I should reveal it.</p>
               <p>Anthill. Did you never call me bloody-minded Thief?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. Yes, because you said you gave him but one Blow, and that was his Death.</p>
               <p>Anthill. We had a great Quarrel because I would not live no longer with her as my Wife. Ask her, if I did not come Home and tell her there was a Gentleman drunk in the Old-Baily, and if I did not say, we staid with him 'till Mr. Atkins and his Son came to him.</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. No, nothing like it; but when he came in he slung down his Hat and trembled.</p>
               <p>Waters. Ask her, why she did not remember me when Anthill was committed to the Counter?</p>
               <p>Tyrrel. I mentioned Waters when I made the Discovery to Gordon, but when I was carried before my Lord Mayor, I was so surpriz'd that I forgot the rest of them.</p>
               <p>- Gordon. I live in Hanging-Sword Alley in Fleet-street; I am a Joiner. I can't remember the Day of the Month, but 'twas one Friday Night Tyrrel was at my House, and seem'd very uneasy. I ask'd her what was the Matter; she was ready to cry, and made no Answer. My Wife told me, that she (Tyrrel) knew something of the Murder of Capt. Innys. I told her, if she did, it was but Justice to bring it out; but I did not ask her much about it that Night, because I wanted to go to Bed; however, next Day she went before the Lord-Mayor and made the Discovery. As to the Men, I know nothing of them; only I know she told the same Story before him, (with Regard to Anthill) that she has told now. I heard her mention Tom Waters, and that he came into Anthill's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173612080036"></xptr> House that Evening, but I can't be sure whether she spoke of him at my Lord Mayor's or not, for I was not near enough to hear all that she said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person547">
                  Peter 
                  Ellames 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person547" type="surname" value="Ellames"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person547" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person547" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of September, about 10 o'Clock at Night, I saw the Deceased lying on his Back in the Old Baily I thought he was dying, and said, it was pity nobody would lend their Assistance to get him to the Watch-House; so I got him thither and sent for a Surgeon to bleed him, and after that he was carried to the Bell-Inn.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Brown. Ask him whether he took Notice of his Buckles?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ellames. When he was taken off the Ground he had both Buckles in his Shoes, but when he was brought into the Watch-House he had but one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person548">
                  Samuel 
                  Hinson 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person548" type="surname" value="Hinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person548" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person548" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After Anthill was committed, I went to see Waters in the Compter, his Mother and several others were with him, and after some Talk he started up, and said, d - n his Soul, Anthill was as guilty of the Murder, as he was innocent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person549">
                  William 
                  Murrey 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person549" type="surname" value="Murrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person549" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person549" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought the Cane of the Prisoner, the Linkman, one Sunday Night; he asked a Shilling for it, I said I had but Six-pence; he said I might lend him that upon the Cane 'till the next Day, and I agreed with him, that if he fetch'd it not the next Day, it was to be my own.</p>
               <p>Mr. Oakley. This Cane is mine; I was visiting at a Friend's House in July last, and left this Cane behind me when I came away. How it came to Mr. Innys, I can't tell.</p>

               <p>Capt. Carr. I know that Mr. Innys had that very Cane, that's all I know.</p>
               <p>Mr. Murray. I cannot swear that Brown brought me the Buckle to sell it, he might or might not; I will not swear what I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person550">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cockran 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person550" type="surname" value="Cockran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person550" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person550" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday September 19, the Prisoner Brown, came to my Room with a carv'd Buckle, about Half an Hour after Ten at Night, he said he had taken it out of the Gentleman's Shoe in the Old-Baily, and if the People had not come up, he should have got something else. There was some Blood upon his Coat, I asked him how it came, and he told me his Nose had been bleeding. My Husband had given him Leave to lodge with me in my Room.</p>
               <p>Anthill. 
               <persName id="t17361208-74-person551">
                  Nathan 
                  Cockran 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person551" type="surname" value="Cockran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person551" type="given" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person551" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is now in Newgate, and Brown is an Evidence against him on that Account.</p>
               <p>Maccartey. I was a Hackney-Coachman, but being reduc'd to Poverty, I <rs id="t17361208-74-deflabel368" type="occupation">carried a Link</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend531 t17361208-74-deflabel368"></join>. Towards Charing-Cross the Gentleman ply'd me, and I was to light him to Fleet-Ditch; when we came there he said he had no man Money, and bid me go about my Business. I said it was very hard; and told him, I had never seen him before; upon that he struck at me with his Cane, and dropped it; I took it up, and every Body said, keep the Cane, poor Man, keep it, and the Gentleman cry'd, d - n the Cane, 'tis not worth Three-pence</p>
               <p>Anthill. I happened to come by and saw the Gentleman lying in the Street, there was Atkins the Constable's Son with me, but I have no Money to Subpoena him. I own I was by at the same Time; all the Woman has said is Spight, because I would not live with her. I have no Friends here at present.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Anthill. I am a <rs id="t17361208-74-deflabel369" type="occupation">Baker's Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361208-74-defend527 t17361208-74-deflabel369"></join> in Rose-Street.</p>
               <p>Waters. I shall prove I was at Home all that Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person552">
                  Thomas 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person552" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person552" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Waters's Mother's House that Night with the Prisoner, and his Brother Jack, and Mr. Target, from Six, till Half an Hour after Ten; I did not see him go out of the House all that Time. He came down Stairs to us between Seven and Eight in a Dishabille and undrest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person553">
                  Daniel 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person553" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person553" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person553" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Moss's that Night the Gentleman was found in the Old Baily, from four or five, till ten o'Clock; I left the Prisoner Waters at Home; I was going into Black-and-White Court to one Mr. Crane, a Cabinet-Maker, and passing up the Old Baily, I saw the Gentleman lie, I thought he was fuddled; I did not stay by him above two or three Minutes, nor did I take Notice of any of the People that were about him.</p>
               <p>Target. I was at Mrs. Moss's House, the Prisoner's Mother, the Sign of the Hospital-Gate in Smithfield, from eight till eleven that Night, and he was not absent at all from eight till eleven, except when he went down to draw Beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361208-74-person554">
                  Phoebe 
                  Hinson 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person554" type="surname" value="Hinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person554" type="given" value="Phoebe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person554" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Night one 
               <persName id="t17361208-74-person555">
                  Dickey 
                  Sawyer 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person555" type="surname" value="Sawyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person555" type="given" value="Dickey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person555" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17361208-74-person556">
                  Margaret 
                  Franklyn 
               <interp inst="t17361208-74-person556" type="surname" value="Franklyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person556" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-person556" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were charged with this Murder. All <rs id="t17361208-74-verdict370" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361208-74-verdict370" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
