<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-43">
               <interp inst="t17370907-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-43" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-43" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-43-off222-c221" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-43-defend308 t17370907-43-off222 t17370907-43-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>46 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-defend308" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Runnington 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-43-defend308" type="surname" value="Runnington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-defend308" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-defend308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370907-43-defloc221">Allhallows Honey-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-43-defloc221" type="placeName" value="Allhallows Honey-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-43-defloc221" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-43-defend308 t17370907-43-defloc221"></join>, was indicted for that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c<rs id="t17370907-43-off222" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-off222" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-off222" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               . on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-43-victim310" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Reynolds 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-43-victim310" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-43-victim310" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-43-victim310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-43-off222 t17370907-43-victim310"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an Assault, and a certain Knife made of Iron and Steel, value 6 d. at and against the Body of the said Reynolds did cast and throw, giving him a mortal Wound of the Length of one Inch, and the Depth of 2 Inches, on the right side of the Belly, near the Groin of the said Reynolds; of which mortal Wound he languish'd from the 24th to the 25th of August, and then died
            </rs> in the Parish of <placeName id="t17370907-43-crimeloc223">St. Bartholomew the Less</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-43-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="St. Bartholomew the Less"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-43-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-43-off222 t17370907-43-crimeloc223"></join>. He was likewise charged by Vertue of an Inquisition taken by the Coroner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-person311">
                  Sarah 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person311" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person311" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person311" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent to Market on an Errand, and there I saw Watts the Butcher-woman tussling with the Prisoner, she held him with his Arms confin'd a-cross, and his Back against the Wall. Another Butcher-woman standing by, bid the Deceased go and assist the Woman; he went accordingly, and putting his Arms round the Woman's Waste, he pull'd her aside; then he pushed the Prisoner to the outside of the Stall. Upon this, the Prisoner came up and struck the Deceased a Blow in his Face, and the Deceased pushed him by the Side of the Stall, on the outside. Then the Prisoner turn'd round, and went behind the Stall, and took a Carver, and threw it at the Deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the Deceased from the Prisoner at this Time?</p>
               <p>Williams. About 3 Yards. - The Prisoner took up the Knife by the Handle, and threw it directly at him, so it stabb'd him on the right Side, - in his Bowels, a little above the Wastband of his Breeches.</p>
               <p>Counc. When the Deceased came to part the Prisoner and the Woman, did he tell him any Thing of his Design?</p>
               <p>Williams. I did not hear him say any Thing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner striking the Woman?</p>
               <p>Williams. No, she held him confin'd, with his Back against the Wall.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from them when the Blow was given?</p>
               <p>Williams. About 5 Yards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-person312">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sanney 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person312" type="surname" value="Sanney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person312" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When this Accident happen'd I was at my Stall, about 10 Yards distant from the Place where the Deceased stood when he receiv'd the Hurt. The Prisoner and Mrs. Watts were quarrelling and scolding, so she got up and struck the Prisoner several Blows, and held him up against the Wall. Upon this, the Deceased's Mistress bid him go up and part them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that said so loud that the Prisoner could hear it?</p>
               <p>Sanney. I don't know that. The Deceased went up to the Prisoner, and asked him how he could strike a Woman with Child?</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner strike the Woman?</p>
               <p>Sanney. I believe he did strike her once; but whether the Deceased struck the Prisoner first, - or the Prisoner, - the Deceased, I can't tell. I saw the Deceased strike the Prisoner up against the Stall, when the Woman was sat down in her Chair; her Stall is just a-cross the Row. Then the Prisoner turn'd short, and snatch'd up a Knife, and flung it at the Deceased; he did not dart it, but flung it at him; I did not see where it struck him, because I was in the Inside of my Stall.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know of any intimacy there was between the Prisoner and the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Sanney. Yes, I can safely swear there was no Malice in the Case.</p>
               <p>Jury. We ask whether the Knife lay by the Prisoner, or whether he went from the Place where he stood to take it?</p>
               <p>Sanney. I was very much surprized: but to the best of my Knowledge it lay by him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-person313">
                  William 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person313" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person313" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Watts beating the Prisoner, and he retired 3 or 4 Steps back against the Wall. Mrs. Smith the Deceased's Mistress, bid him go and part them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe how they stood together, when Smith bid the Deceased part them?</p>
               <p>White. Yes, Watts struck him 2 or 3 Times in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070033"></xptr>the Face, then took hold of both his Hands, and held them cross his Breast, with his Back against the Wall, behind the Stall. The Deceased stepp'd up to him, gave him a Push on the Breast, and said, what will you strike a Woman, - or a Woman with Child, and immediately the Woman withdrew, and the Deceased along with her. They were obliged to come through a little Passage from the Place where the Prisoner stood. The Woman went to her Stall, and the Deceas'd turn'd about and said something to the Prisoner; upon which the Prisoner turn'd about and catched up the Knife and flung it at him. I believe he might be 3 or 4 Yards from the Deceased when he did it; there was not more than a Minute between the Woman's retiring and the giving the Blow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Deceased do any Thing to the Prisoner after the Woman was retired.</p>
               <p>White. No, there was some Words passed between them I believe, but the Deceased never went near him after the Woman withdrew. I saw the Deceased draw the Knife out of his Body, just above the Wastband of his Breeches; he dropt it down, then clapp'd his Hands upon the Place and walk'd by me directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any Intimacy between them?</p>
               <p>White. I believe but very few Days passed, wherein they did not eat and drink together.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not the Deceased push the Prisoner after the Woman was gone?</p>
               <p>White. No, he never came near him, and the Prisoner never stirr'd a Yard from the Wall 'till the Knife was flung.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Words that passed between the Prisoner and the Deceased, after the Woman retir'd?</p>
               <p>White. I did not take Notice of them. The Prisoner was crying, (weeping) and the Knife lay at his left Hand, my Eyes were not off them 'till the Wound was given.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner strike the Woman?</p>
               <p>White. No, he did not strike her at all.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Deceased turn'd, and the Words passed between him and the Prisoner, do you think he had any Intention to offer any Violence to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>White. No.</p>
               <p>Q. To Sanney. Did not you say you saw the Deceased strike the Prisoner up against the Stall after the Woman was retir'd?</p>
               <p>Sanney. Yes, I saw the Deceased strike the Prisoner after Watts was retir'd, I think it was after, to the best of my Knowledge: He struck the Prisoner before the Knife was flung.</p>
               <p>Q. Mr. White says, the Deceased was not near enough to strike the Prisoner at all, and you say, he struck him up against the Stall.</p>
               <p>Sanney. Yes, after Watts retir'd, the Deceased struck him, and before the Knife was thrown.</p>
               <p>Q. To 
               <persName id="t17370907-43-person314">
                  Sarah 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person314" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person314" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you observe the Deceased strike the Prisoner after the Woman was gone?</p>
               <p>Williams. No, the Deceased struck him in the Face, just at the Time that he put the Woman away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-person315">
                  John 
                  Greatrex 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person315" type="surname" value="Greatrex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not see the Quarrel begin but I stood at a Stall, and saw the Prisoner going in a great Passion behind his Stall, and the Deceased stepp'd into the Passage, and gave the Prisoner a Shove, to hinder him from going by; upon that, the Prisoner gave the Deceased a Blow, and the Deceased gave the Prisoner a Stroke on the Side of the Neck. Then the Prisoner brush'd by the Deceased and catch'd up the Carver that lay behind the Stall, and turn'd himself about, and threw it over an empty Stall at the Deceased. This was all done in an Instant.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Watts there at that Time?</p>
               <p>Greatrex. No. I believe the Thing was done in a Passion, for I have often seen the Prisoner and the Deceased eating and drinking together.</p>
               <p>Watts, the Butcher-woman. The Prisoner was saucy, so I slapp'd his Chops; then he call'd me Names, and I follow'd him behind the Stall and slapp'd his Chops again, and held him with his Arms a-cross against the Wall: When I had done I ran directly to my Chair; I don't remember the Prisoner struck me at all. My Chair stood about 5 Yards from the Place where I beat the Prisoner, and I had not sat down a Moment, before I heard the Deceased shriek out; I turn'd to see what was the Matter, and saw the Knife drop down. The Deceased walked away, and I saw no more of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear somebody speak to the Deceased to come to your Assistance?</p>
               <p>Watts. I don't remember it.</p>
               <p>Counc. Don't you know that the Deceased and the Prisoner were intimate Friends?</p>
               <p>Watts. They were always very great. I believe there was no Malice - only Heat and Passion, - they were like two Brothers.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say you did not hear any Body bid the Deceased come and help you?</p>
               <p>Watts. No.</p>
               <p>Counc. Then consequently the Prisoner could not hear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-43-person316">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370907-43-person316" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person316" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased's Mistress. Watts and the Prisoner were quarrelling, so I said to my Man (the Deceased) step up, he'll do the foolish Woman a Mischief. I saw no more.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070034"></xptr>Q. What Distance was you from the Place where the Deceased and the Prisoner were?</p>
               <p>Ann Smith. About three Yards; I saw the Deceased pull the Knife out of his Bowels.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was there any Intimacy between the Prisoner and the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Smith. They were like 2 Brothers.</p>
               <p>The Surgeon The Patient was brought to me just after he received the Wound; 'twas upon the lower Part of the Belly, and was undoubtedly the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>Defence. That Woman - Watts, - came and slapp'd me, and the Deceased took her Part and struck me, and call'd me Son of a Bitch, - tho' I lov'd him as well as if he had been my own Brother, and as such we almost always eat and drank together. I have repented as much, since I did it, as if it had been my Father.</p>
               <p>Mr. White, Mrs. Sanney, and Mrs. Smith, gave the Prisoner the Character of an easy, innocent, honest Fellow.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Horton. The major Part of the Night, that the Deceased dyed, I sat up with him (I am a Sister in St. Bartholomew's Hospital.) The Deceased pray'd to God to forgive the Prisoner; he said he was sure he did not do it willingly, and was very uneasy when he heard he was taken up, and blam'd himself that he should meddle in Contentions that he had no Business with.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17370907-43-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-verdict224" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               Acquitted the Prisoner and found 
                     <persName id="t17370907-43-person317">
                        William 
                        Reynold 
                     <interp inst="t17370907-43-person317" type="surname" value="Reynold"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-43-person317" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-43-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  's Death, Accidental
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
