<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-36">
               <interp inst="t17360721-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-36" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-36" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-36-off166-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-defend286 t17360721-36-off166 t17360721-36-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>41  
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-defend286" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Hussey 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-36-defend286" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-defend286" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-36-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               marrying 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-36-victim288" type="victimName">
                           Margaret 
                           Beauchamp 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim288" type="surname" value="Beauchamp"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim288" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . at the <placeName id="t17360721-36-crimeloc167">Parish of Stepney</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-crimeloc167" type="placeName" value="Parish of Stepney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-crimeloc167" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-off166 t17360721-36-crimeloc167"></join>, <rs id="t17360721-36-cd168" type="crimeDate">June 13</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-off166 t17360721-36-cd168"></join> last, his former <rs id="t17360721-36-viclabel169" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-victim290 t17360721-36-viclabel169"></join> 
                  Sarah
                   being then living
               
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Council. This Prosecution is for Bigamy; an Offence which the Prisoner has committed in marrying two Wives. On the 9th of September, in the 7th Year of his Majesty, he married 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-victim290" type="victimName">
                     Sarah 
                     Seaton 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim290" type="surname" value="Seaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim290" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-victim290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and afterwards on the 13th of June last, he married Margaret Beauchamp: We shall clearly prove both Marriages, and then you'll find him guilty of the Offence. We shall produce a Clergyman, who married two People in the Names of Robert Hussey and Sarah Seaton, and shall prove that they co-habited together some Years, and the Children were looked on as the legitimate Issue of this Marriage.</p>
               <p>Dr. Gainham. The 9th of September, 1733. I married a Couple at the Rainbow-Coffee-house the Corner of Fleet-Ditch, and entered the Marriage in my Register. As fair a Register as any Church in England can produce. I shewed it last Night to the Fore-man of the Jury, and my Lord Mayor's Clerk, at the London Punch-House.</p>
               <p>Reads.</p>
               <p>Robert Hussey, of St. James's Westminster, Batchelor; and Sarah Setyon of St. Martin's in the Fields, Spinster. - As fair a Register as any Church can produce, and 'tis all my own Hand-writing. The Persons I won't swear to. This Certificate is all my Writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you the Names of these People?</p>
               <p>Dr. Gainham. The Man gives always the Names of both, and the Parishes where they live. A Spinster, is as much as to say a single Woman.</p>
               <p>Council. Are not you ashamed to come and own a clandestine Marriage in the Face of a Court of Justice?</p>
               <p>Dr. Gainham. (Bowing) Video meliora, deteriora sequor.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know any Thing of it, But by that Paper?</p>
               <p>Dr. Gainbam. Yes, I'll swear to my Register: 'tis as fair a Register as any Church in England can show you. This Paper is a Copy from my Register, and I examined it by my Register.</p>
               <p>Q. You are on your Oath: I ask you whether you never enter Marriages in that Book, when there's no Marriage at all?</p>
               <p>Gainbam. I never did in my Life. I page my Book so, that it cannot be altered, and all Marriages are put down Alphabetically, that I can very readily find them.</p>
               <p>Council. Pray who directed you, to shew that Paper to the Fore-man of the Jury?</p>
               <p>Gainham. My own common Judgment, Sir: because I thought I could not be here to Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person291">
                  Mary 
                  Stallwood 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person291" type="surname" value="Stallwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner, he has been very often at my House, and owned 
               <persName id="t17360721-36-person292">
                  Sarah 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person292" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person292" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for his Wife: I have been at her Lyings to, she appeared publickly as his Wife, and he owned her as such. I am Sarah Hussey's Aunt, and an honest Girl she is. They have lived three Years together: he is a <rs id="t17360721-36-deflabel170" type="occupation">Frame-Guilder</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-defend286 t17360721-36-deflabel170"></join>, and has been at my House many and many a Time, and supped there, and always owned her for his Wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person293">
                  Ann 
                  Humphries 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person293" type="surname" value="Humphries"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person293" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner, and the Prisoner knows me, as well as I know him. He and his Wife lived next Door to me. I visited her as a Neighbour, and Mrs. Hussey visited me: They passed for Man and Wife, all over the Street. They lived at Mrs. Whittle's, in Brownlow-street; they lived there more than a Year or two, and all the Time no one made any Objections to their being Man and Wife; I have often been in Company with them; once I was abroad with them, and they behaved as other Men and their Wives do.</p>
               <p>Council. Have you never been abroad with a Gentleman that has had a Mistress?</p>
               <p>Humphries. I know nothing of them; but as Man and Wife.</p>
               <p>Council. Why, you may have seen a Man use his Mistress very kindly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person294">
                  James 
                  Whittle 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person294" type="surname" value="Whittle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person294" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was my Journeyman, and Sarah Hussey lived with him in my House two Years and a half. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210017"></xptr> was satisfied they were married, else they should not have lived in my House.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever question them about it? Had you ever any Doubt of it?</p>
               <p>Whittle. He was about to leave her, and I perswaded him to stay; and told him, it was the Part of every honest Man to stay with his Wife and Children; then he said he was not married. I told him then he should not live in my House; I would go and see whether he was or not. I went, and this Gentleman (Dr. Gainham) remembered the Marriage, and I saw the Register fair and clear; I came home and told him I had seen the Register, and he said he knew that before I went. I was God-father to his Children, and with his own Mouth, he ordered one of them to be registered.</p>
               <p>Council. Such Evidence as this, such presumptive Evidence has always been rejected, 'till the Fact be established.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own this last Marriage.</p>
               <p>Q. Cannot a Man come and confess a Felony, and is not his own Confession to bind him? If a Man confesses himself guilty of Bigamy, shall not that be Evidence?</p>
               <p>Council. This is only presumptive Evidence, and the Consequence of admitting it may be dangerous.</p>
               <p>A Parish Clerk. I was called to two Christenings, at Mr. Whittles; I don't know the Man, but I registered two Children in such Names.</p>
               <p>Mr. Whittle I heard him give Directions, and saw the Clerk take those Directions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person295">
                  John 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person295" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with Mr. Martin, when he took up the Prisoner; and I asked him how he could be so wicked as to deceive the young Girl? How he could marry her, having a Wife alive, and this other Woman says she is your Wife?</p>
               <p>As to the Wickedness of it, says he, 'tis not so wicked as you imagine: I don't deny but I am married to this Woman, (Sarah Hussey); but as to the Wickedness of it, you'll forgive me; I have had a learned Council's Opinion of it, a Seajeant at Law, and he says, the Marriage with this Woman, is a very bad one, because I had another at the same Time; another Wife before this; I have had Council's Opinion, says he, and I shall hold the Woman I have married now. We had this Discourse at Sir 
               <persName id="t17360721-36-person296">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person296" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person296" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Mr. Martin. I know the Prisoner owned the second Marriage.</p>
               <p>Council. It must be granted me, that here is only circumstantial Proof; as to the Registring of Children, there is nothing at all in that. But we say, he could not have a Marriage at this Time for at the Time he was married to this Seaton, he had a Wife, and she did not dye, till 6 Months after this pretended Marriage.</p>
               <p>Court. Our Business is not to annul the Marriage, but to punish.</p>
               <p>Council. If the first Wife was living, the second Woman could not be a Wife, neither de Jure, nor de Facto.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person297">
                  Mary 
                  Brothers 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person297" type="surname" value="Brothers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person297" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the Mother of the first Wife; her Name was Elenor Brothers; she was married to the Prisoner at St. Martin's Tabernacle: I saw them married, and her Father gave her away; she died, March was two Years ago. I do not remember who married them, for I have been out of my Senses since that Time.</p>
               <p>The 16th Day of September, she was in the 10th Year of her Marriage, and she has been dead above two Years. I think she died in March.</p>
               <p>Council. And their Marriage was in September 1733, then she must have been alive at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she live with this Man?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Brothers. Yes, 8 Years, but at last they did not agree, and so they parted. I went and carried my Daughter to her, and told her, (Seaton) that this was Mr. Hussey's Wife. This second Marriage broke my poor Daughter's Heart, and made me run out of my Senses.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you hear the Prisoner at the Bar was married to this Girl, (Seaton) before your Daughter's Death?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Brothers. Yes, yes, this Girl told me she was married to him; and my Daughter<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210018"></xptr> liv'd 2 Years after that. My Daughter and I went twice to her; the first Time she did not tell me she was married; but the second she did, and that she was married at St. Brides.</p>
               <p>Council. We have prov'd he was married to these 2 Women, in Court; now the Proof they would set up, is, that he was married before, and antecedent to each of these Marriages; that he had a Wife when he married the Woman first mentioned in the indictment, and therefore that this Marriage was void.</p>
               <p>Council. I did object that here was no positive Evidence of the first Marriage mentioned in the Indictment; and I do say, I don't remember any Case, where on this Act of Parliament, circumstantial Proof was ever given in Evidence, without there was some positive Evidence likewise.</p>
               <p>Q. If the Prisoner confess'd his Marriage, is that circumstantial Evidence?</p>
               <p>Council. I objected it was not sufficient for this Reason: It has been too licentious a Custom for People to live together, who have never been married; and they call one another my Dear and my Wife, and if you ask whether they are married, yes to be sure, they'll tell you; they would not expose, and bring a scandal upon themselves. But on this Act, it being a Felony, what I submit to the Court is, whether there ought not to be some solid Proof in this Case. This was not a Marriage Facie Eclesia, but a Fleet Marriage, and should be prov'd either by some Body who gave her away, or who saw the Book opened and read, 'tis not sufficient I think without some solid Proof of this Kind; but your Lordship thinks it sufficient Evidence to be left to the Jury.</p>
               <p>Council. The first Marriage (in the Indictment) if it is to be made void, must be annulled by an Ecclesiastical Censure; this has not been done, it has not been voided by an Ecclesiastical Censure, therefore the Marriage is good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person298">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person298" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner married to 
               <persName id="t17360721-36-person299">
                  Elener 
                  Brothers 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person299" type="surname" value="Brothers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person299" type="given" value="Elener"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in St. Martin's Tabernacle, 12 or 13 Years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-36-person300">
                  Peter 
                  Abel 
               <interp inst="t17360721-36-person300" type="surname" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person300" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner: His Wife Elenor died in the Street in York Buildings, over against the Sun-Tavern. upon a Bench in the Street, I saw her draw her last Breath; it was in 1734 or 1733-4.</p>
               <p>Council. I have one Thing I would just mention; Gainham said he shew'd the Certificate of this Marriage to the Fore-man of the Jury beforehand; I must leave it to the Court whether that should not take off his Testimony. <rs id="t17360721-36-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17360721-36-punish172" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-punish172" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-36-punish172" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-36-defend286 t17360721-36-punish172"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
