<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340710-17">
               <interp inst="t17340710-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-17" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340710-17" type="date" value="17340710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off63-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend106 t17340710-17-off63 t17340710-17-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off63-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend109 t17340710-17-off63 t17340710-17-verdict68"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off64-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend106 t17340710-17-off64 t17340710-17-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off64-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend109 t17340710-17-off64 t17340710-17-verdict68"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off65-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend106 t17340710-17-off65 t17340710-17-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340710-17-off65-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend109 t17340710-17-off65 t17340710-17-verdict68"></join>
         
               <p>19, 20 
               <persName id="t17340710-17-defend106" type="defendantName">
                  Mary
                   Haycock
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend106" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend106" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (<rs id="t17340710-17-deflabel62" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend106 t17340710-17-deflabel62"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17340710-17-person107">
                  John 
                  Haycock 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person107" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17340710-17-defend109" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Haycock 
                  <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend109" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend109" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-defend109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             her Daughter, were indicted for <rs id="t17340710-17-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               High Teason, for having in their Custody a Pair of wooden Flasks for Coining
            </rs>, without any lawful Cause. They were a second Time <rs id="t17340710-17-off64" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off64" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off64" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               indicted for concealing the said Flasks
            </rs>: And a third time for <rs id="t17340710-17-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               Coining 3 false and counterfeit Six pences
            </rs>, <rs id="t17340710-17-cd66" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off63 t17340710-17-cd66"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off64 t17340710-17-cd66"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off65 t17340710-17-cd66"></join>.</p>
               <p>The first and second Indictments appearing defective , the Prisoners were then try'd on the third.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-17-person110">
                  Ann 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person110" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person110" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners were discharged out of Newgate the Sessions before last, and the very Night of their being set at Liberty, they came to Lodge in my Room, in Drury-Lane, almost facing Backer's-Lane. I saw them do nothing there, but in 2 or 3 Weeks my Landlord was put to a Nonplush, and so we were all forced to move - Then I took a Room up two Pair of Stairs in Mrs. Weaver's House in <placeName id="t17340710-17-crimeloc67">Baldwin's-Gardens</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-17-crimeloc67" type="placeName" value="Baldwin's-Gardens"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340710-17-crimeloc67" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off63 t17340710-17-crimeloc67"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off64 t17340710-17-crimeloc67"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-off65 t17340710-17-crimeloc67"></join>, and the Prisoners went with me. I had 2 Beds, the old Woman 
               <persName id="t17340710-17-person111">
                  Mary 
                  Haycock 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person111" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person111" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lay with me (for my Husband who is a Shoemaker, worked at Battersea ) and her Daughter 
               <persName id="t17340710-17-person112">
                  Ann 
                  Haycock 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person112" type="surname" value="Haycock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person112" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another lay together in the other Bed - There was a little Closet in the Room with a Door to it, but no Lock nor Key, where we used to put odd Things out of the way. It was darkish, tho' not so dark neither, but one could see common Things. The old Woman used often to take a Candle and go into this Closet, and shut the Door, and stay there a pretty while. The Daughter seldom went in but when she was call'd.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know what the old Woman did there?</p>
               <p>Russel. I thought she was at Work.</p>
               <p>Council. What Work?</p>
               <p>Russel Coining.</p>
               <p>Council. What reason had you to think so?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100004"></xptr>Russel. She had been try'd at Hicks's-Hall for putting off bad Money, but was discharged, and I was in hopes she was innocent when I took her in to Lodge with me. But one Night, when I was in Bed, I heard her blowing the Fire, upon which I got up anend, an asked her what she was about; she said, No harm - There was an Instrument full of Whiting, which was a Mould, that lay upon the Hearth; she put some Metal into two Tobacco-pipes, and put them into the Fire, and when the Metal was melted, she took the Mold in one Hand and the Pipe in another, and Teem'd [ pour'd ] the Metal into the Mold, and afterwards open'd it, and took out a Six-pence, and put it into her Pocket Apron, and so she did several times, but her Daughter was not with her all that Time. Mrs. Haycock (says I) I thought you were not guilty of such Things, but since I find how it is, in my Room you shall stay no longer: she said I need not be so uneasy, for no harm should come to me. This was on a Tuesday Night.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. And why did not you inform sooner?</p>
               <p>Russel. Because I did not know who to apply to, but upon enquiring I found out Mr. North who belongs to the Mint.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you see the Girl Ann Haycock do any thing?</p>
               <p>Russel. I came up Stairs one Day, and knock'd at the Door, the Mother asked who was there? I said it was I, she did not open the Door directly, but when I got in, I saw two Pipes in the Fire, and the Mold upon the Hearth. She took the Pipes out and laid them aside, and put the Mold into her Apron, and her Daughter was then with her. I did not then see the Daughter do any thing. But once I saw the Daughter boiling something in a little Tin-pot, I look'd into the Pot, and there was 14 or 15 Shillings and Six-pences. I ask'd her what she was doing, but she took the Pot away and said it did not concern me - There was a sort of Red stuff in the Pot - Another time I saw the Girl with several Six-pences in her Lap, and she was rubbing them with Whiting.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. On the 27th of May, Ann Russel gave me much the same Account as she has given now - I appointed to meet her on Saturday, June 1, and accordingly, taking two (Mr. Morris and Mr. Atkins ) to assist me, we met. The Street Door was open: We went up softly, and Atkins being foremost he push'd against the Door of the Room, and it gave way, and we went in. The old Woman made a great Outcry of Murder, and was so turbulent, that we were oblig'd to tye her Hands, tho' we had some difficulty in doing it. There was a Candle in the Closet - Atkins said that he saw something glitter in a little notch in the Floor, just by the Wall, and there he found two counterfeit Six-pences, which he gave to me: Morris found three more, and these are the five - I take them to be nothing but Pewter. There were several Rags and Pieces of Leather that seem'd to be whited with Whiting. There was a Deal-box too: I ask'd the Girl for the Key of it, she said it belong'd to a young Woman who was gone out, and had taken the Key with her; upon which I was going to break it open, but upon second thoughts I resolv'd to search the old Woman first. I did so, and in her Pocket found this Key. It fitted the Lock, and I open'd the Box with it. There was a pretty deal of Cambrick in the Box, and several odd Things of little value, which I suppose they had bought in putting off their bad Money. At last I met with this Pair of wooden Flasks for Coining: The way is, to fill these with fine powder'd Chalk, and then make an impression of the Money they design to Counterfeit; there was likewise this little Box of Red Argol: 'Tis what the Silver-smiths Use, by boiling it with the Silver they have cast, to fetch the sand out of the Pores of the Silver, and cleanse it from dirt and soil. It appears to be the same that the last Evidence observed in the Tin-pot when the Girl was boiling the Counterfeit Money, for here is that Pot (which we found in the Closet) and some of the Argol is still sticking about the sides.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. Was I in the Closet, or the Room when you came in?</p>
               <p>Mr. North. I am not certain which, but I think you were near the Closet, if not in it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173407100005"></xptr>M. Haycock. I was just stept into the Closet with a Candle in my Hand to fetch a Dish to take up my Husband's Dinner.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. When I first open'd the Box the Daughter desir'd me not to take the Linnen away, because it was all they shou'd have to live upon in Newgate. When I came to the Flasks, I said to her, You pretend to a great deal of Innocence; but how came you by these? She pleaded Ignorance; but while I was searching farther, she turn'd aside to her Mother, and said softly, Mother we are gone!</p>
               <p>I carried them before my Lord Mayor, and then I return'd to the Room, to see what else I cou'd meet with. I poked among the Ashes, where I found some dross, and little pieces of Metal, and several Tobacco-pipes, that look'd as if they had been burnt in the Fire.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. Any body might happen to have a burnt Pipe in their Room.</p>
               <p>Mr. North. But these Pipes had Metal in them, and it was run a good way up the holes - Here is one that is broke, but the pieces hang together by the Lead.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. Did you find any bad Money upon me when you searched me?</p>
               <p>Mr. North. No - I found some Money, but it was good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-17-person113">
                  Henry 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person113" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person113" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I assisted Mr. North. I went up first, and found the Door ty'd with a piece of red Tape. I push'd it open, and went directly into the Closet, where the Mother was kneeling or sitting with a Candle in her hand; she set up a terrible Irish Hallaloo. I pull'd her out into the Room, but she was so very troublesome that we were forced to tye her Hands. I saw something glitter in a Crevice in the Closet Floor, just by the Wall; upon examining, I found two counterfeit Six-pences, which I gave to Mr. North. I heard him ask the Girl for the Key, and heard her say, that another young Woman had got it; and saw him take it from the old Woman, and open the Box, and found the Flasks; but I did not hear what the Girl said to the old Woman - And I was with Mr. North when he found the Pipes with the Metal in them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-17-person114">
                  Henry 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person114" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person114" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Clerk to Mr. North. Mr. Atkins went in first, and got the old Woman out of the Room; she made a great Noise and resisted; and thereupon we ty'd her Hands. Mr. North asked for the Key; it was deny'd, but he found it on the old Woman, and open'd the Box, and as soon as he found the Flasks, she fell into a greater Agony than before, and shriek'd out, Murder and Thieves! Atkins found 2 Six-pences, and I found 3 more.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. It was not my Box, but Mrs Russel's where the Things were found.</p>
               <p>Russel. That's true, but I lent her the Box to put her Things in, and I made no use of it while she was there.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. I had no occasion for a Box, for I had not a ha'porth of any thing to put into one, having been 5 Weeks in Prison, where I and my Daughter got the Jail Distemper - And I have 6 Children - It's very strange that after I had suffer'd so much on Suspicion of putting off bad Money, I shou'd venture to Coin in an open Room, that had no Lock to the Door: And besides, there was another Woman, Katherine Kelly, constantly in the same Room, and therefore they only swear this against me, for the sake of a Reward. Here, Mrs. Kelly - Pray</p>
               <p>Mrs. Kelly did you ever see me Coin? or handle any bad Money? or see any body come after me with bad Money? or see me sit up later than ordinary?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340710-17-person115">
                  Katherine 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17340710-17-person115" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person115" type="given" value="Katherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No.</p>
               <p>M. Haycock. And I defy all the World to say otherwise.</p>
               <p>Council. But some part of the World have sworn otherwise.</p>
               <p>Council. What Country Woman are you?</p>
               <p>Kelly. An Irish Woman - I lay in the same Room with the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Russel. Yes, she was in the same Room but she was a Bed and asleep when the Prisoner made the Six-pences.</p>
               <p>Kelly. I might be asleep, I don't deny that.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17340710-17-verdict68" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-verdict68" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Daughter, and found the Mother <rs id="t17340710-17-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17340710-17-punish70" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-punish70" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340710-17-punish70" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="burning"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend106 t17340710-17-punish70"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340710-17-defend109 t17340710-17-punish70"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
