<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-16">
               <interp inst="t17370907-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-16" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-16" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-16-off88-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-defend128 t17370907-16-off88 t17370907-16-verdict92"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-16-off88-c95" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-defend130 t17370907-16-off88 t17370907-16-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>18, 19. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-defend128" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Franklin 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend128" type="surname" value="Franklin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend128" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-defend130" type="defendantName">
                     Dorrel 
                     Smalt 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend130" type="surname" value="Smalt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend130" type="given" value="Dorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-defend130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17370907-16-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-16-victim132" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim132" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim132" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the Hour of 12 in the Night Time, and stealing thence 12 Yards of leaden Pipe, and a brass Cock fixed thereto, val. 38 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-victim134" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Hoare 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim134" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim134" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-victim136" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim136" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim136" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-victim136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370907-16-cd89" type="crimeDate">June 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-off88 t17370907-16-cd89"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-person137">
                  Richard 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person137" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person137" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Man (
               <persName id="t17370907-16-person138">
                  Joseph 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person138" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person138" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) came and surrender'd himself to me, in order to make himself an Evidence for the King; and he made an Information before my Lord Mayor of Several Thefts and Street-Robberies, in which he had been concern'd with the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Joseph Smith. On the 3d, of June last, the two Prisoners Franklin and Smalt, met at Tom Gale's House; 'tis a disorderly House in Black and White-Court in the Old-Bailey, for the entertainment of lewd Women. We came thither from Smalt's House, and we staid at Gale's 'till about 12 at Night. Smalt keeps a House in Fleet-lane himself, for the harbouring of such People, and there I became acquainted with him and Franklin. While we sat Drinking at Gale's, Smalt said he wanted Money, and Tom Gale told Dorrel that he was informed, that he (Dorrel) had taken to the Lead-Lay, and that he understood that Lay very well. Says Dorrel Smalt, yes, I formerly went out on that Lay, and my Custom was to walk the City and Suburbs in the Day Time, and observe where Cocks and Pipes were fixed; the Places I used to set down, and at Night I went and took them up. He (Smalt) asked me and Franklin, whether we would go and rob an adjacent House of a Pipe that was there? It was a House inhabited by one 
               <persName id="t17370907-16-person139">
                  Richard 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person139" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person139" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17370907-16-viclabel90" type="occupation">Printer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-victim132 t17370907-16-viclabel90"></join>. We agreed, and accordingly about 12, we went out of Tom Gales House and got into the Yard; then we broke down a Partition next to the Ground Floor of the House, and by that Means we got into the House: this Partition joins to the House, and is a part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a Part of the Wall of the House?</p>
               <p>Smith. 'Twas a boarded Partition, and join'd to the House.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you call it a Partition?</p>
               <p>Smith. It parted the House from the Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the Fence of the House it self?</p>
               <p>Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get into the House?</p>
               <p>Smith. By breaking down the boarded Partition: Part of the Pipe was in this boarded Partition. When we had broke into the House, we took the Case off the Pipe, and cut away about 2 Yards, or 2 Yards and a half, with the Brass Cock in it, and we carry'd it to Tom Gales.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get out of the House again?</p>
               <p>Smith. The Way we got in.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the House was the Cock and Pipe in.</p>
               <p>Smith. On the Ground Floor. Smalt and Franklin went into the House, and I watched in the Yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the Lead?</p>
               <p>Smith. We broke it to Pieces at Tom Gale's House, and then we carry'd it to Smalt's Room, in Black-Boy Alley in Chick-Lane. The next Night, the 4th of June we met at Gale's again, and about 12 at Night we went to the same House and took up the Frame of the Cellar Window, Bars and all; then the 2 Prisoners went in thro' the Window, and brought out of the House the remaining part of the Pipe. The whole that we took was about 12 or 13 Yards, and Smalt sold it to one White, who liv'd next Door to him. I have enquired after this White, and I hear he is dead.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it sold for?</p>



               <p>Smith. Smalt said he could get no more than 4 s 6 d. for it, and that we shar'd among us. I made my self a voluntary Evidence, and according<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070013"></xptr> to my Directions, the Constable went to Smalt's House, and found 2 Pistols loaded, in a Box under his Bed: they were Joe Emmerson's Pistols, and were given Smalt by 
               <persName id="t17370907-16-person140">
                  Sarah 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person140" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person140" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who belonged to Mac Cray's Gang.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-person141">
                  John 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person141" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person141" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Barber in <placeName id="t17370907-16-crimeloc91">Black and White Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-crimeloc91" type="placeName" value="Black and White Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-16-crimeloc91" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-off88 t17370907-16-crimeloc91"></join>. The Cock and Pipe which they stole served me with Water, and I know there is so much lost as is laid in the Indictment. The House was broke open twice, but the particular Times I can't tell. I have always had a Suspicion of that Franklin the Sailor.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the House broke?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. There was a Board thro' which the Cock came, and the first Night that Board was broke down, and the Cock stole. The Board was about 9 or 10 Inches wide, and 2 Foot, or 2 Foot and a half high; if that is removed, any Person may enter side-ways. After this, the Frame of the Cellar Window was taken away, with all the Bars, and, as much Pipe as to come to 12 Yards. Mr. Porter in Turn-again Lane was the Plumber that put the Pipe down again, and he charges 38 s. for 12 Yards of Pipe and a Cock. I know they used to be frequently at this Gale's, and he kept a disorderly House. I have seen the Evidence and the 2 Prisoners backward and forward there several Times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-person142">
                  Sam 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person142" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person142" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the Constable and the Accomplice when the 2 Pistols loaded were found in Smalt's Box, by the Evidence's Directions.</p>
               <p>Q. How comes it that Richard Walker is not here?</p>
               <p>Davis. Walker only rents a Room in the House to publish in 2 or 3 Times a Week. The House belongs to Messieurs Hoar and Smith, as Assignees to 
               <persName id="t17370907-16-person143">
                  Thomas 
                  Darlow 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person143" type="surname" value="Darlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person143" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner Franklin. At the Time they swear this Robbery was committed, I was confined in New-Prison, Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370907-16-person144">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person144" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person144" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was then Keeper of the Prison. Here is a Copy of my Committment, dated June 2.</p>
               <p>Accomplice. I think it was in June, - the latter End of May, or the beginning of June, that we robb'd this House.</p>
               <p>Q. Why you was precise as to the Day, in the beginning of your Evidence.</p>
               <p>Accomplice. In my Information I set down the latter End of May, or the beginning of June, but when I gave Instructions for drawing the Indictment, I was told I must fix upon a particular Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-person145">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person145" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Turn-key of New-Prison, this is a Copy of Franklin's Commitment, and I know it to be Mr. Gavannah's (the Keeper's) own Hand Writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-16-person146">
                  William 
                  Belt 
               <interp inst="t17370907-16-person146" type="surname" value="Belt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person146" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I mov'd Franklin from New-Prison to Newgate last Sessions.</p>
               <p>Tho.Smith. At that Time I enter'd every Thing into the Books, but as I was not subpoena'd, I am not prepar'd to be exact and particular as to the Time of his Commitment; the Book and the Original Commitments are at New-Prison. I remember the Time he was committed, and I receiv'd him my self, I don't remember how long he was in our Custody, but it was some considerable Time.</p>
               <p>Mr, Nicholls. His Commitment is enter'd in our Calender of last Sessions, - 'twas the 2d of June last: When they are brought from other Prisons to us, they bring Copies of their Commitments with them, and I enter them in our Calendar.</p>
               <p>C. To Jenkins. Produce the Plumber's Bill.</p>
               <p>Jenkins. Here it is, but 'tis almost worn to Pieces in my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Clerk reads.</p>
               <p>Here's no Date - only - 12 Yards of new Pipe, I l. 4 s. 4 (something) of Soder, 8 s.</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I believe the Facts were committed before the Time they say Franklin was committed; for about the beginning of June, I had the Misfortune to have my Shoulder broke, about the 5th or 6th of June, and I am positive the Facts were committed before that Time, - I believe it might be a Fortnight before, - for when the Pipe was cut, the Water ran into the Cellar, and I stopp'd it with a Spiggot and Fosset, - a Fortnight I am sure before my Shoulder was broke.</p>
               <p>Franklin. I came Home about the middle of May, in the Windsor Man of War, and was then paid off, so that I had no need of stealing Leaden Pipe.</p>
               <p>Smalt. I was a House-keeper in Fleet-Lane, and it is likely I should steal 2 or 3 Yards of Pipe, I was Master of 20 l. Every Morning I rose.</p>
               <p>Q. To Jenkins. The House was broke at two different Times; was your Shoulder broke after the last Robbery, or the first?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. After the last Robbery was committed. Both <rs id="t17370907-16-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370907-16-punish93" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-16-punish93" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-defend128 t17370907-16-punish93"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-16-defend130 t17370907-16-punish93"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
