<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390117-3">
               <interp inst="t17390117-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-3" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390117-3" type="date" value="17390117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-3-off14-c33" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-defend39 t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-verdict19"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390117-3-off14-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-defend41 t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>71. 72. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-defend39" type="defendantName">
                     Charles
                      Cockle
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend39" type="surname" value="Cockle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend39" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , the Younger, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-defend41" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend41" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend41" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-defend41" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17390117-3-defloc13">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-defloc13" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-defloc13" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-defend39 t17390117-3-defloc13"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-defend41 t17390117-3-defloc13"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17390117-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390117-3-victim43" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Mac Ben 
                        <interp inst="t17390117-3-victim43" type="surname" value="Mac Ben"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-3-victim43" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-3-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17390117-3-person44">
                        Charles 
                        Cockle 
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person44" type="surname" value="Cockle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-3-person44" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390117-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   the Elder, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 5 l. and 6 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390117-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">Dec. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-cd15"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. On the 27th of last Month, between 10 and 11 o'Clock at Night, I met that Woman at the Bar, near the Corner of <placeName id="t17390117-3-crimeloc16">Denmark Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-crimeloc16" type="placeName" value="Denmark Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-crimeloc16" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-crimeloc16"></join>. She asked me to give her a Pint of Ale, so we went to the <placeName id="t17390117-3-crimeloc17">White Hart</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-crimeloc17" type="placeName" value="White Hart"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390117-3-crimeloc17" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-off14 t17390117-3-crimeloc17"></join>, in that Court. She called for a Decanter of Ale, and as soon as the Ale was brought, the Landlord demanded his Money. It troubled me, to pay my Money before I had drunk the Liquor, and I was not willing to do it; upon which the Woman Prisoner up with her Fist, and gave me a Blow in the Face. I got up and asked her the Reason of her striking me? However, I paid for the Liquor, and forgetting the Dispute that had happened between her and me, I went up Stairs with her, into the Dining Room. I don't know what Money I paid below Stairs, for I gave the Landlord a Shilling for what she and I had had there, and he gave me something out of it, which I put in my Pocket without looking at. We were no sooner got up Stairs, but she knocked with her Foot, and a young Girl brought up another Decanter of Ale, for which I refused to pay. We sat a little while, and then we agreed to go to Bed together. I had seven Shillings in my Pocket,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170004"></xptr> and after all, I did not go to Bed with her, but she asked me for a shilling, and a shilling I gave her. Then she wanted to have my Watch, and made hard-drive at it, but I kept my Hand upon it; she attempted to get it by Force, and struck me; I struck her again, and upon that, the Prisoner Cockle came up, and halled me down Stairs by the Leggs, into a little Back Cellar, where she sat upon my Belly, and swore, with a Knife in her Hand, that she would cut my Throat. Cockle trail'd me downStairs into the Cellar by the Heels, and there they took my Watch from me, and all the Silver and Copper I had in this Pocket. After this, I came up Stairs, and I thought if I went out of the House, they might say I lost my Watch and Money Abroad; So I sat down, and call'd for another Decanter of Ale; and sometimes I was - fighting, - and sometimes I was - crying: - but knowing I had a Fob in the Hinder-part of my Breeches, with Money in it still, I called the Landlord, and asked him, If I could have a Bed there that Night? Yes, says he, if you'll pay for it before-hand. I had both Gold and Silver in my Fob; so I took out some Silver, and paid a Shilling for a Bed. Then I went up Stairs, and put my Cloaths under the Sheets, and my Shoes under my Head. But I had not been three Minutes in Bed before the Woman Prisoner came up, and kiss'd me, and wanted me to be great with her again but I called the Landlord up, and said, 'twas very hard to pay for a Bed, and not have Liberty to lie quietly in it; upon this he turned her down Stairs. In the Morning I got up, and went down; but seeing no body stirring, I open'd the Doors, and walk'd an Hour and a Half in the Court before the Door. Then I went to the Blue Ball in the Neighbourhood, and sent for Mr. Cameron; when he came, we went into the House, to see if I could get any Retaliation. They were for beating me again, but we got them before a Justice, and now let the Justice of the Law do what it thinks proper.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. When did you agree to pay a Shilling for a Bed?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. After I came up from the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. What Time was it, when you was drawn down into the Cellar?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Past Twelve o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Were not several People drinking in the Fore-Room?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. I saw no body there.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. How many Pair of Stairs do you say you was trail'd down?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Two Pair.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did you cry out when you was trailing down by the Heels into the Cellar?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Yes, I did, indeed - manfully.</p>



               <p>Prisoners. What Time o'Night was it when you paid the Shilling for the Bed?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. About 1 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did any body attempt to hinder your going away?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. No; no one at that Time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Walker. Did not I go with you to a Publick House, between St. Clement's Church Yard and Denmark-Court?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. No.</p>
               <p>Walker. Where did I take the Money out of your Pocket?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. In the Dining Room.</p>
               <p>Walker. I met him in St. Clement's Church Yard, and I was going Home with some Candles. He went with me to the Door, and staid till I had delivered the Candles. I was forc'd to go to a Publick-House with him; for he said, if I did not go with him, he would make a Noise about the Door, and would say I was his Wife. How much Beer had you in the Dining-Room?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Upon my Word, I don't know, nor whether I paid for any thing in the Dining-Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Cockle. Did not you come the next Day to the House, and offer to spend a Guinea, if the Landlord could help you to the Watch?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Yes.</p>
               <p>Cockle. Did you charge me with any thing then?</p>
               <p>Mac Ben. Yes; I did.</p>
               <p>A Witness. The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17390117-3-deflabel18" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390117-3-defend39 t17390117-3-deflabel18"></join>, and his Father keeps a Publick-House: I was there on the 27th of December. I had been there two or three Days, copying out some Accounts. The Prosecutor came in with the Woman about 11 o'clock, and went up Stairs. Presently I heard a Disturbance, and the Landlord went with me into the Dining-Room, where I saw the Prisoner Cockle standing by the Fire-Side. The Woman and the Prosecutor were struggling together, on one Side of the Room, and the young Fellow went to part them, upon which the Prosecutor turned about, and thrust his Fist into the Man's Face, and said to the Woman, - You B - h, you have got my Watch. The Landlord desired him not to make a Disturbance, and ordered his Son to bring the Prosecutor down Stairs. Accordingly the young Man took him by the Left-Hand and by the Collar, and brought him down Stairs, then he let him go, and he ran into a Nook behind the Kitchen-Door, and stood there about<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173901170005"></xptr> a Minute and a Half, making a great Noise. Several People being in the House, the Father desired his Son not to let him stand making such a Noise there; so he brought him by the Arm into the Room, and set him upon a Bench. He said again, the Woman had robbed him, but did not mention a Word of the young Fellow. The Landlord told him, if the Woman had robb'd him, she should not stir, if he insisted upon it. The Woman then struck him a Slap in the Face, and said, You Villain, how can you charge me with such a Thing! Then the Prosecutor immediately said to her - Go about your Business - you have not robbed me. He was quite mad and drunk; one would have thought he had really been a Mad Fellow. When the Watchman came Twelve, the Landlord threaten'd to send him to the Round-House, which made him change his Tone again, and he declared, the Woman had not done him any Injustice, upon which she went out, and returned again in a Quarter of an Hour. In the mean time, he got up, talked freely, and paid the Landlord 7 d. When the Woman returned, he began to be sweet upon her, and she comply'd with him. Then I thought the Disturbance had been all over, and left him in the Drinking-Room among other Company, about One o'Clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-person45">
                  John 
                  Ray 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person45" type="surname" value="Ray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. The Prosecutor brought me a Warrant in the Morning against the Prisoner Cockle: I went with him to the House, and found the young Fellow in his Shirt by the Fire. The Prosecutor did not give me Charge of him, so he went away. I asked the Father, where he was gone? He told me his Son knew I had a Warrant against him, but he was only gone to shift him, and he called to him, to make haste, for the Constable waited for him; he answer'd he would come presently, and did so; then I took him to my House, and the Prosecutor offer'd to make it up for 3 l. several times. The Woman heard I had Justice Frazier's Warrant out against her, and she came to my House, and surrender'd herself.</p>
               <p>Cockle the Elder confirm'd the Account the first Witness gave in Behalf of the Prisoners, adding, That the Prosecutor never was in the Cellar at all, and that the Prisoner Walker, after her coming in the second time, was desired by the Prosecutor to come and sit down by him, which she did, and that in the Morning, when he went out, he heard him, and called out to him, to shut the Door after him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-person46">
                  Mary 
                  Cockle 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person46" type="surname" value="Cockle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person46" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person46" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said the Prosecutor refused to pay his Reckoning, which put the Woman into a Passion, because she supposed she must pay it if he did not: In every other Circumstance she corroborated the former Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-person47">
                  Anne 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person47" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person47" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was there that Night, and said the Prosecutor was not in the Cellar at all; if he had been carry'd there, she must have seen it. And that he himself declared that Night he had not been robb'd, and bid the Woman go about her Business.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Frazier. When the Prosecutor came before me, I understood that the Robbery was committed in a Ground-Room: I sent to see the Situation of the Cellar, and found it full of Water. Then he could not be positive whether it was done in the Cellar, or not; but he was positive to the Man, he said; yet he wanted to make it up. There was a third Person with him when I examined him, a Woman, whom I could not cause to be now produced.</p>

               <p>- Ballard; 
               <persName id="t17390117-3-person48">
                  William 
                  Sympson 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person48" type="surname" value="Sympson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390117-3-person49">
                  William 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person49" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person49" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner Cockle the Character of a civil, honest, young Fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390117-3-person50">
                  Alexander 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17390117-3-person50" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person50" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account, that Mac Ben came to him, on the 27th of December, in the Morning, with his Face bloody and scratch'd, and that he told him he had been robb'd and almost murder'd at the White-Hart in Denmark Court. He had known the Prosecutor seven or eight Years, and took him to be an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17390117-3-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390117-3-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
