<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380222-57">
               <interp inst="t17380222-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-57" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380222-57" type="date" value="17380222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380222-57-off247-c238" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-57-defend363 t17380222-57-off247 t17380222-57-verdict251"></join>
         
               <p>66. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-defend363" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Brian 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-57-defend363" type="surname" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-defend363" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-defend363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17380222-57-off247" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-off247" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-off247" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Moidore value 27 s.
            </rs> from the Person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-victim365" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Room 
                  <interp inst="t17380222-57-victim365" type="surname" value="Room"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-victim365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-victim365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-57-off247 t17380222-57-victim365"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17380222-57-cd248" type="crimeDate">Jan 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-57-off247 t17380222-57-cd248"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mary Room. I <rs id="t17380222-57-viclabel249" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17380222-57-crimeloc250">Swan and Horshoe in Wild Street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-crimeloc250" type="placeName" value="Swan and Horshoe in Wild Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-crimeloc250" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-57-off247 t17380222-57-crimeloc250"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380222-57-victim365 t17380222-57-viclabel249"></join>. I can't tell the Day of the Month, but 'twas on a Thursday, - the Day before the Court would not take Bills, - last Sessions; the Prisoner and Harris and Slowman came in and call'd for a Bottle of Wine, and after that - another. I had shewn them into a Room even with the Bar, and they asked me to drink with them. After this I went into the Bar, and the Prisoner followed me, and began to be rude with me. I had a Wrapper on, and my 2 Pockets were on the outside: I had nothing in the right Hand Pocket but a Bunch of Keys and a Moidore, which Money I missed immediately: I was sure his Hand was in my Pocket, for I felt him, but I thought he was going to throw my Wrapper aside; at that Instant I missed my Money, and I am positive I had it in my Pocket 3 Minutes before. He endeavour'd to get out of the House, but I charg'd him with the Fact, and lock'd up the Doors till I could get an Officer. Slowman got away, but I carry'd the Prisoner before Captain 
               <persName id="t17380222-57-person366">
                  Mitford
               <interp inst="t17380222-57-person366" type="given" value="Mitford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person366" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I apprehend he was drunk, for he only gave the Justice a few wicked S ings. I charg'd Harris as an Accessary, but he was never out of the Room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-person367">
                  Mary 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17380222-57-person367" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person367" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mrs. Room. I saw the Prisoner go into the Bar with my Mistress, he was very rude with her there, and in a Minute she turn'd as pale as Death, and cry'd out, - she had lost a Moidore. There was no one but the Prisoner and she in the Bar; Slowman stood at the outside of the Bar, and asked the Prisoner what he was about? She said nothing at all to Harris, but when we sent for the Watch to take charge of the Prisoner, Slowman got off. Harris was not out of the Room where they were drinking.</p>
               <p>- Longbottom. I live at the Globe Tavern in Drury-Lane; I am a Servant there, and do all the Business relating to the Wine Trade. About 5 or 6 Weeks ago, Mrs. Room sent for me to assist her, telling me the Prisoner had robb'd her. I sent for the Watch to carry him to the Round house. As we were going up Colson's-Court, he offer'd me a Guinea to let him go, and told me, if he should be sent to Newgate several other Things would come against him. I refused to let him escape, and he then call'd out, - Informers! - Bailiffs! - all the Way we went. The Prisoner is a notorious Fellow for playing a Knife, therefore she sent for me to secure him. I am no Constable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Man is a Waiter at a bad House, and is a Party concern'd with the People that live there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-person368">
                  John 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17380222-57-person368" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person368" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mrs. Room, and I was at this Time in her House, she keeps a disorderly House by Report; I know no Body that will<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173802220020"></xptr> give her a Character, and what she has sworn is as false as God is true. The Prisoner, Slowman, and I, went in and call'd for a Bottle of Wine; she shew'd us into a Parlour, and sat herself down, between Slowman and I. She sat with us a considerable Time, and drank four or five Glasses of Wine; then she asked the Prisoner if he had any Money about him? For she had bought a 20 l. Bank Note that Day for 17l. and she had no Money left? He told her he could change it, but Slowman said, it was impossible she should have bought a good Bank Note of 20l. for 17 l. Words arose, and I paid for two Bottles and was going Home. Slowman and the Prisoner would have another Bottle; I said if we must have another, we'll take it standing. Upon this, the Prisoner and I went into the Bar; and while we were drinking in the Bar, she went into the Room we came t of, and call'd her Maid; then she rash'd into the Bar again and cry'd out, she was robb'd. The Prisoner asked her, who robb'd her? You! you Dog, said she, and call'd the Watch, and we were both taken into Custody. The Constable ask'd her if she was sure the Prisoner had robb'd her? She equivocated, and he told her she deserv'd to be charg'd too. There was her Maid and her Man, and one Brock present at the same Time. The Room we had been drinking in, joins to the Bar, and she came in and drank with us, - I suppose she does so with all the People that comes into her House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-person369">
                  Patrick 
                  Slowman 
               <interp inst="t17380222-57-person369" type="surname" value="Slowman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person369" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave much the same Account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380222-57-person370">
                  Catherine 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17380222-57-person370" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person370" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday in last Sessions, I saw this Woman in a Beer-House and heard her say, her Evidence was not strong enough to hang Brian; therefore she would put it off 'till next Sessions, and then she would get a Man to hang him, right or wrong. This was at the Yellow Lion by Hick's Hall. I and the Prisoner's Sister. <rs id="t17380222-57-verdict251" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380222-57-verdict251" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
