<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-15">
               <interp inst="t17381206-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-15" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-15" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-15-off68-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-defend121 t17381206-15-off68 t17381206-15-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>18. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-15-defend121" type="defendantName">
                     Constance, alias <rs id="t17381206-15-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-defend121 t17381206-15-alias-1"></join>Costantia</rs> James<interp inst="t17381206-15-defend121" type="given" value="Constance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-defend121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            ,* of St. Martin's in the Fields, was indicted for <rs id="t17381206-15-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing fourThirty six shilling Pieces, value 7 l. 4 s. and a Half Guinea, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-15-victim123" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-15-victim123" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-15-victim123" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-15-victim123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-off68 t17381206-15-victim123"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17381206-15-cd69" type="crimeDate">Nov. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-off68 t17381206-15-cd69"></join>.</p>
               <p>* She was tried in the Year 1736, for stealing four Shillings and a Dutch Half-Crown, from the Person of 
               <persName id="t17381206-15-person124">
                  William 
                  Vannimore 
               <interp inst="t17381206-15-person124" type="surname" value="Vannimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person124" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , July 8. and acquitted. See the Sessions Book 1736, p. 146. Numb. 6.</p>
               <p>In 1737 she was indicted for stealing nine Guineas from the Person of 
               <persName id="t17381206-15-person125">
                  James 
                  Silk 
               <interp inst="t17381206-15-person125" type="surname" value="Silk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person125" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but the Prosecutor not appearing, she was acquitted. See the Sessions Book 1737, p. 196. Numb. 7.</p>
               <p>In 1737 she was tried for stealing a Watch, &amp;c, the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17381206-15-person126">
                  William 
                  Bance 
               <interp inst="t17381206-15-person126" type="surname" value="Bance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person126" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and was again acquitted. See the Sessions Book 1738, p. 16. Numb 1.</p>
               <p>William Davis. On the 22d of November, about 11 at Night, the Prisoner picked me up in <placeName id="t17381206-15-crimeloc70">Catherine Street in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-15-crimeloc70" type="placeName" value="Catherine Street in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-15-crimeloc70" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-off68 t17381206-15-crimeloc70"></join>, as I was going home. She told me, she would go along with me. I said, I was going home to my Lodging, and wanted none of her Company. We had no more Talk together, but when I came to my own Door (which was but a little Way from the Place where she first spoke to me) I bid her begone about her Business, and she went off some Paces. I thought she had been gone, but while I was taking the Key out of the Door, after I had opened it, she brushed in upon me, and while I was in the Entry, she pushed one of her Hands to the Waistband of my Breeches, and the other she employ'd in picking my Pocket. I cry'd out - '' What are you doing!'' and drew back, and clapping my Hand into my Pocket where I had five of these Portugal Pieces, and a Half Guinea, I missed all but one Thirty-six shilling Piece. I fastened the Door immediately, and called my Landlord; she then pretended to strip herself, but I was not satisfied with that; therefore we got a Watchman, and this Woman, to take her up Stairs, and after some little Time, they brought me down my Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-15-person127">
                  Mary 
                  Baily 
               <interp inst="t17381206-15-person127" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person127" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When we got her up Stairs she was unwilling to be searched by Force, - she would undress herself, and when she was all undressed, as she stood upright, one of the Pieces of Gold dropped from her. Then she clapped herself down upon a Bed in the Room, and would be searched no further. I resolved to search her, and she finding it must be done, she clapped her Hand under her, and put the rest of the Money into the Bed, where it was found directly. I imagine she swallowed the Half Guinea, while we were searching her for the other Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-15-person128">
                  Ralph 
                  Rotheram 
               <interp inst="t17381206-15-person128" type="surname" value="Rotheram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person128" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Watchman). While the Prisoner was in the Entry, she cry'd out - Fire! Murder! I hearing the Outcry, ran with my Candle and Lanthorn to see what was the Matter. I heard how it was, and we got her up Stairs to be searched; while she was laying her Apron upon the Bed, I heard something fall from her; I stooped down, and took up a Thirty-six<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060009"></xptr> Shilling-Piece. Three more were found in the Bed, upon which she afterwards sat herself down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I met the Man, and we drank some Gin together in the Street; then he told me he was a single Man, and I should go home with him to his Lodging, but I must not make any Noise, for he had the Key of the Door in his Pocket. When he got me into the Entry, he would have used me ill, &amp;c. and I being with Child, cry'd out, Fire! Murder! to get rid of him. But the Watchman came and forced me up Stairs; where the Woman that searched me told him there were prettier Girls at home than I was. There were three Pieces found in the Bed, but I don't know how they came there, and what they have said is entirely false. <rs id="t17381206-15-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17381206-15-punish72" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-15-punish72" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-15-defend121 t17381206-15-punish72"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
