<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390718-13">
               <interp inst="t17390718-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-13" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390718-13" type="date" value="17390718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390718-13-off60-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-13-defend115 t17390718-13-off60 t17390718-13-verdict63"></join>
         
               <p>400. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390718-13-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Broderick 
                  <interp inst="t17390718-13-defend115" type="surname" value="Broderick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-defend115" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-defend115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17390718-13-person116">
                  Noah 
                  Gooby 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person116" type="surname" value="Gooby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person116" type="given" value="Noah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken) for <rs id="t17390718-13-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390718-13-victim118" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Reynolds 
                        <interp inst="t17390718-13-victim118" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-13-victim118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390718-13-victim118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-13-off60 t17390718-13-victim118"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, in the Parish of St. Leonard, Shoreditch, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 20 s. a Silver Chain, value 4 s. a Silver Seal, value 12 d. a Glass Seal, set in Base-Metal, value 2 d. a Gold Ring, with a Chrystal Stone set therein, value 8 s. and five Shillings and Sixpence in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390718-13-cd61" type="crimeDate">March 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-13-off60 t17390718-13-cd61"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Reynolds. On the 20th of March, I was coming out of the Country, in a Chaise, with a Friend, and on this Side the Turnpike, by <placeName id="t17390718-13-crimeloc62">Kingsland Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-13-crimeloc62" type="placeName" value="Kingsland Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390718-13-crimeloc62" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-13-off60 t17390718-13-crimeloc62"></join>, three Fellows stopped the Chaise, and commanded me out. Then they put a Pistol to my Breast, and two to my Head, swearing they would shoot my Brains out if I made any Resistance. They took from me, a Silver Watch, and after they had got that, they took my Money out of my Pocket, and bid me go about my Business. 'Twas then nigh Ten o'Clock at Night. When they had got my Watch and Money, one of them bid the others see if I had no Rings; I said I had no - Rings, for I had but - one; and at the same time I endeavoured to shuffle it off, with my Glove, but one of them guessing what I was about, cry'd - d - mn you, are you going to serve me so, and catching hold of my Glove, he tore it off, and took my Ring, - 'twas a Mourning Ring, set with a Chrystal Stone. I advertised the Watch, and Mr. Gardiner brought it to me, but the Ring I never had again. I can't swear to the Prisoner, he has been fetched up a great Way out of the Country, but he agrees with the Height of one of the Persons.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-13-person119">
                  Samuel 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person119" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person119" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and 
               <persName id="t17390718-13-person120">
                  Abraham 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person120" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person120" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was condemned last May * Sessions, with the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17390718-13-person121">
                  Noah 
                  Gooby 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person121" type="surname" value="Gooby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person121" type="given" value="Noah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went out from Crown Court, in Chick-Lane, on Tuesday Night, in order to rob somebody or other. We went to a Place between Shoreditch and Kingsland, and staid sometime on the Causeway; and not seeing any body come by, we went past Kingsland Town, it was about half an Hour after Nine, when we had got beyond the Town, about a Quarter of a Mile, we met this Chaise, with a grey Horse: The Horse trotted, and we followed it to Kingsland Town, then it walked, and we ran before the Chaise, till we came to a vacant Place, where we thought proper to stop it. 'Twas just at the Stone Watch-house, when two of us went on one Side the Chaise, and two on the other, and stopped it. The Prisoner was on the Off-side of the Horse; Nash and I were on the other. Nash ordered the Gentleman to come out of the Chaise, and when he had got out, Nash stepped in, and bid me rifle his Pockets: So I took his Watch, and Gooby searched for Money. The Watch was an old-fashion'd Silver one, without a Minute Hand, but had a new outside Case, and a Silver Chain, and Seal. We took likewise, a Mourning Ring with a little Stone in it, and five Shillings and Sixpence in Money; these Things we took from<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173907180009"></xptr> Mr. Reynolds. Nash took from the other Gentleman, a large Silver Watch and Silver Chain, and the Name on that Watch was Barrow, and a Gold Ring, with the Name Atwood in the Inside, and between eight and nine Shillings in Money, and his Hat. Then we went directly to Chick-Lane, and stay'd there all Night. Next Morning we went to a Shop in the Minories, and Gooby went in and sold the Watch: He had at that Time this Coat upon him, which I have on now. 'Twas Mr. Reynolds's Watch we sold there, and got 12 s. for it: The Silver Seal we had taken off before. When we had sold the Watch, we went to the Sign of the Pack Horse, in Goswell-street, where the Prisoner's Wife lived, and from thence to Chick-Lane. From Chick Lane we went to St. Giles's, to Nash's Sweetheart's Lodging; from whence we all went together to Bedlam, and spent most of the Money which we had divided between us for the Watch and the Hat; we gave Money to the Prisoners in Bedlam, and when we came out, we had a Supper in that Neighbourhood, and then we all went together to the Pack-horse. The next Morning we sold the Ring for nine Shillings, and parted the Money equally. The Prisoner was concerned in this, and in several other Robberies: He sent up his Confession from Ipswich to London, not knowing that I had made an Information.</p>
               <p>* See his Trial, No. 239. Watts was an Evidence against him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was committed to Goal, at Ipswich, the 25th of March, and I set out from London for Ipswich, on the 18th, where I made myself an Evidence before Justice Sparrow.</p>
               <p>Watts. After we had sold these Things, we quarrelled about our Shares of the Money for the rest of them, so we parted, and the Prisoner and one 
               <persName id="t17390718-13-person122">
                  Dick 
                  Cadman 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person122" type="surname" value="Cadman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person122" type="given" value="Dick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             agreed to go down into the Country together; and they accordingly set out the next Day but one after this Robbery was committed. The Prisoner and Cadman proposed to go down to Newmarket, and they set out between Eight and Nine in the Morning: They wanted one of our Pistols, but we would not let them have it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-13-person123">
                  Thomas 
                  Gardiner 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person123" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person123" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought the Watch on the 21st of March, which Mr. Reynolds was robbed of; and the next Morning I saw an Advertisement at the Coffee-House, in which the Watch was described; upon which I carry'd it to him, and he owned it. Neither the Prisoner nor the Evidence, was the Person I bought it of. The Man who brought it to me had the same Coat on, or one very much like that which the Accomplice has on now. 'Tis an old String Watch, and goes but twelve Hours: The Movement not being worth a Farthing, I gave 12 s. for it, which was 2 s. more than the Worth of the Silver. The Fellow brought it to me about Ten o'Clock in the Morning, and asked me two Guineas and a half for it: He told me he bought it at Spalding, in Lincolnshire, and had paid so much for it there. After I had paid him the Money, he said, - Sir, if my Brother wont take this Money for it, you'll let me have it again? Aye to be sure, says I: So he went away, and came back again to me, and said, his Brother did not chuse to take that Money: Upon this I gave him the Watch, and took my twelve Shillings again. After this, he brought it to me again, and said, - Sir, you are a very honest Man, I have been with it to a Watch-maker in Whitechappel, and he will give but half a Guinea for it: So I brought it you again. There were three other Men at the same time hanging over my Show-Glass; if I had known them, I could have taken them all together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-13-person124">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person124" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person124" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I moved the Prisoner by Habeas Corpus from Ipswich Goal: I asked him if he knew 
               <persName id="t17390718-13-person125">
                  Samuel 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person125" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person125" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, very well, says he, and he told me he had committed several Robberies with him, but he was in Hopes of being admitted an Evidence. This was, I think, on the 7th of this Instant. [July.] He desired me to go after Cadman and Gooby, and do my Endeavour to apprehend them; he had made an Information before Mr. Justice Sparrow in Ipswich, in which he had mentioned them both.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not guilty of this Robbery, but was gone out of Town when it was committed. If I had time I could prove where we lay, every Night, till we had got down to Ipswich.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390718-13-person126">
                  Thomas 
                  Cable 
               <interp inst="t17390718-13-person126" type="surname" value="Cable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person126" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Keeper of Ipswich Goal; he was committed there on Lady-Day last, about Twelve o'Clock. This is the Copy of his Commitment. <rs id="t17390718-13-verdict63" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-verdict63" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390718-13-punish64" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390718-13-punish64" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390718-13-defend115 t17390718-13-punish64"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
