<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-4">
               <interp inst="t17361013-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-4" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-4" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-4-off15-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-4-defend66 t17361013-4-off15 t17361013-4-verdict18"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-4-defend66" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Morgan 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-4-defend66" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-defend66" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-defend66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-4-off15" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-off15" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-off15" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-4-victim68" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Pullvash 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-4-victim68" type="surname" value="Pullvash"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-4-victim68" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-4-victim68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-4-off15 t17361013-4-victim68"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain open Field near the King's Highway, putting her in fear, and taking from her a Holland Gown value 8 s. a pair of Stays value 3 s. a callamanco quilted Coat value 17 s. a Bermudus Ha: value 7 s. a a cambrick Mob value 2 s. 6 d. a dimity Petticoat value 3 s. a flannel Petticoat value 1 s. and pair of damask Shoes value 2 s 6 d. a pair of silver Buckles value 7 s a gold Ring value 8 s. a a cambrick Handkerchief value 2 s. 6 d. a muslin ditto value 1 s. a linnen Apron value 1 s. and 9 d. half penny in Money
            </rs>. <rs id="t17361013-4-cd16" type="crimeDate">August 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-4-off15 t17361013-4-cd16"></join>.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Pullvash On Tuesday Night, I cannot possible tell the Day of the Month, but it was towards the two last Days of Tottenham Court Fair, the Prisoner met me coming from <placeName id="t17361013-4-crimeloc17">Tottenham Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-4-crimeloc17" type="placeName" value="Tottenham Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-4-crimeloc17" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-4-off15 t17361013-4-crimeloc17"></join>, in the middle of the Road near the Town, there were two more with him, he had a Dagger in his Hand, and they had Pistols, They took hold of me, and said, if I cried out I should die. I begged hard for my Life, but they led me out of the Way, and stripped me stark naked. They seized another young Man (whom I never saw before in my Life) at the same time. They kept me at some distance from the other Man, and that Man at the Bar stripped me naked, and left me naked, all but my Shift, then he bound me and did what he pleased with me; he tried to lie with me, and he did all that was in his Power. After he had done every thing he pleased, he took hold of one of my Legs and bound it behind me, and cut my Pocket and stuffed it into my Mouth. I down'd on my knees, and begged of him to spare my Life; I told him I was with Child to make him more favourable to me; he took my Gown, my Stays, a quilted Coat, my Hat, a laced Mob, a flannel Coat, a dimity Coat, my Shoes, a gold Ring, an Apron, and nine Pence Half penny in Money - all I had in the World; they left me nothing on but my Stockings and Shift and one Petticoat. One of the Men snapped a Pistol twice at my Breast, but it did not go off, the Prisoner was the most resolute, wickedest Fellow of them all; for he was so long about me doing what he did, that I knew him again; they kept me 'till 12 o'Clock, doing one thing or another to me. The other Man they robbed at some distance from me, and told him if he looked that way, towards me, he should die; but when they had done with us both, they tied us with a Cord, and threw us into a Ditch,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130007"></xptr> where we lay up to the Neck in Water and Mud for several Hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-4-person69">
                  Will 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17361013-4-person69" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-person69" type="given" value="Will"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go over the Field about 4 o'Clock the next Morning, and I thought I heard a Man cry out murder; I went to see what was the matter, and found the Man and Woman in the Water and Mud. I was up to my middle in getting them out. They were tied Hand and Legs, and this is a piece of the Cord they were bound with. I think she had no Petticoat on, and the Man was quite naked; their Hands and Legs were tied behind them, and they lay flat upon their Backs in the Water and mud with their Mouths stopp'd. I cut them loose and this is the Cord that tied the Woman's Hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-4-person70">
                  Eliz 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17361013-4-person70" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-person70" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Husband was out at work, where this last Witness works, and he came and told me, there was a Woman just lost, in a Ditch; will you give her leave to be brought up, and put into our Bed says he, if you will no, she must die with being so long in Mud and Water. I consented, and with much ado, we got her to Bed, but I thought she would have died after that. I live at the Brill. between Pancrass and Tottenham-Court: My Husband is sick, and I come here in his behalf.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day was it this happened?</p>
               <p>Field. It was on a Wednesday Morning. between 5 and 6 o'Clock in the Morning, that she was brought to my Lodging.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never was at Tottenham-Court in my Life I was at home at Work when this Fact was committed, but happening to have a Quarrel, I was carried to New Prison, and this Woman was brought there by 3 or 4 Fellows who make it their business to swear People's Lives away, and they carried me before Justice Midford and then to Mr Barns's, and I was to give him a Note of Hand, and be discharged, but this Woman came violently up Stairs and rushed into the Room, and said I was the Man that robbed and ravish'd her, so they sent me to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Witnesses, either with regard to the Fact you are charged with, or to your Character?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They have been here, but they are gone. <rs id="t17361013-4-verdict18" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-verdict18" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17361013-4-punish19" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-4-punish19" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-4-defend66 t17361013-4-punish19"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
