<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360115-45">
               <interp inst="t17360115-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-45" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360115-45" type="date" value="17360115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360115-45-off255-c231" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-defend336 t17360115-45-off255 t17360115-45-verdict259"></join>
         
               <p>51. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-defend336" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Kirk 
                  <interp inst="t17360115-45-defend336" type="surname" value="Kirk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-defend336" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-defend336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17360115-45-defloc254">St. Ann's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-45-defloc254" type="placeName" value="St. Ann's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-45-defloc254" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-defend336 t17360115-45-defloc254"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360115-45-off255" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-off255" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-off255" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a green silk Purse, value 2s. and 49 Guineas, the Money and Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360115-45-victim338" type="victimName">
                           Patrick 
                           Callan 
                        <interp inst="t17360115-45-victim338" type="surname" value="Callan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-45-victim338" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-45-victim338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-off255 t17360115-45-victim338"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17360115-45-person339">
                        Matthias 
                        Prime 
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person339" type="surname" value="Prime"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-45-person339" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360115-45-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. <rs id="t17360115-45-cd256" type="crimeDate">December 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-off255 t17360115-45-cd256"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person340">
                  Catherine 
                  Callan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person340" type="surname" value="Callan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person340" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Mr. Prime's House in <placeName id="t17360115-45-crimeloc257">Grafton street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-45-crimeloc257" type="placeName" value="Grafton street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360115-45-crimeloc257" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-off255 t17360115-45-crimeloc257"></join>. Half an Hour before this thing happened, I took out of my Trunk, a Purse with 50 Guineas. I wanted to change one of them; the rest I tyed up and layed down upon an Oak Table in my forward Room: I was making a Shirt, and I covered the Purse with a Corner of the Linnen. I was going to the Washer-womans for some Cloaths, so I bid my Brother, who was in the back Room, and expected he should be arrested, to lock the Door after me: I stood on the Stair-head, till he had locked the Door, and then went down Stairs. When I came back, this Man (the Prisoner) and two or three more, with a Woman, was at the top of the Stairs. What do you do there, says I? What's that to you, said he, and set his Shoulder to the Door - away flew the Lock into the middle of the Room. I seeing the Door fly open, was so astonished - I was frighted out of my Wits - he layed his Hands on my Brothers, and shoving over to where the Table stood, he spy'd the Purse, and being nearer the Table than I, he snatched it up. Well says I, if you come to arrest the Man, do not rob me.</p>
               <p>Q. But how came he to see the Purse; you said it was covered.</p>
               <p>Callan. He had shoved the Linnen off, and then he saw it; and when he had taken it, the rest of the Fellows gathered close about him. I cryed out, I was robbed! - I was robbed! You Bitch, says he, say a Word, and I'll cut your Throat, and out he pulled a long Knife - Woman! Woman! says my Brother, hold your Tongue, or we shall all be murdered! I dropped back on a Chair, and had not power to speak a Word more - My Money lost, my Life in danger - Then away he hurried down Stairs, and they with him, and took my Brother with them. In 5 or 6 Minutes I came to my self, ran down Stairs, and said to the Folks below, I am robbed, which way are the Fellows gone? They directed me, and away I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173601150017"></xptr> came to the Prisoner's House. He had locked up my Brother, and I saw no body but him in the Parlour - Give me my Money, says I. Tell me of any such thing and I will kill you, says he - but be easy, and I will make up Matters with you. I found I could not get my Money, so away I came to get a Warrant for him immediately, thinking to take my Purse upon him; but all the Justices were at Hicks's Hall; so I could not get a Warrant 'till Night, and then he was not to be found; he is a Prisoner in the Fleet, though he has a House of his own. On Saturday last he was taken; the Fact was committed on December 12.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her whether I did not stay 'till she had taken a Shirt out of her Lap; and 'till he had put it on?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. He put a Shirt on, to be sure -</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Shirt he put on, part of the Linnen in your Apron, or of that which lay on the Table?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. The Shirt he put on was in the Room before; there were Shirts in the Trunk, whether it was one of them in the Apron, or one taken out of the Trunk, I cannot well tell.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her if she did not give him one, and he refused it, because it had not a ruffled Bosom?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. I cannot tell; I don't know whether I gave him a Shirt or not</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her, if her Brother did not ask her for 5 s. before I brought him out of the House?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. Yes, but it was before I fainted away; and I told him that you had got all my Money: I had but 2s. out of the Guinea I had changed:</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her if she did not say, she had 3s. and that she had pawned a Shirt for that?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. I said no such thing.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her whether her Brother's Sister was not at my House, when she came there?</p>
               <p>C. Callan. I did not see her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person341">
                  Patrick 
                  Callan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person341" type="surname" value="Callan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person341" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Sunday before this happened, I told 50 Guineas, and put them in a Green Silk Purse, and left them with my Wife. I went to the Prince of Wales's at Ken-Green to work, and was away all the Week, and came home the Saturday following. I went up Stairs, and found a Padlock on the Door - What is the Fancy, said I to my Landlady, that my Door is padlock'd? Your Door, said she was broke open yesterday, and you have been robbed by Bailiffs that came after the young Fellow that lodges with you. Your Wife cried out, she was robbed, and is gone after the Men; she had a Warrant for them yesterday, and she did not lye in the Room last Night. I went to Long-Acre, found my Wife, and she told me what had happened.</p>
               <p>Kirk. What Business are you?</p>
               <p>P. Callan. I am a Slater; well known in Town and Country. I have been a Master, am now a Journeyman, and have 12 s. a Week now, according as the Season is favourable, I can earn more.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask, whether he can work in wet Weather?</p>
               <p>P. Callan. Yes, wet and dry; in Slate, Wet does no great hurt.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask, whether he has saved that Money since he came from Ireland?</p>
               <p>P. Callan. No; I have been not 2 Years in England; I can safely say I brought 40 Guineas from Dublin, where I kept a Publick-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person342">
                  Edw 
                  Obryan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person342" type="surname" value="Obryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person342" type="given" value="Edw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . December 12, about 10 o'clock in the Morning, I was very unwell, and was in Bed, and my Sister came and told me she was going to the Washer-woman's, and had taken out a Guinea to change. I being afraid of Bailiffs, got up and locked the Door: I was aware of this Gentleman to arrest me, tho' he is a Prisoner in the Fleet. A Woman came first to the Door, and I let her in; it was the Plaintiff's Sister: I hope, says I, you don't come to set me? No, not I, said she, but presently 2 or 3 Men came to the Door, and, upon my refusing to open the Door, Kirk and all his Men burst open the Door, and the Lock flew off. Kirk entered first, and laying hold of me, the Linnen on the Table was whipped off, and Kirk put the green Silk Purse that lay there into his Coat Pocket. - I saw him do it, as plain as I see your Worship this Moment. My Sister pushed in with them, and seeing him take the Purse, she cry'd out, - I am robbed, and catched hold of the Skirt of his Coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he arrested you before he took the Purse?</p>
               <p>Obryan. He laid his Hand on me first; and said to her, You Whore, if you say a Word, I'll cut your Throat, and drew out a long Knife. Hold your Tongue, says I, or we shall be murdered. There were three or four with him, and they had great Clubs as thick as my Leg. Then they dragged me to Kirk's House, by the Seven-Dials, and my Sister followed. Upon this, Kirk comes to me, and desired me to make my Sister easy, - if I did, he told me I should be discharged. You have robbed her, said I, and if I can't pay the Debt, I must go to Gaol, Moreover,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173601150018"></xptr> my Lord, my Sister went for a Warrant, and he run out of the Way for a Month, and was not to be taken at any seasonable Time.</p>
               <p>Kirk. I would ask him, whether I did not stay till she had given him a Shirt; and till he put it on?</p>
               <p>Obryan. Yes.</p>
               <p>Kirk. I would ask whether he did refuse one Shirt, because it had not a Ruffled Bosom?</p>
               <p>Obryan. They were both ruffled; one was broke in the Wristbands. I put on the best.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask him, whether he made any Outcry either in the Room, or in the Street?</p>
               <p>Obryan. No; there were 6 or 7 Fellows with you.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Did not the Plaintiff's Wife's Sister come in with me?</p>
               <p>Obryan. No; she was in the Room before.</p>
               <p>Kirk. What Business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Obryan. I am a Glover, and sell my Work to Country Chapmen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person343">
                  Jane 
                  Prime 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person343" type="surname" value="Prime"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person343" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person343" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Matter; I was not at home when the Man was arrested; Callan came down presently (afterward) and said she was robbed.</p>
               <p>Kirk. I would ask her, when she heard of Callan's being robbed?</p>
               <p>Prime. Pray, my Lord, discharge me. - I heard a little matter of a Noise before. - It was no Business of mine. - Pray, my Lord, let me go.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask her, what Character they bear?</p>
               <p>Prime. If you please, my Lord, to let me go - They had not been long with me: I can't say much to that.</p>
               <p>Kirk. I would ask her -</p>
               <p>Prime. Don't force your Discourse to me. Pray, my Lord, let me go.</p>
               <p>Kirk. Ask, whether she has not been forced to call in the Watch to quiet them?</p>
               <p>Prime. Once I did. What's that to the purpose? Pray, my Lord, discharge me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On Thursday Night, the Plaintift's Wife 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person344">
                  Ann 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person344" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person344" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person344" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me to get Obryan arrested. I went that Night to the Play-houses to look for him, for there he goes to pick Pockets; I did not find him that Night. In the Morning, Bridget Casey came and agreed to set him: She was to go to his Lodging, if she stayed a Quarter of an Hour, I was to go in: she stayed half an hour, so I went up and one Man with me; he knocked at the Door, but would not open it; and immediately he says to the Woman, that was with him, You. B - h, you have set me. I will kill you, I went down Stairs and told Ann Casey, that I heard his Voice in the Room, so she came up with me and one Mrs Mitchell; Ann Casey knocked at the Door, and bid her Sister Bridget open the Door. Obryan fell upon the Woman within, and made her cry out, Murder; the Plaintiff's Wife then opened the Door, and I went in and arrested him. He begged I would stay; his Sister, he said, was gone for a Shirt, and I stayed a Quarter of an Hour before Mrs Callan came in. When she came in, he told her he was arrested; then you must go to Goal, said she. Hold your Tongue, you B - h, says he, and gave her 3 or 4 Kicks. - He said he had been robbed in Fleet street last Night, when he was drunk; had fell in the Kennel, and must have a clean Shirt: she gave him one, and he did not like it; so she gave him another. My Lord, I will prove my Writ against 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person345">
                  Edward 
                  Obryan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person345" type="surname" value="Obryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person345" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Suit of 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person346">
                  Thomas 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person346" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person346" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Rose. The Prisoner is now a regular <rs id="t17360115-45-deflabel258" type="occupation">Officer in the Marshal's Court</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360115-45-defend336 t17360115-45-deflabel258"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person347">
                  Ann 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person347" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person347" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to my Sister Bridget Casey, and told her I wanted to arrest Obryan. She gave me Instructions where to find him, and went with me to Kirk's House; we came all together to an Alehouse just by, and sent my Sister to see for Obryan. If she stayed a Quarter of an Hour we were to come; if he was not at Home, she was to return to us. We stayed the drinking of 2 Pots of Beer and eat Bread and Cheese, and concluded he was at Home; we went Kirk went before, and I staid in the Street; but he came down presently and told me, he was abusing my Sister for setting him. Upon this, I went up Stairs, and hearing the Outcry within, I put my Hand to the Door and opened it: then Kirk entered and arrested him; and he begged he would stay till his Sister came with a clean Shirt, and to make us pity his Moan, he told us he had been robbed, &amp;c. - and had not a Shilling in the World It was more than a Quarter of an Hour before his sister Callan came in; there was not a Word of the Purse mentioned till next Day. He asked her for Money: she said she had but 2 s. and told him, she had pawned a Shirt for 3 s. out of which she had paid 1 s. for washing the Linnen in her Apron, and she gave him the 2 s. that were left. Callan was at Kirk's House as soon as we, and made a Noise at him for arresting her Brother; but Obryan called her backward, and said, Don't speak a Word, you Whore, - but swear what I bid you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person348">
                  Margaret 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person348" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person348" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore she was present; her Evidence was to the same effect; and she was positive that no Knife was produced, nor did she see any Clubs, or any other Weapons.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173601150019"></xptr>Henry Smith, 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person349">
                  John 
                  Devine 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person349" type="surname" value="Devine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person349" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (who were the Prisoner's Assistants) and Bridget Casey, confirmed the Evidence of Ann Casey and Margaret Mitchell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person350">
                  Sarah 
                  Connolly 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person350" type="surname" value="Connolly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person350" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account of a Quarrel that 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person351">
                  Patrick 
                  Callan 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person351" type="surname" value="Callan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person351" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his Wife had about 5 or 6 Weeks ago with another Person, which was made up at a Publick-house; and neither of them having any Money to pay the Reckoning, Mrs. Callan pawned her Ring to this Witness for 5 s. and has never since been able to redeem it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person352">
                  Edward 
                  Cotterel 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person352" type="surname" value="Cotterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person352" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Constable, swore the same.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character has Obryan?</p>
               <p>Wm James. I have seen him in Company with 
               <persName id="t17360115-45-person353">
                  Moll 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person353" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person353" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Thief, and have likewise seen him iron'd in Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person354">
                  Geo 
                  Fidoe 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person354" type="surname" value="Fidoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person354" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Callan told me, that Kirk had robbed her; but she gave me a very different Account of it from what she has done here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person355">
                  Edward 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person355" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person355" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Callan used to come to my House with a Soldier to drink; she owes me for a Pot of Beer and Ale now; I have sent to them 3 or 4 times for the Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360115-45-person356">
                  Michael 
                  Lutwych 
               <interp inst="t17360115-45-person356" type="surname" value="Lutwych"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person356" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Obryan is a Pickpocket and a Thief; has been in the Goals in Dublin, and in Newgate here, for picking Pockets; and the Woman is a Shoplifter.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner calling several to his Reputation, the Jury <rs id="t17360115-45-verdict259" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360115-45-verdict259" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
