<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-40">
               <interp inst="t17360610-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-40" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-40" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-40-off167-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-40-defend295 t17360610-40-off167 t17360610-40-verdict169"></join>
         
               <p>48. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-defend295" type="defendantName">
                     Bartholomew 
                     Swift 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-40-defend295" type="surname" value="Swift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-defend295" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-defend295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-40-off167" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-off167" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-off167" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing an Iron Anvil, Weight 400 lb. value 5 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-victim297" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Mabson 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-40-victim297" type="surname" value="Mabson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-victim297" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-victim297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-40-off167 t17360610-40-victim297"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17360610-40-cd168" type="crimeDate">September 4 1734</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-40-off167 t17360610-40-cd168"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Mabson. September last was twelve Months, I lost the Anvil from my Door, between Night and Morning, and did not hear of it for a Twelve-Month. At last I had several Letters from one 
               <persName id="t17360610-40-person298">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Weston 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person298" type="surname" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person298" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , telling me, if I would come to Newgate, I might hear of it. In one Letter I was inform'd if I would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100014"></xptr> come, I might have it with very little Trouble; I went, and Mr. Austin was so kind, as to let the Woman come into the Lodge; she told me she could inform me where the Anvil was, but she would not, unless I would give her two Guineas. I gave her one Guinea and was to give her another if I found the Anvil. She told me Mr. Swift had bought it; that he was at home when it was brought, and that he paid the Coach-hire. I found it in Mr. Swift's Shop: It was under the Stairs, but I cannot say it was secreted, any Body might see it that went into the Shop. I told him, it had cost me two Guineas to come at it, and if I could come by it safely, I would take it again. He said he was willing I should have it again; but I would not take it without Advice, and my Advice was, that I must indict him here. I went to Justice Jones, and he would not grant me a Warrant. Mr. Swift did not deny the Anvil, yet I have never had any Satisfaction for it; and when I came here to enquire how I must come by it, I was told, I could not have it without prosecuting. I swear the Anvil is mine; 'tis worth 6 l. - and he gave but 30 s. for it. I did not want to prosecute him, if I could have got it safely, and without Charge; it was a Trifle for him to give (30 s.) for a Thing worth 6 l.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-person299">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person299" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person299" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had the Anvil in my Custody a Year or a Year and half, to sell for Mr. Mahson: I was to sell it for four pence half penny a pound, I was bid three pence half penny, and he would not take it. I thought I might lose it from my Door; so he took it home, and from his Door it was stole. I went with him to the Prisoner's House, and there we saw it. He did as good as offer to send it back, but Mr. Mabson say'd, it was not safe for him to take it back, and he had been at two Guineas charge about it. I hear a good Character of you in one sense, but the Price does not shew it; For the Anvil weighs about 4 hundred, or 4 hundred and odd Weight, and 30 s. is not a Market Price.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-person300">
                  Robert 
                  Ince 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person300" type="surname" value="Ince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person300" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Anvil brought into Mr. Swift's Shop; I helped to take it out of the Boat, and heard the Agreement at 20 s. per Hundred, to be paid half Cash, and half in Iron Plate; and the Gentleman came afterwards and made a strong Demand for more Money than the Agreement; my Master refus'd to give him more Money, and would have him take the Iron according to his Agreement; he went away, and never came afterward to demand the Plate. Mr. Swift was not at home when the Anvil came; it had been two Hours in the Shop before he saw it: We question'd whence it came, and the Man told us, it came from above-Bridge; that it was his own, and that he sold it out of necessity. When my Master came home, he said he did not want any such thing, he had enough by him. 'Tis a good Price that was given for it, and is as much as any Body will allow: There was 2 l. 3 s. and 6 d. paid for it in Cash, and the Difference between paying in Iron Plate and Cash, is not above 4 s. in a Hundred Weight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-person301">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person301" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Mr. Mabson and the Prisoner and I were at the Tavern, the Prisoner said he knew the Man he bought it of, and that he liv'd somewhere about Golden-Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-person302">
                  Josiah 
                  Roper 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person302" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person302" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Swift's Foreman: This Anvil came to our Shop in a Wherry: I order'd the Men to heave it up. I asked who it belong'd to; he said it was his own; that Necessity drove him to sell it; and he was to have 20 s. a Hundred and half in Plate. I have made them, and I think this is a Market Price.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it part of your Master's Trade to buy and sell Iron in this manner?</p>
               <p>Josiah Roper. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-40-person303">
                  Thomas 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person303" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person303" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , depos'd to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Justice Jones. Mr. Swift had told me the Story before; that he was charg'd with buying 2 stolen Anvil. Mr. Mabson and Mr. Swift and another Man came to my House; Mr. Swift said, this is the Man that claims the Anvil: well says I, what would you have of Mr. Swift? Mr. Mabson reply'd, either that he would let me have my Anvil, or that you will give me a Search Warrant. Why you know where it is, says Mr. Swift, and if you will swear it is your's, you may have it: I believe he designed to make some Advantage of him; For he demanded two Guineas, and said he was so much out of Pocket: Let me have a Search Warrant then says Mr. Mabson; I told him I would not grant a Search Warrant, he knew where the Anvil was; if you will not let me have a Search Warrant, says he, I'll have him sent to Newgate in half an Hour's Time: You'll hardly do that, says I, for he is a reputable Man. Mr. Swift has been Smith to me many Years; is a general Dealer in Iron, and is an honest and just Man.</p>
               <p>Justice Cross, 
               <persName id="t17360610-40-person304">
                  Zachariah 
                  Cave 
               <interp inst="t17360610-40-person304" type="surname" value="Cave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person304" type="given" value="Zachariah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and others, gave Mr. Swift the Character of an honest, just, and reputable Man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100015"></xptr>The Jury <rs id="t17360610-40-verdict169" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-40-verdict169" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him, and the Court granted him a Copy of his Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
