<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-24">
               <interp inst="t17351210-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-24" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-24" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-24-off106-c113" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-defend165 t17351210-24-off106 t17351210-24-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>29, 30. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-defend165" type="defendantName">
                     Burton 
                     Brace 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-24-defend165" type="surname" value="Brace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-defend165" type="given" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-defend165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17351210-24-person166">
                  James 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person166" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person166" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (not yet taken,) for <rs id="t17351210-24-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351210-24-victim168" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Bardin 
                        <interp inst="t17351210-24-victim168" type="surname" value="Bardin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-24-victim168" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-24-victim168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-off106 t17351210-24-victim168"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him five Shillings and six Pence
            </rs>, <rs id="t17351210-24-cd107" type="crimeDate">December 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-off106 t17351210-24-cd107"></join>.</p>
               <p>Peter Bardin. My Lord, on Tuesday Morning at one a Clock, going in a Coach to see that Lady home, the Prisoner, with a Pistol in his Hand, attacked me turning out of <placeName id="t17351210-24-crimeloc108">Hemming's Row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-24-crimeloc108" type="placeName" value="Hemming's Row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-24-crimeloc108" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-off106 t17351210-24-crimeloc108"></join>. Your Money, Sir. says he, quick, or by G - you are a dead Man - There was another with him, who ran to the Horses Head, and stopt the Coach - Some Silver I gave to the first, but he, not satisfied, demanded what I meant by trifling with him. D - ye, Sir, says he, more Money. or I will shoot you through the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100008"></xptr> Head. I offered him some Copper, but he swore it was Silver that he wanted and would have. I told him there was all, and he was welcome to search me if he pleased. Then he demanded what Money the other Gentleman had got. That Gentleman's a Lady, Sir, says I; for on the side she sat it was so dark, the Window being drawn up, that he could not by light distinguish the Sex. His Companion then went and drew that Window down, and robbed the Lady, that being done, towards Covent Garden, the Prisoner went, and we drove on.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it dark?</p>
               <p>Mr. Bardin. Indeed it was not Moon-light: But opposite to us there was a Lamp, by which I clearly saw the Prisoners Face. A Face, I well remembred I had seen a hundred times before, but in what place I could not recollect - When I came home, I met with Mr. Taylor, told him how, and where I had been robbed, and then described the Prisoner's Face, and Voice, and Dress exactly. Taylor, next Day went to the Golden Lyon in Russel street. Thence to the Theatre in Drury-lane, he sent for me. I went; and there immediately the Prisoner I singled out, and seized him by the Shoulder, Sir, you're the very Man that robbed me! I, Sir? Yes, you Sir! Then a Constable was called, but he was so drunk, he could not carry himself, much less the Prisoner: So we called another. In a little time the Prisoner was conveyed to Justice Mitford, and by him examined. Nothing would he confess, but only said, he had been a <rs id="t17351210-24-deflabel109" type="occupation">Drawer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-defend165 t17351210-24-deflabel109"></join> at the Devil - Then I recollected I had seen him there. On searching him, some Bullets in his Pocket were found, and under his Arm a loaded Pistol.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person169">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Vanbrackle 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person169" type="surname" value="Vanbrackle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person169" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Coach with Mr. Bardin, when we were robb'd, but I don't know the Persons who robb'd us. On the side I sat, the Window of the Coach was drawn up. One of the Men pulled it down and took from me three Shillings and Six-Pence, or five Shillings and six pence, I forget which, As soon as they were gone, Mr. Bardin said he had seen the Man who rob'd him before, but could not recollect where.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Prosecutor is a Player, and the lady is one of the Women of the Town. He's Jealous that I should Rival him, and to prevent it, he has carried on this Prosecution.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person170">
                  Thomas 
                  Goodale 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person170" type="surname" value="Goodale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person170" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I searched the Prisoner slightly at the Yellow-Lion and then I carried him before Capt. Mitford, where I search'd him again, and then I found a Pistol under his Arm, and a paper of Gun-powder and two Bullets in his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own I had the Pistol, but it was in my Pocket, and not under my Arm.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person171">
                  Thomas 
                  Alderson 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person171" type="surname" value="Alderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person171" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Coachman. Driving along Hermitage Row with this Gentleman, and that Lady in my Coach, a Man came up and asked me if I was hired. I said yes, and then another came up and said, stop Coach or I'll shoot ye One of the Windows was drawn up, and one of the Men pulled it down again.</p>
               <p>Mr. Taylor. On Monday Night, I was at the Golden Lyon in Russel-street Covent-Garden, and lost Four Guineas at the Bar. I went away and returned in half an Hour, and took the Money again. The Prisoner and another Person were then there, and saw me receive it. I observed that they kept an Eye on me, which made me suspect them; It was then about Ten a Clock, I went over to the Kings Arms, and they followed and staid till near twelve. Next Day the Prosecutor told me that he had been rob'd and describ'd one of the Men. On Wednesday I went again to the Lyon, and saw the same two Persons. Mr. Ellis (Sir 
               <persName id="t17351210-24-person172">
                  Robert 
                  Walpole 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person172" type="surname" value="Walpole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person172" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Steward) coming in I said to him. By Mr. Bardins Description one of those Men must be one of them that rob'd him. I sent to the Play-house for the Prosecutor, and in a little time he came and went to the Fire-side, looked at the Prisoner, and seized him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He told me Mr. Bardin would not prosecute, if I would give him 100 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Taylor. A Message was left at Drury-lane Play-house, to desire me to come to the Prisoner. When I went, I asked him what he had to say, and he said he could get a Friend to be bound to raise him 100 l. If Mr. Bardin would not Prosecute; I bid him speak to Mr. Bardin himself, for I would have nothing to do with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person173">
                  Edward 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person173" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person173" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at a Publick house by Covent-Garden, where the Prisoner was drinking in the next Box to me. In an Hour the prosecutor came in, and turning his Back to the Fire, looked wishfully on the Prisoner, and then reaching over took him by the Shoulder, and said, You are the Man that robb'd me. Sir, says the Prisoner, you're mistaken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you see me at the Rose-Tavern in Bridges-street, on Tuesday Morning, from between Twelve and One till Four. Did you not bett with me there, and then go to King's Coffee-house.</p>
               <p>Mr. Thomas. No I saw you there between Three and Four, but not sooner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have Witnesses to my Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person174">
                  Richard 
                  Keys 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person174" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person174" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner since Michaelmas-last, I bought an Estate of him (the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100009"></xptr> Ship Ale-house, and three other Houses in Walworth) for 200 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person175">
                  John 
                  Hilliard 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person175" type="surname" value="Hilliard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person175" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the Prisoner nine Years, I knew him before he went to the Devil, and while he was there, and since he came away, and he always bore a good Character. He left off being a Drawer when Mr. Goosetry left the Devil, which is about nine Months ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person176">
                  Thomas 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person176" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person176" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Oylman. I have known him about eighteen Months, my Acquaintance begun with a view of purchasing part of his Estate.</p>
               <p>Ralph Hall. I am his Brother in-law. He was bound apprentice to the Devil, and behaved extreamly well in that Service.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-24-person177">
                  David 
                  Odell 
               <interp inst="t17351210-24-person177" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person177" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seven or eight Years, We were four Years Fellow-servants to Mr. Goosetry, the Master of the Devil, in which time, Mr. Goosetry had not any Servant of whom he had a better Opinion than of the Prisoner. He had engaged to go to Sea with Mr. Woodford, a Captain of an India Man, and was to have gone on the twentieth of November last.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17351210-24-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17351210-24-punish111" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-24-punish111" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-24-defend165 t17351210-24-punish111"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
