<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-58">
               <interp inst="t17351210-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-58" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-58" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-58-off246-c326" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-person452 t17351210-58-off246 t17351210-58-verdict252"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-58-off246-c327" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-defend453 t17351210-58-off246 t17351210-58-verdict252"></join>
         
               <p>75. <rs id="t17351210-58-off246" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-off246" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-off246" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17351210-58-victim451" type="victimName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17351210-58-person452" type="defendantName">
                              
                                 <persName id="t17351210-58-defend453" type="defendantName">
                                    Philip 
                                    Williams 
                                 <interp inst="t17351210-58-defend453" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17351210-58-defend453" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17351210-58-defend453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           </persName>
                              
                           <interp inst="t17351210-58-person452" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17351210-58-person452" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17351210-58-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        , was indicted for the Martha
                         his 
                        <rs id="t17351210-58-viclabel247" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-victim451 t17351210-58-viclabel247"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-58-victim451" type="surname" value="his"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-58-victim451" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-58-victim451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-off246 t17351210-58-victim451"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , by kicking and beating her, and throwing a Tin Kettle at her, and thereby giving her several mortal Bruises, and one mortal Wound on the left Side of her Head, of the length of one Inch, and depth of a quarter of an Inch, <rs id="t17351210-58-cd248" type="crimeDate">November 18</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-off246 t17351210-58-cd248"></join>, of which mortal Wound and Bruises the languished till the ninth of December following, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-58-person454">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17351210-58-person454" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person454" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person454" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner, and his Wife and I, were all acquainted, she <rs id="t17351210-58-viclabel249" type="occupation">kept a Milk Cellar</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-victim451 t17351210-58-viclabel249"></join> in <placeName id="t17351210-58-crimeloc250">Queen-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-58-crimeloc250" type="placeName" value="Queen-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-58-crimeloc250" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-off246 t17351210-58-crimeloc250"></join>, and he is a <rs id="t17351210-58-deflabel251" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-person452 t17351210-58-deflabel251"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-58-defend453 t17351210-58-deflabel251"></join> in the First Regiment of Guards, and a very honest Man he is, and his Wife had been ailing a long time, and was dropsical, and he did not strike her at all. But as I was a going to say, I went to see his Wife at this Milk Cellar, and we sat down to eat, and by and by in comes the Prisoner. Pat, says he, It is a strange thing that I can never come home but my Neighbours find fault with you for scolding and quarrelling, and with that, she took him by the Shoulder, and threw him against the Wainscot, for which he gave her a slight Kick on the Tail of her things, and she took him by the Hair of his Head, and threw herself on the Bed, and dragged him to her, and gave him several Blows on the Face, and scratched him till the Blood came. I did what I could to part them, and then he went towards the Chimney to take his Hat, and she flung the Cow at him, and struck him on the left Side as he could scarce recover his Breath.</p>
               <p>Q What Cow?</p>
               <p>Mary Wilson A Sign-board of the Cow, that stood next the Street - And so in his Passion, the first thing he took up was a Tin Milk Kettle, he threw it at her, and hit her on the left side of the Head, and it bled very much, at which he seemed to be frighted, and ran to fetch a Surgeon - Next Morning she went to milk her Cow, and I found her with the Kettle upon her Head. I wonder Mrs. Williams, says I, that you will carry the Kettle upon your Head when you know it is out of order - O, says she, It is not my Head that I stand upon, but it is my side, for I got a drop in my Eye, and fell over the Churn and hurt my side - At one o'Clock next Morning she was got so drunk at a milk Celler in the Strand, that she had much ado to get home; and when she was dead there was nothing but a bit of Oyl-skin on the Wound.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-58-person455">
                  Mary 
                  Prat 
               <interp inst="t17351210-58-person455" type="surname" value="Prat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person455" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person455" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard say, that the Prisoner had killed his Wife, and so I went to see how it was, and meeting a Man coming up the Stairs, I asked him if she was dead; he said, No, she stirs; and the Prisoner said he was sorry for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-58-person456">
                  Richard 
                  Hales 
               <interp inst="t17351210-58-person456" type="surname" value="Hales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person456" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On the twenty or twenty first of last Month, the Deceased came to my House in Pall-mall, and complained of a Wound in her Head - I found the Skull bare about an Inch long, a little above her left Temple, but no Fracture, nor Fissure. I drest it eight or nine times. She complained of a pain in her side. I let her blood, and gave her a Plaister for it, and she came no more. When dead, I took off<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100035"></xptr> the Top of the Scull, and all was right in respect to the external Wound. Taking off the Dura Mater (a strong Membrane that every where nes the internal Part of the Scull, and covers the Brain.) I found in the Top of the left Lobe of the Brain, two small Ulcers, from whence a small Quantity of Matter was discharged - These Ulcers might be the Cause of her Death; but I cannot say that the Blow was the Cause of the Ulcers; but I rather think they might proceed from some Obstruction in the small Capillary Blood Vessels of the Brain, which might be occasioned by an ill Habit of Body. On opening the Breast, I found a small Adhesion of the Lungs to the Pleura, and a pretty large Quantity of Matter on that side of the Breast: This with the Matter in the Brain, might be a concurring Cause of her Death: And I can hardly think that the Wound was partly the Cause - I found nothing else particular in the Breast, or any other of the Cavities.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-58-person457">
                  John 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17351210-58-person457" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person457" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Ulcers in the Lobe of the Brain might proceed either from a Concussion of the Brain, or an ill Habit of Body; and the Matter in the left Cavity of the Breast might proceed from the same ill Habit.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Wife and I lived very happily till I was lame and could work no longer; and then she used to get drunk, and lye out a Nights, and when she came home, would cry out Murder; and so I lay in the Barracks - She wanted Money to pay her Cow man; I told her, My Dear, I have spent three Half pence out of the two Shillings; and then she fell upon me, upon which, I told her I would have no more of this Milk Trade, and so I took the Pail, and threw it up Stairs, not with any Design to hurt her; but it unluckily hit against the Corner of the Stairs, and so struck her on the Head.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351210-58-verdict252" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-58-verdict252" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
