<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-6">
               <interp inst="t17360721-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-6" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-6" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-6-off38-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-defend78 t17360721-6-off38 t17360721-6-verdict42"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-6-off39-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-defend80 t17360721-6-off39 t17360721-6-verdict42"></join>
         
               <p>7, 8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-defend78" type="defendantName">
                     Rose 
                      Mahon , otherwise <rs id="t17360721-6-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-defend78 t17360721-6-alias-1"></join>Shepperd</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend78" type="surname" value="Mahon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend78" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-defend80" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Shepperd 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend80" type="surname" value="Shepperd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend80" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-defend80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, Mahon <rs id="t17360721-6-off38" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-off38" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-off38" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               for stealing a Gold Watch, Seal and Chain, value 20 l.
            </rs> from the Person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-victim82" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Gould 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-6-victim82" type="surname" value="Gould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-victim82" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-victim82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            ; and Shepperd for <rs id="t17360721-6-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-6-cd40" type="crimeDate">June 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-off38 t17360721-6-cd40"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-off39 t17360721-6-cd40"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person83">
                  Thomas 
                  Boniface 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person83" type="surname" value="Boniface"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person83" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the Prisoner Mahon, about 3 o' Clock in the Morning, on Sunday, July 4. in Windmill-street. I carry'd her to the Round house, and thence to Justice De Veil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person84">
                  Henry 
                  Gould 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person84" type="surname" value="Gould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person84" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of June about 10 at Night, I was coming through <placeName id="t17360721-6-crimeloc41">Coventry-Court, near the Hay market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-6-crimeloc41" type="placeName" value="Coventry-Court, near the Hay market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-6-crimeloc41" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-off38 t17360721-6-crimeloc41"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-6-off39 t17360721-6-crimeloc41"></join>, and saw Rose Mahon at a Door, and she asked me to walk up Stairs with her.</p>
               <p>Mahon. Don't say so my Dear, - don't tell that Lye.</p>
               <p>Gould. I was pretty merry, and though I never saw her before, I went up one pair of Stairs, at one Mrs. Maxwell's, and says I, I have got no Money to satisfy you; well, well, says she, no matter for that I was not so much in Liquor as she thought me to be; she thought I suppose, I could not miss my Watch.</p>
               <p>We went into a Room where there was a Bed, and she fell immediately to opening the Waistband of my Breeches. I asked her what she meant by that? O says she my Dear, nothing, - I will please you, I'll please you; and she picked the Watch out of my Fob, and run down Stairs as fast as she could. I cried out to the Woman below, who was with her Daughters in the Passage to stop her, for I had lost my Watch, but she got off; and I waited in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210005"></xptr> House from that Time 'till Eight the next Morning. Some Time after she was gone, in came 
               <persName id="t17360721-6-person85">
                  Joseph 
                  Shepperd 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person85" type="surname" value="Shepperd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person85" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he pretended to be Mahon's Husband. -</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been at this House before?</p>
               <p>Gould. Yes, my Lord, I had been there once before.</p>
               <p>Q. What, is it a Publick House?</p>
               <p>Gould. No, 'tis not a Publick House; 'tis a House where they keep such Women.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a Bawdy House?</p>
               <p>Gould. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. And yet you say you have been there before, don't you?</p>
               <p>Gould. Yes, once before.</p>
               <p>Q. You knew what the House was, yet you must go there.</p>
               <p>Gould. I did. So when Shepperd came in, the Woman of the House told him his Wife had done a fine Thing; she has pick'd this Gentleman's Pocket of a Gold Watch; and, says Shepperd, what Business had he with my Wife, I did not meddle with your Wife, says I, only she has been so good as to run away with my Watch; if you'll let me have it again I'll give you half a Guinea. He said, he would go and see if he could find her, and in a little Time he return'd with a Butcher of St. James's Market, and said, she was not to be found; then they went out again, and returned no more that Night.</p>
               <p>Mahon. I beg my Lord he may turn his Face to me. I would ask you on the Vertue of your Oath, whether you did not insist upon going up into my Chamber? Whether, as I was standing at the Door you did not ask me what it was a Clock? Whether I did not tell you, it was Time for you to be at Home, and whether you did not say, my Dear I'll not go Home 'till I've seen your Apartment? I told you, I did not live there; you said I did; why, said you, is not this Rosy? I stepp'd up, and he follow'd me.</p>
               <p>Gould. My Lord, she ask'd me to go up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask you, Sir, whether you never declared to any one, that you gave her the Watch?</p>
               <p>Gould. No. I never gave it her, nor did she ever ask for it, she was not so good as to ask me, she took it without asking I thank God I never was in such a Scrape as this before.</p>
               <p>Mahon. I desire he may be asked, if he did not tell me he had no more than 9d in his Pocket, and whether he did not give that to my Maid?</p>
               <p>Gould. She took the 9 d. herself.</p>
               <p>Mahon. But I gave my Maid your 9 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person86">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person86" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person86" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Kitchen at the Red-Lyon Alehouse, in Coventry Court, and in comes Joseph Sheppard; this was the Night the Watch was lost, and he told us, his Rosy had made a Gold Watch; I ask'd him from who; he said from the King's Messenger, and described him: He said, he had blue Grey Cloaths on, white Spatterdashes, and a Whip in his Hand. The Watch he said was very heavy, and would pawn for 14 Spankers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person87">
                  Mary 
                  Maxwell 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person87" type="surname" value="Maxwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person87" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person87" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That Jo. Sheppard took the Lodging in my House in Coventry Court for him and his Wife, and he never lay out of the House 'till this 28th of June; then Sheppard came in while the Gentleman was in my House, and he said, if his Wife had done such a Thing he would cut her Nose off, and that he would go and see for her; but he went up to his Room, and carried off all the Goods.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you any Discourse with Mr Gould that Night?</p>
               <p>Maxwell. He sat all Night in my Room, we must say something to be sure. As to the Watch, I have nothing to do with it: he told me, she had run away with it. He came to my House about 9 a Clock.</p>
               <p>- Council He says it was 10.</p>
               <p>Maxwell. God bless me; - then the Bells don't go right about; it must be but 9, because when he cry'd out upon the Stairs, Watch, Watch, I answer'd, what, Watch call'd at 9 a Clock! I know no more on't. - There's the Man, I never saw him before, I told him, it was pity if he wanted a Woman, he did not go to his Wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person88">
                  Sarah 
                  Maxwell 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person88" type="surname" value="Maxwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person88" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Gentleman came running down Stairs with his Breeches in his Hand, and said his Watch was gone; I went to the Nagg's-Head and fetch'd Sheppard home; when he came in, he set his Elbow thus, and said to Mr. Gould, G - D - you Sir, what Concerns have you with my Wife, - pray what did you give her Sir? He said 15 d at first, but afterwards he owned it was but 9 d. Sheppard threatned to sue him, for having something to do with his Wife, and went out, but returned no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-6-person89">
                  Thomas 
                  Bonniface 
               <interp inst="t17360721-6-person89" type="surname" value="Bonniface"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person89" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While Mahon was examining before Col. De Viel, some Body brought the Watch; but who it was I cannot tell, this is the Watch.</p>
               <p>Gould. This is my Watch I declare.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210006"></xptr>Mahon. My Lord, be so good as to hear what I said to the Gentleman.</p>
               <p>I was standing at my own Door and this Man came by, what's a Clock my Dear says he? I told him I could not tell. What's this Rosy says he? Yes says I, and smiled, my Lord. My Dear says he, I am just come to Town and have but 9 d. else I would have gone up and drunk with you. Well, says I, come up, and make a Present of that to my Maid, so up he came, and the Maid had the 9d. I sent her out, and then - he said my Dear, trust to my Honour, my Generosity. In the Morning, I'll pay you. I said I did not chuse that, I owe my Landlady 10 s. give me something in lieu, and accordingly he gave me the Watch in my Bed-chamber, to pawn for four Guineas: My Lord, when a Gentleman is in Privacy with any of us Ladies of the Town, and has no Money, he don't care it should be known; I was not willing to let my Servant into the Gentleman's Case. As I hope to be saved, I was to have two Guineas for myself; would you be willing, Sir, a Lady should be guilty in that Way, and to make your Case known to a Servant. The Prisoner Sheppard is an innocent Gentleman. Both <rs id="t17360721-6-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-6-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
