<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-59">
               <interp inst="t17370420-59" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-59" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-59" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-59" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-59-off296-c319" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-59-defend456 t17370420-59-off296 t17370420-59-verdict299"></join>
         
               <p>* 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-defend456" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Dounahough , otherwise <rs id="t17370420-59-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-59-defend456 t17370420-59-alias-7"></join>Dennis</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-defend456" type="surname" value="Dounahough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-defend456" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-defend456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-59-off296" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-off296" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-off296" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370420-59-victim458" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Pulwash 
                        <interp inst="t17370420-59-victim458" type="surname" value="Pulwash"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-59-victim458" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-59-victim458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-59-off296 t17370420-59-victim458"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   (now 
                     <persName id="t17370420-59-person459">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Pate 
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person459" type="surname" value="Pate"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-59-person459" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370420-59-person459" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ) in a certain open Field near the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a Linnen Gown, value 7 s. a Pair of Stays, value 3 s. a Cambrick Handkerchief, value 18 d. a Muslin ditto, value 1 s. a Linnen Apron, value 2 s. a callimanco quilted Coat, value 15 s. a dimitty Petticoat, value 3 s. a Pair of Damask Shoes, value 2 s. 6 d. a Pair of Silver Buckles, value 8 s. a Bermudas Hat, value 7 s a Suit of Cambrick Headcloths laced, value 2 s. 6 d. a Gold Ring, value 8 s. and 9 d in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370420-59-cd297" type="crimeDate">August 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-59-off296 t17370420-59-cd297"></join>.</p>
               <p>* 
               <persName id="t17370420-59-person460">
                  Samuel 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person460" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person460" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was try'd for this Fact in October Sessions 1736. and was executed for the same, See Sessions Book No. 8. p. 198.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Pate. I was robb'd in <placeName id="t17370420-59-crimeloc298">Tottenham-Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-59-crimeloc298" type="placeName" value="Tottenham-Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-59-crimeloc298" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-59-off296 t17370420-59-crimeloc298"></join> Fair Time; 'twas one of the two last Days of the Fair, - the latter End of August it was, but I could never tell the Day of the Month, only I remember 'twas the latter End of August. I was then coming from the Fair, - my Sister and some other Company were with me, but I stay'd a little longer than ordinary to see the Clock-work, so my Company was just gone before me, - I staid a little behind them too, to tye up my Garter. - Morgan, not this Man ( the Prisoner) came up to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200036"></xptr> me first; he had a Dagger, and he led me to the Prisoner, and he had a Pistol; - there were 3 of them in all, and the third Man had a Pistol too. The Prisoner and the other, had seiz'd a young Man, so he and I were robb'd by them. The Prisoner held his Pistol to my Breast, and it snapp'd twice, but did not go off, I down'd on my Knees, and begg'd for Christ's Sake they would spare my Life; then they carry'd me over a high Bank towards the Brill, I begg'd for Christ Jesus Sake they would have Mercy on me, I told them I was with Child, and begg'd for Mercy for the Infant's Sake within me. I was not with Child, but I did tell them so indeed, that they might be favourable: The Prisoner said, my Life should be safe. -</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other Man who was robb'd go with you to this Place, or did you go alone?</p>
               <p>Pate. Two of them carry'd the Man a little Distance from me, and after they had stripp'd him, they came up to me, and made me strip my self, all but my Hat, Cap and Shoes, - those they pull'd off themselves. The Prisoner assisted in making me strip, and he took my Cloaths as they were taken off. I lost a Holland sprig'd Gown, a Pair of Stays, a quilted Coat, and a Pair of Shoes, they left me one Petticoat on and my Shift, but they did not know it. They left likewise my Stockings and a Petticoat which I had mended up, to wear under another. Then they put a Gag in my Mouth, (and broke this Tooth out,) and they tore my Pocket, and put that into my Mouth too, and ty'd it down hard behind: The Gag was Iron or Steel, and it cut my Mouth, but I got it away with my Tongue, after I was in the Ditch, so that I could cry out. I lost this Tooth by it, - it did not come out just then, but it cut and rotted it so, that it came out afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. After they had ty'd your Pocket over your Mouth, what did they do then?</p>
               <p>Pate. After Morgan had done what he thought proper with me, then the Prisoner try'd for an Hour, but could not have his Ends, he did not lie with me, but Morgan did, and the Prisoner endeavoured to do it. Morgan did more than the Prisoner did; he attempted it first, and then the Prisoner attempted after him; he (the Prisoner) lay a-top of me, but he did not lie with me: They kept me rather more than 3 Hours, and after they had done all that they thought proper, they took hold of my Hand and said, - come along. I was very much afraid of my Life, and said, Dear Sir, I will come along, but Dear Sir, spare my Life: So they carry'd me to the Man they had stripp'd stark naked.</p>
               <p>Q. During the Time they were abusing you, was the Gag in your Mouth?</p>
               <p>Pate. No, they did not put that into my Mouth, till they bound me to the Man.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did they bind you?</p>
               <p>Pate. They ty'd my Hands to his Hands, and my Legs to his Legs; - they ty'd us Back to Back: I had my Flanel Coat and my Shift on, but they did not know they had left me my Shift, for they had bid me pull it off, and I was pulling it off, but I don't know how it happen'd - God Almighty would not have it so.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the other Man gag'd too?</p>
               <p>Pate. No, nor did they bind him so hard as they did me: they put a Piece of my Pocket into his Mouth, but he could cry out, and I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. When they had done this, what then?</p>
               <p>Pate. They push'd us both into the Ditch, and the Man that was bound with me lay above me, I lay with my Face on the Bank, and that sav'd me. 'Tis not a Ditch that's always full of Water, but 'tis a Drain that comes from the Brill. I was undermost in the Water, and if my Head had not come on the Bank, I must have been smother'd. I lay in this Condition from half an Hour after 12, till about 5 in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoner at the Bar was one of them?</p>
               <p>Pate. Yes, I have great Knowledge to be assur'd; it was very light when they took hold of me, and it was light again before they had done with me. I saw them by Means of the Light of the Heavens, - 'twas Moon-light: - I have great Knowledge of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Moon up before they had done with you?</p>
               <p>Pate. I believe it was the Moon, but it did not shine out bright; - the Moment I was taken out of the Ditch, I said I knew the Men.</p>
               <p>Q. When you and the Man lay in the Ditch, did either of you make any Noise?</p>
               <p>Pate. The Man did, but I could not, 'till about 2 o'Clock, then I got the Gag a little on one Side of my Month.</p>
               <p>Q. You was saying you knew him when you saw him; when was it you did see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>Pate. The Prisoner was taken up on Account of a Quarrel, and I having describ'd the Prisoner so well, the Person that took him up thought he was the Man, so he sent for me, and I -</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it sent for you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200037"></xptr>Pate. Mr. Barnes; and as soon as I saw him, I was ready to sink, and said if there's a God Almighty in Heaven, that was the Man that held a Pistol to my Breast The People bid me be sure, and I said, I could not be surer, than I was in my own Heart. I had been shew'd an hundred Thieves, but I never fix'd on any but the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is all for the sake of the Reward.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he such Hair on, as he has now?</p>
               <p>Pate. I can't say whether he had a Wig or his own Hair, but I am sure he's the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person461">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person461" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person461" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to work between 4 and 5 in the Morning in the Time of Tottenham-Court Fair, 'twas one of the last two Days, and I heard somebody cry, - Murder: I went to the Place from whence the Noise came, and I found a Man and this Woman ty'd together; the Man had never a Rag upon him; - the Woman had a Smock, a Flannel Coat, and her Stockings on, but she was so cover'd with Water and Mud, that I could not tell at first, whether she had any Thing on or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Thing in her Mouth?</p>
               <p>Smith. She had a piece of her Pocket Apron ty'd about her Mouth, but I did not see any Thing in it. I took them out of the Ditch; here's a piece of the Cord they were ty'd with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person462">
                  George 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person462" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person462" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One Wednesday Morning about 5 o'Clock, a Man came to me for a Quartern of Gin, and said, there was a poor Woman had been thrown naked into a Ditch, and was almost starved, he would drink some of it himself, he said, and would give her the rest. I took the Gin in my Hand and went with him. Our Men that work in the Fields had put her into a Clamp, (or Brick-Kiln ) but there was but little Heat in it. When I came up, the Men ask'd me for a Dram; No, no says I, the Woman wants it more than you, so I gave her a Glass, and look'd at her, she had a good likely Face, but she was in a most miserable Condition. After I had seen her, I went to my Spouse and said, Bett, there's a Woman bound in a miserable Manner, and must certainly dye; if you think well, I'll bring her here, and she shall be put to Bed; she consented, so I brought her Home and she was put to Bed, and we kept her till Friday Evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what's become of the Man that was bound with you?</p>
               <p>Pate. I never saw him before; when we were unbound, he ran away as fast as he could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person463">
                  Ann 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person463" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person463" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person463" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Pate lodged in my House at that Time; she went out, in order to go to Tottenham Court Fair, and did not come Home all Night; in the Morning a Man came and told me she desired I would send her something to cover her Nakedness.</p>
               <p>Pate. My Lord the Prisoner has a great many Witnesses, I am afraid they are bad, let them come in one by one.</p>
               <p>- Barnes the Constable. I took the Prisoner in custody for an Assault, and a Woman telling him he was a Highwa man and a Thief, and that he had not walked to Highgate and Hampstead for nothing, I suspected him to be concerned in this Robbery, so I sent for her, and as soon as she came into the Room, she said, to her sorrow she knew that Man to be one that us'd her ill with Morgan. I had shewn her several suspicious Persons? before, but she never accus'd any but Morgan and the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. A Woman that I had some Dispute with, swore an Assault against me, and I was carried to this Barnes's House, so he sent for this Woman, whom I never saw in my Life, and the Design is, to take away my Life for the sake of the Reward. I beg you'd dive into this Woman's Character, and enquire how she gets her Living.</p>
               <p>Q. When you Swore against Morgan, did not you swear he Ravish'd you.</p>
               <p>Pate. It was not asked me in that Manner; I said, he did all that lay in his Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person464">
                  Richard 
                  Carsew 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person464" type="surname" value="Carsew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person464" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to my House at Sittingborn the 14th of August last, and liv'd there a Fortnight; Sittingborn is 43 Miles from London. He was at Harvest-work in the Island, before he came to my House.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time did he go away from your House?</p>
               <p>Carsew. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you never here before - to give Evidence.</p>
               <p>Carsew. No; if you want a Character of me, I can send to Sittingborn, there's Justice Hole, and the Heads of the Place, will give me a Character.</p>
               <p>C. But we can't stay to send to Sittingborn; do you know Mr. Pemberton there?</p>
               <p>Carsew. No.</p>
               <p>C. Mr. Pemberton lives within a Quarter of a Mile of the Town, and is a Gentleman of 5 or 600 a Year. What's the Man's Name at the Rose-Inn?</p>
               <p>Carsew. I can't remember.</p>
               <p>A Stranger. Do you know Mr. Adney?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200038"></xptr>Carsew. Aye! that's the Name. (The Stranger was reprimanded by the Court.)</p>
               <p>Mr. Keaton and the Stranger deposed, that they knew Mr. Pemberton, and it was their Opinion every body that lives there must know him too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person465">
                  Mary 
                  Carsew 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person465" type="surname" value="Carsew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person465" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person465" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd her Husband's Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person466">
                  David 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person466" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person466" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work'd with the Prisoner the 14th or 15th of August at Mr. Tassel's, a Farmer at Sittingborn, and we worked there a Fortnight We were eighteen of us work'd in a Field together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person467">
                  William 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person467" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person467" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutrix's Name I thought had been Hoskings, then she changed it to Pulwash, and now to Pate. She was lock'd out the Night before she was robbed, and begged a Lodging at my House. She sent for me after she was robbed, and told me she could swear but to one Man, and he had a Scar in his Cheek. Afterwards she told me the Thief-takers and she had seen the Fellows that robbed her at Welch-Runt Fair, and that they knew how to find them. Some Time after this she told me the Thief-takers d - mn'd her for a Bitch, and said she must swear to some body right or wrong, for they would not spend their Time after her A - se for nothing.</p>
               <p>Pate. They never said so; I have consider'd of the Thing, and have begg'd of God they might die before they were taken.</p>
               <p>Low. Pate has lived about Black-Mary's-Hole, plying at the Bawdy Houses. I have heard her say, she'd swear away a Person's Life for a Farthing; she said so to my Sister, and my Sister hit her a knock in the Face for it.</p>
               <p>Q. (To Low) Have you any body here that knows you?</p>
               <p>Low. No; I am a Turner in Castle-Yard, Holbourn.</p>
               <p>Pate. This Man (Low) keeps a vile House in Gray's Inn-Lane, and the Woman he lives with, has another Husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person468">
                  Charles 
                  Shippey 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person468" type="surname" value="Shippey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person468" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Cooper in St. John-street; I know Low, he lives in Gray's-Inn Lane; I look upon him to be a Man whose Oath may be believed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person469">
                  Susan 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person469" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person469" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person469" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was married to Mr. Low at the Fleet. - The Night before she was robbed she told me, she had dream'd that she was robb'd, and gagg'd, and thrown into a Ditch; and when I saw her after the Robbery, I told her, her Dream was fatal. When I asked her, if she knew the Men, she said, - as she hoped to be sav'd she could swear but to one. Another Time she told me, the Thief-takers seiz'd her to fix upon some body. I never saw the Prisoner before, so I don't come for Interest.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Prisoner know you could say all this?</p>
               <p>Low. I don't know, but I was subpoena'd here.</p>
               <p>Pate. This very Woman was try'd here for picking Pockets.</p>
               <p>Marget Anderson. About a Week or a Fortnight before last Sessions, she said she had seen one of the Men in Tothill Fields Bridewell. On Saturday in the same Sessions, she said she saw the Man in King-street, St Giles's, and she called me to look at a Man like a Chair man, - as there's a Christ in Heaven, that's the Man, says she; and this was a Man nothing near so tall as the Prisoner, and she said his Name was O Bryan. I live in King-street, St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-59-person470">
                  Peter 
                  Sneath 
               <interp inst="t17370420-59-person470" type="surname" value="Sneath"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person470" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I have known the Prisoner a Twelvemonth, and take him to be an honest Man; I keep a Chandler's Shop in St. Giles's. In August last the Neighbours told me he was somewhere in Kent, at Harvest Work; and from that Time I did not see him till the latter End of December.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17370420-59-verdict299" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-59-verdict299" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
