<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350522-8">
               <interp inst="t17350522-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-8" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-8" type="date" value="17350522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350522-8-off41-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-8-defend77 t17350522-8-off41 t17350522-8-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-defend77" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Ruberry 
                  <interp inst="t17350522-8-defend77" type="surname" value="Ruberry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-defend77" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-defend77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17350522-8-defloc40">Kensington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-8-defloc40" type="placeName" value="Kensington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-8-defloc40" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-8-defend77 t17350522-8-defloc40"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17350522-8-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17350522-8-victim79" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Pointer 
                        <interp inst="t17350522-8-victim79" type="surname" value="Pointer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-8-victim79" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17350522-8-victim79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-8-off41 t17350522-8-victim79"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by knocking her down with a Hoe and giving her several Mortal Wounds and Bruises, <rs id="t17350522-8-cd42" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-8-off41 t17350522-8-cd42"></join>. of which she languished till the 13th and dyed
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person80">
                  Ann 
                  Newby 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person80" type="surname" value="Newby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person80" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Easter Tuesday, going down by the side of a thick set Hedge, I saw two Gentlemen looking thro' the Hedge, Pray what's the Matter says I. They answer'd, there's a Man beating a Woman unmercifully. I did not see him beat her, but going farther I heard her say, Ye Villain! you would not beat a Man so. I went up to her, and he and she were a little apart, and he was a Hoing. She said he had knock'd her down with a Hoe and stamp'd upon her Groin, and threatned to cut her Cloaths to pieces and stamp her Guts out at her Mouth for going upon his Crop. Ye Villain, says I, how can you serve a Woman so? Hold your Tongue, says he, or I'll give you as much more. I can't say the Prisoner is the Man. The Woman came every Day after, to my House, except the Day she dyed which was on the Sunday following. On the Thursday she got a Warrant; when she came back her Eye was black and swelled; she said she was afraid he had broke something within her, and she should die the death of her Husband, who was kill'd by Fighting.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person81">
                  Margaret 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person81" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person81" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came to my House on Tuesday Night with a black Eye, and complained that a Man in the Fields had beat her, and trod on her Belly. On Wednesday she lay a-bed all Day, and at Night Ann Newby asked if a poor Woman was there. The Deceas'd said, a Quart of Blood came from her, and she was worse than when she lay in. On Thursday she said she'd see for the Man (she did not then know his Name.) On Saturday Night she had taken him, and he had made it up. She went out at six on Sunday Morning, and at ten the same Morning she was found dead in a Stable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person82">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person82" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person82" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She got a Warrant against the Prisoner for assaulting her, it was served at the New Tavern in Kensington. When she came there and saw him, he asked her if he was the Man. She said, she did not know, but it was one whose Name was Will. Ruberry, and he had beat her with a Hoe and stampt upon her. The Prisoner said he had only whipt her. They went before Justice Vincent, where the matter was made up upon the Prisoners paying her six Shillings. On Sunday Noon the Beadle came and told me she was dead.</p>
               <p>Surgeon. I examined the Body. On the lower Part of the Belly which we call the Pubis I found a Bruise externally. And opening the Part I found a quantity of extravasated Blood and Matter about the Gut, we call the Rectum - She was a distemper'd pocky Body.</p>
               <p>Jury-man. Might that Blood be occasion'd by Blows?</p>
               <p>Surgeon. Yes. I believe Blows might be the cause of the Vessels breaking.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person83">
                  Mary 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person83" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person83" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Thursday in Easter Week, the Deceas'd and 
               <persName id="t17350522-8-person84">
                  Betty 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person84" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person84" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             quarrel'd in Holland Walk. The Deceas'd held up a Knife at Morris, and Morris hit her a slap o'the Face, and so the Deceas'd fell into Fits and foam'd at the Mouth.</p>
               <p>Fox. I saw the same, and know the Deceas'd was subject to Fits.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person85">
                  Richard 
                  Chowny 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person85" type="surname" value="Chowny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person85" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard 'em a scolding, and saw the Deceas'd lying on her Back in a Fit, and says I to Betty Morris, what do<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173505220006"></xptr> ye beat her for? Says Betty, she threatned my Life and bit my Finger off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person86">
                  Joseph 
                  Biggs 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person86" type="surname" value="Biggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person86" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At seven o'Clock on Sunday Morning, she had a Dram of Gin at my House; I saw she was in Liquor, and she wanted to light her Pipe, but I bid her go about her business, for I had other Company and did not want such Cattle - She was a drunken quarrelsome Creature.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-8-person87">
                  Francis 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person87" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person87" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17350522-8-person88">
                  Samuel 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17350522-8-person88" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person88" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - Gains, and - Harrison, gave the Prisoner the Character of a laborious careful honest quiet Man. and not inclinable to be quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17350522-8-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-8-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
