<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340911-27">
               <interp inst="t17340911-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-27" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-27" type="date" value="17340911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340911-27-off127-c144" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-27-defend210 t17340911-27-off127 t17340911-27-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>33. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-defend210" type="defendantName">
                     Anthony 
                     Langloge , alias <rs id="t17340911-27-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-27-defend210 t17340911-27-alias-8"></join>Porta</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-defend210" type="surname" value="Langloge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-defend210" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-defend210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , (a Millanese ) was indicted for <rs id="t17340911-27-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 15 Guineas, and 10s. the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340911-27-victim212" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Tadie 
                        <interp inst="t17340911-27-victim212" type="surname" value="Tadie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-27-victim212" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-27-victim212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-27-off127 t17340911-27-victim212"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17340911-27-person213">
                        James 
                        Bowden 
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person213" type="surname" value="Bowden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-27-person213" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-27-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17340911-27-cd128" type="crimeDate">August 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-27-off127 t17340911-27-cd128"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner and some of the Witnesses being Foreigners, a Gentleman was sworn to Interpret.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person214">
                  Joseph 
                  Tadie 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person214" type="surname" value="Tadie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person214" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have Lodgings at Mr. James Bowden's. The Prisoner was directed to me by Mr. De Costa, and came to my Lodgings on Sunday the 18th of August, about 4 in the Afternoon. He brought a Letter, in which he said he had received a Bill of Exchange on Mr. Vassalli, and desired me to inform him where Mr. Vassalli lived, that he might direct to him. I told him I would enquire. He came again on Monday, and I went with him to Mr. Welford, who gave him Directions. He came a third time on Wednesday Morning, and desired me to let<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110012"></xptr> him write a Letter in my Room. I told him he might have been furnish'd with Pens, and Ink, and Paper at his own Lodgings, which was in Cecil-Court, near St. Martin's-Lane; but if he chose to write in my Room he might. And so he sat down at my Desk and began his Letter. My Desk was open, for I had just been writing there my self; and I had left 17 Guineas, 3 Crown pieces, and some Shillings in one of the Drawers. Before he had done, he desired me to help him to a Glass of Water. I went down and brought a Glass: and he was still writing. When he had finish'd his Letter, he directed it to Mr. Vassalli, and then I shut my Desk, and we both went to Dinner to Mr. Angelis, where we staid till evening; and then went again to my Lodgings, where I found Mr. Costa waiting for me. We all 3 went up into my Room, I open'd my Drawer, and mist my Money. Mr. Costa perceiving some alteration in my countenance, asked me what was the matter, I said I have lost 15 Guineas and 10 s. But I know and can swear who has it - For while my Desk was open, there was Nobody left in the Room but the Prisoner - I added, I'll take the Law, and have satisfaction. The Prisoner turned pale. I went down to ask Mr. Bowden's Advice what I had best to do. The Prisoner and Mr. Costa quickly follow'd me. I asked the Prisoner to stay, but he would not; and so we all went to the Prisoner's Lodgings. And while I was knocking at the Door, he ran down St. Martin's-Lane, and by the Church, I follow'd, and cry'd Stop Thief! And as he was running, he put his Hand in his Pocket and threw the Money upon the Pavement, for I saw the motion of his Hand, and heard the Money fall. He was stopt soon after, though he made great resistance in the mean time. The mob picked up the Money, and a Sharper coming by and claiming it, they gave it to him. When the Prisoner was carried before the Justice, he said I lent him the Money, and being ask'd why he ran away, He answer'd that I assaulted him with a Knife.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not ask for Water till after I had done my Letter, and you lock'd the Desk, and took the Key before you went down.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tadie. No, I left it open.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Why did you run from your own Door, and throw the Money away?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. After the Prosecutor had complain'd of his Loss, I said to Mr. Costa Let us go, or we shall be imputed. And when I came to my own Door, I was assaulted in the dark by 3 Men, who demanded my Money; and therefore I run.</p>
               <p>Court. But why did you throw the Money away?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I took it out of my Pocket in order to save it, but in the Fray it dropt out of my Hand.</p>
               <p>Mr. Costa. I waited in the Evening for Mr. Tadie at Mr. Bowden's, who said he had not seen him since Noon. While we were talking, Mr. Tadie and the Prisoner came, and we all 3 went up into Mr. Tadie's Room. He open'd his Desk and pull'd out his Drawers; upon which he look'd very uneasy, and gave himself a knock of the Pate, - What have you lost any Money? says I, Yes, by God, says he, but I know by God who has got it, and I'll see the end on't. But he did not name any body then, though he told me the next Day.</p>

               <p>Court. Did not Tadie say, that Nobody was left in the Room but the Prisoner while the Desk was open?</p>
               <p>Tadie. No, I told de Costa that I knew who had it, but I did not name the Person at that time.</p>
               <p>Mr. Costa. While Mr. Tadie went down to Mr. Burden, the Prisoner turn'd his back to me, fumbled in his Pocket, to shift his Money as I thought, and he dropt a Guinea, or some such piece of Gold; I stoop'd to reach it, but he took it up himself - When we came to the Prisoner's Door, Mr. Tadie knock'd, and then the Prisoner ran away, and Mr. Tadie after him; but I staid at the Door - The Prisoner was a stranger, and had been but 2 or 3 Days in England.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person215">
                  John 
                  Martino 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person215" type="surname" value="Martino"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person215" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr. Herbert, the Queen's Jeweller in St. Martin's-Lane. I heard a cry of stop Thief, and ran to the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110013"></xptr> Door with a Candle, and found some Money lying on the steps: What's the matter? Says I, a Gentleman has been robb'd, says one, What Gentleman? Says I. This Gentleman, says another, and pointed to a stranger who was very well drest in a light Suit and Ruffles. So I pick'd up some Gold, and gave it to that stranger, and others did the like. I was going to take up a Guinea and a half more, but my Mistress came and bid me not touch anymore; and so I kick'd it towards the stranger, and bid him take it up himself. Then I went in; but hearing a fresh Noise, I stept to the Door again, and Mr. Tadie had got hold of the Prisoner. What, says I, was it you that was robb'd? Yes, Why here has been a Stranger that has taken all the Money - The Prisoner struck those about him with his Cane, and in the scuffle the Cane was lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person216">
                  Francis 
                  Roboullet 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person216" type="surname" value="Roboullet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person216" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner in the Round-house. He swore that he would Murder Tadie, or some of his Relations, either here or in Italy, or at least he would burn his House - When he came to the Justice, he said he came over hither to change his Religion, and they wanted to murder him, or swear a Robbery against him: That he knew nothing of the Money that was thrown upon the Pavement, but believ'd they might throw it after to raise a Suspicion - The Justice and he discoursed in Latin, but they did not rightly understand one another, for we don't pronounce it in the same manner as the English do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person217">
                  James 
                  Bowden 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person217" type="surname" value="Bowden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person217" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the Prisoner say, that he came over to change his Religion; but that Mr. Tadie dissuaded him from so doing, and the better to prevail with him, lent him the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes, he lent me 16 Guineas on Monday Night; and Mr. Angelis knows I had Money next Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person218">
                  Angelo 
                  de Angelis 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person218" type="surname" value="de Angelis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person218" type="given" value="Angelo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor and Prisoner dined at my House that Tuesday, and about 4 in the Afternoon the Prisoner pull'd out a handful of Money to pay his Reckoning.</p>
               <p>Court. But this was after the Prosecutor's Money was lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-27-person219">
                  Samuel 
                  Martino 
               <interp inst="t17340911-27-person219" type="surname" value="Martino"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person219" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is a Gentleman born: He came over with both Money and Goods: He has now a Trunk and Goods at the Custom-house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have here a Letter from Mr. Vasselli's, in answer to that I wrote to Mr. Tadie's.</p>
               <p>Interpreter. This is sign'd with Fran. Vasselli's Name, and Dated at Lumley-Castle in Yorkshire, August 27. 1734.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17340911-27-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17340911-27-punish130" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-27-punish130" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-27-defend210 t17340911-27-punish130"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
