<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-1">
               <interp inst="t17361013-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-1" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-1" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-1-off1-c26" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-1-defend27 t17361013-1-off1 t17361013-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>1. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-1-defend27" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Rine 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-1-defend27" type="surname" value="Rine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-defend27" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-defend27" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-1-victim29" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Serjeant 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-1-victim29" type="surname" value="Serjeant"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-1-victim29" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-1-victim29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-1-off1 t17361013-1-victim29"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Hat value 10 s. a silver Stock Clasp value 4 s a barragon Coat value 20 s. a Dimity Wastcoat value 10 s. a a barragon pair of Breeches value 10 s. a pair of silver Knee Buckles value 5 s. a pair of silver Shoe Buckles value 10 s. a silver Spoon value 10 s. a pair of gold Sleeve Buttons value 30 s. a pair of steel Snuffers value 2 s. a gold Ring value 10 s. 5 Keys value 12 d. a Knife value 12 d. a Whip value 10 s. and 4 Guineas and a half in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17361013-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">September 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-1-off1 t17361013-1-cd2"></join>.</p>
               <p>Charles Serjeant. On the 22d of September last. I was going home to Uxbridge, at the first Bridge, a little below <placeName id="t17361013-1-crimeloc3">Notting hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="Notting hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17361013-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-1-off1 t17361013-1-crimeloc3"></join>, I was stopped by two Men, it was between 6 and 7 o'Clock in the Evening, and I was riding after the rate of 10 Miles an Hour. I saw People, and cried Hallo, but they presently dismounted me, one took hold of my Leg and threw me off the Horse, and the other caught me on the other side. One of them held a Hanger to my Breast, and said, if you do not hold your Tongue, I will put you to death. They led me to a Gate that opens into a Field just below the Bridge, and robbed me of 4 Guineas and a half, stripped me stark naked as I was born, and took every thing I had in the World, (Breeches and all) except my Wig, and carried me to a Tree; they spoke in French to one another, and said, Il faut que vous obeyez: Then the Prisoner put a Handkerchief cross my Mouth, and tied it on the Nape of my Neck with two hard Knots; with my Bridle they bound me to the Tree, and then left me. In this Condition I was for two Hours, but my Hands being very cold, I slipped them at last through the Bridle; so I got loose, and went to the Sign of I have brought my Hogs to a fine Market. About 7 o'Clock they stripped me, and about 9 I got to this House. The Prisoner put my Breeches on before my Face, and this Coat I have now on my Back is the same he took from me, the rest of the Things are in Court, and were all taken upon him. I swear to the Prisoner's Hair and his Tongue, for I took notice of his thick shock Head of Hair hanging over his Face, and am sure he is the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-1-person30">
                  William 
                  Walmsley 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person30" type="surname" value="Walmsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person30" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner (and another Man) came through Rosemary. Lane with this Whip in his Hand the 23d of last Month. I said to one that was with me, that Fellow has got a good cleaver Whip, ask him if he will sell it: Yes, says the Prisoner, it is to be sold. I asked him what he would have for it; he said half a Guinea: I desired my Neighbour to bid him. D F for it, that is in the way we mark our Goods 4 s. 6 d. I am a Pawnbroker, and sell Cloaths, and so I mark my Goods. The Prisoner would not take 4 s. 6 d. so he bid him a Crown, then 6 s. and at last he allowed it us for 7 s. and a Gallon of Beer. We let them go off, but the Prisoner gave it his Companion, and he brought it back and took 6 s. and 6 d. for it. While he was brushing the Whip, I observed the Name Charles Serjeant at Uxbridge graved in a silver<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130003"></xptr> Plate on the Butt End. So, says I, this Whip is stole, or somebody has been robbed, let us go down into Rag Fair and see for the Men; upon that, we went down about 30 Yards towards the Fair, and then turned back, for I was but a Servant and could not neglect my Master's Business; so these two Fellows went after them but could not find them. They were no sooner come back, but I saw the Prisoner (and the other Man) coming along with the young Man's Coat upon his Arm; the Man that lives next Door to me bought the Coat for 8 s. Tom, says I, here are the two Men, take care of them. He went to them, and said, I hear the Man that owns the Whip lives at Uxbridge, upon which the Prisoner wanted to have the Whip again; and when he had returned the Money he endeavoured to make off, but we stopped him, and he told us, if we would go with him he would shew us the Person from whom he had it. He carried us to the Bull Inn in Holborn, and there we did indeed find how he came by it, though I did not go to the Inn with him my self, but these next Witnesses, for I was but a Servant.</p>
               <p>Charles Serjeant. I swear this is the Whip which the Prisoner took from me when I was robbed.</p>
               <p>Walmsley. And 'tis the very Whip he sold for 6 s. 6 d. to this Man.</p>
               <p>- Lynell. I was standing at my own Door, and the Prisoner and another Man came by with this Whip: Walmsley asked him if it was to be sold, he said yes, and gave it into my Hand; the Price, he said, was half a Guinea. I observed the Grasp to be stitch'd with Wire, so I bid him 6 s. for it, then 6 s. 6 d. he allow'd it at last for 7 s. and went 5 or 6 Doors off, and told me I should have it for 6 s. 6 d. and a Gallon of Beer; I told him I would give no more, so he sent it me by his Companion, for my own Price, and then they both went off. There was a very cleaver Horse engrav'd on the Whip, and I was shewing it to some of my Neighbours, who observed likewise the Name, Charles Serjeant at Uxbridge upon the Butt-end. About half an Hour after this, the Prisoner came up again, to sell this very Coat which the Gentleman has now upon his Back; when he had sold it, I desired to speak a Word with him: I took him in Doors and said, take your Whip again, I don't think you came honestly by it: Why, says he, I'll carry you to the Man I had it from, 'tis but upon Tower-Hill damn it says the other, what Occasion have; you to trouble your self about it? Give him his Money again, so I took my Money and return'd him the Whip: But another Person saying Mr. Serjeant's Coach came in at the Bull, we took the Prisoner thither, and asked them if Mr. Serjeant's Coach came in there; they told us it would be there in a quarter of an Hour. While we were waiting. I asked the Prisoner, if he had bought nothing but this Whip? Yes, says he, this Wastcoat which I have on, the Coat, which I have sold, and a Hat, which I gave 2 s. for, I asked him what he gave for all the rest of the Things, and he told me 8 s. When the Coach came in, we found Mr. Serjeant had been stripp'd, so we search'd the Prisoner; and the first Things we took out of his Pocket, was a Spoon, on which was wrote, Charles Serjeant, at Uxbridge, and a Knife with two Blades, and a pair of steel Snuffers I put the Prisoner into a Coach, and he was carry'd to Sir 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person31">
                  Richard 
                  Brocas 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person31" type="surname" value="Brocas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person31" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , while I rid to Uxbridge to inform Mr. Serjeant, what we had done.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They took Money from me, which no Man in the World has any thing to say to, but my self.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-1-person32">
                  Charles 
                  Serjeant 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person32" type="surname" value="Serjeant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person32" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Spoon, Knife, and these Snuffers, the Prisoner took from me; they are mine: he confess'd the Fact before Sir Richard Brocas.</p>
               <p>The Confession of the Prisoner being proved, it was read in Court.</p>
               <p>The voluntary Confession of 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person33">
                  William 
                  Rine 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person33" type="surname" value="Rine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person33" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , taken this 1st of October, before Sir Richard Brocas, Knt. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>' Who confesseth and saith, that about a Month ' ago, he the said William Rine, with Benjamin ' Finnegar, and 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person34">
                  Bryan 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person34" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person34" type="given" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , assaulted and Robbed ' 2 Men in the Fields at Islington, and with ' the said 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person35">
                  Benjamin 
                  Finnegar 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person35" type="surname" value="Finnegar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person35" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person36">
                  Bryan 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person36" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person36" type="given" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , ' he robb'd a Man by Hampstead, of Coffee and ' Tea, and all his wearing Apparel: And that ' on the 22d of September last, he with the ' same Persons, about 8 in the Evening, near ' Kensington Gravel Pits, assaulted and robb'd ' Mr. 
               <persName id="t17361013-1-person37">
                  Charles 
                  Serjeant 
               <interp inst="t17361013-1-person37" type="surname" value="Serjeant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person37" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of a Coat, Wastcoat, ' Breeches, Hat, Whip, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The People told me, it would be better for me to confess, than to say I was not there. These People came to me in Jayl, and desired me to confess, and to say I was along with these Men, robbing every Body: There are People enough in the Town, that know me, but I believe no Body is here but my Land lady, and she knows nothing of the Matter <rs id="t17361013-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17361013-1-punish5" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-1-punish5" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-1-defend27 t17361013-1-punish5"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
