<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-28">
               <interp inst="t17361013-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-28" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-28" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-28-off134-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-28-defend232 t17361013-28-off134 t17361013-28-verdict137"></join>
         
               <p>36. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-28-defend232" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Smart 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-28-defend232" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-28-defend232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-28-defend232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17361013-28-off134" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-28-off134" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-28-off134" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               marrying 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-28-victim234" type="victimName">
                           Thamar 
                           Trantum 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim234" type="surname" value="Trantum"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim234" type="given" value="Thamar"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17361013-28-cd135" type="crimeDate">August the 29th</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-28-off134 t17361013-28-cd135"></join> last, his former <rs id="t17361013-28-viclabel136" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-28-victim236 t17361013-28-viclabel136"></join> 
                  
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-28-victim236" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Coax 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim236" type="surname" value="Coax"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim236" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-28-victim236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , being then living
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Thamar Trantum. I only desire to be clear'd of him, I never bedded with him, and have nothing to do with him. His first Wife own'd she was marry'd to him; and took her Oath of it before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. I was at Thamar Trantam's Wedding with the Prisoner Smart. She was marry'd to him the twenty ninth of August. I never saw the first Wife 'till Yesterday; and then she was carried away from us by Force.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you brought the Parson that marry'd them?</p>
               <p>Witness. No But I will go and see if I can get him, his Name is Gainham, a Fleet Parson.</p>
               <p>Dr. Gainham. They have a Certificate of this Marriage, but it is none of mine: Mrs. Ball gave it them, but I marry'd them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Prisoner and this Woman?</p>
               <p>Gainham I don't remember Faces, 'tis impossible, quite impossible I should remember Faces. I know I married two People by those Names.</p>
               <p>Q. do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Gainham. I don't remember his Face; but here is my Register.</p>
               <p>Q. What Register is that?</p>
               <p>Gainham. 'Tis my Register; a Register of all the People I marry; and as fair a Register as any in England, of all the People that are married by me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a Parish Register?</p>
               <p>Gainham. No, 'tis my own private Register.</p>
               <p>Q. What, do you keep a private Register; where do you live?</p>
               <p>Gainham. In St. Bride's Parish.</p>
               <p>Q. And where do you marry People?</p>
               <p>Gainham. In several Houses.</p>
               <p>Q. And not in the Church?</p>
               <p>Gainham. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you Licences when you marry?</p>
               <p>Gainham. No.</p>
               <p>Q. And are you not ashamed to scandalize your Character?</p>
               <p>Gainham. I do not chuse it; but I am old, and infirm, and am not able to get any Preferment.</p>
               <p>Q. And will you commit Crimes because you cannot get Preferment? Does your Conscience teach you that?</p>
               <p>Gainham. I do not chuse it, my Lord - but -</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing about John Smart?</p>
               <p>Gainham. (Reading) On the fifteenth of May, one thousand seven hundred and thirty three, I married John Smart, Drummer of the first Regiment of Foot Guards, to Elizabeth Colt, Spinster.</p>
               <p>Q. And do you always marry People by their right Names?</p>
               <p>Gainham. Yes, by their true Names. They always give me their Names; and if they go and take out Licences, they tell their Names themselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know you act contrary to the Canons of the Church? Do you know whether the Prisoner is the Man you married?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130017"></xptr>Gainham. No, on my Oath, I cannot remember. Mrs. Ball who gave the Certificate, was present at the Marriage, but she would not come.</p>
               <p>Q. The Name being in the Book is no Evidence, if you don't know the Man.</p>
               <p>Gainham. I have no Remembrance of the Person. <rs id="t17361013-28-verdict137" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-28-verdict137" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Grand Jury represented to the Court, that Gainham was a Scandal to his Function; and requested that some Method might be taken to suppress his iniquitous Proceedings.</p>
            </div1>
