<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380113-4">
               <interp inst="t17380113-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-4" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380113-4" type="date" value="17380113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380113-4-off24-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-defend56 t17380113-4-off24 t17380113-4-verdict28"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380113-4-defend56" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Jenkins 
                  <interp inst="t17380113-4-defend56" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-defend56" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-defend56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380113-4-defloc23">St. Paul Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-4-defloc23" type="placeName" value="St. Paul Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-4-defloc23" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-defend56 t17380113-4-defloc23"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380113-4-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a silver Watch with a silk String, value 8 l. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380113-4-victim58" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Monday 
                        <interp inst="t17380113-4-victim58" type="surname" value="Monday"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380113-4-victim58" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380113-4-victim58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-off24 t17380113-4-victim58"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17380113-4-viclabel25" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-victim58 t17380113-4-viclabel25"></join>; <rs id="t17380113-4-cd26" type="crimeDate">Jan. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-off24 t17380113-4-cd26"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Monday. Last Saturday Night I was coming out of <placeName id="t17380113-4-crimeloc27">Covent-Garden Play-house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-4-crimeloc27" type="placeName" value="Covent-Garden Play-house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380113-4-crimeloc27" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-off24 t17380113-4-crimeloc27"></join>, and in the Passage leading from the Play-house to the Piazza's, there stood a Man, and stopp'd me from going on: I spoke to him, and after some Time he mov'd on. He was in a blue Coat, and I took him to be a Chairman, so had no Suspicion of him. I pass'd on towards the Posts, under the Arch next Covent Garden, and there a Fellow stopp'd between me and the Posts and jostled me. I spoke to him, and shov'd him from me, upon which he mov'd on, but my Wife, (whom I was leading to a Coach) told me, she believ'd the Man had pick'd my Pocket. I immediately found my Watch was gone. I had look'd upon it to see what Time it was just before I came out of the House, and many Minutes could not pass between that Time, and the Time I lost it. No sooner had I missed it, but a Person came and told me he knew the Man that had taken my Watch, and that he had seen him commit the Fact. He acquainted me where he might be found, and I told him where I liv'd. The next Day when I came Home from Church, I had Information that a Watchman had been to let me know that the Man who robb'd me was taken; I desired a Neighbour to go and enquire into the Matter, and he accordingly did, but he told me the Man had made no Confession. As for the Prisoner, I cannot take upon me to say that I know him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-4-person59">
                  Thomas 
                  Current 
               <interp inst="t17380113-4-person59" type="surname" value="Current"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person59" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going thro' the Piazza's that Night with a Captain that came from Bristol, and I saw a Gentleman come out of the Playhouse. I observ'd the Prisoner to push against him several Times; after that he snatch'd away his Watch, and I saw it in his Hand; but I will not swear it was Mr. Monday, if it was he, he struck at him, and then run away; upon that I came up to him and inform'd him he had lost his Watch, and that I believ'd I knew the Man that took it, and that I could find him out. Then I went a little farther, and saw the Prisoner again, with 10 or 12 of his Gang, besides Link Fellows; when I came up to him, they told him they believ'd he was snitch'd; upon which he ran a cross Covent Garden, and the Captain that was with me ran after him, but Boots would not overtake Shoes, and so we lost him. The Linkmen afterwards told us of some Houses where we might find him, and after searching several, we found him at Mr. Peartree's in Colson's-Court, Drury Lane, and the next Day carried him before a Justice. I am positive to the Prisoner, that I saw him very near the Gentleman; that he put his Hand under his Cloaths, and I saw him take hold of the Watch String, and whip it out of his Pocket. When the Prisoner was taken, his Wife swore bitterly that he should Puff against me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask this Witness whether he did not say at Peartree's that he could not charge me with this Fact?</p>
               <p>Current. I'll tell no Lie about the Matter. The Prisoner is the Man that took Mr. Monday's Watch, and I have no more to say.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. But did not you declare that you would not charge me?</p>
               <p>Current. No, I never said any such Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-4-person60">
                  Tho 
                  Osborn 
               <interp inst="t17380113-4-person60" type="surname" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person60" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Monday's Servant, I saw the Prisoner shove my Master several Times, as he came out of the Play-house, and likewise in the Passage.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eustace. On Sunday Night last, I was at a Tavern with Mr. Justice Midford and the Prisoner, and Mr. Current came in. The Prisoner desir'd to speak with me. The Justice imagining he intended to make a Discovery, desir'd me to take him into a private Room; there he told me, that he would put his Life into my Hands. I told him I did not desire he should do that, but if he could help Mr. Monday to his Watch, I would hear him with Pleasure. Upon this, he own'd he had taken it, and would take Care that it should be return'd to him the next Day. I went to him in New-Prison, and there he told me that one<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173712130006"></xptr> 
            
                  <persName id="t17380113-4-person61">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17380113-4-person61" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person61" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had the Watch, and that he deliver'd it to another Man, the very Moment that it was taken, and promised me again that it should be deliver'd to me next Morning at 10 o'Clock, but I never saw any Thing of it. He has promised me to return it Day after Day, but never did so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He came to me and call'd for a Bottle of Wine and Bread and Cheese, and told me if I would tell him any Thing about the Watch, I should not be hurt, and he told me in the Tavero Kitchen, if I would discover, he would do any Thing to serve me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eustace. He was not a Minute in the Tavern before he spoke to me in the manner I have mention'd, and I told him if he would discover a Gang of 3 or 4, the Justice (I believ'd) would admit him an Evidence, in order to break up a Gang; he said he could not, for he was but just enter'd into a Gang, but he had (he own'd) taken Mr. Monday's Watch, and would help us to it again. I never saw the Prisoner before that Time, in my Life.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When Mr. Current came to me at Peartree's, he took no Notice of me at first, but went out again to fetch the Watchmen. The Constable search'd me, and found nothing upon me. <rs id="t17380113-4-verdict28" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-verdict28" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380113-4-punish29" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380113-4-punish29" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380113-4-defend56 t17380113-4-punish29"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
