<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380518-2">
               <interp inst="t17380518-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-2" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380518-2" type="date" value="17380518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380518-2-off10-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-defend36 t17380518-2-off10 t17380518-2-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-2-defend36" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Hunt 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-defend36" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-defend36" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-defend36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17380518-2-defloc9">St. George's Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-defloc9" type="placeName" value="St. George's Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-defloc9" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-defend36 t17380518-2-defloc9"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17380518-2-off10" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-off10" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-off10" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Brass Drudging-box, value 18 d.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17380518-2-victim38" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Bowers 
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-victim38" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-victim38" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-victim38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-off10 t17380518-2-victim38"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17380518-2-cd11" type="crimeDate">Oct 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-off10 t17380518-2-cd11"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bowers. I <rs id="t17380518-2-viclabel12" type="occupation">keep a Publick House</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-victim38 t17380518-2-viclabel12"></join> in <placeName id="t17380518-2-crimeloc13">Well-Close-Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-crimeloc13" type="placeName" value="Well-Close-Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380518-2-crimeloc13" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380518-2-off10 t17380518-2-crimeloc13"></join>, and wear a Gold Chain. He was drinking in the House in a Sailor's Habit, and while my Maid was gone to buy him some Tobacco, he got up, and came to me as I sat under my Clock, and swore he would have something or else he would blow my Brains out. Immediately he pull'd out a Pistol and shot me in the Arm; I kept my Bed 4 Months, and the Bullet is still in my Arm. My Maid was gone for Tobacco for him, and my Husband was then sick a Bed, so he got away, and took the Drudging Box with him. He was afterwards taken, and I was perswaded to let him make himself an Evidence, and he hang'd 2 Men at Guildford. I swear he took the Drudging box, and I have indicted him at Hicks-Hall for shooting me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Examine her Maid: This Woman took me up in the County of Surrey for this Fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380518-2-person39">
                  Eliz 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17380518-2-person39" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person39" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have liv'd with my Mistress Bowers 8 Years. She took the Prisoner to be a poor Man, so she let him lie 2 Nights in the House, and gave him Victuals. The 3d Night he came with the Man that was lately hang'd at Guildford; and the Prisoner said he would treat my Mistress with a Supper for her great Civility to him. After Supper he sent me out to buy him some Tobacco, and I was returning into the House, I heard the Pistol go off; I ran into the House, and saw the Box full of Smoak. Lord! says I, what's the Matter! Lord! says my Mistress, the Rogue has kill'd me. He threw his Arms about her Neck and would not let her come out of the Box, so I call'd him Rogue, and attempted to run up Stairs, but he then left my Mistress, and caught hold of me; he d - mn'd my Eyes, and said, if I spoke a Word he would kill me. However I got from him, and went out to call the Watch; the Flower-box was then standing upon the Table, but when I came back, the Prisoner was gone and that too.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I pull out half a Guinea to pay the Reckoning?</p>
               <p>Bowers. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yet the Maid swears the Mistress maintain'd me.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Symonds. The Prisoner took out half a Guinea at the white Table, and desir'd Mrs. Bowers to change it; immediately I heard the Pistol go off, and saw the Smother, and she cry'd out, he had kill'd her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her whether she saw any Pistol, either upon me or my Comrade?</p>
               <p>Symonds. No, but I saw the Hole in her Gown Sleeve, and the Blood running about. Some Time after, - but not that Night, she said he had stole her Drudging box.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They'll all swear a Cow's a House This Bowers keeps a Bawdy House. She took me up 3 or 4 Sessions ago; I made my self an Evidence before Sir 
               <persName id="t17380518-2-person40">
                  John 
                  Lade 
               <interp inst="t17380518-2-person40" type="surname" value="Lade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and hang'd my Comrade at Guildford. 
               <persName id="t17380518-2-person41">
                  Jack 
                  Thrift 
               <interp inst="t17380518-2-person41" type="surname" value="Thrift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person41" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Hangman, - please to call him. - he knows I hang'd my Companion and another Man there, and now she thinks to hang me, - for her Drudging Box <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173805180004"></xptr>If I am to be hang'd for her Drudging-Box, what signify'd my making myself a King's Evidence. 
               <persName id="t17380518-2-person42">
                  Daniel 
                  Malden 
               <interp inst="t17380518-2-person42" type="surname" value="Malden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person42" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who broke twice out of Newgate, was taken at this Woman's House. I own myself a Rogue before all the Honourable Court; but Jack Thrift knows I cast two Men at Guildford. I have paid many a Pound for frequenting this House, and if I was to die To-morrow, I never was guilt of so pittyful a Theft. She herself wanted to buy a Watch of me for her Husband. Tis a likely Story indeed - that I should shoot her, when I lodged in her House, and at this very Time there were People drinking there. <rs id="t17380518-2-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380518-2-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
