<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360721-1">
               <interp inst="t17360721-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-1" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360721"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360721-1" type="date" value="17360721"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360721-1-off1-c26" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-1-defend27 t17360721-1-off1 t17360721-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>1. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360721-1-defend27" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Rickets 
                  <interp inst="t17360721-1-defend27" type="surname" value="Rickets"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-defend27" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-defend27" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360721-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a silver hilted Sword, value 20s. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360721-1-victim29" type="victimName">
                           Edmund 
                           Baugh 
                        <interp inst="t17360721-1-victim29" type="surname" value="Baugh"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-1-victim29" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360721-1-victim29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-1-off1 t17360721-1-victim29"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17360721-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">July 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-1-off1 t17360721-1-cd2"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-1-person30">
                  Edmund 
                  Baugh 
               <interp inst="t17360721-1-person30" type="surname" value="Baugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person30" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Night, July 9, about 10 o'Clock, I was going from the Tavern to my Chambers in the Temple; at the <placeName id="t17360721-1-crimeloc3">middle Temple Gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="middle Temple Gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360721-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-1-off1 t17360721-1-crimeloc3"></join> the 
               <persName id="t17360721-1-person31">
                  Duchess
                   of Marlborough
               <interp inst="t17360721-1-person31" type="surname" value="of Marlborough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person31" type="given" value="Duchess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person31" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mr. Green were sitting in her Chariot. I stop'd to look at her, and in a very few Minutes, I found my Sword was taken from my side. I don't know the Prisoner, nor can I swear he took it; but missing my Sword, I cry'd out - Sword lost - stop Thief; the Mob set out and run beyond Temple-Bar, I run after them, and the Prisoner was taken at the Ship Tavern. I asked him if he had got my Sword, he said no. Sir, says I, have you given it any Body? No, says he. What made you run away then? He said he did not run away. It was pretty late and we could not find a Magistrate; so I charged a Constable with him, and carried him to the Compter. The next Day I carried him before the Lord Mayor. John Smith will give you farther Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360721-1-person32">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17360721-1-person32" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person32" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner. I did keep a House at the Ditch-side, and have often been afraid of being robb'd by him.</p>
               <p>The Night the Fact was committed, the Dutchess of Marlborough was in her Coach at the middle Temple Gate: I stood by the Prosecutor to see her, and observed the Prisoner draw the Sword from his side, and could have detected him before he had quite drawn it out; but a Man (one of his Gang I suppose) clapp'd me on the Shoulder, and asked me whose Coach that was; I told him whose it was, and before I could turn again, the Prisoner was gone, and the Mob was running after him. He ran thro' the Bar, and was taken at a Chymist's Door, one of the Houses that was burnt down. This was on Friday, July 9. about 10 o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baugh. I should have told your Lordship, that the Sunday following, I was informed a Person came, while I was at Church, to offer me my Sword again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Smith, Why he did not tell the Gentleman all this, the Night I was taken?</p>
               <p>Mr. Baugh. I did ask, when the Prisoner was taken, if any Body could tell who took my Sword, and Smith only said, he saw the Prisoner run without the Bar; he did not inform me that he saw him take it, 'till next Morning.</p>
               <p>Smith. I live by St. George's Church in Southwark, and having so far to go home that Night, I was afraid, if I discovered the whole Matter that Night, that I should be mis-used in my way Home by some of his Gang; this was the Reason I did not tell the Gentleman till next Morning: He laid hold of me at Sir William Billers's Office that Night.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173607210003"></xptr>Mr. Baugh. The Prisoner at the Coffee-House under the Office, call'd for a Pint of Beer, said he could pay for it as well as any of us, and spurted good Part of it into Smith's Face and down his Bosom. The Prisoner had nothing material to offer in his Defence, nor any Witnesses, either to the Fact or his Character. <rs id="t17360721-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty of the Indictment
            </rs>. <rs id="t17360721-1-punish5" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360721-1-punish5" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360721-1-defend27 t17360721-1-punish5"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
