<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17380628-18">
               <interp inst="t17380628-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-18" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17380628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17380628-18" type="date" value="17380628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-18-off90-c151" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-defend190 t17380628-18-off90 t17380628-18-verdict97"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17380628-18-off93-c151" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-defend190 t17380628-18-off93 t17380628-18-verdict97"></join>
         
               <p>20. 
               
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Grinway , otherwise <rs id="t17380628-18-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-defend190 t17380628-18-alias-7"></join>Greenaway</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-defend190" type="surname" value="Grinway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-defend190" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17380628-18-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17380628-18-victim192" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Goodwin 
                        <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim192" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim192" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17380628-18-viclabel91" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-victim192 t17380628-18-viclabel91"></join>, on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Guinea, and 8 s. in Silver
            </rs>, <rs id="t17380628-18-cd92" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off90 t17380628-18-cd92"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off93 t17380628-18-cd92"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted for <rs id="t17380628-18-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Gelding of a Brown Colour, value 4 l. a Leather Bridle and Saddle, value 5 s
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17380628-18-victim193" type="victimName">
                  Jude 
                  Storer 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim193" type="surname" value="Storer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim193" type="given" value="Jude"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-victim193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17380628-18-cd94" type="crimeDate">May 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off90 t17380628-18-cd94"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off93 t17380628-18-cd94"></join>
               </p>
               <p>Jude Storer. On the 27th of April last, in the Night Time, my Stable was broke open, and I lost a Horse, a Saddle and Bridle; some Time afterwards I saw in an Advertisement, that a Man and Horse were taken on Account of Mr. Goodwin's being robb'd, and I went to Laylam to see the Horse, and it prov'd to be mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person194">
                  Robert 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person194" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person194" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner upon the Horse at Belfount in Middlesex, he went in at the Half-Moon, a little Ale-house in the Parish</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person195">
                  Robert 
                  Chandler 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person195" type="surname" value="Chandler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person195" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             On the 15th of May, I heard that Mr. Goodwin was robb'd, and that the Highway-man was at the Half Moon, I went up thither, and finding his Horse to answer the Description that was given me of him, I took the Prisoner, and found 3 loaded Pistols upon him. The Horse was advertised, and Mr. Storer came and claimed it. The Prisoner all the Time he was in Custody, insisted upon it, that the Horse was his own, and that he had bought it for 2 Guineas at Fulham Bridge.</p>
               <p>The Rev. Mr. Goodwin. On the 15th of May, about 7 o'Clock in the Morning, I was attack'd by a Highway-man upon <placeName id="t17380628-18-crimeloc95">Hounslow Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-18-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="Hounslow Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17380628-18-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off90 t17380628-18-crimeloc95"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-off93 t17380628-18-crimeloc95"></join>, between the Powder-Mills and the Town of Hounslow, who took from me a Guinea, and about 8 s. I believe the Prisoner is the Man; he was mounted on a Horse about 15 Hands high, that went at a great Rate, and had Leather Bags behind him. He came on the Broad-side of me, and would hardly give me Leave to put my Hands in my Pockets, but was in great Haste, and search'd me himself. I had Leisure to view the Horse's Back-side, and when my Neighbours had taken the Prisoner, I went to see the Horse, and knew him again. Upon this Sir 
               <persName id="t17380628-18-person196">
                  Tho 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person196" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person196" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             committed him. The Horse and the Bags being advertised, Storer came and claimed the Horse, and one Gauntlet of Stockbridge own'd the Bags, and that his Name, (almost worn out) was upon them. I can't recollect every Particular of what the Prisoner said when he was taken at the Half-Moon, but the Substance was, - he desir'd to speak to me alone. So old, as I am, I did not think it right to be left alone with him; for tho' they had taken from him 3 loaded Pistols, and some Powder and Balls, or Slugs, yet I was doubtful whether he might not have-a Penknife; but the Constable assuring me he had no Weapons we retir'd, and the Man fell into a great Agony, and put me into one too; for there were some Circumstances in his robbing me, that made me pity him. He told me he was Heir to 5 or 600 a Year, and that he had a Brother a Clergyman at Stamford, whose Name was Sawyer, and he was sure I would let him go, if I was to see his Brother, or any of his Relations at Reading. I thought this might be his first Flight; for I remember'd, when he came a Broad Side of me, and thrust his Head and Pistol into my Chaise, he trembled, and could not hold his Pistol still. I thought at first he did this in Terrorem, and to make me dispatch, but before he had done with me, I perceiv'd his left Leg to shake, and then I concluded he was but a young Beginner, and was frighted. I thought he came out from under a Hedge, on the North Side of the Road, where the Soldiers lie in wait for a Prize, - Highway-men, I mean, - but he said No, he did not come from thence, I came by you when you was smoaking your Pipe in the Chaise; - by the same Token, I remember he broke it, and I had a good Mind to have thrown it in his Face. I had a Guinea in my Pocket wrapp'd up in Brown Paper, and he own'd to me that he took it so wrapp'd up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Reason have you to believe I am the Man?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goodwin. Several. First, my Man swears positively to the Horse that he rode to the Half-Moon on, and I believe it to be the same. Another Reason is, his Manner of dealing with me. I don't know that he swore above an Oath or two. My Man carelesly look'd over his Shoulder while he was rifling me, and he damn'd him, and told him he would shoot him, if he did not put his Head aside. I reason'd with him, and told him, - none of you Gentlemen ever offer'd to rob me before, tho' no one has travell'd Hounslow-Heath more than I have done. That's nothing says he, I am in Want, and Money I must have, and you can draw Bills for more. So he did not leave me a Farthing, (tho' I had two Turnpikes to go thro') except one 6 d. which had dropp'd between us to the Bottom of the Chaise.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173806280015"></xptr>Prisoner. What Habit was I in?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goodwin. Yes; that is another Reason I believe you are the Man. 'Twas in the Summer Time, and he had a great Coat on, that was too big for him; while he attack'd me, he shook, and his Coat Sleeve being too long, he turn'd it up. In my Conscience I believe him to be the very Man. When I saw him at the Constable's House, at Belfount, his Coat was put upon him, and his Hat, at my Request; and he appear'd to me, when his little Hat was pull'd over his Eyes, just as he did when he robb'd me. He told me I should have my Money again, if I would let him go. I told him I could not answer doing that; and that he had a good deal of Confidence and Assurance, to rob me within a Mile of the House where he lay, and to return after the Robbery in the same Habit into the Town.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person197">
                  John 
                  Roseblade 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person197" type="surname" value="Roseblade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Goodwin's Servant, confirm'd his Master's Evidence, and said, he could swear positively to the Horse; but had no Opportunity to view the Highway-man's Face. He took Notice that the Horse had a Star in his Forehead, and that both his Knees were broke.</p>
               <p>- Blake, was with Mr. Footit the Constable, when the Prisoner was taken; he said, they found three loaded Pistols upon him, a Silver Watch in his Fob, a Snuff-Box, a Silver Nutmeg-grater, 10 or 11 Shillings in Money, and some Powder and Slugs.</p>
               <p>- Footit, the Constable, depos'd to the same Effect; and that the Prisoner answer'd the Description exactly that Mr. Goodwin had given of him, and that he saw him upon the Heath, before the Robbery was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person198">
                  George 
                  Rook 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person198" type="surname" value="Rook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person198" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore he saw a Man exactly like the Prisoner upon the Heath, that Morning, driving a Horse before him, which he believed was the same the Prisoner rode upon at that Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person199">
                  William 
                  Prior 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person199" type="surname" value="Prior"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Servant at the Bell, at Belfount, swore, That the Prisoner went out from thence about Six in the Morning, and came in again about Nine; that the Horse the Prisoner rode, was the same that was claim'd by Mr. Storer; and that he himself brought him out of the Stable to the Prisoner that Morning.</p>
               <p>Defence. I was at the Cross-Keys at Colebrook till Breakfast-Time, that Morning the Robbery was committed, and I expected the People of the House would have been here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17380628-18-person200">
                  Thomas 
                  Camplin 
               <interp inst="t17380628-18-person200" type="surname" value="Camplin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person200" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known the Prisoner from his Infancy, and never knew him guilty of any bad Action. He inform'd the Court, that his Father, Uncle, and all his Relations live at Reading, or there about. That he has an Uncle at Reading, one William Greenaway, reputed worth more than 600 per Annum; that the Prisoner marry'd the Daughter of Mr. Young, a Currier, at Newbury, and that by Occupation he was a <rs id="t17380628-18-deflabel96" type="occupation">Bargeman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-defend190 t17380628-18-deflabel96"></join>; but he could not say how he had liv'd of late. <rs id="t17380628-18-verdict97" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-verdict97" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17380628-18-punish98" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17380628-18-punish98" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17380628-18-defend190 t17380628-18-punish98"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
