<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391205-56">
               <interp inst="t17391205-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-56" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-56" type="date" value="17391205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-56-off267-c266" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-56-defend389 t17391205-56-off267 t17391205-56-verdict270"></join>
         
               <p>61. 
               
                  <persName id="t17391205-56-defend389" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Thompson 
                  <interp inst="t17391205-56-defend389" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-defend389" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-defend389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17391205-56-off267" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-off267" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-off267" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391205-56-victim391" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Cheshire 
                        <interp inst="t17391205-56-victim391" type="surname" value="Cheshire"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-56-victim391" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-56-victim391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-56-off267 t17391205-56-victim391"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Silver Watch, val.4 l. a Guinea and Sixpence in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17391205-56-cd268" type="crimeDate">Nov, 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-56-off267 t17391205-56-cd268"></join>.</p>
               <p>Richard Cheshire . On the 14th of November, between Six and Seven at Night, I was attacked on <placeName id="t17391205-56-crimeloc269">Hounslow-Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-56-crimeloc269" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-56-crimeloc269" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-56-off267 t17391205-56-crimeloc269"></join> , by a Man on a grey Horse: He cry'd Hallo! - Hallo ! I said again. Where are you going? said he: What's that to you, said I. D-mn you, said he, I know you are going to Staines ; I know you by your great Coat. I told him, if he had a Mind to have my Company, he must ride faster, and I laid my Head down, clapp'd Spurs to my Horse, and endeavour'd to get off, but he cry'd, - d - mn you, if you don't stop, I'll shoot you dead. I made no Reply, but kept digging my Horse, and got Ground of him: He still hallo'd out, if I did not stand he would shoot me; and upon looking back, I saw him in the Road following me, and holding out a Pistol. He d-mn'd me, and I d-mn'd him, and bid him come along; for as I was well mounted, I did not fear him. But on the Top of the Heath, my Horse cut his Legs, and could gallop no farther. I thought if I surrender'd they would use me ill, so I clapp'd my Gloves under my Thigh, and prepar'd to refill . When the Man (who pursued me) got up to me, he turn'd his Horse round, and said, - D-mn you, why did you ride away? and clapp'd a Pistol to my Mouth, which I threw out of his Hand, and then struck him off his Horse, by a back-handed Blow, with the But-end of my Whip; then I endeavour'd to jump on him with my Horse, and to tread his Guts out, but my Horse jump'd over him, and another Man immediately came up, and said, - d - mn you, if you don't surrender I'll shoot you dead, I caught hold of his Collar, and then a third Man attack'd me on a white-fac'd Horse, and swore he'd shoot me, and fir'd off his Pistol. I d-mn'd 'em, and said, - if I must be robb'd, I must. They took from me a Silver Watch, a Guinea, and a Sixpence; and the last Man who came up to me, shot me. It was dark, and if the three Men were here present, I could not swear to their Faces. While they were robbing me, a poor Man came out of the Powder-Mills to assist me, and the Man on the white-fac'd Horse d-mn'd him, and gallop'd to him, and let fly, and wounded him in the Arm. After this they all got off, and the poor Man got back to the House to have his Wound dress'd. My Bridle was cut all to Pieces; my Coat shot thro', and a piece of my Shirt was shot off; but my Bridle having a Weymouth Bit, with two Headstalls and four Reins, I took them all up in my Hand together, and as I went on, I saw a grey Horse in the Road with a Saddle and Bridle on him. He would not let me catch him, but I drove him in the Road before me to Beont , and then cried, - Stop a Highwayman's Horse. The Horse was stopp'd, and carried to the Black-Dog; I examin'd him in the Stable, and told the People I had been robb'd, but I had given one of the Rogues a damnable Knock on the Left Side of his Head. The People of the House tell me I fainted away in the Stable; - I don't remember that, - but the Thoughts of my narrow Escape with Life, made me faint away twice in the House. I had not been long at the Black-Dog, before a Man came from the Prince William's Head , and demanded the grey Horse. I said no one should have him, but the Owner: Upon which the Man went back, and the Prisoner came for the Horse, with a Knock on his Head, which appear'd to be fresh done, and 'twas on the Top of his Forehead. I thought the Horse I drove to the Black-Dog, was the same the Man who attack'd me rode on, because it was a grey Horse, but I cannot swear to it. When the Prisoner came to demand it, he behav'd very civilly: He said, he had been robb'd himself, and that he belong'd to Mr.Barham of Staines. He and I drank together, and I think we spent 4 s. 6 d. or 5 s. a-piece in the House. I asked him, how he came by that Money, if he had been robb'd? He told me, he had lost one Guinea of his Money in London, but had found 6 s. or 12 s. (I don't remember which) in his Plad Waistcoat Pocket. After we had drank together, he offer'd to go Home with me; but I took two Men with me, (who rode on one Horse) and bid them ride before the Prisoner. In sont-Lane he got past them; I caught him again, at the Turning on this Side the Turnpike. He was to have gone with me to my House at Staines; but when we came to the Town, he said he had borrowed a Whip at the Anchor, and must stop there to return it. I went in at the Anchor with him, and there charged an Officer with him, and had him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17391205-56-person392">
                  Thomas 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person392" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person392" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where he said, the Horse and Saddle was Mr. Barham's, and that he went from Mr. Barham's that Morning<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050034"></xptr> with a Letter to London, and was to call at Brentford about some Trees which his Master had bespoke. I never went to Mr. Barham , to enquire if the Prisoner was his Servant, for several People said they knew him to be his Gardner, but I never saw him before in my Life.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Distance was you from this Town ( Belfont ) when you was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Chester. About three Quarters of a Mile, and I discover'd the Horse without a Rider about 40 or 60 Yards from the Spot on which I was robb'd. He was about thirteen Hands and a half, or fourteen Hands high.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not the Landlord of the Black Dog, where we drank together, a Constable?</p>
               <p>Chester. Yes; but I did not know it then, else I should have charged him with the Prisoner then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I tell you I had been robb'd, and knock'd off my Horse?</p>
               <p>Chester. Yes, after which we spent 4 s. and 6 d. a-piece.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Where did you first charge me with having attack'd you?</p>
               <p>Chester. At Staines ; I did not charge him at Belfont ; I was too much 'frighted.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You say you went forward to Staines, and that I attempted to ride away: Had you charged me with attempting to rob you, before that?</p>
               <p>Chester. No; but we were to go solely, and he rode hard, and I caught him twice, and charged him with attempting to ride away: He said, he would go my Pace, to my own House, and I should charge an Officer with him. As we went along, I asked him, why he went away; I can't tell what Answer he made, but the Men rode before him again, and he rode away again, - I rode after him, and then we went altogether to Staines.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not my Stock torn?</p>
               <p>Chester. He said they had taken his Stock-buckle. - I thought I saw something ragged about his Neck, - about his Stock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had I any Arms about me?</p>
               <p>Chester. I did not search the Prisoner. If he had had any Arms, he would have been a Fool to have brought them with him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How many Times were you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17391205-56-person393">
                  Thomas 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person393" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person393" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Chester. Three Times; and the Prisoner attended every Time. The first Time Sir Thomas (on Account of his being Mr. Barham's Servant) took Fourscore Pounds Bail, and the second Time there was 200 l. Bail given for him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How came you to see the Pistol in the Man's Hand, when you say it was so dark?</p>
               <p>Chester. The Pistol shone bright, and I saw it. I told -the People at Belfont , that I had knock'd a Pistol out of a Man's Hand, and that my Glove fell near the Place. A Man went out, and found the Glove, but not the Pistol.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said, - he had given the Man a Knock on the left Side of the Head, - the Blow I had was on the right Side of my Head.</p>
               <p>Chester. I struck the Man back-handed, and as his Face was toward mine, the Blow must be given on the right-Side.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If I was the Man who first attack'd him near the Powder-Mills, he says his Horse rode fastest at that time; then how can it be supposed that my Horse could outride his afterward? My Horse was very heavily shod, and that was the Reason of his growing resty; but when he got before me, my Horse went better, - so will any resty Horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-56-person394">
                  Francis 
                  Sherman 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person394" type="surname" value="Sherman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person394" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was very frosty that Night, - hard Weather, and I heard Horses galloping hard: By and by there was a Cry of Highwaymen! Thieves! Rougues! Murder! I went out, and saw a Horse shoot out of the Road; hey, says I, you'll break your Neck! Stop that Horse there, says Chester, I have been robb'd, and have knock'd a Man off that Horse, and I believe if I have Help to go upon the Heath he can't get off. I stopp'd the Horse, and before I could get him into the Stable, one Blake came up and said, - the Man who own'd that Horse was at his House Chester said, - then let the Man come to me for-it ; so we put the Horse into the Stable, and Chester fainted away; we got him in Doors, and he fainted away again: Then he wanted me to go home with him, and told me, he would pay me for it. But the Prisoner coming in, and asking for the Man that wanted him, I told him that was the Man, (Chester.) The Prisoner asked him, if he wanted him: Says Chester, I have been robb'd; I want somebody. So have I, says the Prisoner; and after this they lat down, and drank together, for three Quarters of an Hour, and at last Chester told me, I should go home with him. The Prisoner said, there was no Occasion for that; for as they were both going the same Way, and had been Fellow-sufferers, he would lose his Blood before he should be wrong'd any more. Chester would not accept of his Proposal, but desired me to go with him, and another young Fellow who was present offering to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050035"></xptr> go likewise, he got up behind me, and we all went out together. When we got to Staines , Chester took him into Custody, and the Prisoner asked him what he meant? I assisted in seizing him, and should have done so by Chester if the Prisoner had charged him. He said he belong'd to 'Squire Barham , but I knew not 'Squire Barham , nor either of the Persons.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I attempt to get away?</p>
               <p>Sherman . He rode away foremost very hard; - he rode away twice, but once he made a very hard Push, - but I don't say he rode hard with a Design to get off. His Horse could not out-ride Chester's at fair Play; nor did he shew any Sign of Fear at Belfont . He was all over Blood about the Head, and the Button-holes of his Stock were broke.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-56-person395">
                  William 
                  Roseblade 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person395" type="surname" value="Roseblade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person395" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know the Prisoner came and own'd the Horse at the Black Dog, and seem'd unwilling we should go home with Chester.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-56-person396">
                  Thomas 
                  Cheshire 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person396" type="surname" value="Cheshire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person396" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have work'd at the Powder-Mills twenty Years, and happened to be coming out at the Gate when this Disturbance happened. I thought somebody had fell down in the Road; and cry'd, - I'll come to your Assistance this Minute . I ran up to the Place, and in a Moment a Man turn'd his Horse upon me, and said, - D - mn you, keep off, and at that Instant shot me into my Arm. I heard them cry, - d - mn you, where's your Watch, - and d - m you, I'll search you. I can't tell who they were; I wish I could, for I have suffer'd much by them. I saw three Men on Horseback; two of them had got Chester between them, but I saw no grey Horse. As soon as I was shot, I went to the Mills, to get my Wound dress'd, and the Slug came out of my Arm with a Piece of my Shirt.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. On Wednesday the 14th of November, I came from Staines to London. As I came along, I call'd at Mr. Green's at Brentford , about 25 Pear-trees and 25 Cherry-trees, which my Master (Mr. Barham) had bespoke for our Orchard. I put up my Horse (a little grey Pad) at the Nag's-Head in Hedge-Lane, till Four o'Clock; then I set out on my Return home, and the Man of the Inn persuaded me to leave a Guinea (which I had about me) with him. I rode alone till I came to the Turnpike, and 'twas terrible dark, very frosty, and no Stars. The Men at the Turnpike told me, 'twas Five o'Clock, and thought I should get home by Seven. On Hannslow-Heath I heard two Men coming towards me on Horseback, but I could not perceive the Colour of their Horses: As soon as they came up to me, one of them got off his Horse, and caught hold of my Bridlo, and fil'd their Pistols at me. I cry'd out Murder, and wheel'd my Horse away with all my Might; but before I came to the Powder-Mill Bridge, they came again on my right Side, and knock'd me off my Horse, and robb'd me: One of them d - mn'd me, and asked me why I rode away, and whether I imagined they rode with Broomsticks. They robbed me of fifteen Shillings, a Stock-buckle, and my Gloves: Which was all I had about me except a few Half-pence and five or six Shillings, which were in my Waistcoat-pocket , and which I saved by putting my Hand thro' the Folds of my Coat and pulling it aside. After I was robbed, I thought to have catched my Horse, but could not; 'twas so dark, I could not see him, tho' he never was out of my hearing. When I came to Belfont , I got a Man to help me catch my Horse, and told Mr. Blake at The Duke's Head, that I had been robbed, and that I thought the Men who had robbed me were following me. Upon Enquiry, it was found to be only Mr. Chester, who had drove my Horse into the Town. I went to him, and we drank a Bottle of Mountain, and two Bottles of Port, as Fellow sufferers together. Then I desired to have my Horse, and said, if Mr. Chester would go home, I would go with him: He did not say whether he would or not, but asked another Man to go with him. So we all set out together, and in Belfont-lane , my Horse happened to go before theirs; but before I got to the Turnpike, they halloo'd me, and I stopped and answered. From the Turnpike we rode together, till we came to the Road that leads to my Master's House; then Chester asked me to go to the Swan; I declined going, and upon that they seized me. They had not charg'd me at all, before they laid hold of me.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-56-person397">
                  Nicholas 
                  Blake 
               <interp inst="t17391205-56-person397" type="surname" value="Blake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person397" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Duke's Head at Belfont . On the 14th of November, the Prisoner came to my House in the Evening, with his Head broke, and his Face all over Blood. I hope, says he, you are Christians, and that you'll use me like a Christian. - I have been robbed on this Side the Powder Mills, and have been used very barbarously: My Horse is gone, pray send after it. I did so, and found the Horse was stopped at the Black Dog; and Word was sent, that the Owner of it must come there: The Prisoner said he would go immediately. His Head was swelled; which seemed to have been occasioned by a Blow with a Stick or a Whip; and there<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050036"></xptr> was a Cut in it like a Prick with a Sword or a Bayoner. He proposed to go by himself, to Chester, but I went with him, and as soon as he got into the House, he asked who wanted him? Chester said he wanted somebody; and, says the Prisoner, so do I. I have been robbed, says Chester; and so have I, said the Prisoner. After this they sat down, and drank two Bottles of Wine: I staid half an Hour with them, and then left them together. This was at a Constable's House, and where I have seen Chester stop and drink before this Time.</p>
               <p>Sir Thomas Reynolds. Chester did not charge the Prisoner with robbing him: He only said he was robbed by a Man on a Grey Horse. He could el her swear to the Man, nor to the Horse.</p>
               <p>Mr. Barham , Mr. Musle, Mr. Sedgewick, Mr. Morrison , and Mr. Read, gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest, industrious, sober Man. <rs id="t17391205-56-verdict270" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-56-verdict270" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
