<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360225-25">
               <interp inst="t17360225-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-25" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360225-25" type="date" value="17360225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360225-25-off152-c126" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-25-defend176 t17360225-25-off152 t17360225-25-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360225-25-defend176" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Swift 
                  <interp inst="t17360225-25-defend176" type="surname" value="Swift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-defend176" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-defend176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17360225-25-defloc151">St. Luke Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-25-defloc151" type="placeName" value="St. Luke Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-25-defloc151" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-25-defend176 t17360225-25-defloc151"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17360225-25-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360225-25-victim178" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17360225-25-victim178" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-25-victim178" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360225-25-victim178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-25-off152 t17360225-25-victim178"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in an open Field near the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and feloniously demanding his Money, with an intent, the Monies of the said Davis to steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>John Davis. On the <rs id="t17360225-25-cd153" type="crimeDate">20th of January</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-25-off152 t17360225-25-cd153"></join> last, at Night, in a Field behind <placeName id="t17360225-25-crimeloc154">Hoxton Chappel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-25-crimeloc154" type="placeName" value="Hoxton Chappel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17360225-25-crimeloc154" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360225-25-off152 t17360225-25-crimeloc154"></join>-wall between 7 and 8 at Night I met the Prisoner and another Man: I had a Boy with a Link to light me over the Fields, but I had just taken the Link from the Boy and would carry it my self; I step'd out of the Way to let them pass, and said Good Night Gentlemen: Upon which, he struck at me with his Stick and said, G - D - n you, stand and deliver; I struck at him with the Link but miss'd him; then I gave him a Blow with my Cane, and the Boy cry'd, 
               <persName id="t17360225-25-person179">
                  Dick 
                  Swift 
               <interp inst="t17360225-25-person179" type="surname" value="Swift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person179" type="given" value="Dick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I know you, let the Gentleman alone: the Prisoner look'd at the Boy some little Time and then ran away; the other call'd after him and ask'd him what he ran for; but he presently made off too. I had a fair View of the Prisoner and am positive to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-25-person180">
                  Thomas 
                  Holt 
               <interp inst="t17360225-25-person180" type="surname" value="Holt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person180" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am 14 Years of Age.</p>
               <p>Q. What Notion have you of an Oath?</p>
               <p>Holt. If I don't speak truth, I shall go to Hell. I was coming home from my Uncles, and by the Burying Ground I met this Gentleman, it was on a Tuesday Night, in January. I was going home to Old-street, but I ask'd the Gentleman if I should light him: He agreed to give me 3d. to Light him to the Ivey-House. I had but a little bit of a Link, so we got another, and at the Fox and Goose Door we threw away the bit and lighted the other; turning into another Field, we heard 2 Men coming; the Gentleman stood up to let them pass and bid them Good Night: immediately the Prisoner step'd up to him and said, G - d D - n you deliver, and struck at him with his Stick: He aim'd at his Head but the Gentleman bobb'd down, and the Stick lit on his Back: Then he struck at the Prisoner with the Link and miss'd him, but he gave him a Blow with his Cane; I knew the Prisoner, and said Dick Swift let the Gentleman alone, I know you; and he look'd at me about a Minute and then ran away: the other said why do you run? Damn it, can't we walk along the Path? and then he ran after him as hard as he could. The Prisoner had then a Green Apron on, under his Coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360225-25-person181">
                  Richard 
                  Swift  the Elder<interp inst="t17360225-25-person181" type="surname" value="Swift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person181" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his Father. When Mr. Davis came the next Morning to charge my Son with this Fact, he said he could not be positive, but his Master being with him, he would have the Boy call'd; Aye says the Boy, I knew Dick Swift, and then immediately the Prosecutor knew him by his Green-Apron. I live in Old-Street, almost half a mile from Ask's Hospital, and sent my Son twice that Night into Field-Lane; He return'd the first Time and was at Home a little after 7, and the second Time he returned a little before 8: if I had had Time I could have fetch'd a Woman from Fleet-Lane, that I sent him to. Several Persons appear'd to his Character. <rs id="t17360225-25-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360225-25-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
