<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17340911-4">
               <interp inst="t17340911-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-4" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17340911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17340911-4" type="date" value="17340911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17340911-4-off11-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-4-defend42 t17340911-4-off11 t17340911-4-verdict13"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17340911-4-defend42" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Eager 
                  <interp inst="t17340911-4-defend42" type="surname" value="Eager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-defend42" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-defend42" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17340911-4-defloc10">Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17340911-4-defloc10" type="placeName" value="Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17340911-4-defloc10" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-4-defend42 t17340911-4-defloc10"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17340911-4-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17340911-4-victim44" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Essex 
                        <interp inst="t17340911-4-victim44" type="surname" value="Essex"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-4-victim44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17340911-4-victim44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-4-off11 t17340911-4-victim44"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him with a Knife, one mortal Wound in the upper Part of the Left-thigh, near the Groin, of the Length of three Quarters of an Inch, and Depth of 4 Inches, of which Wound he instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17340911-4-cd12" type="crimeDate">August 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-4-off11 t17340911-4-cd12"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time indicted on the Statute of Stabbing, and a third Time on the Coroner's Inquest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-4-person45">
                  Elias 
                  Mealing 
               <interp inst="t17340911-4-person45" type="surname" value="Mealing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person45" type="given" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday was seven-night, between 6 and 7 in the Evening, as the Deceas'd and I and his Son, a Child about 8 Years old, were going to Hampstead, we went into the House of 
               <persName id="t17340911-4-person46">
                  John 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17340911-4-person46" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where we found the Prisoner sitting in a Chair, and eating a Pear; we call'd for a Quartern of Liquor. The Deceas'd sat down by the Prisoner, and gave her a Dram, and she gave each of us a Pear, and then she got up and stood against the Wall, just by where Andrews was sitting upon his Seat at work - he makes Leather-Clogs. The Deceas'd went to her, and said, My dear, I'll have a Kiss. And in a Minute or two, he flew back, and cry'd, O Lord! O Lord! I'm stabb'd ! He had a Loin of Mutton in his Lap, I took it from him, and saw that he was wounded in the Thigh. I did not see any Knife in her Hand, but a Knife drop'd from her side upon Mr. Andrews's Seat, and it was bloody. There was no Quarrel betwixt them, nor one Word of Anger, nor did the Deceas'd offer any Rudeness to her; he only said he would kiss her, but did not kiss her then, tho' he had kiss'd her before when she sat in the Chair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-4-person47">
                  John 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17340911-4-person47" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While I was at work the Prisoner came and stood by me at the Window. I said, Stand aside if you can't be quiet; for the Deceas'd had been playing with her. Then she came down behind my Right-hand, and presently I heard the Deceas'd cry, I am stabb'd! I turn'd about and saw the Blood run, but saw no Knife in her Hand. The<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173409110003"></xptr> Child said, She has thrown it on your Seat; and there I found it bloody. I had us'd it at my work about an Hour before, and left it upon my Seat; but did not see her take it up, nor did I hear any Words pass betwixt her and the Deceas'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17340911-4-person48">
                  John 
                  Gassen 
               <interp inst="t17340911-4-person48" type="surname" value="Gassen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person48" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I came in, the Prisoner and the Deceas'd were sitting together, and he bob'd the Rump of a Loin of Mutton against her Apron and her Breast. They drank together, and then she went to the other side of the Room, and he follow'd her, and in three Minutes, he cry'd, Lord she has stabb'd me! He had his Hand upon her Shoulder, but did not offer any Rudeness, nor were there any Words between them at that time. He had kiss'd her before she got up, but there was no Anger, nor struggling upon that Account, for she liked it well enough. The Child call'd out to his Uncle Mealing, O Uncle, she has dropp'd the Knife, and then I saw the Knife bloody on Andrews's Seat.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kersey, Surgeon. The Wound enter'd the upper Part of the Thigh, a little below the Groin, and divided the crural Artery, so that the Wound was Mortal; for the Deceas'd lost so much Blood, that it was impossible to save his Life. I said to the Prisoner, Was it not barbarous to stab the Man thus? And she answered, Tho' I did stab him, it was but in jest. I reply'd, You will not much care to be hang'd for your Jest. Who heard me say that I stabb'd him? Says she. Why I did, you impudent Jade, says I. I have heard that she and two or three more Women like her self used to resort to Hornsey-Lane.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was eating a Pear when they came in. They call'd for Gin and Anniseed, and gave me a Dram; I got up and took up the Knife to pate a Pear. The Deceas'd bob'd at me with a Rump of Mutton, and went to put his Hands under my Coats. I gave him a push and bid him stand away, and some how he run against the Knife, and I did not know he was wounded 'till he cry'd out.</p>
               <p>Meally. She had then no Pear in her Hand, for she gave me the last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, I had another.</p>
               <p>Three or Four Women appear'd to the Prisoners Character, and deposed they had known her a great many Years; that she sold Fruit, was a very honest and industrious quiet peaceable Women, and never inclin'd to passion, and they had never heard any thing amiss in her Character.</p>
               <p>Justice - She has a most infamous Character, she and her Companions are the common Pest of the Place. I have had several Informations against them; they make it their common practice to lie in Highgate-lane, and expose their Bodies to all comers for a Penny or Two-pence a time.</p>
               <p>They found her <rs id="t17340911-4-verdict13" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-verdict13" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-verdict13" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17340911-4-punish14" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-punish14" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17340911-4-punish14" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17340911-4-defend42 t17340911-4-punish14"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
