<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390221-8">
               <interp inst="t17390221-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-8" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390221"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390221-8" type="date" value="17390221"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390221-8-off57-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-defend98 t17390221-8-off57 t17390221-8-verdict60"></join>
         
               <p>154. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390221-8-defend98" type="defendantName">
                     Peregrine 
                     Audley 
                  <interp inst="t17390221-8-defend98" type="surname" value="Audley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-defend98" type="given" value="Peregrine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-defend98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17390221-8-defloc56">St. Butolph without Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-8-defloc56" type="placeName" value="St. Butolph without Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-8-defloc56" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-defend98 t17390221-8-defloc56"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17390221-8-off57" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-off57" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-off57" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17390221-8-victim100" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Mawley 
                        <interp inst="t17390221-8-victim100" type="surname" value="Mawley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-8-victim100" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390221-8-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-off57 t17390221-8-victim100"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Hat value 2 s. a Peruke value 3 s: and a Shilling in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390221-8-cd58" type="crimeDate">Feb. 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-off57 t17390221-8-cd58"></join>.</p>
               <p>William Mawley. The Prisoner is the Man that robbed me of my Hat, Wig, and a Shilling, at the upper End of <placeName id="t17390221-8-crimeloc59">Rosemary-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-8-crimeloc59" type="placeName" value="Rosemary-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17390221-8-crimeloc59" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-off57 t17390221-8-crimeloc59"></join>, last Sunday Night was Se'en-night, between Eight and Nine o'Clock. He walked-up to me, and looked me full in the Face and, mumbling something, he gave me a Blow on the Breast, which surprized me, and then he took a Shilling out of my Pocket? and when I found my Hat and Wig go, I caught hold of his Coat, but he was too brisk for me, and got loose. I pursued him to the Place where he was taken, getting over a Wall into Justice Riccards's Yard. It was Moon-light, and I knew him again, and picked him out from all the People that were there. I saw the Colour of his Coat, - a White Loose Coat; a blew Waistcoat, and a speckled Shirt. I saw him at the Justice's, in half an Hour after I was robbed, and remember he had a Scar on one Side of his Face; which I took Notice of, when he robbed me. I can't say I minded on which Side it was, when he robbed me, but I knew him again, and swore to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-8-person101">
                  John 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17390221-8-person101" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner is the Man we took in Justice Riccards's Garden, last Sunday was se'en-night, between Eight and Nine o'Clock. We carry'd him into Mr. Riccards's Parlour, and I was present when Mawley first saw him there. Several of our Men were standing together with the Prisoner, and he ( Mawley ) picked him out, and said, that was the Man who robbed him of a Hat, Wig, and a Shilling. The Prisoner had the same Coat on, that he has now; a Blew Jacket, and a Cap. The Hat I found in a back Place, and the Wig in another, about six or seven Yards from the Place where I took him: I brought them into the Parlour, and Mawley owned them. (He swore to them again in Court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-8-person102">
                  Richard 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17390221-8-person102" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person102" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Riccards; and hearing there were Thieves in the Garden, I ran in, and seeing the Prisoner, I laid hold of him, and carry'd him into the Parlour. The Prosecutor, when he came in, picked him out from among Twenty or Thirty People.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390221-8-person103">
                  James 
                  Bradford 
               <interp inst="t17390221-8-person103" type="surname" value="Bradford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person103" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Last Sunday Se'en-night I heard a Cry of Thieves being the Garden, and I went out and found the Prisoner coming out of the Vault, I laid hold of him, but he was too-strong for me, and got away from me: So the last Witness came up and took him directly; and when Maudley came in, he picked him out from among thirty or forty People.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I was the Officer that took him into Custody: I found the Prosecutor bare-headed, with only a Handkerchief about his Head, and he was positive the Prisoner was the Man that robbed him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had been at the Glass House about a Quarter of an Hour, before the Maid said there were Thieves in the Glass House. I thought they had been only playing the Rogue: However, I went to the Door, and a Gentlewoman said, - 'twas a long time before any body came to the House. Madam, says I, I came as soon as I could; then Mr. Riccards bid me go and see if any Body was in the Vault: so I went and poked about there, and these People came and took me, and then the Justice deny'd that he had sent me there. <rs id="t17390221-8-verdict60" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-verdict60" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17390221-8-punish61" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390221-8-punish61" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390221-8-defend98 t17390221-8-punish61"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
