<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370526-20">
               <interp inst="t17370526-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-20" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370526-20" type="date" value="17370526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370526-20-off97-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-20-defend153 t17370526-20-off97 t17370526-20-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>21. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370526-20-defend153" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Meighill 
                  <interp inst="t17370526-20-defend153" type="surname" value="Meighill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-defend153" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-defend153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370526-20-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370526-20-victim155" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Crew 
                        <interp inst="t17370526-20-victim155" type="surname" value="Crew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-20-victim155" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370526-20-victim155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-20-off97 t17370526-20-victim155"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, puting him in Fear, &amp;c and taking from him a Silk Handkerchief, value 5 s. a Hat, value 10 s. and 20 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370526-20-cd98" type="crimeDate">Sept. 3, 1733</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-20-off97 t17370526-20-cd98"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-20-person156">
                  Richard 
                  Crew 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person156" type="surname" value="Crew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person156" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3d of Sept 1733, I went to the King's-Arms at Fulham to the Nutting Feast, (as 'tis call'd or nominated) with some other People in Company, and there I staid till 6 of the Clock or better, then I came home by my self. When I came to the last House in Chelsea Road, call'd the World's End, I went in there and call'd for a Pint of Beer; while I was drinking, a Journeyman Baker came in, and drank with me, and we both came out of the House together. As we were going up the <placeName id="t17370526-20-crimeloc99">King's Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-20-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="King's Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-20-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-20-off97 t17370526-20-crimeloc99"></join>, about 200 Yards from the World's End, the Prisoner overtook us; 'twas then about 7 o'Clock or better; he seemed to come along in a great Hurry, and I slipp'd into a Ditch, endeavouring to make way for him; he was very ready to help me out, and asked me if I was going to London; I told him, Yes; so we all three came together to the Tursntiles, - to the Walk where the Horse chesnut Trees grow; here we went to drink, at the Sign of the King's Head, and had two Pots of Beer; we staid about an Hour and a quarter, and then we all set out again for London.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark when you went into the King's Head?</p>
               <p>Crew. There was a Candle brought into the Room, when we first went in. - From hence we proceeded to the narrow Passage that leads to the open Fields, next London, - they call them the five Fields; when we came there the Baker<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173705260014"></xptr> bid us good Night, and went back again; so the Prisoner and I went on by our selves, and after we had passed over one Field, we met the Patrole of Chelsea-College Pensioners, with their Arms. One of the old Men begg'd of us to give him a Dram, and told us, there was a Man in the Ditch who could let us have a Dram of any Thing: I treated them with a Dram, and after they had drank it, one of them took up the Candle and Lanthorn of the Man that sold the Liquor, and held it up to both our Faces; he look'd in our Faces, and we look'd in his. Then we went on to the Duke of Buckingham's Pallisades, and there he told me 'twas too late to go over the Park, but I might go by <placeName id="t17370526-20-crimeloc100">Hyde Park Corner</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-20-crimeloc100" type="placeName" value="Hyde Park Corner"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370526-20-crimeloc100" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370526-20-off97 t17370526-20-crimeloc100"></join>; I agreed, and as we were going along, he took hold of a Stick which I had in my Hand, (but not in a violent Manner) and I let him take it; so we walked a little farther together, - I was on his Right Hand next the Wall, and all on a sudden he put me on the Left Hand next the Ditch, and we walked 10 or 12 Yards farther, then he turn'd about and said, Sir, I must have what you have got about you, and he rushed both his Hands so violently into my Waistcoat Pockets, that he tore this Flap almost down to the bottom. He took my Handkerchief and some Half-pence; then he rifled my Breeches, and took out 2 crooked Sixpences and some Half-pence; about 19 or 20 d in all. While he was rifling me, I said, Friend, do you know what you are doing? D - n you, says he, don't speak so loud, and out he pull'd a Pistol, and clapp'd it to my Breast: Then he took my Hat, and gave me his in Exchange, and then he left me as fast as he could: I suppose he perceived 2 or 3 Men coming up, or else he would have taken my Coat; for when the Men came up they told me they met a Man, running as if the Devil was in him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the Names of these Men? Are they to be produced?</p>
               <p>Crew. I don't know any Thing of them. On the Wednesday after I was robb'd, I went to the Baker, and he, (after some Talk) told me he was inform'd the Man that robb'd me liv'd somewhere about Turnham Green, and that his Wife keeps a Chandler's Shop, and that he was a Yorkshire Man. I went to enquire after him, but finding no such Person, I left a Direction in Writing with the Baker, where he might find me, if he should hear any Thing of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that Baker here?</p>
               <p>Crew No, he's gone to the East-Indies; but before he went, ('twas in November 1734) I saw the Baker in the Street, and he told me he had seen the Man that robb'd me, leaning over a Hatch at Putney. and that he was informed he liv'd at the House where he saw him. Upon this Information I went to the House, but could not find him, so I left a Warrant at Putney to seize him when he should appear, but he was not taken 'till the Night we had the Storm of Thunder and Lightning, - the 16th of this Instant.</p>
               <p>Q. What House does he keep at Putney?</p>
               <p>Crew 'Tis a little private House; I believe his Mother is the House-keeper. When he was taken up, I was sent for, and I knew him again, and that's the Man upon my Oath.</p>
               <p>Q. The Baker gave you this Information in 1734, how came you not to take him in all this while?</p>
               <p>Crew. He was not to be seen by any Body.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long was I in Company with you from first to last?</p>
               <p>Crew About an Hour and a half.</p>
               <p>C. I believe you may be right in that, for you have been an Hour in telling the Story.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he was not in Liquor when this happened?</p>
               <p>Crew. No, I remember'd every Penny I spent, and where I spent it. Let me see, - three half Crowns when I went out. Spent at Fulham 4 s. - In the Morning 8 d. - King's Head, 6 d. - World's-End, 3 d - Drams in the Ditch, 1 d Halfpenny, and some Money I lent my Companions, I can't justly tell what.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-20-person157">
                  Hen 
                  Mascall 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person157" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person157" type="given" value="Hen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The 6th of this Month, 
               <persName id="t17370526-20-person158">
                  John 
                  Bolton 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person158" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me between 10 and 11 at Night, and asked me to assist him in taking a Highwayman, and told me, 'twas the Man that marry'd Farmer's Daughter, that we were to seize; so we went out and saw him before us, I took hold of him by the Collar, and in a Minute Bolton came up to my Assistance I told him he was a Highwayman, and was my Prisoner, and upon that he immediately turned himself a little and snapp'd a Pistol in my Face; it did not go off, but the Flash burnt my Eye-brows I call'd him murdering Dog, and Bolton wrung it out of his Hand Then we gave him 2 or 3 Knocks, and in searching him, another Pistol dropp'd out of his Pocket upon my Foot; they were both loaded with Ball, and the Pistols were squared or notched in the Nossels, that the Bullets when the Pistols were fired would come out Slugs. We carried him to Justice Pettiward's, and while we stood with him in the Fore Court, he dropp'd a little Leather Purse with Balls in it, and half a Horn of Gunpowder.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the Prisoner at Putney?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173705260015"></xptr>Mascall. I never had much Knowledge of him; nor have I seen him a great while I don't know that ever I saw him out of Doors before that Night in my Life: I have seen him lean over the Hatch sometimes; and he always had a white Napkin about his Head. 'Tis a Year and half since the Warrant was taken out against him. I never saw him drest, (except this Time) in all my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-20-person159">
                  John 
                  Bolton 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person159" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person159" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Mascal's Evidence.</p>
               <p>Tho Mascal About 2 Years and a half ago, I had a Warrant against the Prisoner for this Robbery, and I searched the House where he dwelt, and look'd after him a great many Times, but could never find him.</p>
               <p>Several other Witnesses were ready to give Evidence to the same Purpose, but they were not call'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire that Crew's Information may be read.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17370526-20-person160">
                  James 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person160" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person160" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This was Mr. Crew's Information, taken from him Word for Word, and almost Literatim.</p>
               <p>The Information of 
               <persName id="t17370526-20-person161">
                  Richard 
                  Crew 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person161" type="surname" value="Crew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person161" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Great Swan-Alley, Calender-Man taken this 8th of May 1737.</p>
               <p>Who says, that he went with several others from London to the King's-Arms at Fulham, to the Nutting Feast the 3d of September 1733. and that he stay'd there 'till 6 o'Clock, then left his Company and came towards London, that he fell into Company with 
               <persName id="t17370526-20-person162">
                  Thomas 
                  Meighill 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person162" type="surname" value="Meighill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person162" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and came with him to the King's Head at the Corner of the five Fields, and that between that Place and the Infirmary, the Prisoner stopt the Informant at the Corner of Hyde-Park, under the Wall, the Prisoner stopp'd the Informant, and said, he must have what he had got about him, and then putting a Pistol to this Informant's Breast, he took from him a new Silk Handkerchief, and about 20 d. in Money, 2 crooked Six-pences, which the Informant remembers were in his Pocket; and his Hat, almost new, which he exchanged for his old one, and that he made this Informant pull a Buckle out of his Shoe, to see if it was Silver, but it not being Silver, he return'd it to this Informant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He makes me a very skilful Man; a Man must be very skilful, or must be an Alchymist, to know Silver from Brass in the dark.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370526-20-person163">
                  Samuel 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17370526-20-person163" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person163" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner eight or nine Years: I never knew any ill of him; but I don't know that he ever followed any Business: His Wife and his Mother maintain him I believe</p>
               <p>Another. I have seen the Prisoner sometimes in the Evening with Boots on, but he always went under the Shore.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. These People are so far from coming for the Sake of the Reward, that I was forced to serve them all with Subpaena's to make them appear here.</p>
               <p>Mr. Crew. When he was before the Justice, he said, the Reason why he absconded was, because he was suspected to be one of Whitlock's Gang <rs id="t17370526-20-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370526-20-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
