<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-40">
               <interp inst="t17370907-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-40" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-40" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-40-off205-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-defend279 t17370907-40-off205 t17370907-40-verdict209"></join>
         
               <p>43. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17370907-40-defend279" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-defend279" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370907-40-defloc204">St. Martins in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-40-defloc204" type="placeName" value="St. Martins in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-40-defloc204" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-defend279 t17370907-40-defloc204"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370907-40-off205" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-off205" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-off205" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-40-victim281" type="victimName">
                           Eman 
                           Wilque 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-40-victim281" type="surname" value="Wilque"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-40-victim281" type="given" value="Eman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-40-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-off205 t17370907-40-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Court and open Place near the King's-Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Silver Watch, and Steel Chain, value 5l. and a Steel Seal, set in Bath Metal, value 6 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17370907-40-cd206" type="crimeDate">July 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-off205 t17370907-40-cd206"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Prosecutor being a French-man, an Interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>Eman Wilque. I was robb'd of my Watch, by the Prisoner, the 27th of July, three Quarters of an Hour after Three in the Morning, on the other Side of <placeName id="t17370907-40-crimeloc207">Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-40-crimeloc207" type="placeName" value="Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-40-crimeloc207" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-off205 t17370907-40-crimeloc207"></join>. Being lock'd out of my House, I asked for a Place to pass the Night in, and I was directed to Covent-Garden, - to a Place where the People are up all Night. When I got there, a Woman came and sat down by me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Place was this?</p>
               <p>Wilque. A Night Cellar. - When the Woman sat down by me, I withdrew from her to another Table, and call'd for Beer. While I was here, the Prisoner and another Man came in, - the other Man speak French, and they both sat down with me. I had paid the Master of the Cellar 3d, or 4d, before they came in, and my Reckoning when I was coming away was 9d. I had no Money, so I offer'd my Watch in Pawn for the 9d, to the Master of the Cellar. The Man that was with the Prisoner, pretended to be my Friend, and said it was needless to leave the Watch, for as he was going my way, he would give the 9d, and would go Home with me and receive it again. Upon this I came away with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070026"></xptr> Prisoner and the other Man, between 3 and 4 in the Morning, and as we were going along, the Prisoner frequently asked - What's a Clock? I hesitated to pull out my Watch, but at last I did, and this Prisoner snatched it from me, and the other Man knock'd me down, while the Prisoner ran away with the Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go away between 3 and 4 o'Clock, when you went there to stay all Night?</p>
               <p>Wilque. It had been full Day-light half an Hour, before I left the Cellar. The Prisoner took my Watch, and the other Man that talked French, struck me on the Breast with his Head and tumbled me down. Upon that I call'd two Men, and said I was robb'd of my Watch, and they went in Pursuit of them. I call'd out - Thief - Thief, and some People look'd out and saw the Prisoner, and the other Man. I was told at Home the same Day that the Prisoner was taken, and the Watch was found in his Pocket, so I was asked to go before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they take nothing but your Wathc from you?</p>
               <p>Wilque. Yes; when I tumbled down my Hat fell oft my Head, and they ran away with that too, but that is not in the Indictment. When I came to the Justice's, I saw my Watch, the Name upon it is, Faul'ie.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of the Men paid the Reckoning?</p>
               <p>Wilque. The other Man, - not the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person282">
                  Edmund 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person282" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person282" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I apprehended the Prisoner at the corner of Phoenix Court, in Long-Acre about 12 o'Clock at Noon. I pursu'd him from 4 in the Morning to that Time. I am Beadle, and the Fact was committed in my Walk, and very near my Door. Upon hearing the Noise, at first I thought there had been a Fire, and therefore I jumped out of Bed in my Shirt, and saw the Prisoner running away, and the other Man knock'd the Prosecutor down several Times, to prevent his going after him. I am positive the Prisoner is the Man who was in Company with him that knock'd the Prosecutor down. I took the Prisoner about Noon Fighting with one 
               <persName id="t17370907-40-person283">
                  William 
                  Dorrel 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person283" type="surname" value="Dorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person283" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and when I had him before the Justice we search'd him, and found the Watch upon him. Mr. Justice Frazier has it in his Pocket. (The Watch was produced) I'll Swear this is the Watch that I found upon the Prisoner in his right coat Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. At the Time this Fray happen'd there were a thousand People going by.</p>
               <p>Norton. There were several People going by: but the Frenchman, not expressing himself right, they imagin'd it was only a Battle, and cry'd, Well done little one, for the Prisoner's Companion was less than the Prosecutor, yet he knock'd him about and beat his Head against the Windows - the poor Frenchman (the Prosecutor) was beat in a terrible Manner; I saw how the matter was, and had I not blunder'd about a good while to find my Shoes, I had taken them before they had made their Escape. I apprehend that Dorrel who was Fighting with the Prisoner when I took him, had quarrel'd with him, in order to get a share of the Booty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person284">
                  Rachael 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person284" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person284" type="given" value="Rachael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Red-Lion-Court near Long-Acre, one End goes into Drury-Lane, the other into Long-Acre. I happen'd to be up the 27th of July all Night, with a Child that was dying, and looking out of the Window between 3 and 4 in the Morning, I saw 3 Men come up the Court, and they stopp'd against my House: one of the Men asked the French-man what o'Clock it was? He pull'd out his Watch, and said 'twas almost 4; let me see, says one of them, - but I can't swear which of them it was that said so. Me tell you (says the Frenchman) dat it be almose Vore, why can't you let me see, says the other) Me tell you dat it be almose vore, by mine Vash, says the Frenchman, and was going to put it up in his Pocket; but one of them snatch'd it out of his Hand, and said, - now you know, - me pay de Reckoning vor you, - me pay tres Sheling, and dat Man pay two Sheling, - ven you pay me de Crown, you sall have a de Vash again. Upon this, says the Frenchman, - den you come along vid me, me pawn my Vash, and me pay you, - and so they all went civilly down the Court; but as soon as they had turned the Corner, I heard a great Outcry, and presently the Man that had snatch'd the Watch, came running up the Court again, and the Frenchman after him, crying Teef - Teef - got mine Vash, - got mine Vash; and as he was turning the Corner to go into Long-Acre, the other came up and knocked the Frenchman down; in his Fall, his Hat flew off, and a Woman took it up and ran away with it. I can't be positive to the Men, but I saw the Watch in the Man's Hand that ran away, and saw the other knock the Frenchman down.</p>
               <p>Q. To Wilque. Did the Prisoner and the other pay 5 s. for you?</p>
               <p>Wilque. Not a Farthing more than 9 d. and that the other Man paid, - not the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person285">
                  James 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person285" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person285" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Norton call'd me to assist him; I am a Porter in Long-Acre, at the Corner of Phoenix-Court. 'Twas about 12 o'Clock at Noon, he charged me to hold the Prisoner fast; I did so, and we carry'd him before the Justice;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070027"></xptr> there Mr. Norton searched him, and took the Watch out of his right Coat Pocket. The Prisoner had little or nothing to say for himself, - and that's all I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person286">
                  William 
                  Dorrel 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person286" type="surname" value="Dorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person286" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I will tell you what I know of the Matter. I was walking down Drury-Lane the 27th of July, and there I heard a great Noise about the Prisoner's having robb'd a Gentleman of his Watch; so I went a little farther, and I saw the Prisoner and one 
               <persName id="t17370907-40-person287">
                  John 
                  Cane 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person287" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person287" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             scuffling together; Cane call'd to me, and bid me lay hold of him, for he had that very Morning robb'd a Gentleman of his Watch and his Hat. I laid hold of him, and carry'd him to the White Hart in Hart street, and sent Cane to look for the Constable and the Owner of the Watch. When Cane was gone, the Prisoner started up, and said he would not stay with me, so away he ran, and I after him When I overtook him, he struck me with this Stick, but a Coachman lending me another, the Prisoner surrender'd, and told me, if I would let him go along quietly, he would turn Evidence, and would hang 3 or 4 before he would be hang'd himself. We carry'd him before Justice Frazier, and upon searching him, the Watch was found in his Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person288">
                  John 
                  Cane 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person288" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of July, my Wife and I were coming up Drury Lane, between 3 and 4 in the Morning, and we saw the Prisoner, and his Sister, and his Brother-in-Law, and another Man at the Corner of Red-Lion-Court; they were using the Frenchman in a very barbarous Manner, they beat him terribly, - and his Hair was all over his Eyes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was using the Man ill?</p>
               <p>Cane. Clark's (the Prisoner's) Sister, and her Husband, and the Prisoner struck him (the Prosecutor) upon the Belly, because he made a Noise, and held the Prisoner by the Coat, crying out at the same Time, - O my Vash! my Vash! I went up to them, and asked them if they were not ashamed to use the Man in that manner? The Prisoner's Brother-in-law was speaking French to the Prosecutor, and while he was speaking to him, the Prisoner ran away with the Watch, and his Sister with the Hat; the Prosecutor would have run after him, but the Brother-in-Law knock'd him down and beat him, while the Prisoner got away.</p>
               <p>Q. To Wilque. Did any Body abuse you beside the Prisoner, and the other Man that talk'd French?</p>
               <p>Wilque. No, no Body else.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time might there be between their first demanding what it was o'Clock, and the Prisoner's running away with the Watch?</p>
               <p>Wilque. About two Minutes.</p>
               <p>Cane. About 8 or 9 in the Morning, I heard that one Kelly, (who lodges in one Leadbeater's House with the Prisoner) was taken, and that he had declared, the Prisoner had got the Watch; so I went down to Leadbeater's, and there I saw the Prisoner, and Money and a Watch lying before him upon a Table; there was one Cassedy with him, and I suppose Cassedy was buying the Watch of the Prisoner, for when I asked them what they were doing, and told them, that Watch was the Frenchman's, Cassedy took up the Money again, and said he would have nothing to do with it, and the Prisoner put the Watch into his Pocket. Then I laid hold of him, and said he should not go, 'till the Prosecutor came; he got up, but I kept him safe, and brought him down to Drury-Lane; and as we were going by Little Russel-Street, I call'd Dorrel, the Soldier to assist me, so we carry'd him to the White Hart, in Hart Street, by Covent Garden, and there I left him while I went to get a Constable, but while I was gone, he made his Escape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person289">
                  Eliz 
                  Cane 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person289" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person289" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Husband and I were coming from Covent-Garden, about Three or Four in the Morning, and there I saw the Prisoner, and the Prosecutor, and another Man, at the End of Red-Lyon-Court. The Prisoner struck the Prosecutor several Blows upon the Stomach, upon which my Husband went up, and said, if you have robb'd the Gentleman, don't kill him. The Frenchman cry'd out - rob! rob! - Vash! Vash! My Spouse got between them and parted them, and then the Prisoner ran away. About an Hour after, I saw the Prisoner again, and he pull'd out a Watch at the End of Queen-Street, to shew it to his Sister.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Cane and his Wife were drinking with me, at the same Time; and he stripp'd himself and wanted to fight me.</p>
               <p>Cane. When I saw the Prisoner and the other Man about the Frenchman, in the Morning, I took them to be Sodomites, because the Prisoner had his Hand upon the Frenchman's Breeches.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I will bring sufficient Witnesses, to prove the Watch was pawn'd with me.</p>
               <p>Q. To Norton. What Character has the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Norton. A very bad one; he is upon Record for a Rape, and for willfull and corrupt Perjury. The Cellar where this Robbery was concerted, is a Place that I have mention'd several Times to the Justices, and have desired them to grant no Licence. We are afraid to enter at any Time upon any Occasion, for if we do, the Candles are all put out, and the Constables are severely beaten.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070028"></xptr>The Cellar Man. I keep the Cellar, - my Name is 
               <persName id="t17370907-40-person290">
                  Abram 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person290" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person290" type="given" value="Abram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>C. Then the Justices shall know your Name, Sir.</p>
               <p>Fowler. There are more Night Houses than mine, - why are they not all suppress'd? - About the 27th of July, - there, or thereabout, the Frenchman came down into my Cellar, about 11 or 12 o'Clock. He was there some Time, and paid for two or three Pints of Beer, - for, my Lord, 'tis the Custom of us who keep such Cellars, to make the People pay for the Liquor as it comes in, for fear they should run away and Bilk us. But to go on, - when the Frenchman's Money was out, - he could not sit for nothing, - so he call'd for more Beer, and gave me his Watch to keep 'till Morning. Well, - he drank 5 or 6 Pints of Beer, and I had his Watch in my Custody, that I might be sure of my Reckoning. While he was drinking, in comes the Prisoner, and another Man with him that could talk French. They sat down with the Prosecutor and in a little Time seem'd very familiar together. After they had been together some Time, the Man that spake French, asked me if I had got the Gentleman's Watch in Custody? Yes, says I, 'twas given me to keep 'till he pays me his Reckoning. How much does he owe you upon it, says he? I told him twas pawn'd for 9 d. Bring the Watch, says he, I'll pay you the Money. I brought the Watch and gave it into the Prosecutor's Hands, and the Prisoner's Friend pay'd me the 9 Pence. After this, a Pot of Beer came in, and the Prisoner and his Friend pay'd for the Frenchman. Nay, they drank 2 or 3 Hours after the 9 Pence was paid. I'll tell you how it was, - the Man that spoke French, paid 1 s. for the Prosecutor's 9 Pence, so then there was a Pot to come in, and after that they drank 2 or 3 Hours, and the Prisoner and his Companion paid all the Reckoning. 'Tis true it did not come to much, because they drank nothing - but - Beer - common Beer. - The 9 Pence Reckoning was contracted before these People came.</p>
               <p>Q. And did the Prosecutor stay 2 or 3 Hours in your Cellar after these Men came in? Pray what Time did he go out.</p>
               <p>Fowler. About Four o'Clock.</p>
               <p>C. He came in about 11 or 12, and paid for 2 or 3 Pints of Beer, you say before they came in, and after they came in, you say they drank together 2 or 3 Hours.</p>
               <p>Fowler. My Lord, he gave his Liquor about to the People that were there, he did not drink all that he call'd for himself. - They went away together about Four o'Clock in the Morning, and the next News I heard was - that the Prisoner was taken up and carry'd before Justice Frazier, for stealing the Watch! I went directly thither, and there I saw the Prosecutor, and his Worship asked him if he had lost his Watch? I have given it, says he, to a Man that paid my Reckoning for me last Night. Was you robb'd? - No, - I have given it to a Man that pay'd 9 Pence for me. Then the Justice offer'd him his Oath: But the Prosecutor said he was a Roman. No matter for that, - swear the Truth, says the Justice. When he was sworn, the Interpreter asked him upon Oath, if he had been robb'd? He said No, a Man had his watch who had paid 9 Pence for him, and that he expected to have it again. Why, says the Justice, the Man that has the Watch, says he paid 6 s. 10 d. upon it. No, no, says the Frenchman, it be no Ingliseman take mine Vash, - it be won Frenchman dat ware his own Hair; he pay de 9 Pence vor me. Then the Justice asked the Persons that brought the Prisoner before him, why they took him up? I did make mush Noise (said the Frenchman) but vether I vas rob, I not know; I vant to keep de Man, dat I may get my Vash. The Justice upon this, would have discharged the Prisoner, but one of the Men that took the Prisoner informed him that not with standing what the Prosecutor then said, he did believe he was robb'd in earnest.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Frazier. Mr. Norton brought the Prisoner before me, and charged the Prisoner on his own Oath, as he had seen the Robbery himself. I sent for the Prosecutor, but he did not appear in 2 Hours. The first Thing I did was to search the Prisoner; the Watch being found upon him, I order'd him to give an Account of himself, and how he came by it. He told me he lodged in Surrey with a Washerwoman, and that he was at Home that Night about Nine or Ten o'Clock, in Surrey; then he said he had forgot himself, and own'd he was out till Four in the Morning. I found we could not get the Prosecutor, so I committed him for further Examination. But a little while after I had committed the Prisoner, that Man - who keeps the Night Cellar, brought the Prosecutor to me, and he and his Companions pull'd him about and put Words into his Mouth. I should have told your Lordship, that when the Prisoner was before me, he told me, he had lent 6 s. upon the Watch. When the Prosecutor was examined, he did say he was not robb'd but that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070029"></xptr> the Watch was pawn'd for 9 d. I resolved to enquire farther into the Matter, and as I was then going to St. Martin's Vestry, - I order'd them all to attend me again at 6 o'Clock, for I imagin'd the Prisoner to be a bad Man, and that they had endeavour'd to stifle the Evidence. When I examin'd them again at 6, the Frenchman told me he had been robb'd indeed, and was now willing to give Evidence; that the Men who were before me in the Morning, had disswaded him from prosecuting the Prisoner, telling him it would be chargeable, troublesome, &amp;c. when I shewed the Prosecutor the Watch, he swore to it, and that the Prisoner was the Man that had robb'd him.</p>
               <p>Q. To Wilque. Pray how came you when you was first before Mr. Justice Frazier, to declare that you was not robb'd?</p>
               <p>Wilque. There were 5 or 6 People upon me, terrifying and teizing me, - they told me the Man was not taken, and bid me not insist upon his being committed if he should be taken, for if he was committed he would be hang'd. One of these Men is here in Court, that is one of them, ( pointing to Cassedy.)</p>
               <p>Q. Who are you, Sir?</p>
               <p>Cassedy. I live in Cross Lane in Holborn, - no, I am not a House-keeper, but I pay about 6 or 7 l. a Year for 2 Rooms, and I am a Stay-maker by Trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Who knows you? Is there any Body here can give any Account of you?</p>
               <p>Cassedy. Yes, here's a Gentleman knows me, Mr. Fowler knows me.</p>
               <p>C. O! that's the Man that keeps the Night-Cellar; I suppose the Prisoner knows you likewise.</p>
               <p>Norton. There has been 15 or 16 of this Gang that have threatned my Life, if I appeared in this Matter.</p>
               <p>Wilque That Man ( Cassedy ) told me I should have my Watch again if I would not prosecute, and as a Token thereof, he said I should have his (Cassedy's) 'till my own was return'd</p>
               <p>Q. To Mr. Frazier) Was the Prosecutor upon Oath, when he said he was not robb'd?</p>
               <p>Justice Frazier ) Yes, my Neice understanding French, she interpreted upon Oath.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frazier's Niece ) Two Hours after the Prisoner was committed the Prosecutor came; I ask'd him if he had been robb'd of his Watch? He said no, the Man had lent him 9 d. upon it, And had not robb'd him. This he said several Times over.</p>
               <p>Mr. Frazier. But when he came again about 6 o'Clock, he swore that he was absolutely robb'd, and his Information was read over to him 3 Times, I ask'd him the Reason of his denying it before? He told me, he was afraid of these People, that they had frighted him, and that he did not understand our Laws; but since that, his Landlady had told him, he must speak, and tell the whole Truth.</p>
               <p>Cassedy. I was drinking at the Horse Shoe and Magpye in Clare Market, and the Prisoner came in the Morning that this Accident happen'd, about 6 o'Clock. Some Time after, Cane came in and laid hold of the Prisoner, telling him the Frenchman made a great Noise about the Watch, and that if it was not return'd, he (Cane) should be brought into Trouble. Why, says the Prisoner, I lent 6 s. and some odd Pence upon it, if you'll give me the Money, I will give it you. Cane would not take it, then the Prisoner offer'd it to me; but I would not take it. Then they went to the Bull head in Vere street, and at that Time the Man of the Night Cellar and I came in together. Cane's Wife told them in my hearing that the Frenchman was hard by, and if he might have his Watch again he would be satisfied. After this, I met the Frenchman in Wild-street, and I asked him if he had been robb'd? No, no, says he, and at the same Time I know the Prisoner had the Watch in his Pocket, and the Chain hanging out; so I took him (the Prosecutor) to the Bull head, but when we came there, they had carry'd the Prisoner to Justice Frazier's. Upon this, I carry'd the Frenchman to the Justice's House, and there he said he had pawn'd his Watch to a Man that speak mush French, and that he no was rob. The Justice asked him, how he came to make such a Noise about it if he was not robb'd? No, I vas var drunk (says he) so me lay mine on the Table sometime, so de Men go out, I fear Men not give mine Vash again, so I go after and cry robbe! robbe! mine Vash! mine Vash !</p>
               <p>C. Why, it seems you are the Person that perswaded him to say all this!</p>
               <p>Wilque. He (Cassedy) pull'd out a Watch in an Ale-house, and offer'd it me if I would be quiet: that's the very Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person291">
                  Francis 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person291" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person291" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I keep a Publick-House in Parker's Lane: on Wednesday Night Cane came into my House, and the Prisoner being there, some Words arose between them, upon which Cane said, - by G - d I will swear your Life away.</p>
               <p>Cane. My Lord, that Man's an Irishman</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370907-40-person292">
                  Alexander 
                  Bark 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person292" type="surname" value="Bark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person292" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Why, Cane's an Irishman himself. He came into Lambert's House and said, -<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070030"></xptr> right or wrong, he'd hang the Prisoner, and his Wife said, whoever came to swear for the Prisoner would be committed.</p>
               <p>Cane. This is an Irishman too my Lord.</p>
               <p>Bark. My Lord, - I drove the Lord Chief 
               <persName id="t17370907-40-person293">
                  Baron 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17370907-40-person293" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person293" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Ireland, - I was his Coachman when Cane was transported from thence.</p>
               <p>The Night Cellar-Man. My Lord, I have known the Prisoner this 5 or 6 Years, - I never -</p>
               <p>Q. To Norton. Pray what Character has this Man's Cellar?</p>
               <p>Norton. A very bad one, my Lord. The Reason we can't prevent such Things as these is, we dare not go down into his Cellar for Fear of being knocked on the Head; when the Constable and Beadles go down, the Candles are all put out, and they are beaten almost to Death.</p>
               <p>Cellar Man I was arrested and put in Newgate for Debt; Mr. Nichols can give an Account of me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nicholls. I know nothing at all of him.</p>
               <p>A Woman. I have known the Prisoner 5 or 6 Years, I am a Milliner in Piccadilly. He liv'd 4 Years ago (as a Servant) at my Lord Strafford's; since that he was <rs id="t17370907-40-deflabel208" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-defend279 t17370907-40-deflabel208"></join> to a Relation of mine, one Morris a Doctor of Physick in Soho Square.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. The last Place I liv'd at was Hill's Coffee-House, and since that I have been lame.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you then to frequent Night Cellars at 3 or 4 o'Clock in the Morning?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I got up early that Morning, because I was to go with my Sister to Hampstead, who lives there with some credible People.</p>
               <p>A Witness. That was the Woman that run away with the Man's Hat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had lent 6s. 10d. to the Frenchman upon the Watch, and as we were going along, he collar'd me, and would have it again without paying me the Money.</p>
               <p>Wilque. He paid not one Farthing more than 9 d for me.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I was in Lambert's House, and heard that Woman (Cane's Wife) say, that no Body would have the Assurance to appear in the Prisoner's Behalf, for if they did, they would be secur'd in Court.</p>
               <p>C. When manifest Perjuries are discover'd, the Persons offending ought to be committed and punish'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Lambert can speak to my Character.</p>
               <p>Lambert. My Wife can speak better to it than I can, - she's an Irishwoman.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lambert. I have known the Prisoner 4 Years and a half; for this last Year or two, I never knew nothing of him but what was true, - and just, - and honest. I have known him several Years to behave true and honest. The Jury found him <rs id="t17370907-40-verdict209" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-verdict209" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370907-40-punish210" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-40-punish210" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-40-defend279 t17370907-40-punish210"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
