<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17391205-52">
               <interp inst="t17391205-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-52" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17391205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17391205-52" type="date" value="17391205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17391205-52-off251-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-52-defend359 t17391205-52-off251 t17391205-52-verdict253"></join>
         
               <p>57. 
               
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-defend359" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Bradshaw 
                  <interp inst="t17391205-52-defend359" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-defend359" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-defend359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17391205-52-defloc249">St. Sepulchre's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-52-defloc249" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17391205-52-defloc249" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-52-defend359 t17391205-52-defloc249"></join>, was indicted, for that she not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17391205-52-cd250" type="crimeDate">10th of November</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-52-off251 t17391205-52-cd250"></join>, <rs id="t17391205-52-off251" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-off251" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-off251" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17391205-52-victim361" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Challenger 
                        <interp inst="t17391205-52-victim361" type="surname" value="Challenger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-52-victim361" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17391205-52-victim361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-52-off251 t17391205-52-victim361"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously, &amp;c. did make an Assault, and with both her Hands, in and upon the Breast of the said Challenger, violently and feloniously did push and thrust; by Means of which Pushing and Thrusting, He the said Challenger was with great Force thrown to the Ground, and by the said Fall, received on the Back-part of his Head, a mortal Bruise, of which he languished from the said 10th of October to the 11th, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time charged by the Coroner's Inquest, for feloniously slaying the said Challanger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person362">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tranter 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person362" type="surname" value="Tranter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person362" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived three Weeks with the Prisoner; the Deceased had lodged in the Prisoner's Cellar about five Years. He <rs id="t17391205-52-viclabel252" type="occupation">used to sell Greens about the Streets o'Mornings, and Fish o'Nights</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17391205-52-victim361 t17391205-52-viclabel252"></join>. On Saturday Night, November<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050030"></xptr> the 10th, he came Home between Ten and Eleven, - I believe 'twas between Eleven and Twelve, and the Prisoner said to him, - So Dick, - Where's the Ten-pence Halfpenny you owe me? Says the Prisoner, - Mrs.Bradshaw, I can't give it you To-night, but if you'll stay till Morning, when I have sold my Greens, by G-d you shall have it. She told him she'd stay no longer, and if he did not pay her that Night, he should not come in; - he should come in there no more, till he brought the Money. There are four Steps at the Door, and he was upon the Top of the Steps; when he told her he could not pay her that Night. I saw the Prisoner (as I was standing in her Shop, near the Door) give him a push down all the four Steps. He stood with his Face toward her's; she push'd him down backwards, and he fell down all the Steps. Then she went to Bed, and the Deceased was shut out for Half an Hour: In which Time I heard him call out, - Mr. Constable! Mr. Constable! (the Landlord of the House) is a poor Man to be murder'd because he has got no Money? He spoke this very faintly, and I hearing him, let him in in the dark, so I can't tell what Condition he was then in, but he complain'd of his Head, and went down to his Cellar. I did not see him again till Seven o'Clock next Morning: He was then sitting upright in the Bed, with his Cloaths on; and he had bled a vast deal; his Shirt and Pillow were very bloody, and his Hair was matted with the Blood that came from his Head. The deceased in the Morning halloo'd out, Thieves! Thieves were come to rob him! That was the Occasion of my going down: I asked him how he did? He said he was very ill, - very cold. There was no Surgeon or Apothecary call'd to help him, but somebody got him an Hot-pot, which he could not drink, he was so weak. There was a Woman washing in the Cellar, and she saw all this as well as I. Mr.Constable cut off his Hair, and threw it down the Vault. The Accident happen'd on Saturday Night, and on Sunday Night, about Six, he died. I was present when he was wash'd: A Woman who liv'd at Constable's wash'd him, but she is not here. I saw his Head was bloody, and the Blood came from the back part of his Head; but the Hair was not cut off so near as that I could see any Wound. There was no Coroner call'd, and but one Searcher; and when she came, Mr. Constable call'd me up Stairs, and bid me take no Notice of the Cut in his Head. The deceased was drunk when he fell down, but not so much as to be insensible of what he said, or did; and I don't believe the Prisoner push'd him down wilfully; she did not do it with any great Force.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person363">
                  James 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person363" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person363" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have only to say, that on Saturday, the 10th of November, between Ten and Eleven in the Morning, I was at one Casey's in the Old Bailey, and the deceased came in to fell Greens. He was then as hearty as any one in this Court; and if I had had a Hundred Pounds to have laid out in the Insurance of any Man's Life, I would have insur'd the Deceased's, in the Forenoon of Saturday, the 10th of November. I heard of the Accident at Casey's, but I never saw him after it happen'd.</p>
               <p>Coroner . Constable had the Management of this whole Affair: The Man died on Sunday Night, and on Monday Morning they got him into the Ground, without giving any Notice to the Coroner. But afterwards, by Direction from Sir 
               <persName id="t17391205-52-person364">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person364" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person364" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Robinson sent a Letter to the Coroner, who order'd the Body to be taken up, and a proper Inquiry to be made.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The deceased came Home between Eleven and Twelve on Saturday Night. I asked him for my Money, and swore he should not come in, till he paid me; and I argued some time with him for it. Then I put my Hand to his Shoulder, and he turn'd down the Steps, and tumbled. After this I let him in myself, and he went into the Kitchen, and sat two Hours by the Fire, without making any Complaint, and paid me Five Farthings of my Money.</p>
               <p>Tranter. She went to Bed, and I let the Deceased in myself. On Monday Afternoon, when the Man was buried, People persuaded me to tell what I knew of the Matter; so I left the Prisoner's Service that Day, and did so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person365">
                  Mary 
                  Belville 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person365" type="surname" value="Belville"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Fact; but on Saturday Afternoon, between Twelve and One o'Clock, I drank with the Deceased, at the Lion and Ball, the Corner of Fleet-Lane. He told me, he was not exceeding well, - not so well as he should be. I am so cold, says he, that I am like a Post. I told him, we would have a Pint of Beer, and it should be warm'd. After which I asked the Woman of the House, if she wanted any Greens, if she did, the deceased would bring her some? She said, he might if he pleased; and he went out and brought her his Greens, and she bought four Savoys and six Colliflowers. On Sunday I sent to the Deceased's Cellar for a Head of Sallory , and heard that Dick (the Deceased )<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050031"></xptr> was fuddled, and was not up. And on Monday Morning about Ten o'Clock, Mr. Constable came to my Husband, and told him, Challenger was dead. I wash'd him, and saw a Thousand Blotches and Scabs about him, but no Marks of Blood.</p>
               <p>Tranter . She was the Woman who threw his Shirt down the Vault.</p>
               <p>Belville. No; 'twas only a Collar, which he wore round his Neck. Tranter warm'd two Pots of Water and brought me down to wash him. She helped me to throw the Collar down the Vault. I saw no Blood on him; but I did not examine the back part of his Head.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person366">
                  Beata 
                  Adcock 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person366" type="surname" value="Adcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person366" type="given" value="Beata"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was present when the Deceased came Home on Saturday Night; he was vastly fuddled. The Prisoner ask'd him, if he had brought her the Money she lent him to buy Greens? He said, No, - he had spent it. Then, says she, you sha'nt lie in this House to Night, till you pay me the Six-pence I lent you, and the Four-pence Halfpenny you owe in the Shop. He told her he could not, and at that Instant I turn'd into the Back-Room, and he was push'd down the Steps. I afterwards saw him sitting upon his Breech, on the middle Step; I pass'd by him to go out, and saw no Harm come to him, - but vastly fuddled he was, to be sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person367">
                  Marget 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person367" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person367" type="given" value="Marget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I came Home (to Constable's House) on Saturday Night, between Ten and Eleven, and found the Deceased sitting in the Chimney-Corner: He called for hot Drink, Tranter warm'd it for him, and he seem'd brisk. I sat up in his Company till between One and Two. At One, I told him 'twas time to go to Bed; but he desired to stay longer. At last he took a Candle and went down to Bed; I follow'd him down, to see he did no Mischief with his Candle: He stood Sea sawing upon the Stairs, and told me, he was so drunk that he could not get into his Bed. I desir'd him to take Care of his Candle; for, says I, if we should all be burn'd in our Beds, - what shall we do. So I came up, and desir'd Tranter to look after him. In the Morning, the Prisoner went down, and gave him a Dram of Anniseed. He complain'd of no Wound given him by the Prisoner, nor did I see any Blood.</p>


               <p>Tranter . This was the Night before the Prisoner was push'd down.</p>
               <p>Atkins . No; 'twas the very same Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person368">
                  Joseph 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person368" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person368" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased and I were great Acquaintance: We were Partners, and sold Fish and Greens together; he was the first that let me into the Business. On Sunday Morning I went to his Cellar, and serv'd Belville a Ha'p'orth of Greens. I called, Dick! Dick! but nobody answering, I push'd open the Cellar door, and went down, and found him lying stark-naked on the Ground, with his Knees up to his Mouth. I lifted him up, and put him in Bed, and call'd Mr. Constable . He came down with another Friend, and gave him Part of a Pint of hor Liquor , with Gin or Brandy, or something, put into it. I saw no Blood on him, - there was a Scar upon his Head, just upon his Crown, - you may call it a Scratch, and I believe the Pebble stones behind him might do that, for I found him lying upon them. When the hot Pint came down, he look'd very hard at me, but could only say, - Joe! very cold! - very cold, Joe! I staid with him till Four o'Clock; then I left him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person369">
                  Catherine 
                  Constable 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person369" type="surname" value="Constable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person369" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I went down into the Cellar on Sunday Morning, and saw the Deceased leaning on his Elbow: I ask'd him, what ail'd him? Mrs. Constable, says he, I am so cold, I am like a Post, - feel me! I took hold of him, and found him very cold and chill'd, all one Side of him. Upon which I bid Tranter give him a Glass of Anniseed, and I supported his Head while he drank it. God bless you, Mrs. Constable , said he, I am cold as a Post. He made no Complaints, and as for Blood, - I saw none. I have known the Prisoner about seven or eight Months, and never heard but that she was and honest virtuous Body. When Tranter came from the Elephant and Castle, where the Body was brought, after it had been taken up, the People asked her how she could swear the poor Woman's Life away wrongfully? and she said, she would not have done it if she had not been prompted to it, and if she had not done it, others would.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17391205-52-person370">
                  Hester 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17391205-52-person370" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person370" type="given" value="Hester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is an entire Stranger to me; but I live opposite to this House: And this Tranter coming to my Shop for a Quartern of Tea, told me that Dick who sold Greens was dead. Then God rest his Soul, says I. He came in late, she said, on Saturday Night, and was so drunk he could not stand; that he complain'd of being cold, and drank some warm Ale: but still complaining of Cold, he went to Bed, and died suddenly; and now my Mistress is laying him out; and washing him: I am surprized, says she, how they can touch him, he's all over Seabs s and Sores. She said nothing of his having been push'd down, nor of his being bloody, but that he was a frightful Corps.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173912050032"></xptr>John Row . I am a Surgeon. I was sent for to inspect the Body of the Deceased the Night the Jury sat on it , which was the Thursday after the Accident. Mr. Snowd sealped him, and I examined the Head and Brain. There was no Consesion through the Flesh, - only through the Skin, or in the Way of rubbing, as by a Brick; and there were Blotches all over his Body, through the Instigation of the Venereal Disease. <rs id="t17391205-52-verdict253" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17391205-52-verdict253" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
