<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350522-1">
               <interp inst="t17350522-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-1" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350522-1" type="date" value="17350522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350522-1-off3-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-defend30 t17350522-1-off3 t17350522-1-verdict7"></join>
         
               <p>1. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Becket 
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-defend30" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17350522-1-defloc1">St. Matthew Friday Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Matthew Friday Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-defend30 t17350522-1-defloc1"></join>, <rs id="t17350522-1-deflabel2" type="occupation">Book-keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-defend30 t17350522-1-deflabel2"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17350522-1-off3" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-off3" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-off3" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 500 Guineas
            </rs>, the Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Gibson 
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-victim32" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-victim32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-off3 t17350522-1-victim32"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17350522-1-cd4" type="crimeDate">December 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-off3 t17350522-1-cd4"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Gibson (the <rs id="t17350522-1-viclabel5" type="occupation">Hereford Carrier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-victim32 t17350522-1-viclabel5"></join>.) On Sunday the twenty first or twenty second of December, I receiv'd 500 Guineas of - Clayton, Esq; Receiver General of the County of Hereford, to carry in my Waggon to London. The Money was sealed up in a Bag, and so delivered to my Wife who locked it up. At night, when we were packing the Goods in the Waggon, Tom, says I, to my Brother, Fetch the Bag of Money. My Wife came out and gave it him and the Seal was not broke. He and she roll'd some Straw round it and put it into an old Pair of Leather Saddle Bags. They roll'd more Straw round the Saddle Bags, and then they were put into a small Pack of Goods and corded up, and this Pack was put into the Waggon, towards the Fore-end. The Waggon was loaded about eleven at Night, and about twelve it set out for London, My Brother Thomas went with it, but I did not go my self - On the Monday sennight, my Son In-law, William Mountain (the Monmouth Carrier) came and told me that the Money was lost. My Waggon inns at the <placeName id="t17350522-1-crimeloc6">Saracen's Head in Friday Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-crimeloc6" type="placeName" value="Saracen's Head in Friday Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350522-1-crimeloc6" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350522-1-off3 t17350522-1-crimeloc6"></join>, where the Prisoner has been for some Years my Book-keeper.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not charge others?</p>
               <p>J. Gibson. I charged 
               <persName id="t17350522-1-person33">
                  John 
                  Holden 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person33" type="surname" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17350522-1-person34">
                  Charles 
                  Airs 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person34" type="surname" value="Airs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person34" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two of the Porters who unloaded the Waggon at the Inn.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was there any Passengers in the Waggon?</p>
               <p>J. Gibson. Yes; But I connot say how many.</p>
               <p>P. Council. Did not you send a Bill of Parcels to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Gibson. Yes; for it is a usual thing.</p>
               <p>P. Council. Among the other Particulars in that Bill, Did you mention this Money?</p>
               <p>J. Gibson. No; for I don't think it proper.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not in November last send me a Bill of Parcels, with advice of a parcel of Money that was coming?</p>
               <p>J. Gibson. I might do so, for I have done it sometimes, but have oftner omitted it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person35">
                  Thomas 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person35" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person35" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I packed up the Money in the Waggon, and set out with it for London about twelve on Sunday Night, and am sure the Money was never stir'd till we came to Town, which was on the Friday following. For though there might be Passengers in the Waggon, yet they could not come at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173505220003"></xptr> the Pack where the Money was, because there was a Quantity of Boxes and other things loaded upon, and on each side of it. And where we lay on the Road a Man had so much a Night for watching. And when we came into the Inn-Yard (in Friday Street) I am sure nothing had been removed. I did not stay to see the Waggon unloaded, but being tired, I left that to the care of the Prisoner and his Porters; and not thinking of the Money, I went into the Tap-house where I staid two or three Hours. Then the Prisoner came to me, and asked me about a little Parcel which I had taken up by the way. I have searched the Bags, says he, and it is not there, for there is nothing but Straw in 'em. - Nothing but Straw in 'em.? says I, in great Surprise, for then I thought of the Money - Sure you must be mistaken. I went into the Ware-house and found the Bags lying under his Desk, I searched them but there was none of the Money. The Porters were all gone. But when they came again next Morning, they denyed that they knew any thing of the Money. 
               <persName id="t17350522-1-person36">
                  Charles 
                  Aires 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person36" type="surname" value="Aires"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person36" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (one of them) said that he found the Saddle Bags at the bottom of the Pack, and thought they had been an old pair of Boots and so he delivered them to the next Man. For their Method is, to unload the Goods by the Waggon side, and deliver every Parcel single, to the Book-keeper, who sits in the Ware-house to take an account of them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Were none of the Goods taken out in the Journey?</p>
               <p>T. Gibson. We always have Way-Goods, as we call them, but these we put at the Tail of the Waggon.</p>
               <p>William Mountain. Being acquainted with the Prisoner, on Sunday the twenty second of March, I fell into talk about this Money, and I said it was hard he could not find out who was concern'd in taking it. He said he had done all that he could, and more than any body was aware of: And that he had heard there was two Men and a Woman concern'd. I asked who they were. He said he could describe them, but did not think it proper; and that in a little time a Man would bring a Woman to Confession; and I should see some Person in Goal before the matter all came out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I tell you at the same time how I came by this Intelligence? that I had it from the cunning Man at Wickham in Buckinghamshire; and did not John Gibson himself cunjure for the Thief, with the Book and Key?</p>
               <p>W. Mountain. 
               <persName id="t17350522-1-person37">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person37" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person37" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the Prisoner proposed to go to Wickham to enquire after the cunning Man, and I went with them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person38">
                  James 
                  Fry 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person38" type="surname" value="Fry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person38" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the latter end of March, Gibson charged a Constable with the Prisoner. The Prisoner desired him to have patience and not send him to Goal, for before the end of next Month, he would have all his Money again.</p>
               <p>Council. Aye, if the cunning Man spoke Truth.</p>
               <p>Fry. I believe he might say that the cunning Man told him so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person39">
                  Edward 
                  Rustel 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person39" type="surname" value="Rustel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person39" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday Night about a Fortnight before the Money was found in the Prisoner's House -</p>
               <p>Council. What Money? The 500 Guineas that Gibson had lost?</p>
               <p>Rustel. I cannot say as to that, but being in the Saracen's Head Inn Yard, I heard Gibson say to the Prisoner, Don't ruin me quite, let me have but half, or if that is too much, send me but 100 Guineas in a Box by any Messenger, and I'll take it without asking any Questions. The Prisoner answered, If you expect to have your Money again, you ought not to speak of it in a publick Yard but in a private Room. Then Gibson went away; the Prisoner said to me, I had rather quarrel with a Man of 100 a Year, than with my Master, because I have served him so long.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person40">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person40" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person40" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner's Wife lodges up one Pair of Stairs, and I lodge up two Pair in the same House. Between Christmas Day and New Year's Day, as I was going down for a Pail of Water, she call'd me into her Room, and said she'd shew me something to grease my Eyes with. So she went into a Closer, and took out a great Bag of Money and pour'd it into her Lap. She said there was about 300 Pound. It was all<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173505220004"></xptr> Gold, and she gave some of it to her Child to play with. I asked her whose it was? She said it was a Merchants, and her Husband was to pay it all away for him in a little time. I am glad of that, says I, for I have got a Pad-lock on my Door, and therefore if any Rogues should hear of so much Money in the House, they'll think its in my Room, and so I may be knock'd on the Head. My Husband coming home to Dinner, Edad she calls him in and shews him this Gold; but he loves to have me keep at home, and so says he, What a-pox do ye do out of your own Room? I went out a Nursing, and when I came home again the Prisoner's Wife said to me Ah, pox o' your Pad-lock! the Money's all gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person41">
                  Osborn 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person41" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person41" type="given" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came home to Tinner ant wass coing into my own Room, put the Prissoner's Wife callt to me and sait Here iss your coot Oman. So I hust her a pit, and ask her why a Tiffel she coudn't keep in her own Hapitation when I wanted my Tinner. So the Prissoners Wife prought out a pag with a crate teal of coolt in it. There was a crate many Pieces, a crate teal pigger as Guineas.</p>
               <p>Council. This could not be the Money that Gibson lost, for that was all in Guineas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person42">
                  Osborn 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person42" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person42" type="given" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Ant she pickt out fourteen or fifteen of them crate Pieces, and kafe 'em to the Chilt to truntle apout the Room. Where a Cots Name, says I, did you ket all this Money? O says she, It is none of ours, put my Uspant is to pay it away for a Merchant.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350522-1-person43">
                  Charles 
                  Airs 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person43" type="surname" value="Airs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person43" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I help'd to unload the Waggon. 
               <persName id="t17350522-1-person44">
                  Stephen 
                  Leach 
               <interp inst="t17350522-1-person44" type="surname" value="Leach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person44" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I open'd the Pack. I took out the Leather Bags which lay at the bottom, and said, I thought they were Boots; No says Leach, They are Saddle Bags. I gave them to Goddard, who gave them to the Prisoner, who search'd them, but found nothing in them but a Wad of Straw. They were not fastned at top, and at each end of each Bag there was a Hole big enough to thrust ones Fist in.</p>
               <p>This was confirm'd by Stephen Leach.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner had a very good Character given him and the Jury <rs id="t17350522-1-verdict7" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350522-1-verdict7" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
