<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-4">
               <interp inst="t17341204-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-4" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-4" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-4-off19-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-defend43 t17341204-4-off19 t17341204-4-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>4 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-4-defend43" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-4-defend43" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-defend43" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17341204-4-defloc18">St. Mary le Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-4-defloc18" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-4-defloc18" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-defend43 t17341204-4-defloc18"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17341204-4-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Murder of 
                     <persName id="t17341204-4-victim44" type="victimName">
                        Richard 
                        Row 
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-victim44" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-4-victim44" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-4-victim44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-off19 t17341204-4-victim44"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , by wilfully and maliciously discharging a Musket loaded with Gunpowder and a Bullet; and thereby with the said Bullet giving him one mortal Wound in the Breast of the length of one Inch, and depth of Ten Inches, of which mortal Wound he instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17341204-4-cd20" type="crimeDate">Nov. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-off19 t17341204-4-cd20"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-4-person45">
                  William 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17341204-4-person45" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person45" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of November at Six in the Evening, the Prisoner was set Sentinel, at the Chappel Door, at <placeName id="t17341204-4-crimeloc21">Somerset House</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-4-crimeloc21" type="placeName" value="Somerset House"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-4-crimeloc21" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-off19 t17341204-4-crimeloc21"></join>. Hearing that he had committed some outrageous Facts upon his Post, I went down to take him. But he said to me, Damn ye keep off, or I'll be your Butcher. As I knew him to be a mischievous Fellow I proceeded no farther. At ten a Clock the same night the Deceased 
               <persName id="t17341204-4-person46">
                  Richard 
                  Rowe 
               <interp inst="t17341204-4-person46" type="surname" value="Rowe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person46" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was <rs id="t17341204-4-viclabel22" type="occupation">Corporal</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-victim44 t17341204-4-viclabel22"></join>, brought a Regular Relief. The Prisoner said, who is there? The Deceas'd answered, Relief. The Prisoner said, Damn ye stand off, or I'll shoot ye. Presently after which I heard the Piece go off, and the Deceas'd fell down dead. Then the Prisoner clubbed his Firelock, and struck at these Men. I kick'd up his Heels, and put him in Irons - He was alone on his Post till the Deceased came to relieve him - Here's the Deceased's Wastcoat - Here the Bullet went in, at the third Button-hole on the Breast - And here it came out at the the right Shoulder.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am not guilty of what I have done - As to loading my Piece at 10 o'Clock, it was by a particular Order - Who came for Relief? Did you bring 7 Men or 3?</p>
               <p>Bird. Three; the Deceased, and these two, Henry Thomas, and Richard Godson.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What did I say to the Corporal?</p>
               <p>Bird. You said, Pass your Relief.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did so, and then they crowded in upon me, and in strugling my Piece went off -</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-4-person47">
                  Richard 
                  Godson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-4-person47" type="surname" value="Godson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person47" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When we came to relieve the Prisoner, he asked Who comes there? The Corporal answered Relief. Gentlemen, God damn ye, says the Prisoner, stand off! for the first Man that comes to oppose me, I'll shoot thro' the Body. The Corporal bid us advance, and we went under the Piazza's. The Prisoner turned towards him, and said, Row, stand off! or you're a dead Man. And then his Piece went off: And the Deceased (who was at that time about the Distance of two Firelocks from the Prisoner) went with a wheel this way, and fell on his Side. The Bullet enter'd at his Breast, and came out at his Shoulder, and he died on the Spot. The Prisoner club'd his Firelock, struck at me, and wounded me in the Head.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Are you sure of all this, honest Man?</p>
               <p>Godson. Yes, and with your club'd Fire-lock, you went to knock my Comrade down too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-4-person48">
                  Henry 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17341204-4-person48" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person48" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , When we went to relieve the Prisoner, he said, Who comes there? The Deceas'd, answered, Relief. God damn ye, says the Prisoner, stand off with your Relief - or Row, you're a dead Man. The Deceas'd bid me recover my Piece, and relieve him; when immediately I saw the Prisoner present<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040004"></xptr> his Piece, and heard it go off, and the Deceased fell down dead.</p>
               <p>Then the Prisoner clubb'd his Piece and struck at me thrice, and at the third Blow he broke the Stock of my Firelock; and, had it not been for that, I believe the Blow had killed me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You are sure of all this? Was you under the Piazza?</p>
               <p>Thomas. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I desire the Corporal to let me bide in my Place?</p>
               <p> 
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-4-person49">
                  Thomas 
                  Adcock 
               <interp inst="t17341204-4-person49" type="surname" value="Adcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person49" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Sentry under the Gate-way: The Relief came at Ten o'Clock. The Prisoner asked who went there, and was answered, Relief. Pass the Relief, says he, and then they went under the Piazzas. The Prisoner bid the Deceased stand off, and threatned to fire if he did not. The Deceased bid the Men rest their Firelocks, and then bid them recover their Pieces and relieve him, when presently I heard the Piece go off.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was not done with any Design; but went off while they struggled with me. I had no Malice against the Corporal.</p>
               <p>The Jury found him <rs id="t17341204-4-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17341204-4-punish24" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-4-punish24" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-4-defend43 t17341204-4-punish24"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
