<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17390607-40">
               <interp inst="t17390607-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-40" type="year" value="1739"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17390607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17390607-40" type="date" value="17390607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17390607-40-off189-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-40-defend298 t17390607-40-off189 t17390607-40-verdict192"></join>
         
               <p>377. 
               
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-defend298" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Goodman 
                  <interp inst="t17390607-40-defend298" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-defend298" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-defend298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17390607-40-off189" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-off189" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-off189" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt Perjury in his Evidence against 
                     <persName id="t17390607-40-victim299" type="victimName">
                        Brogdon 
                        Poplet 
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-victim299" type="surname" value="Poplet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-40-victim299" type="given" value="Brogdon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17390607-40-victim299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-40-off189 t17390607-40-victim299"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in February Sessions, at the <placeName id="t17390607-40-crimeloc190">Old Baily</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-crimeloc190" type="placeName" value="Old Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-crimeloc190" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-40-off189 t17390607-40-crimeloc190"></join>.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution having open'd the Charge, and the Nature of the Offence, the Copy of the Record of Mr. Poplet's Acquittal was produced, and read.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person300">
                  William 
                  Keat 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person300" type="surname" value="Keat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person300" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at Poplet's Trial, and remember Goodman's being in Court. I saw him sworn in the usual Manner. The Indictment against Poplet, was for privately taking from him 13 s. 6 d. He swore, That as he was going on the 9th of February, in a Coach from Newgate to the Judges Chambers in Chancery Lane, the Person that sat against him in the Coach, stopped his Mouth, near the Market, and that Brogdon Poplet took from him 13 s. 6 d. by Force. There was a Question subsequent to this; he was asked, - of what particular Pieces the 13 s. 6 d. consisted Goodman answered, - two Half Crown, eight Shillings, and a Six-pence. He was then asked, how lately he had seen that Money? He answered, - about a Quarter of an Hour before. He was asked, in what Manner the Money was taken from him? He made answer, - that Poplet put his Hands into his Breeches Pocket, and took the Money from him by Force. He said, he had been robbed and beat by Poplet. These are the Words which were sworn upon that Trial.</p>
               <p>Counc. You have given a long Evidence; - did you put the Words down in Writing?</p>
               <p>Mr. Keat. Not at that Instant. I did not take them down in Writing at that Time but after the Trial was over, we went to a Tavern (The Baptist's Head) in the Neighbourhood, and staid there two or three Hours, and had some Refreshment.</p>
               <p>Counc. Then you took down the very Words you have repeated at the Tavern.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kents. I did; and have the Paper now at home, among my other Papers; I saw it within these three or four Days.</p>
               <p>Counc. How many Hours did the Trial last?</p>
               <p>Mr. Kent. Not above half an Hour. Mr. Poplet said at the Tavern, he had been grievously injured and would indict him for Perjury: And the Pen and Ink was called for, in about a Quarter of an Hour after we went in, and I wrote down the Evidence, and reduced them into an Indictment the next Day.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not Poplet move for a Copy of his Indictment when the Trial was over?</p>
               <p>Mr. Keat. He was was going to speak something to that Effect, but was told, that Goodman was a Prisoner, and it would be of no Service to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070018"></xptr>Counc. When the Order was obtained from the Attorney General that you should have a Copy, did any one attend on Goodman's Behalf, to shew cause to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Mr. Keat. No, no body at all. Goodman has since owned to me, that he did swear he was going in a Coach from Newgate, to Chancery Lane, and lost 13 s. 6 d. in the Coach.</p>
               <p>Mr. Poplet offering to be sworn, the Councel for the Defendant objected to his giving Evidence, but the Objections were not allowed.</p>
               <p>Poplet. I am an <rs id="t17390607-40-viclabel191" type="occupation">Officer to the Sheriff of Middlesex.</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17390607-40-victim299 t17390607-40-viclabel191"></join> In February last, three Countrymen came to my House and enquired after Goodman, telling me they wanted to arrest him for five or six Horses, he had brought from Northamptonshire, and had not paid for them. I bid them get Processes according to Law, and I would endeavour to take him. Accordingly on the 5th of February I saw him go into a Tavern, and a Woman followed him; I arrested him, and the Son was with him and another Man; there was 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person301">
                  Edward 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person301" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person301" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person302">
                  Thomas 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person302" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person302" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person303">
                  Phillip 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person303" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person303" type="given" value="Phillip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had five Warrants against him, and he had been sheltered in the Globe-Tavern, in Drury Lane, over-against my House for a Month, and when I endeavoured to take him, they opposed me with Sticks, and broke my Head; but I over-powered him, and got him to my House. Then I asked him if he would go into another Officer's House, for 24 Hours? He said, G - d d - mn you, you Rogue, I will hang you. This is one of the Warrants I had against him, but that, by vertue of which I carry'd him to Newgate, I have not about me. I told him he was a silly Man, and that I never had done any Thing to deserve Hanging in my Life, and asked him again, if he would go to another Officer's House? He said, he was protected by 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person304">
                  Baron 
                  Bothmar 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person304" type="surname" value="Bothmar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person304" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and would go to Newgate, so I carry'd him there; and Mr. Hopkins afterward writing to me, to get the Return of a Habeas Corpus, in order to carry him to the Fleet, I bid Murphey get a Coach, and he and I took Goodman into the Coach, to carry him to the Judges Chambers. As we went along, he wanted to go to Fleet-Lane, and put his Head out of the Coach, and call'd out, Bailiffs! Bailiffs! - take me away: There was only Brogdon Poplet, ( himself) 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person305">
                  James 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person305" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person305" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Goodman in the Coach. He was never insulted; no one touch'd his Mouth, nor a Farthing of his Money: He did receive a Blow on the Side of his Head, by a Jolt of the Coach, when he was straining to get out of the Coach-window; he never complain'd; - when we came out of the Coach, there were the two Tip-staves, and we went to the Judges Chambers, and the Clerk indorsed the Habeas, yet he did not complain, as I heard.</p>
               <p>Counc. Here, - Poplet, - you swear he was never insulted, &amp;c. on your Oath when he came to the Chambers, was not he very bloody?</p>
               <p>Poplet. No Marks of Violence, - there was a Blow on the Side of his Head, by the Jolt of the Coach. If there was any Complaint made it was whisper'd among themselves.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-person306">
                  James 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person306" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person306" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Poplet's Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-person307">
                  Benjamin 
                  Boxall 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person307" type="surname" value="Boxall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person307" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, he saw Goodman and his Son knocking down Poplet at the Globe Tavern in Drury Lane, but Poplet being too strong for them, carry'd him to his House, and ask'd him if he would go to any other Officer's House? That Goodman call'd him Names, and said he would hang him, and Goodman told him he would go to Newgate, for he had a Protection, and should then be near home, - the Hartshorn Inn, in Smithfield, where (he said) he lodged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-person308">
                  Lawrence 
                  Sherwood 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person308" type="surname" value="Sherwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person308" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore, he had heard Goodman complain of having been evilly treated by Poplet, but at that Time he did not say he had been robb'd. That about two Days afterwards he saw him again, where he had seen him before, (at Mr. Jones's in Fleet-Lane ) and then he complain'd that Poplet had indicted him in the Crown, but he did not say any Thing of the Robbery, nor did he hear him say any Thing about it, till the Night before the Bill was found against Poplet. The Witness said, he had heard it whisper'd by others, that Goodman had told Jones he had been robb'd; upon which he asked Goodman what he had lost, and he told him, - there were two others in the Coach with him; and they stopp'd a Handkerchief in his Mouth, and took from him two Half crowns, and 3 s. and 6 d. and this the Witness said, he penn'd down, - in his Mind, and advis'd him to indict Poplet by his Name, for robbing him with two other Persons unknown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-person309">
                  John 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person309" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account that Goodman complain'd to him, that Poplet and two others with him robb'd him in the Coach of three Guineas.</p>
               <p>Goodman's Council after having open'd the Evidence in his Defence call'd.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person310">
                  John 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person310" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; ( Tipstaff ) depos'd, that he was call'd out of the Coffee-house to carry Goodman to the Judges Chambers, but Goodman would not come out of the Coach, for (he said) they were going to rob and murder him: That he was bloody, and complain'd in the Chambers that he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173906070019"></xptr> was choak'd with Blood, and wanted something to drink, but he did not hear him say any thing about Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17390607-40-person311">
                  Francis 
                  Harling 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person311" type="surname" value="Harling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person311" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sent for, to come to Goodman the next Day: He found he had been much abused; his Head broke, and his Stomach black and blue. Goodman then told him, he had been abused by Bailiffs, and had been robb'd of 13 s. and 6 d.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hopkins depos'd he came to Jones's to take Bond for Goodman, and he complain'd he had been robb'd of 13 s. and 6 d. by Poplet, and appear'd to have been very ill used.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gumley depos'd, that he saw Goodman that Night, and he complained he had been robb'd of 13 s. 6 d. by Poplet and two others, and had been abused by them in the Coach. This Witness, and Mr. Yewen, 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person312">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person312" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17390607-40-person313">
                  William 
                  Selwood 
               <interp inst="t17390607-40-person313" type="surname" value="Selwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person313" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner a good Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lane saw him the Night he was committed to the Fleet, and deposed, That he complained of having been very much beaten by Poplet, and that he had been robbed by him of 13 s. 6 d. This Witness said, the Man was really in a very bad Condition. <rs id="t17390607-40-verdict192" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17390607-40-verdict192" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
