<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-5">
               <interp inst="t17370706-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-5" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-5" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-5-off22-c44" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend55 t17370706-5-off22 t17370706-5-verdict25"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-5-off22-c45" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend57 t17370706-5-off22 t17370706-5-verdict25"></join>
         
               <p>5, 6. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-5-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                      Gosswell , otherwise <rs id="t17370706-5-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend55 t17370706-5-alias-2"></join>Bob the Butcher</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend55" type="surname" value="Gosswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend55" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-5-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                      Barrow , otherwise <rs id="t17370706-5-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend57 t17370706-5-alias-3"></join>Run well</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend57" type="surname" value="Barrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend57" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-defend57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370706-5-defloc21">St. George's Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-5-defloc21" type="placeName" value="St. George's Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-5-defloc21" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend55 t17370706-5-defloc21"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend57 t17370706-5-defloc21"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-5-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-5-victim59" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Christian 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-5-victim59" type="surname" value="Christian"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-5-victim59" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-5-victim59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-off22 t17370706-5-victim59"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain open Place, near<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060004"></xptr> the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him an iron Key, value 1 d. a silk Purse value 6 d. five brass Medals, value 1 d. one Guinea, and six Shillings and Two-pence in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370706-5-cd23" type="crimeDate">April 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-off22 t17370706-5-cd23"></join>.</p>
               <p>James Christian. Last Easter-Eve, between 12 and 1 o'Clock at Night, I was coming thro' <placeName id="t17370706-5-crimeloc24">Bloomsbury square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-5-crimeloc24" type="placeName" value="Bloomsbury square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-5-crimeloc24" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-off22 t17370706-5-crimeloc24"></join>, and three Men came up to me; one of them clapp'd a Pistol to my Breast, and the others demanded my Money, or (they told me) I was a dead Man. I was surprized, and said, - Gentlemen, don't use me ill, - you shall have my Money, - don't use me ill. One of them said, - No, - God forbid we should use you ill, - 'tis Necessity makes us do this, and he immediately put his Hand into my Pocket, and took out a Guinea, some brass Medals, and about six or seven Shillings in Silver. I don't know any of the Prisoners; but I believe the Man that took the Money out of my Pocket, is this Man here, who has made himself an Evidence. He look'd in my Face after he had done, - but I can't swear to him.</p>
               <p>One of the Prisoners. The Evidence, in his Information, said, there were three Queen Carolina's, and three King George's Medals; ask the Prosecutor what Sort of Medals he lost.</p>
               <p>Christian. They were Queen Carolina's and King George's Medals; such Things as the Children play with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-5-person60">
                  James 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17370706-5-person60" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-person60" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 'Twas Easter-Eve, or rather Easter-Sunday Morning, between 12 and 1 o'Clock, when we committed this Fact. The Prisoner Runwell held the Pistol to the Gentleman, and Goswell came up and pull'd of his Hat to him, and told him, he must rifle him.</p>
               <p>Q. What was taken from the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Wilson. One Guinea, and six Shillings and Two-pence: The Two-pence we spent in Gin, and the Guinea we divided between Runwell and myself: Gosswell had only his Part of the six Shillings, and Part of the Two penn' worth of Gin, - we had a whole half Pint for the Two-pence. Runwell and I had 12 s. 6 d. a piece, that is, - two Shillings out of the six, and half a Guinea a piece out of the Guinea; for we sunk upon Gosswell, he did not know that we got the Guinea. When we took the Medals from the Gentleman, we thought they had been Guineas, and we went to an Alehouse, in Well-street, near Salt-Petre Bank, to see whether they were Guineas or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you all go out on this Design together?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Runwell and I agreed to go out upon this Affair together, and as we were going along, we met Gosswell, and he agreed to go with us: So we all three went together, and meeting the Prosecutor, - There's your Mark, says I, and immediately Runwell clapp'd his Pistol to his Breast, but there was neither Powder nor Ball in it.</p>
               <p>Gosswell. This Man has been an Evidence before: he was three Days together at the Thief-taker's House. They took me several Times to an Alehouse, and would have persuaded me to have been an Evidence against Wilson, and as we had no Money, they lent me a Shilling, and Wilson a Shilling. I told them that I never saw the Evidence 'till I came from Hampstead Races, and that I knew nothing of him. 
               <persName id="t17370706-5-person61">
                  William 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17370706-5-person61" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-person61" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Brock, would have given me Money to have done it, but I knew no more of the Evidence than the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>Runwell. The Evidence and I fell out at a House where we went to drink, and the young Man that was with him, asked me to go out with them, but I refused, and went Home, upon which the Evidence came to the Place where I live, in Well-Street, and fir'd off his Pistol before the Door.</p>
               <p>Mr. Justice Poulson. He came before me, and made himself a voluntary Evidence, and the Account he now gives, is intirely consistent with that he gave before me. Both <rs id="t17370706-5-verdict25" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-verdict25" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370706-5-punish26" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-5-punish26" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend55 t17370706-5-punish26"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-5-defend57 t17370706-5-punish26"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
