<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-10">
               <interp inst="t17370706-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-10" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-10" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-10-off53-c84" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-defend107 t17370706-10-off53 t17370706-10-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>11. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-defend107" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Bailey 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-10-defend107" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-defend107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-defend107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of the <placeName id="t17370706-10-defloc52">Tower of London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-10-defloc52" type="placeName" value="Tower of London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-10-defloc52" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-defend107 t17370706-10-defloc52"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-10-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370706-10-victim109" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Burton 
                        <interp inst="t17370706-10-victim109" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-10-victim109" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370706-10-victim109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-off53 t17370706-10-victim109"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , with a drawn Sword made of Iron and Steel, which he held in his right Hand, and giving him the said Burton on the right Part of the Belly under the right Ribs, a mortal Wound of the Breadth of half an Inch, and the Depth of 6 Inches, <rs id="t17370706-10-cd54" type="crimeDate">June 20</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-off53 t17370706-10-cd54"></join>, by Reason of which, he languished, and languishingly lived, from the said 20th to the 21st of the said Month and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person110">
                  John 
                  Waterman 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person110" type="surname" value="Waterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Night this happen'd I was in Bed in the Barracks, and after the Tattoo was gone by, the Deceased as Serjeant of the Night, came in his Office, to call over the Rolls, in order to see who was absent. When he came to one Darby's Bed, he found him missing, and said he would return him. The Prisoner told the Deceased he should not return him; the Deceased said he would: the Prisoner said he would lay him a Shilling he dar'd not return him; the Deceased replied, G - d sink me if I don't: the Prisoner repeated - that he dar'd not; the Deceased d - mned his own Blood if he did not return him just then, and he immediately laid down his Paper and began to write, in order to return Darby. When he had done it, he commanded the Prisoner to go to Bed; he told him he would not; upon this the Deceased blew the Candle out, and went into the next Barrack to call over his Roll there. Then he returned with a Candle into this Barrack again, and went to Bed, having first put out the Candle. The Prisoner lay in a little Apartment that is enclosed, and taken out of the Barracks for the Use of the Colonel, and the Deceased lay in a Bed that joined close to it. After the Deceased was in Bed, the Prisoner told him he wou'd do for him next Morning; and the Deceased said he did not value him, he could do well enough for himself. Then the Prisoner call'd him a Black-guard, scrubby Fellow, and the other told the Prisoner he was a saucy, ragged, Country Fellow, and came up to the Army without a Shirt on his Back; upon which the Prisoner called the Deceased a Blackguard scandalous Rascal; the Deceased then said, - if you call me so again I'll get up and pull down your Barrack Door and lick you. The Prisoner called him the same Names again and again directly; so the Deceased jumped out of Bed, and went into the next Barrack to fetch a Candle, and he came with it immediately to the Prisoner's Door, and taking hold on the Top he gave it a Shake. Whether he pulled it open, or whether the Prisoner open'd it himself I cannot tell, but the Prisoner had his Hand on the upper Bar of the Door; when the Door open'd, I saw both their Hands on it, and it had not open'd above 18 Inches before the Prisoner gave his Sword (which was drawn in his Hand) a Twirl round, and presented it into the other's Body, thro' the right Part of his Belly. I can say nothing farther, the other Witnesses will give a better Account of it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I tell the Deceased that Darby had thrown up his Pay?</p>
               <p>Waterman. Yes, and you told him he had Leave to be absent.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I told the Deceased I would not go to Bed, did not he strike me over the Face, and beat the Pipe out of my Mouth?</p>
               <p>Waterman. No, the Deceased was not within 5 Yards of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I go to Bed before the Deceased, and make my Door fast?</p>
               <p>Waterman. He went into his Room, but whether he went into Bed, or fasten'd the Door, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Deceased attempt to force open the Door?</p>
               <p>Waterman. He took Hold on the Top of the Door and shook it: I think if he had pulled the Door, with half his Strength he might have broken it to Pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Apartment separated from the rest of the Barracks.</p>
               <p>Waterman. Yes, it was divided from them by a Partition of Boards. 'Tis a little Place about 9 Feet long, - or not so much, and 7 Foot over: the Prisoner's Bed was in this Place. The Colonel puts his Goods in it, and the Prisoner has lain in it ever since I have been in the Company, and I commenced the 6th of May last. I'm but a young Soldier.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you remember what Corporal 
               <persName id="t17370706-10-person111">
                  Lindsey
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person111" type="given" value="Lindsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person111" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said upon this Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Waterman. No, I do not. I know he was never out of his Bed 'till the Deceased was kill'd.</p>
               <p>Counc. Has the Prisoner any particular Service under the Colonel, distinct from that of a Soldier?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060011"></xptr>Waterman. He was <rs id="t17370706-10-deflabel55" type="occupation">Paymaster Serjeant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-defend107 t17370706-10-deflabel55"></join>: there's one Paymaster Serjeant in each Company, and he pays the Company he belongs to. The Prisoner and the Deceased were both <rs id="t17370706-10-viclabel56" type="occupation">Serjeant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-victim109 t17370706-10-viclabel56"></join>s.</p>
               <p>Counc. Had one a Command over the other?</p>
               <p>Waterman. The Deceased in his Office had the Command over the other, and over every one that belonged to that Company.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the Deceased any Weapon in his Hand, when he came to the Door?</p>
               <p>Waterman. No, nothing but the Candle and Candlestick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person112">
                  Anthony 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person112" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person112" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday Night, the 20th of June, the Deceased came into the Barrack I belonged to, and fetched away the Candle in a Hurry; he was naked, and without Shooes or Stockings. I follow'd him into the other Barrack, and saw him clap his Hand on the Top of the Prisoner's Door, I cannot be positive whether he or the Prisoner open'd it; but the Door open'd and I saw a Hand and a Sword come out (before the Door was full open) with a full Push, and the Deceased was thrust into the right Side of the Body. I can't say I saw any more of the Prisoner than his Hand.</p>
               <p>C. What was the Consequence of that Push?</p>
               <p>Sharp. The Deceased clapp'd his Hands here (on his Belly) and immediately stagger'd. He died the next Day between 12 and 1 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see my Hand on the Door?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I can't tell that I did.</p>
               <p>Counc. How far from the Door was the Deceased when he received the Wound?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I believe he might be half a Yard from the Door.</p>
               <p>Councel. Had the Deceased any Command, or Power over his Brother Serjeant?</p>
               <p>Sharp. Yes, he had: He was to see us all in Bed, and that all the Candles were put out.</p>
               <p>Councel. Had he Power to command the Prisoner to open the Door?</p>
               <p>Sharp. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Councel. Supposing the Prisoner had insulted the Deceased, or had given him provoking Language, had he Power to correct him with Blows?</p>
               <p>Sharp. He had Power to take him Prisoner, according to Military Law, and to have sent him to the main Guard.</p>
               <p>Q. If the Prisoner had had a Candle there, had the Deceased a Power to have gone there to have searched?</p>
               <p>Sharp. He is authorised and obliged to put out all the Lights, after the Tattoo has gone about.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had I a Candle in my Room?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Waterman. I believe there was no other Candle, than that which the Deceased had in his Hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person113">
                  Richard 
                  Toombes 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person113" type="surname" value="Toombes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person113" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased and I had been out that Afternoon, drinking at a Friend's House: We came in about 10 o'Clock, and he did his Business and call'd over the Roll One Darby was absent, and the Prisoner said, he had leave to be absent. The Deceased said, he would return him, and the Quarrel began, as the first Witness has mention'd. After many Words, the Deceased put the Candle out, and went to call over the Roll in the other Barrack: When he had done, he returned to his own Barrack, and undrest himself and went to Bed. The Prisoner in his Room, still abused him, and the Deceased said, he would get up and lick him for abusing him: And accordingly, our Candle being out, he got up and fetch'd one from the next Barrack, and coming to the Prisoner's Door, he took hold of it and shook it; the Door was open'd, I know not how, nor by who; but when 'twas about a Foot and a half open, the Prisoner thrust out his Hand, with his drawn Sword, and stabb'd him immediately. As soon as he had done it, he shut the Door again, and fasten'd it in half a Minute's Time. 'Twas fasten'd on the Inside, for Corporal Thomas was forced to fix a Bayonet on a Piece and break the Door open to take the Prisoner</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not see the Deceased strike me, and break my Pipe, before I went to Bed?</p>
               <p>Toombes No; there was no Pipe broke, nor any Blow struck on either Side. The Push with the Sword was all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I was taken, that Man went dancing and singing all the Way before me, and said, he had an Opportunity now to be revenged: And he would swear his Soul to the Devil but I should be hanged.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever express'd any Ill-will to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Toombes. I never used any such Expressions, nor have I any Ill-will to the Man. I borrow'd Money of him but two Days before, and have often drank with him; the whole Company knows it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any Words pass between the Prisoner and the Deceased at the Door, before it was open'd?</p>
               <p>Toombes. I heard none.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person114">
                  Christopher 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person114" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person114" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Deceased was in Bed, many Words passed: The Prisoner call'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060012"></xptr> the other Black-guard, Scoundrel and Rascal. The Deceased said, don't call me so, if you do, I will get up and lick you. You dare not, says the Prisoner, I have got something will keep you from it The Prisoner was then in his Apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoner said he had something would keep him from it?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes; I am sure of that. Then the Deceased ran to the other Barrack, and fetch'd a Candle. He shook the Door, and it open'd; but I cannot say which of them open'd it. Then the Prisoner gave a Push with his Sword, under his own left Arm (for his left Hand was upon the Door;) no sooner was the Sword pushed out, but the Door was made fast, and the Corporal was forced to break it open to take him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not see the Deceased break my Pipe?</p>
               <p>Smith. No: I saw that Corporal that stands there, break his Pipe.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the Door open'd was it, that the Push was given?</p>
               <p>Smith. The Push was given and the Door was fasten'd again, in less than a Minute. 'Twas given immediately, and immediately the Door was shut, and made fast on the Inside.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there Time after the Opening of the Door, for the Prisoner to draw his Sword?</p>
               <p>Smith. No: There was no Time to draw his Sword, it must have been drawn before the Door was open'd.</p>
               <p>Councel. What is the Prisoner's general Character?</p>
               <p>Smith. Since I have known the Company, he has not had an extraordinary Character. He very frequently disturbed the Barracks in the Night.</p>
               <p>Councel. Who do you speak of; the Prisoner or the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Smith. The Prisoner there at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ellis, Surgeon. The Day after the Deceased dy'd, I examined the Body. I found the Instrument had penetrated the right Side of the Belly obliquely thro' the Back. The Wound was downwards, and went quite thro' the Back, and to be sure was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person115">
                  John 
                  Urqubart 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person115" type="surname" value="Urqubart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Quarrel began as hath been related, and after many abusive Speeches, the Prisoner and the Deceased went to their Beds. After they were both in Bed, the Prisoner aggravated the Deceased, and call'd him old rascally Scoundrel, and the Deceased said, if he abused him so, he would get up and lick him. The Prisoner continuing to abuse him, he got up, and went to the other Barrack for a Candle, and when he came back with the Candle, he pull'd once or twice at the Prisoner's Door, and it open'd; but who open'd it I cannot tell. Immediately upon the Opening the Door, I saw his Hand push the Sword into the Deceased's Body, he stagger'd and clapp'd his Hands upon his Belly. I was partly behind the Door, so I could not see whether the Prisoner had his Hand upon the Door, or not. I saw no Blows before this, nor did I see the Pipe struck out of the Prisoner's Mouth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person116">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person116" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person116" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Corporal. I was in the other Barrack when the Deceased came to fetch the Candle. I got up and went after him, and when I got into his Barrack, I saw him stooping as if he was wounded. I was very much flustrated (or very much surprized) so I ran to a Rack, and took down a Piece, and (I believe) I broke open the Door and took him the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the Prisoner lodged there?</p>
               <p>Thomas. We have been eight Months at the Tower, and he has lain there all the Time. I think he purchased it. 'Tis a particular Bed; enclosed with a Partition: The Bed belongs to the King, or the Barrack Master.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the Serjeant that is in Office for the Night, any Right, for the Sake of preserving Good Order, to go into that Place?</p>
               <p>Thomas. Whether he has any Right to go in there, I don't know, - any farther than to see that all the Candles are out, and every Body in Bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Could not the Deceased have seen whether my Candle was out, without coming into my Barrack?</p>
               <p>Thomas. Yes; 'tis but a poor slight Enclosure of slit Deal. If there's any Light in it, those on the Outside may see it; and if there's Light without, the Person within may see that too. There was no Candle in his Apartment, when I took him Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. If there had been a Light in this Place, had the Officer of the Night any Right to have forced the Door open?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I don't know. But if any Abuse is given, the Officer has a Power to take the Person that is Guilty of the Offence, and carry him Prisoner to the Main-guard.</p>
               <p>Q. Might he have enter'd, and have taken him from thence, in Order to have carry'd him to the Main-guard?</p>
               <p>Thomas. Yes: He was under the Command of the Serjeant for Night, in that Place, as much as if he had been in a common Barrack.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060013"></xptr>Counc. Had he, as Superiour of the Night, any Power to go in and strike him?</p>
               <p>Thomas. There's no such Thing as striking, in the Military Way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I ask if there was not a large Quantity of Powder there?</p>
               <p>Thomas. There is some Powder there to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Who keeps the Key of this Place?</p>
               <p>Thomas. He padlocks it himself on the Outside when he goes out. The Serjeant that has the Care of the Company, keeps the Things that are for the Use of the Company; and the Prisoner kept the Company's Linnen there, and the Colonel's Things.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether there's any Fastening on the Inside?</p>
               <p>Thomas. There's a Kind of a Nail and a String on the Inside.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did not the Prisoner buy this Apartment?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I don't know whether he or the Colonel paid for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person117">
                  Daniel 
                  Vandervoren 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person117" type="surname" value="Vandervoren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person117" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Serjeant. I was not there when this happen'd: But I know the Apartment where the Prisoner lay.</p>
               <p>Q. If any Person that lies in that Place, occasions a Disturbance, or abuses the Serjeant that commands for the Night, may he open that Place to correct or apprehend the Person that offends?</p>
               <p>Vandervoren. No; I think not. I know, the Serjeant that commands has Power to quiet any Man; he is empower'd to take him Prisoner, and carry him to the Main-guard. Each Serjeant takes his Week, and we are to see every Man in their Barracks at such an Hour; he is to keep them in Peace and Quietness, and at such a Time, to take Care that all the Candles are out. By Virtue of this Power, if his Brother Serjeants, or Corporals disobey Orders, they are liable to be taken Prisoners, and Complaint is made to the superiour Officers, but they are not to give Correction themselves to any Serjeant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-10-person118">
                  Geo 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17370706-10-person118" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person118" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going thro' their Barrack when the Dispute began, and I saw the Deceased lift up his Hand and strike the Prisoner. He struck him with his Fist, somewhere over the Face, and I think I saw a Pipe fall, but I cannot say the Deceased struck it out of his Mouth. I have known the Deceased three Years, and never heard that he was given to Quarrelling.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you never hear of his Quarrelling with Serjeant Vanderooren?</p>
               <p>Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Lindsay. I can give but the same Account of the Quarrel as hath been already given; there was a great deal of ill Language given on both Sides, both before, and after the Deceased was in Bed, and the Prisoner had shut himself up in his Place. The Deceased lay with me, and I bid them both be quiet, or I would take a File of Men, and carry them both to the Guard. The Deceased said, he'd get up, and pull the Prisoner's House down, and send him to Hell. I know them both perfectly well, and have done so, 9 or 10 Years. In the Way of Strength or Handy-Cuffs, the Deceased, I believe, would have been too hard for the Prisoner, tho' he is a lusty Man. I could not prevail upon them to be quiet, but provoking Language still being given, the Deceased jumped out of Bed, and got a Candle from another Barrack, and came with it to the Prisoner's Door: He took hold with one Hand and shook it; then he sat down the Candle, and put both Hands to it, and shook it again: There was Room enough over the Door, for him to put his Hands in: As I was getting out of Bed to prevent the Dispute, the Door open'd, the Deceased fell back, and I caught him in my Arms, and laid him upon our Bed. He never quarrell'd with me, but he has quarrell'd with the Prisoner, and I have parted them several Times. The Prisoner always lay in that Apartment, and 'tis usual for him to fasten the Door on the Inside. I know he does, because I once wanted to speak with him when he was a Bed, and I shook the Door, but I could not get in, 'till he 'rose and opened it himself. The Deceased lov'd a Glass of Liquor, and in his Cups would sometimes be fractious.</p>
               <p>Q. Where there any Words between the Prisoner and the Deceased before the Door opened.</p>
               <p>Lindsay. Not a Word.</p>
               <p>Vandervoren. I was the Deceased's Comrade 10 Years. In Liquor he would sometimes be good humour'd, and sometimes quarrelsome. He never quarrell'd with any Body when he was sober. I know the Prisoner too, very well: I have seldom seen him in Liquor. We have all been Friends together, the Prisoner, the Deceased and I.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17370706-10-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> on both Indictments. <rs id="t17370706-10-punish58" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-10-punish58" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-10-defend107 t17370706-10-punish58"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
