<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17350911-88">
               <interp inst="t17350911-88" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-88" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-88" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17350911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17350911-88" type="date" value="17350911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17350911-88-off383-c418" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-88-defend612 t17350911-88-off383 t17350911-88-verdict386"></join>
         
               <p>108. 
               
                  <persName id="t17350911-88-defend612" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Dixon 
                  <interp inst="t17350911-88-defend612" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-defend612" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-defend612" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17350911-88-deflabel382" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-88-defend612 t17350911-88-deflabel382"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17350911-88-person613">
                  Andrew 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17350911-88-person613" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person613" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person613" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17350911-88-off383" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-off383" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-off383" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               Murder of her Male Infant, by throwing it into a House of Office, by which means it was suffocated
            </rs>, <rs id="t17350911-88-cd384" type="crimeDate">August 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-88-off383 t17350911-88-cd384"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-88-person614">
                  Jasper 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17350911-88-person614" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person614" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person614" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and her Husband lodged at my House in <placeName id="t17350911-88-crimeloc385">Queen Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-88-crimeloc385" type="placeName" value="Queen Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17350911-88-crimeloc385" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17350911-88-off383 t17350911-88-crimeloc385"></join> in April last. On Sunday the thirty first of August, at a Quarter past eight in the Morning, I went down to give my Cat some Victuals, but she flew down into the Cellar, and I followed her, and hearing a Noise in the Vault, I thought she was fallen in there, for I once had a Cat that met with such a mischance. I got a Candle, and looking down I saw something wabbling about, which I thought was the Cat. But my Wife coming down for some Coals, the Cat came and fondled about her, at which she screamed out and said, It is not the Cat in the Vault - I got a piece of an Iron Hoop, which I tyed to a String and put it down, and by moving it about I discovered part of a Child - We got Assistance, and broke up the Vault, put down a Ladder, and a Boy went down and brought up a Child alive; but it died at about five the same Day - I found a Stick in the Vault about seven or eight Foot long.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-88-person615">
                  Phebe 
                  Webster 
               <interp inst="t17350911-88-person615" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person615" type="given" value="Phebe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person615" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up to the Prisoner about nine o'Clock. She said the Child came from her on the Vault. I asked her how she could be so barbarous, and why she did not call for help. She answered, Because I was wicked.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-88-person616">
                  William 
                  Abbot 
               <interp inst="t17350911-88-person616" type="surname" value="Abbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person616" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person616" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up with the Prisoner's Husband, and he said to her, What a pretty piece of work you have brought upon your self and me; pray to the Lord for the life of the Child - She made no answer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was taken very ill in the Morning, and thought it had been the Gripes. I got up from my Husband and went down to the Vault, where my Senses went from me, and I did not recover my self, nor know what I did or said - I was under no Temptation of being so barbarous, for I had a good Husband who was able to maintain the Child; and I had at the same time one Child living of four Years old.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17350911-88-person617">
                  Phebe 
                  Webster 
               <interp inst="t17350911-88-person617" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person617" type="given" value="Phebe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-person617" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I first went up she lay upon the Bed and I helped her into bed, and it was two Hours afterwards that I asked her how she could be so barbarous: and she answered, because she was wicked - She indeed was very weak and faint as I thought.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Morgan. I spoke to her about nine o'Clock, she made no answer, she was seemingly very weak. But I cannot say whether she was out of her Senses or not.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bouffet. I went up first about nine o'Clock, when I spoke she made no answer, I drew the Curtains and I pulled her by the Arm, but could find no Sense in her; and so I called up the Midwife, and we thought she was dead.</p>
               <p>Phebe Webster. I have known Children come away perfectly involuntary and without any Assistance. And by what I observed at the Vault, I found she might have been delivered there. and I observed no sign in any other place.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17350911-88-verdict386" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17350911-88-verdict386" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
