<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370216-24">
               <interp inst="t17370216-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-24" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370216"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370216-24" type="date" value="17370216"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-24-off124-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-defend164 t17370216-24-off124 t17370216-24-verdict130"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370216-24-off127-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-defend168 t17370216-24-off127 t17370216-24-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>26, 27. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-defend164" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Goodman 
                  <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend164" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend164" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17370216-24-off124" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-off124" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-off124" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370216-24-victim166" type="victimName">
                           Maynard 
                           Gearing 
                        <interp inst="t17370216-24-victim166" type="surname" value="Gearing"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-24-victim166" type="given" value="Maynard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370216-24-victim166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17370216-24-viclabel125" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-victim166 t17370216-24-viclabel125"></join>; on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Gold Watch, value 13 l a Chrystal Seal set in Gold, value 13 s. 6 d. a Ruby Seal set in Gold, value 21 s. and twelve Guineas and a half in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17370216-24-cd126" type="crimeDate">Oct. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-off124 t17370216-24-cd126"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-off127 t17370216-24-cd126"></join>. And</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-defend168" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                      Sutton  otherwise <rs id="t17370216-24-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-defend168 t17370216-24-alias-3"></join>Goodman</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend168" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend168" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-defend168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , for <rs id="t17370216-24-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the Watch, knowing it to be stole.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Mr. Gearing. On Thursday the 28th of Oct. I was coming Home about half an Hour past 9, and on the East Side of <placeName id="t17370216-24-crimeloc128">Soho Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-24-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="Soho Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370216-24-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-off124 t17370216-24-crimeloc128"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-off127 t17370216-24-crimeloc128"></join>, I was stopped by two Fellows, one of them seized me by the Collar, and the other stood on my left Side, they bid me make no Noise but deliver. I had two Purses in my Pocket, one of them was given me the Day before, and I had a Value for it, they took that from me, but as they were going off, I called to one of them (whom I am informed was Bob the Glazier) to return it me again; he stopped to give it me; upon this his Companion, whom I take to be the Prisoner, cry'd; Damn him, - stab him, then they both run away. I pursued them a little Way, but finding it dark and dirty I gave over, flattering myself that my Watch was safe, but it was gone. I can't swear to the Prisoner's Face, but from the Size of the Man and his outward Appearance, I verily believe him to be the same. I never had any of my Goods again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-person169">
                  Margaret 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person169" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person169" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in James-street, Covent-Garden, at an Alehouse; I remember that the Prisoner and Bob the Glazier, was at the House that Night, and had no Money, but they went out and returned again about eleven o'Clock, and called for two Pots of Beer and Ale; I drank with them, and they asked me to pawn the Watch; I told them I did not know where to pawn it, so he and Bob the Glazier pawn'd it at one Bob Fields at Cow-Cross, and afterwards the two Prisoners redeemed it, and they both went over to Holland to dispose of it. Last Sunday I met the Prisoner Goodman in Short's-Garden, and he asked me to drink, telling me he could have lived like a Man in Holland, if he had not carried the Woman-Prisoner with him. He said he got fourteen Guineas for the Watch in Holland, and by his own Description of the Gentleman he took it from, I knew the Prosecutor to be the Person that was robbed, as soon as I saw him.</p>
               <p>Sam Goodman. I know nothing at all of the Matter, I don't upon my Word, my Lord, I know that 
               <persName id="t17370216-24-person170">
                  Margaret 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person170" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person170" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person170" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she is a common Whore, and lives in common Bawdy-houses. I happen'd, 'tis true, to be in Trouble with Sutton, who was cast here for his Life, and I was taken up with him before, and when he return'd from Transportation, I went to Holland. I intended to have gone Cooper's Mate in the Lethieulier an India Ship, but the Ship had got all it's Hands aboard.</p>
               <p>A Witness. (The Prisoner's Brother.) The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17370216-24-deflabel129" type="occupation">Cooper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370216-24-defend164 t17370216-24-deflabel129"></join> by Trade and worked with me. I deal in Cyder and Dorchester Beer; he kept Company with Sutton, and when Sutton returned from Transportation I got rid of him as fast as I could, and he got himself a Ship and went over to Holland, for as he was taken up for a Robbery with Sutton before, so now they take him up whenever they please.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-person171">
                  Samuel 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person171" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person171" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Woman that stands by me at the Bar, is my Wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-person172">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person172" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person172" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And she is 
               <persName id="t17370216-24-person173">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person173" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person173" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Wife too.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Brother. I deal for some Thousand Pounds a Year in Cyder and Dorchester Beer. I paid all this Money to the King this very Morning: - Please to look at these Papers.</p>
               <p>C. You may deal for a great deal of Money, and be never the honester at last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Goodman. I shall call some Persons to my good Character now.</p>
               <p>C. Aye! and perhaps they'll be such Persons as stand by you.</p>
               <p>A Woman. I have known him six or seven Years.</p>
               <p>C. And does he live with you, or do you live with him,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173702160011"></xptr> Witness. No, - I knew him when he worked at his Brother's, and he came of an honest Family.</p>
               <p>C. That may be, and he never the better.</p>
               <p>Witness. But he has been backward and forward in the House, and I have something of Value about me, yet he never wronged me.</p>
               <p>A Justice of the Peace. The Prisoner Goodman has been an Evidence in this very Court. I committed him with Beezly and Sutton; he was try'd with Sutton, when Sutton was convicted. I know him to be a very vile Fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370216-24-person174">
                  Margaret 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17370216-24-person174" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person174" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-person174" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the Prosecutor, 'till I came to Mr. De Veil's; and the Minute I came in, I said, - this is the Gentleman, by Goodman's and Bob the Glasier's Description. They told me he was a very little Gentleman, and had vastly much the Look of a Jew. They told me, after they had robb'd him in Soho square, they were afraid he would have follow'd them; and that they watch'd him into his own House. Goodman was the first that attack'd him; he gave Bob the Glasier the Gentleman's Purse, and Bob stole out some of the Guineas unknown to Goodman, and put in some Shillings instead of them. Goodman found out the Trick, and resolved to redeem the Watch unknown to Bob: So meeting with the Prisoner Bess, away they went with it to Holland together. Both <rs id="t17370216-24-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370216-24-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
