<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360908-9">
               <interp inst="t17360908-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-9" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360908"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360908-9" type="date" value="17360908"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360908-9-off40-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-9-defend81 t17360908-9-off40 t17360908-9-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360908-9-defend81" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17360908-9-defend81" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-defend81" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-defend81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360908-9-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360908-9-victim83" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Green 
                        <interp inst="t17360908-9-victim83" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-9-victim83" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360908-9-victim83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-9-off40 t17360908-9-victim83"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17360908-9-cd41" type="crimeDate">June the 30th</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-9-off40 t17360908-9-cd41"></join>, and giving him with both his Hands, divers mortal Bruises on his Head, Breast, Back, Stomach and Sides; by Reason of which said mortal Bruises, he the said Green did languish, and languishingly liv'd from the said 30th of June, to the 16th of July, at which time he dyed
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest, for feloniously slaying the said Green.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hathwell, Surgeon. I saw him a fortnight before he dy'd: There was a Bruise on his Breast, and several on other Parts of his Body; which with a Pleuretic Fever, was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-9-person84">
                  Hannah 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17360908-9-person84" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person84" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his Widow: He dy'd the 16th of July. On the Thursday seennight before he dy'd, he came home from work, in a bed Condition: He was a <rs id="t17360908-9-viclabel42" type="occupation">Plaisterer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360908-9-victim83 t17360908-9-viclabel42"></join>, and had been at work at Mile-end. On the Monday morning before, he went out in perfect health; but that Thursday night, he was very ill; I asked him what was the matter: He said he had received a Hurt on his Side by a Blow, but would not tell me in what manner he received the Hurt: He desired me to let him alone, and said, he would tell me afterwards how it came. I sent for a Surgeon to bleed him about 7 o'Clock that Night; but he continu'd very ill, and in the Morning he told me, if the Pain he was in continu'd, it would kill him: It will make you uneasy if I tell you, how I have been hurt; but if ever I get well, I will right myself. On Sunday night he told me that 2 of their Men had been gaming; that one having lost his Shirt, he pull'd off his, to lend the Looser: 
               <persName id="t17360908-9-person85">
                  Tom 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17360908-9-person85" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person85" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the Man, he said, he lent his Shirt to; who refusing to let him have it again, they quarrell'd, and Morris had given the Blows. On Monday I sent to Mr. Bransbury the Apothecary, and he order'd him to be blooded; on Tuesday, he was blooded again, and grew so bad, that he could not lye down in his Bed; but constantly complained of a Pain in his Side. My Dear, says I (the Day he dyed,) do you think the Blow Morris gave you, is the Occasion of your Death? Yes, say'd he. I asked him if I should follow the Law? Do what you please says he, he deserves it; but I forgive him, as I hope to be forgiven.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bransbury. I was sent for on Monday, and found the Deceased complaining of a Pain in his Side, and Shortness of Breath. He seemed very uneasy: I asked if he spit Blood, or made<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173609080005"></xptr> bloody Urine; he said no; he was blooded twice: after which he was easier; but in a Day or two, his Pain return'd, and he could not lie down for the Shortness of his Breath. I apprehended it to be a Decay in his Constitution. As for the Bruises, I saw none, nor did he complain of any to me.</p>
               <p>Surgeon. I cannot take on me to say, that any of the Bruises were mortal.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bransbury. I apprehend there was an Adhesion of the Lungs, and that it was a consumptive Case. I asked him if he had not drank hard, particularly, if he had not been us'd to drink Drams; and he said, formerly he had, but he had left them off now.</p>
               <p>Q. If the Bruises had occasion'd some inward mortal Disorder, would there not have been some Symptoms of the Disorder, as bloody Urine, spitting of Blood, or the like?</p>
               <p>Surgeon. I should think so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360908-9-person86">
                  Robert 
                  Millaway 
               <interp inst="t17360908-9-person86" type="surname" value="Millaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person86" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased and the Prisoner, about 3 Weeks before his Death, were playing at Skettles: I came in and play'd with them, the Prisoner lost his Wastcoat, and would play for his Shirt with another Man: the Deceased said he would lend his Shirt to the Man who lost: the Prisoner losing, asked the Deceased for his Shirt; he pull'd it off and lent it him; but I suppose growing a little coldish without his Shirt, he asked the Prisoner for it again, who would not give it him, till he had got another: then they went into the House, drank together, and quarrelling push'd one another against the Table, broke a Pane of Glass, and then sat down again; but the Deceas'd insisting on having his Shirt again, said he would fight him for it, and out they went, but did not strike above 6 Blows; nor did I observe that the Deceas'd had Blows of any Consequence: he said he had enough, and the Prisoner gave over: after this they sat and drank together upon the Bench.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cary. About a Week before he dy'd, he look'd yellow and bad, I asked him how he did; and he told me, he had fallen from a Scaffold, and that a Piece of Wood 15 Foot long, call'd a Ledger fell on him, and had bruis'd him so much, that he could hardly breath: this was about a Week before he dy'd.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17360908-9-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360908-9-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner, and found that John Green dy'd of a Consumption.</p>
            </div1>
