<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17341204-54">
               <interp inst="t17341204-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-54" type="year" value="1734"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17341204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17341204-54" type="date" value="17341204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17341204-54-off270-c254" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-54-defend370 t17341204-54-off270 t17341204-54-verdict273"></join>
         
               <p>53. 
               
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-defend370" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Sutton 
                  <interp inst="t17341204-54-defend370" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-defend370" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted (with</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040023"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-person371">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person371" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person371" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            *, not then at the Bar) was indicted for <rs id="t17341204-54-off270" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-off270" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-off270" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17341204-54-victim373" type="victimName">
                           Abigal 
                           Bingo 
                        <interp inst="t17341204-54-victim373" type="surname" value="Bingo"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-54-victim373" type="given" value="Abigal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17341204-54-victim373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-54-off270 t17341204-54-victim373"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in Peter's Alley, near the Highway, putting her in Fear and taking from her a gold Ring set with a stone, a black silk Glove, a Bunch of Keys, and 20 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17341204-54-cd271" type="crimeDate">Novemb. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-54-off270 t17341204-54-cd271"></join>.</p>
               <p>*
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person374">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person374" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person374" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was an Evidence against 
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person375">
                  Patrick 
                  Mead 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person375" type="surname" value="Mead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person375" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , White and Vaughan in Sept. 1732. Sess. Pap. No. 7. p. 185, 187, 188. And he, 
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person376">
                  William 
                  Simmonds 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person376" type="surname" value="Simmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person376" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Sept 1733. were try d for robbing 
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person377">
                  Philip 
                  Turst 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person377" type="surname" value="Turst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person377" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Marybone Fields, but they were both acquitted. Sess. Pap. Numb. 7. p. 191.</p>
               <p>Abigal Bingo. On Sunday Night (it was a Month ago last Sunday) between 6 and 7 o'Clock I turned out of Cornhill down <placeName id="t17341204-54-crimeloc272">Peter's Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-54-crimeloc272" type="placeName" value="Peter's Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17341204-54-crimeloc272" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17341204-54-off270 t17341204-54-crimeloc272"></join> there were 2 Fellows standing at the Corner of the Alley, and they came behind me and kick'd up my Heels and knock'd me down, and robb'd me of 1 s. 6 d. in Silver, Two Pennyworth of Half-pence, a Bunch of Keys, a black Silk Glove and a Gold Ring with a Stone, and they broke my Arm, and then they made off. I was in a Fright and did not mind their Faces.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-person378">
                  John 
                  Macdonnel 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person378" type="surname" value="Macdonnel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person378" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Night the 3d of November, I and the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person379">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person379" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person379" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             followed this Gentlewoman from Stocks Market to Peter's Alley in Cornhill. George Sutton took her a Fall by a Cross-Buttock, that is, he catch'd her by the Middle and heft her over; then Jack Sutton the Prisoner took 18 d. and 2 d. out of her Pocket and some Keys, and a Glove, and I lifted her up and took the Ring from her little Finger: It was a sinall Ring with a white Stone. She could not stand, but fell down again, and then George kick'd her and broke her Arm. Some People came out and had like to have taken us, but we got away - About a Fortnight afterward I went before Justice Lade and made a voluntary Confession - resolving to break off all my ill Company - George Sutton is now in the New Goal over the Water - I suppose he could not be removed hither time enough, because the Bill was not found before to Day.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. +Macdonnel has been an Evidence three Times before; he makes it his Livelihood and Property to take Men's Lives in this manner; and shall he be admitted to be a Witness again - But I can prove where I was when this Robbery was committed by credible Persons - Here's my Sister Celia, and several more.</p>
               <p>+ In April 1733, He was an Evidence against Wadsworth, White, and Powel for a Burglary, Sess. Pap. Numb. 4. p. 1724. And in Decemb. 1733. against Baxter and Rook for a Robbery, and Baxter and Sickwell for a Burglary. Sess. Pap. Numb, 1. p. 5. and 7.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-person380">
                  Celia 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person380" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person380" type="given" value="Celia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person380" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner, my Brother, served his Time to a Tobacconist, but he has since lived with my Father and Mother at the upper end of New Bond Street. He has always behaved soberly, and kept good Hours - My Father is an Officer in the Third Regiment.</p>
               <p>Court. Do ye know where the Prisoner was on last Sunday was a Month.</p>
               <p>Celia. He went to Church in the Morning, and did not go out after Dinner; I saw him in the House at 6, 7 and 8 in the Evening, and he went to Bed at ten.</p>
               <p>Sarah Young's Husband. I have known the Prisoner from a Child, I have visited his Father and Mother for 16 or 17 Years.</p>

               <p>Court. What is the Prisoner's Character.</p>
               <p>Young's Husband. I never asked into his Character; but his Father the Captain, is as honest a Gentleman as ever lived by God's Bread - On Sunday was 5 Weeks - or 4 Weeks, I can't be sure to a Week, but it was the 3d of November, I came from St. George's Church at a little past five, and went to Capt. Sutton's in New Bond-street, to drink Tea. It might be then half an Hour past five. There was the Captain and his Spouse, and Miss Celia, and Miss Nunny and this Gentleman at the Bar. I am sure he was there, for he paid his Compliment to me - I staid there till near Ten, or exactly Ten - I can't say to a Moment - and this Gentleman was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173412040024"></xptr> backwards and forwards all the Time - I think it was but a short Space that I did not see him - The Family has the best of Characters - As for this Gentleman he was first bound to a Linnen-Draper, and then to an Abacconess - And I know no more of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-person381">
                  Ann 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person381" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person381" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I wash'd for my Lady 
               <persName id="t17341204-54-person382">
                  Betty 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person382" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person382" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person382" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lodg'd at Captain Sutton's. I could not carry all the Linnen home on saturday Night, and so I carry'd the rest on Sunday the 3rd of November in the Evening; because my Lady Betty was to go out of Town on Monday Morning. The Prisoner let me in and he writ out my Bill for Washing, which came to 15 s and 9 d. 1/2, and I gave it to my Lady to cast up. - He began to write between 8 and 9, and after my Bill he wrote the Directions on my Lady's Boxes and Portmanteaus; and when I came down Stairs with the last Box I met him with a Candle going up to Bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17341204-54-person383">
                  Arthur 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17341204-54-person383" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person383" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday was 5 Weeks I waited on my Master Captain Gore, who who used to visit Lady Betty Young at Captain Suttons. The Prisoner opened the Door and my Master went in - I asked for a Copper of Small-Beer about half an Hour afterwards, and the Prisoner brought it up to us. I waited till between 10 and 11, and then my Master came home.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17341204-54-verdict273" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17341204-54-verdict273" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner; but as he stood charged with several Robberies in Middlesex, Surrey and Kent, he was ordered to remain in Custody.</p>
            </div1>
