<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17351210-70">
               <interp inst="t17351210-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-70" type="year" value="1735"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17351210"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17351210-70" type="date" value="17351210"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17351210-70-off295-c358" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-70-defend504 t17351210-70-off295 t17351210-70-verdict299"></join>
         
               <p>84. 
               
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-defend504" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17351210-70-defend504" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-defend504" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-defend504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17351210-70-off295" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-off295" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-off295" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               Ravishing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17351210-70-victim506" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Evans 
                        <interp inst="t17351210-70-victim506" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-70-victim506" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17351210-70-victim506" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-70-off295 t17351210-70-victim506"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17351210-70-cd296" type="crimeDate">May the First</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-70-off295 t17351210-70-cd296"></join>.</p>
               <p>Sarah Evans. The Prisoner <rs id="t17351210-70-deflabel297" type="occupation">keeps a Pawn-broker's Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-70-defend504 t17351210-70-deflabel297"></join> in <placeName id="t17351210-70-crimeloc298">George street, Spittle-Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-70-crimeloc298" type="placeName" value="George street, Spittle-Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17351210-70-crimeloc298" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17351210-70-off295 t17351210-70-crimeloc298"></join>. He was my Father's particular Acquaintance, and I going to School hard by, I used to go to his House in a Morning, and leave my Victuals there, and come back there to Dinner, and so go home at Night. I went there first in March, and one Morning about eight a Clock the latter end of April, as I was in the Prisoner's Shop, and no body at home but he and I, he shut the Street-door, and as I sat in an Elbow Leather-Chair, he first meddled with me with his Fingers, and I fell upon the Ground. He then took me up in his Arms, and set me in the Chair again, and then put my legs over his, and - into - half an Hour - Yes.</p>
               <p>Q Did you make an Resistance?</p>
               <p>Sarah Evans. No - I don't know what Resistance is.</p>
               <p>Q Did you struggle, or cry out?</p>
               <p>Sarah Evans. Yes, I struggled as much as I could, and cry'd out as loud as I could all the while, but no Soul could hear me; for the Shop is in a narrow Street, and the backside of the House is a great Vacancy, tho' People go along the Street; but the Door was lock'd and the Window next the Street was filled up with Goods. Then he shewed me a naked Sword, and said he would kill me if I told any Body what he had done to me; and so I went to School and said Nothing. In two or three Weeks afterwards, I began to break out, and he told my Father it was the Itch; and so the Prisoner took me in Hand, and gave me Physick for six Weeks; and then it proved to be the Foul Disease, and I was forced to go into the Hospital. I never told any Body how the Prisoner had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100037"></xptr> used me, till eight Weeks after he did it, and then I told my Mother - I was fifteen Years old last May - No Man ever medled with me but the Prisoner, and he never did but that once.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person507">
                  Edward 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person507" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person507" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When my Daughter had discovered this, I asked the Prisoner how he could serve her so? He said, if he did do it, he could have done it at other times if he would, and he bid me get out of his House, and said if I gave him an ill Word he would trounce me. When the Girl first broke out (about Whitsuntide) he said it was the Itch, and undertook to Cure her, for he pretended to be a sort of a Surgeon, but it proved to be the Foul Disease, and so I got her into the Hospital.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person508">
                  Jane 
                  Blackman 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person508" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person508" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person508" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near the Prisoner. The Girl was in Health and had no Blemish when she went to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person509">
                  Judith 
                  Sykes 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person509" type="surname" value="Sykes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person509" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person509" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner's shop is in such a Thoroughfare that if she cryed out, the People in the street must needs have heard her. She had been my Apprentice two Years, and went away about three quarters of a Year ago, she behaved but very indifferently, for she was a very bold Girl, a great Liar, and a Pilferer. She sometimes used to stay out late at Night, and has seem'd to be in Liquor, and hardly able to stand when she came home, and her Clothes have been very Dirty as if she had fell down in the Street. Her Father used to tell me next Day she had been at his House, and therefore desired me to excuse her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person510">
                  Samuel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person510" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person510" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner's half-Brother. Long before any thing of this, her Father complained to me, that Mr. Sikes her Master had attempted to ravish her. I sent for Mr. Sikes, and when the Girl saw him she run away. Her Father desired she might be discharged from her service, for fear she should be ruined, and he perswaded me to go with him and the Girl before a Justice, to get a Warrant against her Master for an intent to Ravish. And the Girl there said that he used her rudely with his Fingers, but that she did not offer to cry out. I have heard she is a loose Girl, and kept Company with a Barber that was Pox'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person511">
                  Sarah 
                  Olney 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person511" type="surname" value="Olney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person511" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person511" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (the Prisoner's Daughter.) The Girl has a very base Character, rather lewd than otherwise, and her Parents were always litigious People. When her Father first brought her to my Father it was to complain that Mr. Sykes had been rude with her, and had lain with her upon the Hearth - I lay in my Father's House in all April last, and the House was always open by six in the Morning, tho' its possible the Door might be shut by chance, and if she cryed out but half as loud as I speak now. she might have been heard on both sides of the House by the Passengers that were constantly going by. My Father is hard of Hearing, and therefore. I or my Mother were obliged to be in the way to attend the Customers - My Father and I have both charg'd her before her Father's Face, with having the Pox, but she always deny'd it. Her Mother had a sort of a Leprosy, and the Girl her self was a little broke out before she came from Mr. Sykes's, for Mr. Sikes had 'nointed her, and given her Flower of Brimstone, and made her wear a Smock two Weeks on that Account, and her Father desired my Father to give her Physick. She used to go from our House to her Writing Master, at Six in the Afternoon, and her Father has often come with a Candle and a Lanthorn at eleven and twelve at Night, or one in the Morning, to enquire for her - After I had told him I believed she had the Pox, he came the next Day, and said he had searched her himself, and was sure she had never known Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person512">
                  Ann 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person512" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person512" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person512" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her Father come several times to look for her at Midnight - she had a loose Character, and would keep Company with any Man, tho' she did not know him, if he did but say, Come Sal go with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person513">
                  Margaret 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person513" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person513" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person513" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live so near the Prisoner that if she had cryed out I should have heard, and so would the People that past the Street. The Prisoner has the Character of a very sober modest Man.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cockin. After the Rape was sworn, I ask'd her if he had entered her Body. She said no. I asked her if he was a Man, or a Woman, and she said she could not tell. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173512100038"></xptr> had sent her Mother for a Pot of Beer, but she stood upon the stairs to listen; and hearing me ask these Questions, she came in and said, she was betrayed, and flung me down seven stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person514">
                  John 
                  Yallop 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person514" type="surname" value="Yallop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person514" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person514" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard one ask the Girl who gave her the Pox, and she said she could not tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person515">
                  Mary 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person515" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person515" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person515" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Girl had a breaking out, last Christmass. I asked what it was, and her Father said, he believed it was the Leprosy, for her Mother broke out so when she was with Child. In September he told me the Prisoner had ravished his Daughter; and if the Prisoner would give him one hundred Pounds he would make it up. I told the Prisoner this, and he refused - Her Father told me that his Wife was a base Woman, and had advised the Girl to swear this Rape, and was the Occasion of all the false Swearing about it - I have heard that she is a wicked vile base lying Girl, that she used to lye out till twelve or one in the Morning, and that a Barber gave her the Pox.</p>
               <p>Several gave the Prisoner the Character of a sober modest honest Man, and not inclinable to Women.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17351210-70-person516">
                  Lydia 
                  Hyley 
               <interp inst="t17351210-70-person516" type="surname" value="Hyley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person516" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-person516" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Girl has the Character of a very harmless honest sober Girl, and I never heard that she loved Company. The Truth is, she is not over burthened with Sense, but was always more for playing with Children, and Baby's, than keeping Company with Men.</p>
               <p>Several other of the Girl's Neighbours deposed, that her general Character was that of a very sober modest Child, and her Father a very honest Man, and that they could have brought the whole Street to have said the same, if there had been occasion for it.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17351210-70-verdict299" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17351210-70-verdict299" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
