<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17361013-6">
               <interp inst="t17361013-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-6" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17361013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17361013-6" type="date" value="17361013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-6-off32-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend104 t17361013-6-off32 t17361013-6-verdict39"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-6-off32-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend105 t17361013-6-off32 t17361013-6-verdict40"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17361013-6-off35-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend105 t17361013-6-off35 t17361013-6-verdict40"></join>
         
               <p>8, 9. 
               
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-defend104" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Mickey 
                  <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend104" type="surname" value="Mickey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend104" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17361013-6-defend105" type="defendantName">
                  Joshua 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend105" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend105" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130011"></xptr> indicted, for that they with divers other Persons to the Number of one hundred, <rs id="t17361013-6-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assault"></interp>
               the dwelling House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-6-victim107" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Waldon 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim107" type="surname" value="Waldon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , scituate and being in <placeName id="t17361013-6-crimeloc33">Cable Street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-crimeloc33" type="placeName" value="Cable Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-crimeloc33" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off32 t17361013-6-crimeloc33"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off35 t17361013-6-crimeloc33"></join>, with Sticks, Clubs, &amp;c. did assault, and the Windows and Shutters of the said House did break in Pieces and destroy, &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17361013-6-cd34" type="crimeDate">July 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off32 t17361013-6-cd34"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off35 t17361013-6-cd34"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-person108">
                  Joshua 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person108" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person108" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17361013-6-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assault"></interp>
               breaking (as aforesaid) the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17361013-6-victim110" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Wharfington 
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim110" type="surname" value="Wharfington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim110" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17361013-6-victim110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, July 30.</p>
               <p>John Waldon. <rs id="t17361013-6-viclabel36" type="occupation">I keep the <placeName id="t17361013-6-crimeloc37">Bull and Butcher in Cable Street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-crimeloc37" type="placeName" value="Bull and Butcher in Cable Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-crimeloc37" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off32 t17361013-6-crimeloc37"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-off35 t17361013-6-crimeloc37"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-victim107 t17361013-6-viclabel36"></join>, and have a great Number of Country Shopkeepers lodge in my House when they come to Town; we have some 60 or 70 People in the House, but then we had but 18. The 30th of July, every one in the House was gone to bed but my self, and I was stripped all but my Stockings and Breeches; but hearing the Mob come down, and crying, down with the Irish, and seeing all the Houses illuminated, I bid all my Lodgers get up and shift for their Lives: I got over a Wall 8 Feet high, and some of the Neighbours helped the Lodgers off. I left the House to their Mercy, (for my Wife was out at a Woman's Labour) and they stole and broke every Thing I had. I staid in the House, 'till the Shutters and Glass all flew in together. They did not enter the House, but they reached in with their Arms, and took Meat out of the Windows. Six of my Shutters were broke, and 70 odd Panes of Glass, which Damage cost me 3 l. 13 s. to repair. I can't say I saw any of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-person111">
                  Mary 
                  Conelly 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person111" type="surname" value="Conelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person111" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I livs about 20 or 30 Yards from this Man's House; and the Night this Disturbance happened, somebody came and told my Mother the Mob was coming, and that her Name (
               <persName id="t17361013-6-person112">
                  Ann 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person112" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person112" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) was mention'd. They order'd the English People to put out Lights, and the Cry was, down with the Irish. I saw Mickey and several others beating against Waldon's House. I went out among the Mob, but shifted from one Place to another, lest they should know me. When the Soldiers came, they threw away their Sticks, andran away, and Mickey followed them after his Stick was gone. Hall I can't say I remember, but I got Mickey secur'd that Night. I went next Morning to see him in the Tower, and he cry'd to me d - n ye, what are you upon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-person113">
                  John 
                  Bivin 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person113" type="surname" value="Bivin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person113" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Serjeant. The Prisoner Mickey I seiz'd at this Woman's Request; somebody said, this is one of the Rioters, and I laid hold of him I can't say I saw him do any thing, or that he had any Thing in his Hand.</p>
               <p>- Potter. July the 30th, I saw a great Number of People breaking Waldon's House; among the rest I saw Hall in a red (I believe it was his Regimental) Wastcoat, he hollow'd out down with the Irish, but I did not see him do any thing I met him afterwards, and asked him, if he was not ashamed, he being a <rs id="t17361013-6-deflabel38" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend105 t17361013-6-deflabel38"></join>, to be guilty of such Things? Hush, hush, said he, for God's sake hold your Tongue. I saw him at some Distance from Walden's House, hollowing, while others were breaking the Windows; I heard them call out for the English to put out Lights, and saw them hand Meat out of the Window.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-person114">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person114" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person114" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Hall a good while; the Night this Riot happened I saw him going before the Mob; when they had broke Waldon's House, they went to the Windmill, then they came back to Mrs. Austin's, and broke that, and Hall was with them, crying down with the Irish</p>
               <p>Mickey's Defence. After I had done work that Night, I call'd upon my Master (who sells a Dram) and I had part of a Quartern of Gin, then I went to the Queen's Head in Rag Fair and had a Full Pot of Beer; going home I met an old Master of mine, who is a Headborough, at the End of Church Lane, and he charged me to assist him; I went to the Watch House, and was seized by the Soldiers. Conolly when she came to the Tower, said, she could swear against a Brewer's Servant, and took him for me.</p>
               <p>- Abbot, gave the Prisoner a good Character, and said, Conolly's was but very indifferent.</p>
               <p>Mosely (Headhorough.) I was called up at that time to assist my Neighbours, and followed the Mob to the Bull and Butcher; at the End of Church Lane, I met Mickey, and charged him to assist me. He went up White Lyon Street with me, where the Mob were beating down another House; I lost him in the Croud, and found afterwards that he was taken up. I have known him some Years.</p>
               <p>- Adams. Mickey lived in my House, and the Night that this happened he stood at my Door while the Mob was beating down some Houses in Church Lane, where I live, I miss'd him, and went down to see them, at the Bull and Butcher; I did not see him there, but in half an Hour after I heard he was seiz'd. I told him before he went, he would go and look on, and get himself taken up.</p>
               <p>- Lyddal. I saw Mickey standing by the Watch House, and says he, what pity it is they take up the English? they ought to take up the Irish; a Soldier said, he was one of them, and shoved him into the Watch House.</p>
               <p>Hall's Defence. I worked at Mr. Sharp's, a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173610130012"></xptr> Sawyer and Lath render; as I came home from work I staid half an Hour, as others did, to look on; the People that swore I had a Club in my Hand are mistaken. 'Tis common for Lath-renders to bring home a Bit of a Chip or a Lath in their Hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17361013-6-person115">
                  Mary 
                  Abbot 
               <interp inst="t17361013-6-person115" type="surname" value="Abbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person115" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Mob go one way and Hall was going another: I heard him say to a young Woman that was shutting up her Windows, do not be frighted, and he helped her to shut them up</p>
               <p>Justice Phillips. I was by when Mickey was taken, the Girl said she had marked him, and followed him, and that he was never out of her sight, I was with the Soldier that took him, and the Girl did charge the Soldier with him; she gave the same Account, that she has now done, when she was examined before me, and Colonel Williamson. Both <rs id="t17361013-6-verdict39" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-verdict39" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Joshua Hall was likewise found <rs id="t17361013-6-verdict40" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-verdict40" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> on the 2d Indictment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-6-punish41" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-punish41" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend104 t17361013-6-punish41"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend105 t17361013-6-punish41"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17361013-6-punish42" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-punish42" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17361013-6-punish42" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend104 t17361013-6-punish42"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17361013-6-defend105 t17361013-6-punish42"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
