<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370706-14">
               <interp inst="t17370706-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-14" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370706-14" type="date" value="17370706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370706-14-off75-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-14-defend138 t17370706-14-off75 t17370706-14-verdict78"></join>
         
               <p>18 
               
                  <persName id="t17370706-14-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Lee 
                  <interp inst="t17370706-14-defend138" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-defend138" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-defend138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370706-14-defloc74">St. Ann's Black-Fryars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-14-defloc74" type="placeName" value="St. Ann's Black-Fryars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-14-defloc74" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-14-defend138 t17370706-14-defloc74"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370706-14-off75" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-off75" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-off75" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 4 Guineas and 35 s. in Money
            </rs>, from the Person of 
               <persName id="t17370706-14-victim139" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-victim139" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-14-off75 t17370706-14-victim139"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17370706-14-cd76" type="crimeDate">May 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-14-off75 t17370706-14-cd76"></join>.</p>
               <p>W - T - . I had been drinking very freely with some Friends in Thames-Street, and meeting with the Prisoner in St. Paul's Church-yard she conducted me to a House in <placeName id="t17370706-14-crimeloc77">Evangelist's Court in Black Fryars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-14-crimeloc77" type="placeName" value="Evangelist's Court in Black Fryars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370706-14-crimeloc77" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370706-14-off75 t17370706-14-crimeloc77"></join>. I had 11 Guineas and a half, a 6 s. Piece, and 35 s. in Silver in my Pocket. When I came to her House, we went up Stairs together, and a Woman brought us up some Punch; I staid some little Time, and then I lay down with her on the Bed, - and she pick'd my Pocket. My Gold was in this Pocket, and I had thrust a great Piece of whited brown Paper upon it, to secure it, but she pull'd out the Paper, and took 5 Guineas and the 36 s. Piece, the Paper I found on the Bed, but the 5 Guineas and the other Peice was gone. At the Watch-house she dropp'd one Guinea from under her Petticoats, and as she did not claim it, I took it my self, and I have indicted her for 4 Guineas and a 36 s: Peice. There was no one in the Room but our selves and the Woman that brought in the Punch, and she did not stay with us, - she went down Stairs. I was in Liquor, but I was not insensible, for I told my Money by the Candle.</p>
               <p>C. If you was sensible, you was a very wicked, impudentt Man, to pick up this Woman in order to debauch her.</p>
               <p>W - T - . I can't pretend to justify the Thing: 'Tis a wicked Thing to be sure; but 'tis what is often done when Men are in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say before the Justice?</p>
               <p>W - T - . I perswaded her to deliver my Money to save Trouble, and she said it was not in her Power: this seem'd to be a tacit Confession that she took it. After she had robb'd me, she ran down Stairs in a hurry; I follow'd her, and the Woman of the House let her out, and shut me in, and then she blew out the Candle. The Bell-man was providentially going by, and (he hearing the Noise; seized her</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not say when he pull'd out his Money before me, that he had been done some Injury to before; and that he was not willing to be served so again.</p>
               <p>W - T - . I told her what Money I had in my Pocket, and I bid her take Care what she did. - I had promised to make her a little Present, and that was 'all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was stripp'd quite naked in the Watch-house, and they found nothing upon me. He and my Landlady were fumbling in the Dark, - perhaps she might take his Money.</p>
               <p>W - T - . The Prisoner wou'd had me to have lain there all Night, and then I suppose I should have lost all the Cloaths upon my Back.</p>
               <p>C And you would very well have deserv'd it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-14-person140">
                  William 
                  Sadler 
               <interp inst="t17370706-14-person140" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-person140" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bell man. I was just by the Place, and I heard a Noise, - I am robb'd, I am robb'd - I will have my Money; so I came back, and got 2 Watchmen, and away we came all 3 to the Alley: we heard the Gentleman cry, - he would have his Money, and we perceiv'd they were struggling in the Entry; by and by the Door flew open, and the Prisoner tumbled down 2 or 3 Steps at the Door. Madam, says I, I believe you've hurt your self, I must take you up; so I have, says she, and shall feel it for some Time. If I had not been there to have help'd her up tho', she had gone cleverly off. The Gentleman came out presently, and charged us with her, so we took her to the Watch-house directly, and there she neither own'd it, nor deny'd it; but a Guinea dropp'd from her, and the Gentleman look'd under the Table and took it up. Upon this I bid him search her, for he would find more where that came from, and she had her Hands - ('tis a little immodest too,) - here. This is the Truth, and I'll stand by it, and die by it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370706-14-person141">
                  John 
                  Crookshank 
               <interp inst="t17370706-14-person141" type="surname" value="Crookshank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-person141" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I was call'd up about 1 or 2 o'Clock to take charge of the Prisoner. Mr. W - T - said she had robb'd him of 5 Guineas, and a 36 s. Peice, but he had found one of the Guineas. She had no Petticoats on, only a loose Gown, and but one Stocking; as I was carrying her to the Counter, she desired to be search'd, where, says I; shall I get Women to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173707060015"></xptr> search you now, except they are Whores, - like your self. She was asked for the Money, and she said 'twas out of her Power to produce it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I beg'd and pray'd, and crav'd, and ask'd them to search me: I had not a Farthing in the World, and my poor Cloaths, - they were not upon me. I have no Acquaintance in London, for I have been but a very little while in Town.</p>
               <p>C. You have been here long enough to be concerned in a very scandalous Affair. <rs id="t17370706-14-verdict78" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370706-14-verdict78" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
