<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370907-44">
               <interp inst="t17370907-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-44" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370907-44" type="date" value="17370907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370907-44-off227-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-defend318 t17370907-44-off227 t17370907-44-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>48. 
               <persName id="t17370907-44-defend318" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-defend318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17370907-44-defloc225">St. Clement Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-44-defloc225" type="placeName" value="St. Clement Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-44-defloc225" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-defend318 t17370907-44-defloc225"></join>, <rs id="t17370907-44-deflabel226" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-defend318 t17370907-44-deflabel226"></join>; was indicted, for <rs id="t17370907-44-off227" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-off227" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-off227" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370907-44-victim320" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Keate 
                        <interp inst="t17370907-44-victim320" type="surname" value="Keate"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-44-victim320" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370907-44-victim320" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-off227 t17370907-44-victim320"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, did make an Assault, and her against her Will, feloniously did Ravish, and carnally know
            </rs>. <rs id="t17370907-44-cd228" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-off227 t17370907-44-cd228"></join>.</p>
               <p>Councel. We beg a Letter may be read that the Agent for the Prosecutor told me he wrote.</p>
               <p>To L - I H - y, Esq; in Garden-Court, in the Temple.</p>
               <p>Sir, I was last Night sent to by a Client of mine to take Instructions for a Bill against you, for an Outrage of the blackest Dye, committed upon 
               <persName id="t17370907-44-person321">
                  Ann 
                  Keate 
               <interp inst="t17370907-44-person321" type="surname" value="Keate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-person321" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-person321" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and had an Information put into my Hands to that Purpose; but in Regard to your being a Gentleman, I thought it better, to desire you might be sent to, before this was attempted, but it was deny'd me; however, if you will make any Overtures you may, if not I shall proceed. I am, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. To the Agent. What are these Overtures? what do they mean Sir?</p>
               <p>Agent. There was an Information put into my Hands, and I thought he would make some Application to her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Keate. On the 24th of June, about 7 or 8 o'Clock in the Evening, I was going from Fountain-Court in the Strand, to the Old Bailey, for a Bottle of Daffey's Elixir, for this Gentlewoman's (Mrs. Mitchel's) Child; I live in her House. -</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what Business is that Gentlewoman?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Keate. A Widow, and she has an Annuity. I live with her, - but not as a Servant, - I keep my self, and can give an Account - how I have 30 l. a Year, of my own. As I was going along, my Foot stumbled, and this Gentleman came after me, and asked me where I was going? What's that to you says I. Why my Dear, I have had a terrible Misfortune; I have had a Girl that has jilted me and used me ill: and he desired me to take a Glass of Wine with him. I told him, I would not go with him. Then he asked me where I was going? I told him to the Old Bailey. He said he would not let me go, 'till I had taken a Glass of Wine with him. He promised he would not molest me, and went all the Way to the Old-Bailey with me. When I got there, I went into a House, and I thought I should have lost him, - but when I came out again, - there was he waiting for me, and still said he would not leave me, 'till he had drank a Glass of Wine with me, and so he follow'd me to the Ship Tavern by Temple-Bar; at the Corner of Butcher-Row, pray, says he, go in and drink, - we'll sit in the publick Kitchen, or wherever you please; and says he, if I am rude, - keep this, (pulling a very handsome Diamond Ring off his Finger.) So - I went into a publick Room with him, and there he told me, if I would go down into the Country with him, he would marry me, to spite his Girl, who had gone and marry'd his Plow-Fellow And says he, if you'll consent to go down, you shall go with me to my Chambers to Night. But pray, says he, whenever you come to me, be sure to be dress'd very fine, that my Servants may tell her, and that will make her mad. I told him I could not lye out of my Lodgings all Night; why then says he, come To-morrow Morning. When we come out of the Tavern, he call'd a Chair to carry me Home, and the Chairmen instead of carrying me Home, - they carried to - another Place. Why Fellows, says I, I did not bid you bring me Here! But damn them, says he, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of Night was it, when he met you:</p>
               <p>Keate. Not quite Eight o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Pints of Wine did you drink?</p>
               <p>Keate. I can't tell. But we staid at the Tavern 'till about 10 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173709070035"></xptr>Q. Pray where did the Chairmen carry you?</p>
               <p>Keate Into a very long Room, - an Entry, in <placeName id="t17370907-44-crimeloc229">Garden Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-44-crimeloc229" type="placeName" value="Garden Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370907-44-crimeloc229" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370907-44-off227 t17370907-44-crimeloc229"></join>. When the Men lifted up the Top of the Chair, I told them I did not live there. The Prisoner told them I did, and took the Candle from them, and so made me go up 2 pair of Stairs, and shew'd the Gold Watches, Silver Salvers, and a great many fine Things, which he said he would give me, if I would lye with him. Then he brought out Shrub and several Bottles of Wine, and would have me drink; I insisted upon going Home, but he would not let me. - I have a great Cut here, - which I got by his flinging me out of Bed. When he had stripp'd himself, he told me if I would not strip my self, he would, or he would send for Porters that should do it for me, - and all this while I begg'd and pray'd he would let me go Home, but he would not let me.</p>
               <p>Q. And was not you prevail'd upon at last?</p>
               <p>Keate. No. He tore off my Gown and my Shoes and Stockings, but my Petticoats were none of them pull'd off.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, and what was next?</p>
               <p>Keate. I can't speak it in Court - for all the World.</p>
               <p>Q. When you found your self in Garden-Court, with all this prodigious unwillingness, why did you not complain? Why did you suffer your self to be carry'd up 2 pair of Stairs?</p>
               <p>Keate. He took the Candle from the Chairmen and it went out before we got up Stairs; but when we came into his Room he struck a Light with a Thing like a Pistol.</p>
               <p>Q. When you was in his Room, why did not you cry out?</p>
               <p>Keate. I did break a pane of Glass, but he told me no Body would hear me if I did cry out. He used me in a very barbarous Manner, but I can't tell it for ever so much.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mitchel. Miss Keate came Home crying the next Day, after this happen'd, about 2 o'Clock in the Afternoon. Miss Nanny, says I, What is the matter with you? What made you stay out all Night Child? Don't ask me, says she, and fell into a violent Passion of crying, and so went to Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. When was any Information given to a Justice of the Peace?</p>
               <p>Keate. I employed a Man to get a Judges Warrant, and gave him a Guinea to do it, but he run away with the Money.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I went to the Prisoner's Chambers the next Day.</p>
               <p>Counc. I believe you have been there often enough to see for Overtures.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner was <rs id="t17370907-44-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370907-44-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, and the Court granted him a Copy of his Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
