<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370114-6">
               <interp inst="t17370114-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-6" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370114-6" type="date" value="17370114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-6-off26-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-defend54 t17370114-6-off26 t17370114-6-verdict28"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370114-6-off26-c44" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-defend56 t17370114-6-off26 t17370114-6-verdict28"></join>
         
               <p>6, 7, 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-6-defend54" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Insome 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend54" type="surname" value="Insome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend54" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend54" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17370114-6-defend56" type="defendantName">
                     Esther 
                     Redding 
                  <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend56" type="surname" value="Redding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend56" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-defend56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17370114-6-defloc25">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-6-defloc25" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370114-6-defloc25" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-defend54 t17370114-6-defloc25"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-defend56 t17370114-6-defloc25"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17370114-6-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 5 l. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17370114-6-victim58" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Powel 
                        <interp inst="t17370114-6-victim58" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-6-victim58" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17370114-6-victim58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-off26 t17370114-6-victim58"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17370114-6-cd27" type="crimeDate">Dec. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370114-6-off26 t17370114-6-cd27"></join>.</p>
               <p>James Powel. On Tuesday Dec. 14, about one in the Morning, I happen'd to light on this Creature, ( Clare Dickenson ) and she asked me to give her a Dram? so we went to the Prisoner Insome's House; I don't know whether 'tis Insome's House or 
               <persName id="t17370114-6-person59">
                  Robert 
                  Redding 
               <interp inst="t17370114-6-person59" type="surname" value="Redding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person59" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, but I had my Watch there, and there I lost it: I am sure I had it when I went in, but when I put my Hand into my Pocket to pay for the Drams, I had neither Money nor Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-6-person60">
                  Clare 
                  Dickenson 
               <interp inst="t17370114-6-person60" type="surname" value="Dickenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person60" type="given" value="Clare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was the Person that went into Redding's with the Prosecutor to drink a Dram, and there he lost his Watch: I saw Insome take it, and deliver it to Redding. They said, truly they wonder'd how he could pick up such a nasty black-guard Creature as I am: But we had three Quarterns of Gin, and Insome I am same took the Watch and gave it to Redding. I told the Prosecutor so in the House, but yet they stripp'd me there, and used me so improperly, that I should have had a Midwife. Then they search'd me again, in Holborn Watch-house, and used me ill there. The Prosecutor would not mind what I said, 'till he got me to the Watch-house, and the Prisoners were glad to get us out of the House, for if we were but gone, they said they should be safe enough. They call'd me a Black-guard, and wonder'd how he could have any Thing to do with such a dirty Wretch as I am.</p>
               <p>Q Where does Redding live?</p>
               <p>Dickenson. Over-against St. Giles's Church; I don't know the Sign.</p>
               <p>Insome. My Lord I did bring them their Liquor; but ask her if I sat down with them.</p>
               <p>Dickenson. Yes; you sat down by him; you took the Watch out of his Pocket; then you took the Candle and went down Stairs, and said, you wonder'd how any body could pick up such a Black-guard, dirty Bitch as I was.</p>
               <p>Insome. The Man brought the Creature into the House, and asked for a Lodging: I shew'd them up Stairs and carried them Liquour: When I call'd for the Reckoning, he said he had lost his Money and his Watch. I told him, he had not lost it in our House; why then says he, I have lost it in Drury-Lane; with that he fell upon his Creature and beat her sadly; Redding call'd the Watch, to take them out of the House; the Watchmen asked him who he could charge with the Robbery, and he said, he could charge no one, but Dickenson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-6-person61">
                  John 
                  Barringer 
               <interp inst="t17370114-6-person61" type="surname" value="Barringer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person61" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman, and was call'd to take this Man and Dickenson out of Redding's House. He said he had lost a Watch, and a Guinea in Gold, and Silver; but, says he, I don't value the Money, if I could but get my Watch. We search'd Dickenson, but found nothing upon her; so we carry'd her to the Round-House, and next Morning before the Justice: there she said she saw Insome take it and give it to Redding, and so we took them up. In Redding's House, he charged the Fact on Clare Dickenson only</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173701140004"></xptr>Thomas Price. I was crying, - past One o'Clock, - and they call'd, Watch! but please your Honour my Lord, I would not go, without the other Watchman. This Gentlewoman is a common Night Walker, she was there, and the Man told us he had lost his Watch, and he fell a beating the Creature as if he had been mad: says I, - don't beat her so, before us, but charge us with her, and take her according to Law, please your Honour my Lord. We search'd her, but found nothing: I said, do you charge any of these Women, (for there was three Women more in the Room) no, says he, I can't say whether the Prisoners were any of them that were then Present.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370114-6-person62">
                  Susannah 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17370114-6-person62" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person62" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-person62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Appear'd to the Prisoners Characters. Both <rs id="t17370114-6-verdict28" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370114-6-verdict28" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
