<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17370420-4">
               <interp inst="t17370420-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-4" type="year" value="1737"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17370420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17370420-4" type="date" value="17370420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17370420-4-off20-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-4-defend52 t17370420-4-off20 t17370420-4-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>5. 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-defend52" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Jay 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-defend52" type="surname" value="Jay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-defend52" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-defend52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17370420-4-defloc19">St. Olave, Hart Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-defloc19" type="placeName" value="St. Olave, Hart Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-defloc19" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-4-defend52 t17370420-4-defloc19"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17370420-4-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 12 Carolina Deer Skins, val. 5 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-victim54" type="victimName">
                     David 
                     Goddin 
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-victim54" type="surname" value="Goddin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-victim54" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-victim54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-4-off20 t17370420-4-victim54"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17370420-4-cd21" type="crimeDate">Feb. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-4-off20 t17370420-4-cd21"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. David Goddin. I live in <placeName id="t17370420-4-crimeloc22">French Ordinary-Court, Crouched-Fryars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="French Ordinary-Court, Crouched-Fryars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17370420-4-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17370420-4-off20 t17370420-4-crimeloc22"></join>: My House having been broke open, and Money and Plate, having been Stole to a great Value; I examin'd my Warehouses, and found a Bag of Ambergrease, and these 12 Carolina Deer-skins missing. I desire Mrs. Tollman may be called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person55">
                  Catherine 
                  Tollman 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person55" type="surname" value="Tollman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person55" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person56">
                  Joseph
                   O'Brian
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person56" type="surname" value="O'Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person56" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought 'em into my House, and desired me to let him leave<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200005"></xptr> them there for his Partner 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person57">
                  Tom 
                  Jay 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person57" type="surname" value="Jay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person57" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner. I know nothing else; I saw they were some sort of Skins.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goddin. Did not he bid you deliver them to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tollman. Yes, and I did so, sometime in February about the Dusk of the Evening.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goddin. Did not O'Bryan tell you who he had the Skins of?</p>
               <p>Tollman. Yes; he said he had them from his Uncle.</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person58">
                  Simon 
                  Pyke 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person58" type="surname" value="Pyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person58" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Leatherseller in the Strand, between Norfolk-Street, and Surrey-Street. The Prisoner, on or about the 14th of February, call'd on me and asked me if I would buy some Deer Skins: He said he had a Friend, a Sea-faring Man, who had some to dispose of. My Answer was, that if I saw them and liked them, I did not know but I might buy them at a Market Price The Day following the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person59">
                  Josiah
                   O'Bryan
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person59" type="surname" value="O'Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person59" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came with ten Skins; and this O'Bryan, the Sea-faring Man, prov'd to be an Apprentice to one Mr. Garret, a Packer in Bell-Alley, Coleman-Street We soon agreed for the Skins; I was to have them for Twenty-eight Shillings; but after the Agreement, I was not satisfied about their Property in them, so I insisted upon Vouchers. Upon this, the Prisoner and O'Bryan said, there was a Neighbour a Publican, one 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person60">
                  Thomas 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person60" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person60" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Golden Lyon, who could give some Account of them; but Bennet gave me no satisfaction. Then I sent to Mr. Garret's in Bell Alley, to know if his Apprentice was a Dealer in Deer-Skins; Bennet gave me a Caution, and directed me to Mr. Garret's. Mr. Garret sent me Word that he knew nothing of his Man O'Brian's being a Dealer, so I stopp'd the Skins. The Prisoner and O'Bryan were dis-satisfy'd, and insisted on the Money or the Skins, and were very urgent on the Question; either the Money or the Skins they would have; but that did not prevail on me; I detain'd them, and told them I would send for a Constable: I sent my Man for one, and O'Bryan went away very fast, and the Prisoner went off afterwards. In the Afternoon the Prisoner return'd to Bennet's, to know my Christian Name in order to give me Trouble; passing by my Shop, I told him, I did not want Trouble, if O'Bryan's Master would appear for his Servant, the Skins or the Money should be ready. On the Friday following Mr. Garret, O'Bryan's Master with his Uncle, appear'd in his Behalf, and told me they were satisfy'd in some Measure about the Skins, for there was a Piece of Cloth (they said) bought and truck'd for them, and that they were equally concern'd in the Cloth. These Gentlemen appearing, and the Prisoner being likewise Mr. Garret's Journeyman, I offer'd them the Skins? but Mr. O'Bryan said, as I had the Trouble, I might pay his Kinsman for them and keep them; so I paid the 28 s. as before we agreed, and took a Receipt from O'Bryan. I sold them afterwards to a Gentleman in Court for two Guineas, and they are here to be produced.</p>





               <p>Q. Was the Price you gave for these Skins, a common Price?</p>
               <p>Pyke. No; it was a low Price.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I receive any Money from you?</p>
               <p>Pyke. The Prisoner was not in my Shop when the Money was paid, but he was the Person that came first to me about them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Have not you known me many Years?</p>
               <p>Pyke. In the Year 33, he and his Wife was pass'd upon me, out of the City: I was then Overseer of St. Clements.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person61">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person61" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person61" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happen'd to be in Master Pyke's Shop when the Skins were offer'd him, and doubting how they came by them, he went to the Alehouse to enquire after their Characters; when he return'd to his Shop, he sent me to Mr. Garret's with the Prisoner; as we went along he asked me what Mr. Pyke's Christian Name was; I told him Simon, then by G - d I'll arrest him in an Hours Time; for O'Bryan and I bought a piece of Cloth for 24 s. and we truck'd it for these Skins, and if the Man has bit me in them, I am even with him, I have bit him in the Cloth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person62">
                  James 
                  Pellisent 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person62" type="surname" value="Pellisent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person62" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do know them Skin which be here, I have bye them of Mr. Pyke.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goddin. You don't interrogate Mr. Pellisent.</p>
               <p>Q. What would you have me ask him? It is incumbent upon you to shew they were your's, and that you lost them.</p>
               <p>Job How. Here's three of the Skins we have sworn to already: When we first rummaged the Warehouse, we counted over these Skins, and one of them hit a Piece of Skin off my Thumb, and it bled very much, here's some of my Blood upon this Skin, - here's more upon this too, but I shall hardly swear to them. There was 1212 of them when we rummag'd the 2d of February, and when we rummag'd them the 7th or 8th of March, these Skins were missing: I believe they are Master Goddin's, by this Worm-eaten Skin, which I remember, and there's my Blood upon some of the rest; - that's a Circumstance very plain I think.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person63">
                  James 
                  Desnard 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person63" type="surname" value="Desnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person63" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd How's Evidence</p>
               <p>Defence. I am innocent of the Thing; I recommended the Lad to Mr. Pyke, to sell his Skins<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173704200006"></xptr> to him: they were no Property of mine. I can call several People to my Honesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17370420-4-person64">
                  Alice 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person64" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person64" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person65">
                  Thomas 
                  Sheriff 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person65" type="surname" value="Sheriff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person65" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person66">
                  Richard 
                  Powney 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person66" type="surname" value="Powney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person66" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person67">
                  John 
                  Addington 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person67" type="surname" value="Addington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person67" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person68">
                  Samuel 
                  Harford 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person68" type="surname" value="Harford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person68" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person69">
                  Absalom 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person69" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person69" type="given" value="Absalom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17370420-4-person70">
                  Mary 
                  Myers 
               <interp inst="t17370420-4-person70" type="surname" value="Myers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person70" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , appeared, and gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest Man. <rs id="t17370420-4-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17370420-4-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
