<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17381206-38">
               <interp inst="t17381206-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-38" type="year" value="1738"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17381206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17381206-38" type="date" value="17381206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17381206-38-off166-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-defend244 t17381206-38-off166 t17381206-38-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>41. 
               
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-defend244" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Dickinson 
                  <interp inst="t17381206-38-defend244" type="surname" value="Dickinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-defend244" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-defend244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17381206-38-defloc165">St. Mary le-Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-38-defloc165" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le-Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-38-defloc165" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-defend244 t17381206-38-defloc165"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17381206-38-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he, not having GOD before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17381206-38-cd167" type="crimeDate">16th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-off166 t17381206-38-cd167"></join>, in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17381206-38-victim246" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17381206-38-victim246" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-38-victim246" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17381206-38-victim246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-off166 t17381206-38-victim246"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously, &amp;c. did make an Assault, and with a certain Sword made of Iron and Steel, val. 5 s. &amp;c. him the said Peter in and upon the left Side of the lower Part of the Belly, near the Navel, did strike and stab, giving him a mortal Wound, of the Breadth of one Inch, and of the Depth of two Inches, of which mortal Wound he languish'd from the 16th of October to the 19th, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Statute for Stabbing. And</p>
               <p>He was a third time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest, for feloniously Slaying the said Price.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person247">
                  Robert 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person247" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person247" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. On Monday-Morning, between One and Two, I was going my Rounds, and heard a Noise in a Night-Cellar, where they sit up, all Night, and sell Beer and Ale, and any thing, and every thing. I ask'd my Beadle if I had any Power to go there, because 'tis out of my Parish? He told me I had. So I went and found People standing at the Cellar Door, whom I dispersed; then I went down into the Cellar, and saw a great many People, forty, I believe. The Woman of the Cellar led me to the farther Part of it, to some Women, that, she said, had been troublesome; when I returned to the Middle of the Cellar again, I saw the Prisoner and another <rs id="t17381206-38-deflabel168" type="occupation">Serjeant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-defend244 t17381206-38-deflabel168"></join> standing upright, and my Beadle said to me, - '' Master, '' here's a poor Man wounded! '' Wounded, says I, let me see! The Deceased was a Welsh Man, and spoke such broken English that I could hardly understand him; but he lifted up his Coat and Shirt, and I saw no Blood, but something that I thought had been a Wart upon his Belly: He kept groaning and sighing, and said he was stabb'd and murder'd; upon which I said, - Prithee let's look at it again; I saw it again, and perceived some Spots of Blood upon his Shirt, and that 'twas the poor Man's Cawl which hung half an Inch out of his Belly. I ask'd him who did it? He told me the Prisoner, who then stood near to, and facing the Box, where the Deceased sat, and made no Answer to what the Deceased said. I bid him be sure of what he said; - Yes, says he, That was the Serjeant, (pointing to the Prisoner) that stabb'd and kill'd me. Then I turn'd to the Prisoner, and told him I must secure him; he had his Sword then in his Belt, but Serjeant Duckworth, who stood by him, took hold of it, and turn'd the Point of it towards me, before I took it out of the Prisoner's Belt, that I might see the Point was naked, and without a Chape, (i.e. the Metal Cover at the Point of the Scabbard) I took notice of this, and after I had seiz'd the Sword, I order'd him to be carry'd to the Round-House, where I waited for the Deceased to come and confirm his Charge. He was no sooner came in, but I observ'd his Countenance change; so I sent for a Surgeon: And while he was gone for, I enquir'd again of the Deceased, how he came by his Wound? The Prisoner was present at the same time, and heard the Deceased tell me He was the Man that had stabb'd, and kill'd, and murder'd him. The Prisoner said, - '' Could I do it, with my Scabbard '' on, and my Sword-undrawn?'' The Deceased (in a Passion) said, '' Yes, you did it, - '' and, d - n you, you Villain, you know you did '' it. Your Sword was naked, and you knew it. '' I only said - it was not fair to draw upon a '' naked Man, and you said, - G - D d - mn your '' Bl - d, I'll stab you, and you did it directly.'' This was what the Deceased said, and I did not hear the Prisoner make any Answer at all to it.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060017"></xptr> When the Surgeon came, he said the Wound was dangerous, so I ordered a Bed for him (the Deceased) in the Watch-House. The Prisoner also had a Bed, and lay in the Watch-House that Night, and next Morning he was carried before Mr. Justice Hilder, and from thence to St. Martin's Round-House, as the securer Place. In the Evening the Surgeon declared his Sense of the Danger the Deceased was in, and desired the Justice might be sent for to him, before he died. Accordingly, I brought the Justice and Prisoner to the Deceased; he was then in a colour'd Coat, but the Deceased knew him immediately; the Justice gave him his Oath, and he swore that was the Man who murder'd him. I don't remember the Prisoner said any thing at all in his own Vindication.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was the Deceased sober at that time, or in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Burton. I can't tell; I believe he had been drinking.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person248">
                  William 
                  Roice 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person248" type="surname" value="Roice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Beadle) confirm'd Burton's Evidence: He said that while the Constable went to the farther End of the Cellar, he stood between the Prisoner and the Deceased, who told the Witness he was stabb'd by the Prisoner; and that he had only said to him, 'twas a Shame for him to draw upon a naked Man; to which the Prisoner did not answer one Word. The rest of his Evidence tallied with Mr. Burton's. He added, that he was one who attended the Deceased to the Watch-House, who seem'd likely to faint away several times, as they were bringing him along; that he went for the Surgeon who dress'd the Wound, and then the Deceased swore again at the Prisoner, and said he had kill'd him, and that his Sword was naked; that when the Justice was examining the Deceased, some body ask'd the Prisoner if he was not sorry? to which the Prisoner reply'd, - Sure, - I am sorry; he likewise said - the Deceased had been drinking, but he imagin'd he was sensible with regard to what he said and did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Sealy 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person249" type="surname" value="Sealy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a Watchman) deposed, that the Deceased was a <rs id="t17381206-38-viclabel169" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-victim246 t17381206-38-viclabel169"></join>; that he saw the Prisoner in the Strand, and heared him say, - D - mn your Bl - d, what signifies killing one Taylor, - eight more makes a Man. That he heard him, say this in Clare-street, when he was in the Custody of the Watchman and Constable. That he attempted to knock up one of the Watchmens Heels, that he might escape. That when the Prisoner and the Deceased were at the Watchhouse, the Deceased said - I am a dead Man, by G - d, - that's the Man that has killed me, - pointing to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. to Burlon. Did you hear the Prisoner say, when he was in your Custody, What signifies killing one Taylor, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Burton. No: but I was sometimes six or seven Yards behind him; I did not hear him say this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person250">
                  James 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person250" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person250" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             corroborated the Constable and Beadle's Testimony, in every other Respect, but this - He said the Prisoner refused to deliver up his Sword; that he, upon his Refusal, set down his Lanthorn and Staff, and told him, he would snap it in two, and that upon the other Serjeant's Persuasions he delivered it. That he had hold of him when he was carrying to the Watchouse, yet did not hear him say, - What signifies killing a Taylor, &amp;c. But, that he once turned about, - and he believed intended to have kicked up one of their Heels. That the Deceased, while the Surgeon was dressing him, started up and cry'd - d - mn your Bl - d (to the Prisoner) did I say any thing else to you than this, - '' It was not fair Play to draw '' upon a naked Man''? - upon which you said, - d - mn you, I'll stick you. And that the Prisoner did not answer a Word to this.</p>
               <p>[It was here urged that the Justices should endeavour to suppress these Night-Houses and Cellars, which served as harbouring Places, for loose, disorderly People.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person251">
                  Francis 
                  Sherrard 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person251" type="surname" value="Sherrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person251" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a Watchman) confirmed the Account the Constable, Beadle, and Andrews, gave of the Affair, from the Deceased's being led out of the Cellar, to his being put to Bed in the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person252">
                  John 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person252" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave exactly the same Accout with Sherrard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person253">
                  Catherine 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person253" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person253" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Widow of the Deceased, deposed, that she saw her Husband in Bed at the Watch-house at 7 o'Clock the next Morning; that he told her, he saw a Coachman and a Serjeant quarrelling against the Cellar-door. That he only said, It was not fair to draw upon a naked Man, upon which the Prisoner said, - G - d d - mn you, - you shall have it, and stabbed him. That he died at the Watch-house on Thursday following; that she attended him to his Death; found him sensible to the last, and that he did not vary in the Account to his last Minute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person254">
                  Richard 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person254" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person254" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the Coachman). I was coming out of this Cellar that Morning, between One and Two, and the Prisoner and another Serjeant came out likewise. The Prisoner's Comrade stood to make Water, at the Cellar-Head. As I passed them, I cursed my Fortune, that I had got<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060018"></xptr> no more Money that Day. The Man that was making Water damned me. I told him I said nothing to him; but he damned me again, and said he would thresh me. I walked on, but he followed me, and struck me in the Face, and the Prisoner came up, and twirled my Hat and Wig off, and gave me a Blow on the Shoulder. I had nothing in my Hand, nor did I strike at them, 'till they struck me. While we were quarrelling, two Men came by; then I said, if either of these Gentlemen will stand by me, I'll fight either of you; upon which one of the Gentlemen said, - if you'll fight one of them, I'll fight t'other. I made no more to do, but fell upon the Prisoner, and we both tumbled down in the Dirt, when I got up and ran away thirty or forty Yards; then I turn'd, and saw a naked Sword, and heard a Cane or Stick struck against the Ground, but I don't know who had either the Sword or the Stick, for I came no more near them.</p>
               <p>The Widow. My Husband had taken no Stick out with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person255">
                  John 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person255" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (another Coachman) said, - He saw a naked Sword in the Prisoner's Hand, while a little Man and a tall Man (between One and Two in the Morning) were disputing with him. That there was likewise a Gentleman present, who had a Stick in his Hand, and who got behind a Post and struck at the Sword with it. That the two Soldiers, upon this, went down into the Cellar, and the little Man threw a Handful of Dirt and Oyster Shells after them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person256">
                  Robert 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person256" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person256" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased's Brother, deposed, that the next Morning he went to the Watchhouse to see his Brother. That the Prisoner came and looked at the Deceased, and said, - nothing vexed him, but the Scoundrels dragging him along like a Thief. That the Surgeon came about ten o'Clock to dress him, and at that Time the Prisoner cry'd, - I did stick him! I did stick him! But you gave the Affront. To which the Deceased reply'd, - I only said, 'twas a Shame to draw upon a naked Man; I went up into a Corner away from you, but you followed me and stabbed me. This, he said, was spoke before the Prisoner, who answered not a Word, and when he was before the Justice he owned again, that he had stabbed him, and said, - Sure I am sorry. And the Deceased continued making the same Declaration to his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person257">
                  Sarah 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person257" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person257" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account of the Deceased's Words.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person258">
                  Henry 
                  Holdip 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person258" type="surname" value="Holdip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person258" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Surgeon) was sent for to the Deceased between Two and Three in the Morning, Oct. 16. and found a Wound, which had penetrated into the Cavity of the Belly, and the second of the small Guts was wounded. He said that a great Quantity of Blood was contained in the Cavity of the Belly, and the Guts inclined to a Mortification. That he believed he did say he received the Hurt from a Soldier; and that the Wound was the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person259">
                  Samuel 
                  Frost 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person259" type="surname" value="Frost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person259" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was coming by at the Time this happened, and saw four People giving hard Words to one another at the End of <placeName id="t17381206-38-crimeloc170">Swan-Yard, in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-38-crimeloc170" type="placeName" value="Swan-Yard, in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17381206-38-crimeloc170" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-off166 t17381206-38-crimeloc170"></join>, among whom were the Prisoner and the Deceased.</p>
               <p>This Witness went down into the Night-Cellar to drink; the Deceased came down after him, with his Cloaths unbuttoned, and shrieking. The Prisoner and his Comrade followed him, and the Deceased said to the Prisoner, - Lord, what have you done! The Prisoner said, - have I stabbed you? Yes, says the Deceased, and shewed the Wound; a Spot of Blood was upon his Shirt and something white hung out of his Belly. He added that one of the Men he saw quarreling was a little Man, and that the Deceased was a little Man.</p>
               <p>Defence. 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person260">
                  John 
                  Duckworth 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person260" type="surname" value="Duckworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account, that he and the Prisoner, and Serjeant Brown, had been drinking that Night, 'till between One and Two o'Clock, in this Cellar. That he went out first, the other two following him, and missing the Prisoner, he went back to the Cellar Door, and found him speaking to 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person261">
                  Dorothy 
                  Willmot 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person261" type="surname" value="Willmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person261" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and treating her with a Pint of Two-penny. That he then went from them seven or eight Yards to make Water, and a Man came up and d - mn'd, and said, he had been out all Night, and had got no Money. That he told the Man, he had been out too all Night, and had spent his Money. That upon this, the Man d - mn'd him again, and said, - He was one of K - G - s bad Bargains, and he had licked one of his Bull-Dogs, a Night or two ago, who was as big as himself (Meaning the Witness.) That he jostled up to him, tho' he told him he had no Inclination to quarrel, and the Prisoner hearing the Matter, came up, and asked him why he abused his Friend. That they both had him be gone, but he jostled between them, knocked the Prisoner down with his Fist, and then fell upon him; that he took off the Man, and while he was doing it, received several Blows from Stones or Oyster Shells. That by the Fall, the Prisoner's Hat flew off, and his Sword fell half- way out of his Belt, which the Witness took hold of, but the Prisoner drew it, Scabbard and all, through his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173812060019"></xptr> Hands, and the Chape was off, which was found in the Place where he fell, next Morning. That the Prisoner when he recovered his Sword, only kept his Arm straight, and the deceased running violently upon him, might receive the Point of it, the Prisoner not knowing (he believed) that the Chape was off, and the Point bare. He said, the Deceased immediately went down into Holder's Cellar, and was followed by himself and the Prisoner, to prevent having their Brains knocked out by Stones and Brickbats. That they were four or five Minutes in the Cellar before they knew the Deceased was the Man they quarrelled with; that he did not complain 'till Holder called the Constable, and that the Prisoner's Sword was never drawn at all. He said the Prisoner was as far from being a quarrelsome Man as any in the three Regiments.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person262">
                  Dorothy 
                  Willmot 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person262" type="surname" value="Willmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person262" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Duckworth's Evidence.</p>
               <p>Marget Holder gave an Account that the Deceased had been two or three times that Night at her Cellar, he had been very troublesome, and that she believed he was in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person263">
                  William 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person263" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             found the Chape of the Sword next Morning in the Street where the Scuffle: had been.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person264">
                  Walter 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person264" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person264" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Sword-Cutler, said the Chape of the Sword appear'd to him to be loose, and 'twas his Opinion it dropp'd off by Accident.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17381206-38-person265">
                  John 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person265" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             depos'd, That about three Weeks ago he heard Sharp (the former Evidence) say he saw a Sword drawn, and a Man with a Stick offering to strike, but he could not tell who held the Sword, nor who the Stick.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hilder depos'd, That when he was with the Deceased and the Prisoner, the Deceased said the Sword was drawn; the Prisoner said it was not; and when he was ask'd concerning the Stabbing of the Deceased, he neither own'd it, - nor denied it.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Phillips gave an Account of his having seen both the Prisoner and the Deceased in the Watch-House; that the Prisoner said the Accident happen'd by his engaging in a Quarrel, and he did not know the Chape of his Sword was off; that the Deceased's Wife was present, and said her Husband was at home at Twelve, but upon a Quarrel he went out again; and when a Man in the Watch-House told the Prisoner he might be let out; he said, - no, - if I have wounded the Man, 'twas innocently, and I'll do no such thing.</p>
               <p>Upon a Question from the Jury, the Surgeon gave his Opinion that the Wound might be made with the Sword as it was produced in Court (without the Chape.)</p>
               <p>Captain 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person266">
                  Car
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person266" type="given" value="Car"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person266" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Captain 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person267">
                  Hilsley
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person267" type="given" value="Hilsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person267" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Captain 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person268">
                  Boscawen
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person268" type="given" value="Boscawen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person268" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person269">
                  Edward 
                  Ellage 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person269" type="surname" value="Ellage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person269" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17381206-38-person270">
                  Francis 
                  Corderoy 
               <interp inst="t17381206-38-person270" type="surname" value="Corderoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person270" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of a peaceable, sober Man. <rs id="t17381206-38-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-verdict171" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17381206-38-punish172" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-punish172" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17381206-38-punish172" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17381206-38-defend244 t17381206-38-punish172"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
