<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17360610-32">
               <interp inst="t17360610-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-32" type="year" value="1736"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17360610"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17360610-32" type="date" value="17360610"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17360610-32-off136-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-32-defend241 t17360610-32-off136 t17360610-32-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>38. 
               
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-defend241" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Durant 
                  <interp inst="t17360610-32-defend241" type="surname" value="Durant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-defend241" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-defend241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17360610-32-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17360610-32-victim243" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Williams 
                        <interp inst="t17360610-32-victim243" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-32-victim243" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17360610-32-victim243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-32-off136 t17360610-32-victim243"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and giving him divers mortal Bruises with a Mopstick on his Head, Neck, Stomach, Back, Belly, Thighs, Knees and Legs; by reason of which mortal Bruises, from the <rs id="t17360610-32-cd137" type="crimeDate">5th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-32-off136 t17360610-32-cd137"></join> to the 27th of the said Month he languished, and then dy'd
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person244">
                  Mary 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person244" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person244" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceas'd was the Prisoner's <rs id="t17360610-32-viclabel138" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-32-victim243 t17360610-32-viclabel138"></join>: And because he did not do his Work better, he beat him on the 5th of May (excessively) and had no Mercy. I heard the Boy cry sadly, and heard him say, he would murder him. I saw no more of the Boy 'till he came before the Justice next morning; he liv'd three Weeks after this. The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17360610-32-deflabel139" type="occupation">Peruke-Ribbon-Weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17360610-32-defend241 t17360610-32-deflabel139"></join>. The Boy said he would do better, and the Prisoner said, D - you, I will beat you no more with my Fist, I will beat you with something else, I will murder you. He had a vast Cut upon his Head, and a Blow over his Eye, and his right Ear was perfectly lugg'd off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Skin broke?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. I did not see it, there was a Plaister upon it, but the People told me so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person245">
                  Ann 
                  Lewen 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person245" type="surname" value="Lewen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person245" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased was a very little Boy between 13 and 14 Years old: And I am a Neighbour and live just by. Hearing the Disturbance I look'd out of Doors and saw the poor Child going to the Justice's. I wash'd and dress'd him the same Day the Hurt was done him: He had a Cut on his Head, another on his Eyebrow, and his right Ear very black and seem'd as if it had been torn with Fingers, and the Blood run from his Temples about his Face, he was very wet, with his Master's throwing Water upon him. I saw blue Marks on his Neck, Shoulder and Stomach, the Breadth of my Finger. He told me his Master had beat him with a Mopstick, and had broke it into twenty pieces upon him, because he could not work; why, you are starv'd Child, says I, how should you work? No, says the Child, I can't say he starves me, for there's Bread and Cheese if I could eat it. I led him Home, and the next Day I saw him again, and his Fingers stood astrut, and he had Blows up to his Elbows: Then the Parish Barrow came to fetch him to the Work-house, but he was not able to walk, so the Beadle took him away in his Arms; and after this I never saw him alive.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person246">
                  Mary 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person246" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person246" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same House, and have heard Noises, but could not distinguish Words, nor what pass'd. I saw the Boy come down Stairs with his Face bloody, and his Master cry'd where are you going you Dog? and the Boy said, to do his Occasions; he took him back, and then I heard a rumbling Noise. One side of his Head and Face was black and blue; I think he liv'd about three Weeks after this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person247">
                  John 
                  Lowther 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person247" type="surname" value="Lowther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I attended him in the Work-house, and upon Examination I found several large Contusions about his Body, on his Head and right Temple; several on his Arms, Wrists, Fingers, and a large one on his right Knee. He was very much emaciated. I ask'd him the Reason of the Abuse, and he said, because he could not Work, his Master had beat him with a Mopstick. He was in a Consumption, and had a Cough, a Fever, and a Diarrhea upon him: But he must to be sure be worse for the Bruises, and they must hasten his Death: He all along charg'd his Master with his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person248">
                  Charles 
                  Balgay 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person248" type="surname" value="Balgay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person248" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I open'd the Body the 28th of May: I found him very much emaciated; nothing but Skin and Bone. He had a large Wound on the right Temple, but on opening the Head I found it had not affected the Scull; The Brain was clear and there was no extravasated Blood. The Bowels were all in Order, but on opening the Breast, I found the Lungs adher'd so strongly to the Pleura and Ribs, that I could hardly separate them. There were Marks of Violence upon him, but they went little farther than the skin; he was a very unfit Subject for such barbarous Usage, but I cannot think this was the immediate cause of his Death, tho' it might hasten it. I believe he could not have liv'd much longer.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="173606100013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person249" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard him say he would beat him till he kill'd him, and then he should be hang'd for him; and the Boy declared before the Justice, that his Master said he would end his Days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17360610-32-person250">
                  Benj 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person250" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person250" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Boy's Face bloody, but saw no stroke given.</p>
               <p>Defence. The Deceased flung his Shuttle at me, and I gave him a Blow with the back of my Hand, and made his Nose bleed. I don't know but the Bruises might come by a Fall; for the Spring of his Battins being broke, and got upon the top of the Loom to mend them, he fell down upon his Side; there was none but the Boy and I there, so I have no Witnesses. The Jury <rs id="t17360610-32-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him, and found that 
               <persName id="t17360610-32-person251">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17360610-32-person251" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17360610-32-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             died of a Consumption.</p>
            </div1>
