<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-11">
               <interp inst="t17430114-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-11" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-11" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-11-off56-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-11-defend136 t17430114-11-off56 t17430114-11-verdict59"></join>
         
               <p>77. +
               <persName id="t17430114-11-defend136" type="defendantName">
                  Ann 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-defend136" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-defend136" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-defend136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted, with another Person to the Jurors unknown, for <rs id="t17430114-11-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430114-11-victim138" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cooper 
                        <interp inst="t17430114-11-victim138" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-11-victim138" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-11-victim138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-11-off56 t17430114-11-victim138"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Money-bag, Value 1 d. and 35 s. in Money
            </rs>, his Property, <rs id="t17430114-11-cd57" type="crimeDate">Dec. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-11-off56 t17430114-11-cd57"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person139">
                  William 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person139" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person139" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Dec. 28th. As I was going into Shoe-Lane , to look after my Waggon, I met the Prisoner in <placeName id="t17430114-11-crimeloc58">Eagle and Child Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-11-crimeloc58" type="placeName" value="Eagle and Child Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-11-crimeloc58" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-11-off56 t17430114-11-crimeloc58"></join>, between Shoe-Lane and the New-Market. She laid hold of me, and cried out for Nan, Nan came in a Minute. - Not this 
               <persName id="t17430114-11-person140">
                  Nan 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person140" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person140" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were two Nans. Then they both laid hold of me, the Prisoner with her Right-Hand , and the other with her Left. The Prisoner had one Arm round me, and dived with the other into the left Pocket of my Breeches; and she pulled my Shirt out before she got to my Pocket. Then they both cried out for George, but George did not come. I cried out Murder, but no Soul came. - When she found my Shirt was not a Bag, she put her Hand into my Breeches Pocket, and took hold of the Bag. There was in the Bag 35 s. She got the Bag out. I got hold of the Bag as well as she: But she had got hold of the Money part. She gave it a Jerk out of my Hand, and gave it to the other Woman, and she run away with it. Then I takes fast hold of her. God gave me more Strength then, I think, than I have had for some Years. She cried out for George ; but, thank God, George did not come. I cried out, Murder, and dragged her quite down the Alley. And just at the end of the Alley stood three Men. I said to them, Gentlemen , I am robbed by this Creature, and beg your Assistance to help me to the White-Swan-Inn at Holbourn-Bridge, where my Horses were. Two of them would not. They asked, what I would give them. I told them, I would give them what Drink they would; but as to Money, I had none. One of them said, he would take the Country Man's Part, and he went along with me; I never let go my hold of the Prisoner, 'till I came to the Tap-house at the Swan ; and there I gave him part of two Pints of Beer. I thanked him, and craved his Name. But he said, he dared not tell it me, for he should be knocked on the Head by her Bullies if he should. She was that Night carried to the Counter: And next Morning, when she came before my Lord Mayor, she said I was suddled, and that my Shirt hung out of my Breeches; and that I took her up without any Reason. - My Pocket was then buttoned up, as it is now, that one would have thought it impossible for her to have got her Hand into it. - I looked in the Bag two or three Days before, and the Money was in then. I have had no Occasion to open it since, and I am sure the Money was in it. - I always lay my Breeches under my Pillow, so that no body could get to it. - I am sure the Bag was in my Pocket when she came up to me. - The Man that assisted me said, he lived in White Fryars . I enquired at 20 Houses, and could not find him.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. The Man came running down the Alley with his Shirt out, and said he was robb'd ; says he to me, you are the Woman that robb'd me, for I can find no Body else. I did not touch the Man.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person141">
                  Sarah 
                  Basset 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person141" type="surname" value="Basset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person141" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went down into the New Market on Tuesday after Christmas-Day, to buy my Husband something for Supper, and I saw that old Gentleman come and pull the Prisoner up Eagle and Child Alley, in a very indecent; Manner; his Breeches<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140008"></xptr> were down, and his Shirt hung out, and he said, I am robb'd, and you are the Woman that robb'd me. He had hold of her by the Arm, and cried out Murder; says she, you hurt my Arm, what would you have with me; he said, she had robb'd him, and he would give any Body a Dozen of Beer to go to some Inn with her. - He was hawling her into that Part of the Alley that comes into the Market; there was abundance of Mob in two or three Minutes, and there was a Gentlewoman that came down the Alley, and said, Master, do not murder your Wife. - I saw their Faces very plain; I took Notice of her, because she is a black Woman, and so the more remarkable; and I thought it a little strange, that an old Man should want a Woman. - It was about a Quarter after eight at Night. - I did not see the Man till he cried out Murder; I was among the other Mob; there was a Lamp which he hawl'd her up to, which was as nigh as the Candle is to you.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person142">
                  Ann 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person142" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person142" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That old Gentleman was in Eagle and Child Alley the Tuesday in Christmas Week, with two other Women. - Both fair Women; one in a Cloak, and the other without: (I keep a House, or my Husband does, in Eagle and Child Alley, next Door to Mr Pauley's, an Alehouse-keeper, at the Sign of the Three Compasses.) They were first under the Lamp; and as the People came down, the Women mov'd backward and forward, and the old Gentleman stood with his Back to the Corner: I only speak this to show that there were two Women with him, and his Shirt hung a little indecently out of his Breeches; I had no Business to see what they were doing of, because it was immodest: I had a Candle in my Hand at my own Gate, and I had a thorough Sight of the Women, and I heard somebody say, Do not murder your Wife. Said he, G - d d - n her, I do not murder her. - You, honest Man! can you deny these Words?</p>

               <p>Cooper. Yes, I can; I am sure I never said so.</p>

               <p>Phillips. Did not you ask me to help you?</p>

               <p>Cooper. Why did not you help me then?</p>

               <p>Phillips. Then the Mob cried, What's the Matter, honest Man? And he said, I am robb'd! I am robb'd! I will give you a Gallon of Beer to take her away to some Place; where he said, I cannot tell. - The Woman he was pulling up the Alley was a black Woman. - There were abundance of People, black-guard Boys and Girls: Her Arm looked very big, as if it was swell'd.</p>

               <p>Q. to Cooper. Did you see this Woman in Eagle and Child Alley that Night?</p>

               <p>Cooper. No, I wish this Hand may rot off if! did.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person143">
                  Mary 
                  Forrester 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person143" type="surname" value="Forrester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person143" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner from a Child; I never heard any Thing amiss of her before: She did go to Service, but she has not been at Service for a great while.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person144">
                  Ann 
                  Judge 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person144" type="surname" value="Judge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person144" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have kept a House sixteen Years , and have trusted her in my Shop with all I had , and she never wrong'd me of a Penny; I have known her from a Child; her Father was a Black Man , and used to teach Gentlemen to Fence. - I cannot tell how long she has been from her Father and Mother. - I believe I have not seen her this Year or two, - and by what I know of her, I would trust her again with any Thing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person145">
                  Mary 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person145" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person145" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the Prisoner from a Child; her Mother is an honest good Woman; as to the Prisoner's Behaviour of late, I know nothing.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person146">
                  James 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person146" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person146" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Church-Warden of St Sepulchre's , and at that Time I was obliged to be Church-Warden, Constable, Beadle, Watchman, and all; she came into the Watch-House indeed with her Arm bound up, that is true.</p>

               <p>Cooper. I am sure I never hurt her Arm.</p>

               <p>Townsend. I do not believe you did. - It was bound up from the Elbow to the Wrist; she said to the Prosecutor, how could I clasp you with both Arms, when I am a Cripple with one. - She did offer to have her Arm unbound, but I did not do it. - She did not give any Account what was the Reason of its being bound up. - The People at the Watch-House thought it was bound on Purpose to deceive them. I do not believe there was any great Matter of a Wound.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Doctor Lee gives me Stuff for it now: and when I was before the Lord-Mayor, I could not stir Hand nor Finger.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person147">
                  Charles 
                  Pickfat 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person147" type="surname" value="Pickfat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person147" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live upon Holbourn-Hill , I have lived there all my Life Time; and our Neighbourhood is become now so notorious, that we have more Thieves between our Parts and Deputy Nash's , than in any Part of the Town: The Prisoner at the Bar I know to be a common Street-Walker, and has been so a great many Years. - Plying between my House and Fetter-Lane, decoying and seducing Mankind.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-11-person148">
                  Joshua 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-11-person148" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person148" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I kept a Publick-House a little while ago, and Mrs Phillips, the Witness, who lives next Door to the Three Compasses in Eagle and Child Alley, and her Husband, frequented my House, and I never saw any Ill by them; but I have heard a bad Character since: As to the Prisoner at the Bar, her Character is very vile, as bad as can<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140009"></xptr> be at all ; she is very notorious, I believe. <rs id="t17430114-11-verdict59" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-11-verdict59" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
