<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-61">
               <interp inst="t17401015-61" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-61" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-61" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-61" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-61-off327-c323" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-defend406 t17401015-61-off327 t17401015-61-verdict331"></join>
         
               <p>498. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-defend406" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Cook 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-61-defend406" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-defend406" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-defend406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401015-61-defloc326">Finchley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-61-defloc326" type="placeName" value="Finchley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-61-defloc326" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-defend406 t17401015-61-defloc326"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17401015-61-off327" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-off327" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-off327" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17401015-61-victim407" type="victimName">
                        James 
                        Thomason 
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-victim407" type="surname" value="Thomason"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-61-victim407" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-61-victim407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-off327 t17401015-61-victim407"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Mare of a Bay Colour, val. 8 l. the Property of William Davis, a Pair of Silver Buckles, val. 5 s. a Half-Guinea, and 5 s. 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of James Thomason, <rs id="t17401015-61-cd328" type="crimeDate">September 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-off327 t17401015-61-cd328"></join>.</p>
               <p>James Thomason. I live with Mr Parker in Aldermanbury. On the 29th of September, I was sent for to Whetstone ; and returning to London, about a Quarter before 7 in the Evening, I was stopped between the 7 and 8 Mile Stone, on <placeName id="t17401015-61-crimeloc329">Finchley-Common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-61-crimeloc329" type="placeName" value="Finchley-Common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-61-crimeloc329" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-off327 t17401015-61-crimeloc329"></join>, by a Person on a little Bay Poney; who it was, I can't say, for it was Night. I was on a Bay Mare which belonged to William Davis. The Man who stopped me, presented a Pistol, and swore he would shoot me through the Body, if I did not give him my Money; I was very much terrified, and he took from me a Half-Guinea, two Half-Crowns, 6 d. and a pair of Silver Buckles; he likewise took the Mare which I rode, and left me his in the Room. After this was done, he went toward the Right-hand of the Common; the Mare was advertised, and the Prisoner taken upon her; but whether he is the Person that robbed me, I can't tell. I can't say but the Prisoner may be about the Size of the Man who attack'd me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He advertised the Mare, and I picked her up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person408">
                  John 
                  Kerton 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person408" type="surname" value="Kerton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person408" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Thursday after the Robbery was committed, a Boy at Barnet told me, that a Man had stolen a Mare, and was upon her about 200 Yards off; I went after him, but missed Sight of him, and coming back I met a Man, who was likewise in pursuit of him; he desired me to go with him, I did so, and we met the Prisoner on the Mare. We seized him with the Assistance of one or two more, and pulled him off the Mare, down on his Back. When we first took hold of him, he swore he would shoot the next Man that touched him; upon that we searched him for Arms, and found 2 Brace of Pistols loaded in his Pockets, and a Hanger concealed under his coat; not visible to any Body. I did not see his Pistols before he was taken, if I had, I should have been cautious of touching him. We tied his Hands, and carried him to Whetstone , and sent for the Man who was robbed, but he could only swear to the Mare. The Prisoner said, before the Justice, that he was in Debt, and carried those Arms about him only for his Guard. These are the Pistols, and one of them we found loaded.</p>
               <p>Thomason. I saw this Mare which the Prisoner was taken upon, and is the same that was taken from me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Kerton, whether I behaved like such a Man when he seized me?</p>
               <p>Kerton. When he was pulled down on his Back, and could do nothing, he said he was in Debt. The Man looked to have no Harm in him. The<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150029"></xptr> Pistols were in his Pockets, the Hanger was under his Coat, and not visible to any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person409">
                  George 
                  Christmas 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person409" type="surname" value="Christmas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person409" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I pursued the Prisoner, having had a Description of the Mare, and desired another Man to help me. I assisted in taking him, and saw the Pistols taken out of his Pockets, and the Hanger from under his Coat. He said, he was not afraid of any Thing we could do to him, for he was in Debt, and carried those Arms about him for his own Safety.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person410">
                  Samuel 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person410" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person410" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking of the Prisoner, he said when he was down, he had no Occasion to fear any Body, and if we would let him get up, he would go any where with us. We asked him how he came by the Mare, and he said, that he found her on the Common. I saw the Pistols taken out of his Pockets, and the Hanger from under his coat.</p>
               <p>Defence. On Thursday Morning I was going to gather Mushrooms, and saw this Mare bridled and sadled upon the Common; she was advertised, reasonable charges born, and no Questions asked, but I can't tell what Paper it was in.</p>
               <p>Thomason. The Mare was advertised, to be left at the Axe-Inn in Aldermanbury.</p>
               <p>Kerton. When we took him he was in a back Road, and said he was going to Enfield .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person411">
                  Mary 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person411" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Enfield : The Prisoner lay at my House Tuesday and Wednesday, he is no Relation, only a Friend. I have known him a great while, he is a <rs id="t17401015-61-deflabel330" type="occupation">Leather-Cutter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-61-defend406 t17401015-61-deflabel330"></join>, and lives at Stratford . When he came to my House he was on Foot, and carried away a Pair of Boots, which my Husband wanted to be done. I don't know where he was on the Monday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person412">
                  Robert 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person412" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person412" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner these 8 Years, he is a Cordwainer, and keeps a House at Stratford : I live in Shoreditch Parish . He was with me on Sunday about Noon, and said he was going to a Christening to his Wife. On the Monday he din'd with me at Haggerstone : he left me between 1 and 2 in the Afternoon, and said he was going to Enfield . I know him to be very honest, but in Debt. He was very shy of the Bailiffs, and I know that he has had a Hanger and Pistols a pretty while, but I saw none on him when he was at my House. I have seen him have them sometimes, and when he has come in, he used to lay them down, and take them up when he went away. I take him to be very honest, as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person413">
                  Thomas 
                  Hodson 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person413" type="surname" value="Hodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person413" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew him when he was 6 or 7 Years old his Father and Mother are very honest People, and as for being in Debt, I know he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person414">
                  Thomas 
                  Harvey 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person414" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person414" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Stratford . I know this poor young Fellow; he has (been) absconded from his Family a long while, but I never heard of his Dishonesty.</p>
               <p>Zaccheus Bourne. I have had Knowledge of the Prisoner some Years, and never heard any thing a miss of him in my Life. I am Beadle of Aldgate Parish , and his Father lives in Aldgate Parish now, and is a Man of Reputation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person415">
                  John 
                  Organ 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person415" type="surname" value="Organ"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person415" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between 6 and 7 Years, and have served him with Bread; he has a great Family, and I always thought him a very honest young Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person416">
                  Thomas 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person416" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person416" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 6 Years, and took him to be a very honest, industrious Man. I serv'd him with Shoes, and all the Time I dealt with him he behaved well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-61-person417">
                  Anthony 
                  Spire 
               <interp inst="t17401015-61-person417" type="surname" value="Spire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person417" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between 6 and 7 Years, and he always bore a very good Character: I never heard any thing amiss of him, his Father is a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>The Jury withdrew for some time to consider of their Verdict, when they found him <rs id="t17401015-61-verdict331" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-61-verdict331" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Not Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
