<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451016-22">
               <interp inst="t17451016-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-22" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-22" type="date" value="17451016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451016-22-off120-c181" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-22-defend225 t17451016-22-off120 t17451016-22-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>388. 
               
                  <persName id="t17451016-22-defend225" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17451016-22-defend225" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-defend225" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-defend225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17451016-22-defloc119">St. Clement Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-22-defloc119" type="placeName" value="St. Clement Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-22-defloc119" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-22-defend225 t17451016-22-defloc119"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17451016-22-off120" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-off120" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-off120" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver medal, value 2 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17451016-22-victim227" type="victimName">
                     Frances 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17451016-22-victim227" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-victim227" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-victim227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-22-off120 t17451016-22-victim227"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17451016-22-cd121" type="crimeDate">October 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-22-off120 t17451016-22-cd121"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-22-person228">
                  Frances 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17451016-22-person228" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-person228" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . (About fourteen years of age, <rs id="t17451016-22-viclabel122" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-22-victim227 t17451016-22-viclabel122"></join> to Mrs. Stockes, a mantua-maker ) I was going to the post house on Tuesday was se'nnight with a letter about nine o'clock at night, and the Prisoner laid hold of me by the two shoulders, and took me up into a court, put her hand into my pocket, and took a medal out. Then says she you shall go along with me. She said, this is not silver. I said, it was silver. And she said , D - n it, 'tis not silver; I think I should know silver . Then she took me into Drury-lane , and a watchman seeing me, said, that child does not belong to you: and he asked her where she was going to take me; and she said to one Morris : and then the watchman took her up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What time did the watchman lay hold of me?</p>
               <p>Wilson. About eleven o'clock .</p>
               <p>Q. What was she doing all this time from nine o'clock to eleven ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174510160016"></xptr>Wilson. She was dragging me from one place to another; and when she took the money out of my pocket, she stopped my mouth.</p>
               <p>The Watchman. The Prisoner and this girl were coming down Drury-Lane about eleven o'clock. I said to the Prisoner, where are you going? Said she, I am going to bed, (that was at one Morris's.) I the child's arm, and said, do you know where you are going? And she said, she did not know. I her, whether she had lost any she had left a silver medal. I had, this does not look like one that is going to such a place. I took her to the watchhouse, and where the medal was Then the Prisoner the piece of silver out of her, and threw it down upon the table in the was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Don't say so, for I had it in my hand all the time.</p>
               <p>Watchman. Then we took the piece of silver and looked at it, and for the girl's mistress, and the girl's father and mother and they came .</p>
               <p>Q. What did the girl say then?</p>
               <p>Watchman. She said the Prisoner had taken her into an alley and beat her , and took the piece of silver out of her pocket by force.</p>
               <p>Mark Harding (Constable ) I was in the watch-house when this child was brought in: she trembled and was frightened out of her wits: she shook as if she had got an ague , and she said the Prisoner had got a pocket piece of hers . The Prisoner denied it, but the child said she was sure she had it; and then she pulled it out, and threw it down upon the table. I am sure this is the piece the Prisoner threw down. [The child claimed that as her medal.]</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had been washing at Grosvenor's Meuse, and was going towards Drury-lane , and met this child. She find she wanted a lodging. Said I, my dear, you look like a creditable person's child, and not as if you wanted a lodging. She said she had staid out too late, and did not care to go home.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wilson. You said she met you about nine o'clock, and the watchman says he saw you with her about eleven: what did she do with you all this while ?</p>
               <p>Wilson . She took me out of one court into another, and so from place to place .</p>
               <p>Jury . Where does your mistress live?</p>
               <p>Wilson . In Arundel-street in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you to carry the letter to?</p>
               <p>Wilson. To the Temple.</p>
               <p>Q. That a publick place; if you had called to your assistance they must have come: it is very odd you should be carried all this way by force; you went thought Temple Bar, did not you ?</p>
               <p>Wilson . No, she stopped me before I came to Temple Bar .</p>
               <p>Q. Then you met her at Temple Bar ?</p>
               <p>Wilson . No, she came behind me just before I was got to Temple Bar, took me by the shoulder, and said, D - n you, you shall go along with me ; and she took me into a little place by Temple Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you in the street all this time, form two hours together ?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Jury to Mrs. Stokes. What time did you send this girl out with the letter ?</p>
               <p>Stokes. I think it was about nine o'clock, but I am not certain. This girl has been with me a year and a quarter, and the never out in her life: I have always used her as if she was a child of my own, and she had no to be afraid of coming home. <rs id="t17451016-22-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-22-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
