<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-35">
               <interp inst="t17430907-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-35" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-35" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-35-off181-c277" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-35-defend342 t17430907-35-off181 t17430907-35-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>408. 
               
                  <persName id="t17430907-35-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Carter 
                  <interp inst="t17430907-35-defend342" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-defend342" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-defend342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17430907-35-defloc180">St Leonard Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-35-defloc180" type="placeName" value="St Leonard Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-35-defloc180" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-35-defend342 t17430907-35-defloc180"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17430907-35-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430907-35-victim344" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Lewis 
                        <interp inst="t17430907-35-victim344" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-35-victim344" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-35-victim344" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-35-off181 t17430907-35-victim344"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by casting and throwing of a Knife made of Iron and Steel, value 1 d. * at the said 
                     <persName id="t17430907-35-person345">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Lewis 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person345" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-35-person345" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-35-person345" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; by which casting and throwing she gave her a mortal Wound on the left Side of the Breast, near the Collar Bone, of the Length of one Inch, and the Depth of three Inches, of which Wound she instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430907-35-cd182" type="crimeDate">July 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-35-off181 t17430907-35-cd182"></join>.</p>
               <p>* In an Indictment for Murder, the Value of the Weapon is found by the Jury; for the Weapon is a Deodand, forfeited to the King; and the Township are chargeable for the Value, if delivered to them.</p>
               <p>She stood a second Time charged on the Coroner's Inquisition, for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>The Examination of 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person346">
                  Susannah 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person346" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person346" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person346" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , taken by Justice Wroth, July 16, 1743, was prov'd viz.</p>
               <p>This Examinant saith, that about five o'Clock this Morning, she having some Difference in Words with one 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person347">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person347" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person347" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lodged in the same House with this Examinant, she took a Knife that lay near her, and threw it at the said 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person348">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person348" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person348" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which gave her a Wound in the Breast, of which Wound she instantly died.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-35-person349">
                  Samuel 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person349" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person349" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On the 20th of July, the Church-Warden of Shoreditch Parish came, and desired me to look at the Body of the Deceased, which I did; and there was a Wound on the upper Part of the left Side of the Body, which penetrated between the first and second Rib, and there was a large Quantity of extravasated Blood lodg'd upon the Diaphragma; I am persuaded this Wound occasioned her Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-35-person350">
                  Ann 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person350" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person350" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Kingsland Road, next Door to the Gentleman and Porter, the 16th of July, in the Morning, the Prisoner got up a little before four o'Clock, to hang up some Cloaths for Mrs Hornibrook, and afterwards sat herself down to cut some Matches; and the deceased 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person351">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person351" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person351" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in pretty much in Liquor; 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person352">
                  Susannah 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person352" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person352" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person352" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said to the Deceased, You B - h, you have been great with a Butcher in White-chapel for Sweet-Breads and Kidneys - 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person353">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person353" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person353" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had a Husband somewhere, but they did not live together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Carter begin to quarrel with Lewis, or Lewis with Carter?</p>
               <p>Price. They both began to quarrel together; but Carter's saying that, made 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person354">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person354" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person354" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             angry; and 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person355">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person355" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person355" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to Carter, You B - h, I never gave the Carman the Clap in White-chapel; then Susannah Carter says to her, Say so again, and I will do you a Mischief (they lodged in the same House, and both lay together) the Deceased said the same Words over again; then Susannah Carter took hold of a Basket, and hurled it on one Side, in order to get to the Door, and threw a little broken Knife out of her Hand, that she was cutting her Matches with - she threw the Knife down, when she went to open the Door to get to the Deceased<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070018"></xptr> - they were both in the same Room at first, and 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person356">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person356" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person356" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went into the other Room for fear of Mischief, and shut the Door - then Susannah Carter thrust her two Hands against the Door and pushed it open (I did not see any Thing in her Hands) and immediately the Deceased came out, and said, Lord, Lord, look how she has stabbed me; she was stabbed in the Breast, on her left Side.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Knife slick in?</p>
               <p>Price. I did not see the Knife till it was found bloody; then, I said, 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person357">
                  Betty 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person357" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person357" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is in a Fit, and I got a little Water; but all we could do was to no Purpose, for she died presently.</p>
               <p>Q. What did 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person358">
                  Susannah 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person358" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person358" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say?</p>
               <p>Price. 
               <persName id="t17430907-35-person359">
                  Susannah 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person359" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person359" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             owned she did it, and did not desire to go away - the Deceased died in about four Minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner shew any Concern about it?</p>
               <p>Price. She did not look much concerned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-35-person360">
                  Mary 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person360" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person360" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was lying upon a Couch, where the Prisoner was sitting, cutting of Matches; I was asleep, but the Noise waked me; when I awaked, I heard the Prisoner say, You B - h, I never was concerned with the Butcher in White-chapel for Sweet-Breads and Kidneys; the Deceased made answer, and said, I never gave a Butcher nor a Carman the Clap in White-chapel; the Prisoner said, if you say so again I will do you a Mischief; the Deceased rehearsed it over again; and being in Liquor, aggravated the Prisoner very much; the Deceased was in another Room - the Door was shut when these Words passed; there was but a slight Partition, that they might hear very well - the Deceased began first, for she was very much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Deceased in Bed or up?</p>
               <p>Brown. She was in Bed; the Prisoner then opened the Door - there was no Lock upon the Door, it was a Sort of a Spring Bolt, tied with two Strings, and they were twisted round a Nail; and the Door was easily got open; the first Thing I saw, was, that the Prisoner laid hold of a Knife; which, I suppose, was the first Thing that came to her Hand - it lay upon a Chest of Drawers, and she flung it at the Deceased - I saw her sling it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then she did not stab her ?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, she flung it at her, and she received a Wound under the Collar-Bone, on the left Side; and the Deceased said, Lord, Lord, see how she has stabbed me.</p>
               <p>Jury. Stabbing implies a sticking with the Knife in her Hand; did she strike her with it in her Hand, or did she throw it at her?</p>
               <p>Brown. She flung it, I do assure you.</p>
               <p>Jury. At what Distance was it flung ?</p>
               <p>Brown. About two Yards and an half - then the Deceased said, Lord, Lord, see how she has stabbed me; and the Prisoner said, I am sorry for it; and if I have done it, I am willing to suffer, I will not run away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you upon your Oath say she threw it at her?</p>
               <p>Brown. She flung it at her, I do assure you - I will never vary a Tittle for the best Person upon Earth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-35-person361">
                  John 
                  Rumbold 
               <interp inst="t17430907-35-person361" type="surname" value="Rumbold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person361" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Parish Officer; I was called up at five o'Clock in the Morning; when I came into the House I saw a Woman lying dead; I asked who did it; the Prisoner said, she did it, and that she was sorry for it; I told her, she would be hanged, she said, she could not help it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I got up between three and four o'Clock that Morning, and was cutting of Matches, when she came in drunk; I got some Gin for her, and she would have had me have got some Tobacco; and as I would not do that, she abused, and aggravated me very much, and, I said, I would lick her; but my Landlady hindered me, says she, let her come; and as I could not come to her, I took up the Knife, and threw at her. <rs id="t17430907-35-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-verdict183" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430907-35-punish184" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-punish184" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-35-punish184" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-35-defend342 t17430907-35-punish184"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
