<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450424-15">
               <interp inst="t17450424-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-15" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-15" type="date" value="17450424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450424-15-off89-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-defend167 t17450424-15-off89 t17450424-15-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>206. 
               
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-defend167" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Sommers , otherwise <rs id="t17450424-15-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-defend167 t17450424-15-alias-4"></join>Sommerville</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-defend167" type="surname" value="Sommers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-defend167" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-defend167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17450424-15-defloc87">Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-15-defloc87" type="placeName" value="Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-15-defloc87" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-defend167 t17450424-15-defloc87"></join>, was indicted, for that he after the 1st day of May 1734, to wit. on the <rs id="t17450424-15-cd88" type="crimeDate">2d day of April 1745</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-off89 t17450424-15-cd88"></join>, <rs id="t17450424-15-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain field or open place near the King's highway, upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450424-15-victim169" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           James 
                        <interp inst="t17450424-15-victim169" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-15-victim169" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-15-victim169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-off89 t17450424-15-victim169"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, and in a forcible and violent manner the money of the said Edward feloniously did demand, with a felonious intent the money of the said 
                     <persName id="t17450424-15-person170">
                        Edward 
                        James 
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person170" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-15-person170" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-15-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   to steal, take, and carry away, against the form of the statute, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person171">
                  Edward 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person171" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person171" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (a black) On the 2d of April about 10 o'clock in the morning, as I was going about my business, the prisoner stopped me in a field.</p>
               <p>Q. What business are you?</p>
               <p>James, I am a trumpet - I have been in the King's service, but I am not now. - I was going to pay some money to the woman at the Adam and Eve at Pancras. The prisoner said he wanted my money; I said I had none for my self, nor he neither. (I had 3 s. 6 d. in my pocket, and was going to pay half a crown away) He struck at me with a bag, jumped upon me, and seized me. He pulled and hawled me, and tore all my clothes. I bid him let me alone, for he should get no good of me. And he said, you black son of a b - h I'll be revenged on you, and finding he could get no good of me, he let me go, and went away. Then he came back, and attacked me again, laid hold of me, and said, you are not gone yet; but he soon let go his hold and run. There happened to be a gentleman and his lady in the church-yard ; the gentleman said he saw all the action, and advised me to get an officer to take him up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he strike at you with?</p>
               <p>James. He struck at me with a bag with an empty cag in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say when he struck at you?</p>
               <p>James. He demanded my money. I had a young woman with me, and she bid him be easy; and he struck at her, and knocked her down upon her back.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know that ever I saw him in my life. Ask him what I had to strike the gentlewoman down with.</p>
               <p>James. He struck her down with his fist, but he struck me with the cag, and stripped himself naked to fight me, at the second attack; and when he ran away, I followed him, and took him - the prisoner was not drunk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person172">
                  Mary 
                  Mustafer 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person172" type="surname" value="Mustafer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person172" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the second of April, Mr. James asked me to take a walk with him to Pancras , we met the prisoner at the bar, and he stopped us, and said, he would have money, and struck at 
               <persName id="t17450424-15-person173">
                  Edward 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person173" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person173" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with a cask or something in a bag; and took hold of him by the waistcoat and shirt and pulled him first one way and then another.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say he wanted?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174504240011"></xptr>Mustaser . He said he wanted money and revenge and he would have it by G - d. I believe he quarrelled with him about three quarters of an hour, then he went away, and came back again presently, and said, by G - d you are not gone yet, and money I will have before I go home.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do in this case, when they were quarrelling?</p>
               <p>Mustaser . I went up to the prisoner, and desired him to be easy; and he struck me down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he strike you?</p>
               <p>Mustafer . He struck me upon my breast.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>Mustafer . I can't remember what he said, he bid me be gone or something like that. Justice Hole was by, and saw all the action done.</p>
               <p>Justice Hole deposed, That he had been taking a walk with his lady, and setting in Pancras church-yard, he saw the prisoner take up his bag and strike at the black, and struck the woman, who was with him; and that he fell upon some persons who came by before, and they took to their heels, and run for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person174">
                  Charles 
                  Turnell 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person174" type="surname" value="Turnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person174" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . When he was carried before Justice Poulson, he was very much fuddled, but he had no weapon about him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person175">
                  James 
                  Burgess 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person175" type="surname" value="Burgess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person175" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the beadle.) About ten o'clock in the morning, the Black said, he wanted a constable, for he had been ill used in the fields; and the prisoner was taken; he submitted himself and asked pardon: I believe he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Justice Hole. I am sure, my lord, he could run as well as I could.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was very much fuddled; I <rs id="t17450424-15-viclabel90" type="occupation">deal in liquors</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-15-victim169 t17450424-15-viclabel90"></join>, and sell them in the country - I am an Irishman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person176">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person176" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person176" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner five or six years; he used to deal in liquors. I take him to be an honest man, I never saw any otherwise by him; he will get drunk now and then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person177">
                  Catharine 
                  Shaw 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person177" type="surname" value="Shaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person177" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years, he has the character of an honest labouring man, and I believe he would not hurt man, woman, or child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person178">
                  John 
                  Hawksley 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person178" type="surname" value="Hawksley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person178" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner buys brandy frequently at my house: I give him credit more or less, he has dealt with me four or five years. I take him to be an honest man, and I can't conceive he would be guilty of any such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-15-person179">
                  John 
                  Hatfield 
               <interp inst="t17450424-15-person179" type="surname" value="Hatfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person179" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the prisoner some years, he has been my tenant ever since I have known him, and I believe him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilson said, he had known him five years, always took him to be a pains-taking, hardworking man, and always bore a vast good character. Being asked whether he is apt to be quarrelsom when in liquor, he said, he is apt to be quarrelsom. <rs id="t17450424-15-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-15-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>*.</p>
               <p>* Though the prisoner was acquitted of the assault with an intent to rob, he might have been indicted for an assault; which would have been done, if it had not been compromised between the parties.</p>
            </div1>
