<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-19">
               <interp inst="t17400416-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-19" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-19" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-19-off106-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-defend149 t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>210 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-19-defend149" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Collet 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-defend149" type="surname" value="Collet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-defend149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-defend149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400416-19-defloc105">Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-defloc105" type="placeName" value="Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-defloc105" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-defend149 t17400416-19-defloc105"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-19-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-19-victim151" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Curtis 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-19-victim151" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-19-victim151" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-19-victim151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-victim151"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Field, and open Place, near the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from her 12 Pence Halfpenny
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-19-cd107" type="crimeDate">April 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-cd107"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mary Curtis. Last Easter-Monday , about 12 o'Clock at Noon, I was walking between <placeName id="t17400416-19-crimeloc108">Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc108" type="placeName" value="Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc108" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-crimeloc108"></join> and <placeName id="t17400416-19-crimeloc109">London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc109" type="placeName" value="London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc109" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-crimeloc109"></join>, and the Prisoner came up to me in a Field, joining to <placeName id="t17400416-19-crimeloc110">Fig-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="Fig-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-19-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-19-off106 t17400416-19-crimeloc110"></join> , and ask'd me for some Money. I told him, I had but a Shilling to pa y my Coach-hire, and I pulled out a Shilling, and a Halfpenny at the same Time, which I gave him, and then he went off. He had something in his Hand, which surprized me, (being alone) tho' I can't tell what it was: he presented nothing to me. I was 'frighted because I was alone, and had a Guinea about me, and more Shillings: but he did not threaten me with any Words, nor did he lay Hands on me; and there were People passing along in every Fields, but this. - I can't say the Prisoner is the Person; but a Man saw him with me, and pursued him, and took him. The Man who saw<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160013"></xptr> him with me, came up to me, after he had got the Shilling, and asked me if he had not robbed me? I said, - nothing but a Shilling which I had given him. He had something in his Pocket, but I can't tell what it was, for I was in a Surprize, and alone. I was not in Fear of his proceeding to use Violence, because there were People in all the Fields. - He offered no Violence to me. I was afraid because I was alone, and I saw Part of something in his Hand, but I could not tell what it was, being alone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-19-person152">
                  William 
                  Staples 
               <interp inst="t17400416-19-person152" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person152" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . This young Woman and my Master were walking together from Hampstead, and just before they came to this Field they parted, and she went down the Field. I was upon the Shafts of my Cart, driving towards London, and saw a Man run up to the young Woman in the Field: she drew back, and he followed her: and I saw her put her Hand into her Pocket, and give him something. Then I jump'd off the Copses of the Cart, and made up to her. When I was come within 20 Yards of her, I asked her if the Man had not robb'd her? She said, yes: upon which I desired her not to be frighted, but to make over to the Houses, and I would bring the Man back to her. I pursu'd the Prisoner, and he took to his Heels, and ran up the the Field, into the Road that goes to St Giles's, and from thence into another Field, and as he was getting over a Bank, I saw another Man, and called out to him to stop the Prisoner. The Man caught hold of him, and collared him immediately: He struggled to get away, but I got up to his Assistance in a Minute, and told the Prisoner, he must go back to the young Woman, for I did not know what he had taken from her. The Prisoner is the Man; he is altered in his Dress now, but I remember his Face particularly well.</p>
               <p>Q. to Curtis. Did not you apprehend you was robbed at that Time?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I did give him a Shilling, and desired him not to follow me. - I gave it to him.</p>
               <p>Staples. He had no Pistol about him when we took him, but he had a Tinderbox made in the Shape of a Pistol, and a Gardener's Knife naked in his Pocket: and when we took him, we carry'd him to a publick House, where the young Woman swoon'd away several Times at the Sight of him. - We had much ado to bring her to herself.</p>
               <p>Curtis . I was more surprized when he was taken, than I was before.</p>
               <p>Jury. What did the young Woman say concerning the Prisoner, when she recovered out of her Fits?</p>
               <p>Staples. She told us the Prisoner came up to her, and asked her for some Money: that she put her Hand into her Pocket, and dropped a Halfpenny; and that she afterwards pulled out a Shilling, and gave it him; and that he told her, if she would not give him the Money, he must take it.</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes, my Lord, he did say so.</p>
               <p>Jury. How came you not to say so at first?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I have not been apply'd to; - I should be sorry to take a Man's Life away.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was the Prisoner in Liquor at that Time? (To Staples.)</p>
               <p>Staples. No: he told us he had neither eat nor drank that Day; till we took him to the Publick-house, and there he drank Part of two Pots of Beer. When the Constable came, he asked him if he had the Money about him? He said no, he had flung it away; but when he was before the Justice he was searched, and a Shilling and a Halfpenny were found upon him, and 18 Pence which was given him at the Adam and Eve Alehouse .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-19-person153">
                  John 
                  Wilden 
               <interp inst="t17400416-19-person153" type="surname" value="Wilden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be in the Field where the Prisoner cross'd the Bank: after he had got over, he hid himself under some Brambles; I got up to him, and he said, - Pray let me go! Yes, said I, when the Man comes that followed you, and I have known what you 've done. So I held him by the Collar till Staples came up, and then we carry'd him to the Alehouse, where the young Woman was, and she told us, that was the Man, who had taken a Shilling and a Halfpenny from her, and as soon as ever she saw him, she fell into a Fit. He did not appear to be in Liquor, for he said he had neither eat nor drank that Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-19-person154">
                  John 
                  Crist 
               <interp inst="t17400416-19-person154" type="surname" value="Crist"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person154" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am the Constable who took the Prisoner into Custody. Upon searching him I found this Pistol-Tinderbox, this Knife and this Wig in his Pocket. He had a Cap on, when he was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had a Wife who lay-in, and was starving, and I begg'd this Money out of Charity. It is not consistent with Reason, that I should attempt to rob her in the open Day, and while so many People were passing and repassing . If I had intended to have robb'd her, I should have taken a properer Time and Place. <rs id="t17400416-19-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-19-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
