<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-23">
               <interp inst="t17421208-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-23" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-23" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-23-off126-c158" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend201 t17421208-23-off126 t17421208-23-verdict129"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-23-off126-c159" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend203 t17421208-23-off126 t17421208-23-verdict129"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-23-off128-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend207 t17421208-23-off128 t17421208-23-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>23, 24. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-defend201" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Delaney 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend201" type="surname" value="Delaney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend201" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-defend203" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Campbell 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend203" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend203" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17421208-23-defloc125">St Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-23-defloc125" type="placeName" value="St Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-23-defloc125" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend201 t17421208-23-defloc125"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend203 t17421208-23-defloc125"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend207 t17421208-23-defloc125"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17421208-23-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing two Velvet Manteels, fifteen Pair of Womens Kid Gloves, one Pair of white Damask Shoes with Gold Lace, one Pair of Flowered Silk Shoes, seven Yards of black Silk, one Rowler for a Child's Head, one Brocaded Shoe, several Yards of Lace, and a Snuff-box, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-23-victim205" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Lenson 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-23-victim205" type="surname" value="Lenson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-23-victim205" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-23-victim205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , out of her Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17421208-23-cd127" type="crimeDate">November 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-off126 t17421208-23-cd127"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-off128 t17421208-23-cd127"></join>. And,</p>
               <p>25. 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-defend207" type="defendantName">
                     Patience 
                     Forrester 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend207" type="surname" value="Forrester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend207" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-defend207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , for <rs id="t17421208-23-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving one Pair of white Damask Shoes laced with Gold, one Brocaded Shoe, and three Pair of Womens Gloves, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person208">
                  Ann 
                  Lenson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person208" type="surname" value="Lenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person208" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday se'nnight , the 25th of November, the Sash-Window belonging to my Shop was lifted up, which I did not know before would push up, and I lost two Velvet Manteels, two dozen of Kid Glove s, though I put no more in the Indictment than the Evidence confessed, and the other Things therein mentioned; these I am sure of: On Monday a Person came to me, and asked, if I had not lost a Velvet Manteel, and said, There is a Man in Bridewell who will be admitted an Evidence, and can inform you concerning your Goods. When I came to Bridewell, 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person209">
                  John 
                  Eckley 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person209" type="surname" value="Eckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Evidence, said, he could tell me what I had lost, and how I might have them again; he told me, I might find Part of my Goods in the Possession of 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person210">
                  Patience 
                  Forrester 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person210" type="surname" value="Forrester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person210" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and I found at Forrester's, one Pair of Silk Shoes, one Brocaded Shoe, and some Gloves, I think three Pair; but I do not know any Thing of the taking of them away.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know these were your Goods ?</p>
               <p>Lenson . I can swear to one Pair of the Gloves; but there were more Gloves in a Box that look'd like mine ; said Mrs Forrester, I have sold the Gold Laced Shoes , and the Velvet Manteel to Duke William's Footman, and I will take Care you shall have them again .</p>
               <p>Q. What did she give for these?</p>
               <p>Lenson . She said, she gave eleven Shillings and Six-pence for them. - I do not know what she sold them for.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person211">
                  John 
                  Eckley 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person211" type="surname" value="Eckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Last Thursday was se'nnight, the two Prisoners, and myself, were going along St Giles, Campbell and I put our Hands to the Sash of a Shop Window, and lifted it up; we could not easily lift it up, and we put a Panen under it, to keep it up; 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person212">
                  George 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person212" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person212" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             got the Goods out of the Window, and gave them to me, and Delavry stood by to watch if any Body came by . - This was agreed upon before-hand, that he should stand to see if any Body came by while we got the Goods. - There were two Velvet Manteels , a great one and a little one ; but I lost the little one, and several Pair of Women's Gloves, in running along; we sold fifteen Pair of Gloves to that Gentle-woman , a Snuff box , 2 Pair of Womens Shoes, and an odd Shoe, several Pieces of black Silk, three Pieces of Brigade, (I think they call it) [ Brocade ] and a Pudding done with Gold, such as they put round a Child's Head; we sold the Gold Laced Shoes for Half a Crown, and the rest of the Things at nine Shillings: We had a Crown for the other Shoes, and some odd Things, which we shared between us; we divided 20 d. a-piece, and we had 4 s. for the Manteel; but Delaney had nothing of that: Campbell and I shared that between us; that four Shillings, with the Crown, makes nine. - I knew where to carry them: We carried them to Mrs Forrester, and she asked, Whether we got them all from one Person, or from several? I said We got them all from one; and she said, It is no Matter how you got them.</p>
               <p>Delaney . Please to ask him what Time o'Night it was?</p>
               <p>Eckley. It was past Eight, but not Nine; St Giles's Bell rung Nine when we got the Things to our House.</p>
               <p>Delaney. Was I along with you when you sold the Things?</p>
               <p>Eckley. Yes; you were along with me when I sold the Mantelet, and the Gold Laced Shoes: Campbell was with me, when I sold the other Things.</p>
               <p>Juryman. I desire to know whether the Evidence did ever sell any Thing before to this 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person213">
                  Patience 
                  Forrester 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person213" type="surname" value="Forrester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person213" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? s</p>
               <p>Eckley . I had sold several trifling Things to her before; some Pewter Gin-pots, &amp;c. - Both<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080014"></xptr> the Prisoners were with me when I sold Things to her before.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she knew them to be stolen?</p>
               <p>Eckley. She must know them to be stolen; I leave that to yourself to consider, whether she did, or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they sold in a public Shop, or in a private Manner?</p>
               <p>Eckley. They were sold in a back Room. - When I went to her, I told her we had a Bargain to sell her, if she would buy it; that there were several Sorts of Things that would do for her Use: She asked what they were; I told her I had a Pair of Gold Laced Shoes; she said, if they would fit her she would buy them. I told her I had a Velvet Mantelet, but I had it not about me then; she bid me fetch it; I said, I had several other Things; so she bid me come the next Morning, and she would Bargain with us: I went the next Morning and she bought them. - I sold the Shoes and the Mantelet over Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Body there when you sold them?</p>
               <p>Eckley. There were two idle Women in the House that I have seen several Nights in the Street, waiting to be picked up.</p>
               <p>Forrester. Did you never say your Wife was an Earthen-ware Woman, and had taken these things in Change, and that she wanted to sell them?</p>
               <p>Eckley. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Forrester. Did not you say she was in Necessity, and wanted Money?</p>
               <p>Eckley. I never said any such Thing; you knew very well how we came by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Mrs Lenson, what are these Things worth?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person214">
                  Ann 
                  Lenson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person214" type="surname" value="Lenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person214" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They are laid at about 40 s. in the Indictment, but I could make above 50 s. of them in my Shop: I have laid them at the prime Cost.</p>
               <p>Forrester. Was the Mantelet new?</p>
               <p>Lenson. No, they were all second-hand Things; if the Mantelets were new, they would be worth above thirty Shillings, and that Mantelet I value but at seven Shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person215">
                  Benjamin 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person215" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person215" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I went along with the Constable to search Mrs Forrester's House: I said I had a Warrant to search the House; she said I might search and welcome. I saw her open a Box, and give the Constable some Shoes and other Things, and said she had sold the rest to a Woman in Rag-Fair, and that she would tell them where they were. She said she had sold the Mantelet and a Pair of Shoes to the Duke's Servant. She said she did not know where he liv'd, but she would endeavour to find him out; and that she would do what she could to get the Things again.</p>
               <p>Lenson. She said she had sold the Mantelet to Duke William's Servant for 8 s.</p>
               <p>Delaney. I know nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Campbell's Defence.</p>
               <p>Campbell. The Evidence asked me to take a Walk with him, he told me that he was going into the Strand; we went and came back together before eight o'Clock; then I went Home to Bed, and saw him no more that Night.</p>
               <p>- Fransham. I have known 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person216">
                  George 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person216" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person216" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ever since he suck'd, and I believe he is now Eighteen Years of Age. My Mistress that I liv'd with took him into the House, and cloath'd him, and put him Apprentice to a Painter, but he did not like his Trade; she took him into the House again, and got him a Footman's Place, where he liv'd honestly and justly, I believe about twelve Months ; then he went to Sea, and has been come from Sea about a Year: He might have taken away 500 l. in Plate and Jewels, if he had been inclined that Way, and never took a Pin's-worth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person217">
                  Jonathan 
                  Brewster 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person217" type="surname" value="Brewster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person217" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Painter; Campbell was Apprentice with me about five Months : He behaved very honestly, but the Trade did not agree with him; that was the Reason of his going from me. I knew him a Year or two before, when he was in Madam Lumley's Family.</p>
               <p>Mrs Brewster . He was very honest when he liv'd in our Family, and I never heard that he wrong'd any Body before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person218">
                  Eleanor 
                  Lumley 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person218" type="surname" value="Lumley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person218" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person219">
                  George 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person219" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person219" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             always behaved very well when he lived with us - I think it was in July last that he was with us. - He has lived with us twice, and I never knew any thing but what was honest of him: He had it in his Power to have robbed us of Things of great Value, if he had a Mind to do it, and I never lost any Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person220">
                  Stephen 
                  Abellavan 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person220" type="surname" value="Abellavan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person220" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . [This Gentleman wrote his Evidence in Court, and read it; for he said he could not speak English so properly without Reading.] I have known 
               <persName id="t17421208-23-person221">
                  George 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person221" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person221" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner at the Bar, for many Years, before he went to Sea, and since he came back: He has made several Errands for me and my Family, and carry'd Goods, and always prov'd honest: The last Time I employ'd him was to carry Goods to a Waggon. He always had a good Character.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080015"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person222">
                  Patience 
                  Forrester 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person222" type="surname" value="Forrester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person222" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Evidence brought some Things to me in a Handkerchief, and said his Wife was sick, and desired I would lend him some Money upon them: I told him I would not lend Money upon them, but if he had a Mind to sell them, I would buy them outright; and he brought all the Goods to me which the Woman said she lost, except one Velvet Manteel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person223">
                  Mary 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person223" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person223" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and two more went into that Woman's (the Prisoner's) Shop, to drink a Glass of what we call'd for, and a Man came in and asked whether she would take in a Pawn? She said no , she took in no Pawns, but if he would sell them , she would buy them. - There seemed to be some odd Pieces of black Silk, some Gloves, and a Pair of yellow Damask Shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was this?</p>
               <p>Rhodes . This was, as high as I can guess , about Noon. - I am not certain whether this is the Man, but it looks like him. - They were sold in the public Shop; and when he received the Money, he went away: He said his Wife was an Earthen-ware Woman, that she was sick, and that he sold these Things to support her, and if she would buy them, it would save him the Trouble of going further: He said she came by them in Exchange for Earthen-Ware .</p>
               <p>Q. What did she give for them?</p>
               <p>Rhodes. She gave him eleven Shillings and Six-pence for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Month was it?</p>
               <p>Rhodes . It was the 25th of November. - I know it because I happened to be out at Work the same Day. Some Part of these Goods, some black Silk and black Lace she sold to an Earthenware Woman that came by.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person224">
                  Ann 
                  Lenson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person224" type="surname" value="Lenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person224" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost them on the 25th, so it must be on the 26th.</p>
               <p>Rhodes. It was the 25th.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person225">
                  Martha 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person225" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person225" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Shop drinking a Dram when Mrs Forrester bought some Goods. I cannot tell whether this is the Man that sold them. There was, I think, the Lining of a black Petticoat, some black Lace, a Pair of Shoes and a Mantelet .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Body with him at that Time?</p>
               <p>Jones . There was no other Person with him: He asked Mrs Forrester if she would take in a Pawn? She said, no: but if he came honestly by them, and would sell them, she would buy them. He said his Wife had them in Exchange for Earthen-Ware - This was in the fore Shop, the Doors and Windows are always open. - There was a Straw-colour'd Pair of Shoes, they were not laced, and some old dirty Gloves, and some other Things. This young Woman and another were in the Shop. - There were several People in the Shop, and the Lodgers came thro' the Shop at the same Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person226">
                  Philip 
                  Dorset 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person226" type="surname" value="Dorset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person226" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs Forrester ever since she was a Child; I do not know what Business she follows, but she has a very good Character; she did formerly carry on a Chandler's Shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person227">
                  Nicholas 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person227" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person227" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs Forrester five or six Years, I live just by her, and never heard any Thing amiss of her: She did formerly keep a Chandler's Shop: I hear she sells Liquors now, but she does not deal with me.</p>
               <p>- Pelham . I have known her 3 Years: Her Character is as good as any Body's can be; she lives with an old Gentleman that sells Liquors; he keeps a Distiller's Shop. - The Shop is not her own. - She did follow the Business of a Seamstress.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-23-person228">
                  John 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17421208-23-person228" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her some Years, and never heard but she always had a good Character.</p>
               <p>Delaney. I have no Witnesses; I did not think my Trial would have come on so soon.</p>
               <p>Delaney and Campbell <rs id="t17421208-23-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-verdict129" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty to the Value of 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs> Forrester <rs id="t17421208-23-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17421208-23-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-23-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend201 t17421208-23-punish131"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend203 t17421208-23-punish131"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-23-defend207 t17421208-23-punish131"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
