<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440510-32">
               <interp inst="t17440510-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-32" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-32" type="date" value="17440510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440510-32-off167-c421" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-32-defend489 t17440510-32-off167 t17440510-32-verdict170"></join>
         
               <p>281. + 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-defend489" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-defend489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17440510-32-off167" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-off167" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-off167" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 50 pieces of ancient English gold coin of the value of 25 l. the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17440510-32-victim490" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17440510-32-victim490" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-32-off167 t17440510-32-victim490"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17440510-32-viclabel168" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-32-victim490 t17440510-32-viclabel168"></join>; in his dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440510-32-cd169" type="crimeDate">March 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-32-off167 t17440510-32-cd169"></join>.</p>
               <p>Taylor 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person491">
                  White
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person491" type="given" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went out of Town the 1st of March to go the midland circuit, and lost these coins which I have in my hand, and for which the prisoner stands indicted, locked up in a cabinet together, with a great many other old English Coins. In my absence, I was informed by a letter that all my gold and some of my silver coins were sold: when I came to town I found them all gone; I advertised them in several news-papers, that the public might have notice, that such a remarkable collection of English coins which are hardly to be found again in the Kingdom, from Edward the 3d to this time, were lost. Mr. Burgess a refiner came to my house, and brought me this parcel of coins, which I can swear are my own coins which I lost. It seems to be a little particular to swear to such a thing as money, and therefore I will give you a little trouble to show you that these are my own in Distinction from others, among these coins there is a counterfeit coin of Queen Elizabeth, it is silver gilt over, I have put it into the fire several times to remove the gilding which has done it some damage, and there are some pieces so remarkable in other respects that I can swear these are what were stole out of my house; the Prisoner was brought to my house and afterwards taken to Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person492">
                  Thomas
                   De Veil
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person492" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person492" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's to know how he came by these coins, and he said one 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person493">
                  David 
                  Gratrix 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person493" type="surname" value="Gratrix"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person493" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (who had been a Footman of my own) had given them to him to dispose of. He said he lodged at the Bull and Gate in Holbourn; there was an inquiry made after him, but the man was gone from that place, and the justice thought fit that the prisoner should be prosecuted: and I did consent he should be committed for further examination. When the justice was making his commitment, he was under some concern, and said, he believed he might take Gratrix at his own house, his saying that, is the occasion of my bringing him before you; for as the prisoner has the character of an honest man, I inquired into the acquaintance that was between him and Gratrix, and I found he is his nephew, not his nephew by blood, but by affinity; I thought it would be very hard to keep this man in prison, and therefore I thought fit to lay this thing before you, as I think it is my duty in order to do justice to my Country, that you may censure him as you think proper.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100037"></xptr>Mr. Burgess. I am a refiner, the 30th of March the Prisoner brought some gold coins to know the most I could give for them; I told him the most I could give was 3 l. 18 s. an ounce. He desired I would weigh them, and make a note of them. After I had bought them, I put them in a paper till I had an opportunity of looking them over. When I came to look them over, I had some reason to think that they belonged to some collection. My partner (Mr. Scot) immediately thought of Mr. White, and I went to Mr. White's to know if they were his, and he told me they were his.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the Advertiser then?</p>
               <p>Burgess. No, not then; I told Mr. White I would bring the man I bought them of, for he told me he lodged at the Bull and Gate in Holborn. I went there, they said he lodged there the night before, but was gone.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had those pieces of gold of my kinsman, and he sent me to Mr. Scot and Mr. Burgess to know what they would give, and they said 3 l. 18 s. I took them in a paper, carried them to Mr. Burgess, and he gave me the money, and I carried it to 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person494">
                  David 
                  Gratrix 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person494" type="surname" value="Gratrix"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person494" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the Bull Head alehouse in Wood Street, where he waited for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-32-person495">
                  George 
                  Cooks 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person495" type="surname" value="Cooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person495" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Bull Head and three Turns in Wood Street, the Prisoner and a little man with his hair tied up like a livery servant came in, the Prisoner went out of the house, staid about a quarter of an hour, and brought a handful of gold and silver to this little man - I cannot tell how long ago it was - I think he had a green livery coat on -</p>
               <p>White. He had not my livery.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money do you guess he brought to that man?</p>
               <p>Cooks. I guess it to be about 30 l. - there was as much as he could grasp in his hand - both guineas and silver.</p>
               <p>Burgess. I think I paid the Prisoner about 33 l. it was within a few shillings more or less.</p>
               <p>It appeared by the evidence of 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person496">
                  William 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person496" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person496" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person496" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person497">
                  Gregory 
                  Sewel 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person497" type="surname" value="Sewel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person497" type="given" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person497" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that the Prisoner had caused this Gratrix to be apprehended in Southwark by Mr. Walker the constable. That he confessed to them that he did not come honestly by it, but before Justice Hammond he denied that he said any such thing; and returning from the Justices he made his escape out of the Constable's hand.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17440510-32-person498">
                  Young 
                  Alworth 
               <interp inst="t17440510-32-person498" type="surname" value="Alworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person498" type="given" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-person498" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (clerk to Justice Hammond) proved that the Justice had examined him, and made his commitment to goal for further examination.</p>
               <p>Mr. Scot and Mr. Burgess, by whom the Prisoner had been employed in their house, said, they verily believed him to be a very honest man: several other Persons gave him the like character. <rs id="t17440510-32-verdict170" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-32-verdict170" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
