<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471209-40">
               <interp inst="t17471209-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471209-40" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471209-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471209-40" type="date" value="17471209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471209-40-off183-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend339 t17471209-40-off183 t17471209-40-verdict186"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471209-40-off183-c260" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend341 t17471209-40-off183 t17471209-40-verdict186"></join>
         
               <p>+ 48, 49. 
               
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-defend339" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     White , otherwise <rs id="t17471209-40-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend339 t17471209-40-alias-3"></join>May</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend339" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend339" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend339" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-defend341" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Page , otherwise <rs id="t17471209-40-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend341 t17471209-40-alias-4"></join>Mary Willis</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend341" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend341" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-defend341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , indicted for <rs id="t17471209-40-off183" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-off183" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-off183" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing on the King's high-way, on the <rs id="t17471209-40-cd184" type="crimeDate">7th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-off183 t17471209-40-cd184"></join>, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17471209-40-victim343" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Lasebee 
                        <interp inst="t17471209-40-victim343" type="surname" value="Lasebee"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471209-40-victim343" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471209-40-victim343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-off183 t17471209-40-victim343"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and putting him in fear and danger of his life, and stealing from him his proper money from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person344">
                  Joseph 
                  Lasbee 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person344" type="surname" value="Lasbee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person344" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along the <placeName id="t17471209-40-crimeloc185">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17471209-40-crimeloc185" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17471209-40-crimeloc185" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-off183 t17471209-40-crimeloc185"></join> upon the 14th of November between 8 and 9 o'clock in the evening, two women stood at the corner of a court near the New Church they said, countryman! I stopt, and ask'd them what they had to say to me; they directly laid hold of me, and bid me come to the end of the alley, and that I need not be afraid. no-body would hurt me. I stept to the end of the alley, and ask'd them what business they had with me; they ask'd me for a dish of tea: I said I had no such thing: then they ask'd me for a dram; I said I must go about my business; then they took me by the colar and pull'd me down; I clapt my hand to my coat-pocket to secure my money; then they endeavour'd to pull me down; I took my hand out of my pocket to defend myself, and I found 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person345">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person345" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person345" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person345" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hand in my pocket, and the other had hold of my colar at the same time; she took her hand out of my pocket, and I found immediately my money was gone, and I said I am robb'd. White went away, and the other had hold of me, and when I would have gone, she d - d me, and would not let me go: It struck such a terror upon me, I did not know whether she would cut my throat, or what. I broke from the other woman and followed 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person346">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person346" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person346" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person346" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and I told a man in the Strand that I was robb'd, and he told me of a Justice in the neighbourhood, that I might go to; I kept with White, and the other followed me for some time; at last she left me, and brought in a little time five or six men, the first, like a soldier, run his head against me; and another, like a gentleman, said he was a Constable, and if I would not let the woman go he would knock me down, which he did: but I would not quit her; then another knock'd me down. I was knock'd down three times, then they took them both away; then they drew me towards the end of the alley, and said they would knock me or any body else down that offered to come after them. There was a gentleman said to me, I know a house where a gang of very bad people use, where I will go with you, and do you justice: as soon as I came in I saw Willis, and charg'd a Constable with her, and we had her before the justice, and he committed her: I came to town to prefer an indictment against Willis, and I heard the other was in New Prison, and I am positively sure she is the woman that assaulted me: I have no farther to say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person347">
                  Mary 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person347" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person347" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Ask him whether there were not two women he ran after up the court?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you usually carry money in your coat-pocket?</p>
               <p>Lasebee. I usually carry it there, because my breeches pocket was bad; I was carrying that money to my sister in St. Katharine's, who is married; her name is 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person348">
                  Mary 
                  Jugam 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person348" type="surname" value="Jugam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person348" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person349">
                  John 
                  Frazier 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person349" type="surname" value="Frazier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person349" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver by trade; I was coming towards the New Church in the Strand, and heard Lasebee cry out for help: he said, I have lost 16 s. When I went up to him the two Prisoners were three or four yards off; we seized White, and 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person350">
                  Mary 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person350" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person350" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was scolding at us for holding White; I had hold of White with one arm and the Countryman another; 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person351">
                  Mary 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person351" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person351" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was very willing to go up Katharine-street, and she said that was the way to Justice Burdus; as we were up the street we miss'd Willis a little while: in a little time five or six men came up; we that came was a soldier, he run his head against him; and another came up and said he should let her go; if he did not, he would knock him down, which they did two or three times, and after they had releast the Prisoner they went up Katharine-street; I watched them into a house and I went back to the Country-man again, and a gentleman at an oil-shop offered to assist him; I told him where they were gone, and the Gentleman went with the Countryman to an ale-house, and there we found Willis and took hold of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure White is the woman you had hold of with the Country-man first?</p>
               <p>Frazier. Yes, I saw her last week in New Prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person352">
                  Tho 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person352" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person352" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between St. Katharine-street and the New Church these two men had hold of her, White the Prisoner and Willis collar'd the Countryman; I heard him say he was robb'd and his collar was all tore: as they were carrying 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person353">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person353" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person353" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before the Justice, there came up a soldier and run against the Countryman, and presently some more fellows came up and struck him several times and made his head bleed; after this the Countryman and the other Witness went to this house in the court in little Katharine-street, and there we found Willis the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person354">
                  Thomas 
                  Indd 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person354" type="surname" value="Indd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person354" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was opposite Little Katharine-street. and I heard a noise, and they said 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person355">
                  Ann
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174712090016"></xptr> Page<interp inst="t17471209-40-person355" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had robb'd a man and she was gone before Justice Burdus.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is the person they call Page?</p>
               <p>Indd. Willis is the youngest person; I have known her seven years, and never knew her any thing but a common woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know White?</p>
               <p>Indd. Yes, five or six years; she lives in Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who keeps this house in Little Drury-lane?</p>
               <p>Indd. Their names are Smith; Willis has lodg'd there these two years. One of the Prisoners goes by the name of May, and the other by the name of Page.</p>
               <p>Q. to White. Have you any thing to say, or any Witnesses?</p>
               <p>White Prisoner. They were here all yesterday, but now are gone home. I never saw this man the prosecutor, 'till I saw him in Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. to Willis. What have you to say ?</p>
               <p>Willis. He ran after two women up the court and knock'd me down.</p>
               <p>Q. to - Allison. Do you know Lasebee the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Allison. I keep a publick-house at Brandford, I have known him near a year, and he is a man of as honest a character as any in the country.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471209-40-person356">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person356" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person356" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17471209-40-person357">
                  Mary 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17471209-40-person357" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person357" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             both <rs id="t17471209-40-verdict186" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-verdict186" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-verdict186" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of the Felony, but acquitted of the Robbery
            </rs>,</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471209-40-punish187" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471209-40-punish187" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend339 t17471209-40-punish187"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471209-40-defend341 t17471209-40-punish187"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
