<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480224-41">
               <interp inst="t17480224-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-41" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-41" type="date" value="17480224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-41-off222-c298" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-defend371 t17480224-41-off222 t17480224-41-verdict226"></join>
         
               <p>163. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480224-41-defend371" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Woolley , otherwise <rs id="t17480224-41-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-defend371 t17480224-41-alias-5"></join>Zachery Woolley</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-defend371" type="surname" value="Woolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-defend371" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-defend371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17480224-41-off222" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-off222" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-off222" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480224-41-victim373" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Hardy 
                        <interp inst="t17480224-41-victim373" type="surname" value="Hardy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-41-victim373" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-41-victim373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-off222 t17480224-41-victim373"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by driving and drawing his cart, by which the near wheel of the said cart threw the said Sarah on the ground, and run over the head of the said Sarah, by which she was mortally bruised, and of those bruises died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480224-41-cd223" type="crimeDate">January 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-off222 t17480224-41-cd223"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-41-person374">
                  Charles 
                  Haynes 
               <interp inst="t17480224-41-person374" type="surname" value="Haynes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person374" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of January last about eight at night, I was going from my master's house (Mr. Sheppard's an apothecary in <placeName id="t17480224-41-crimeloc224">Woodstreet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-41-crimeloc224" type="placeName" value="Woodstreet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-41-crimeloc224" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-off222 t17480224-41-crimeloc224"></join> ) and saw a cart standing at Mr. Brook's door, and I heard the Prisoner say, have you any thing for the cart to night? he was the carter, and carries goods for Mr. Brooks: Mr. Brooks's man said they had nothing for him to night, but they had some hogsheads for him in the morning; whether the Prisoner's cart killed the deceased , I cannot tell: as I was going to Mr. Glyde's a gold and silver lace shop, I heard a violent groaning.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this afterwards?</p>
               <p>Haynes. Not above half a minute; then I saw the <rs id="t17480224-41-deflabel225" type="occupation">carman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-41-defend371 t17480224-41-deflabel225"></join> going away, he crossed the way and went off, and then I heard the groans after I had delivered my medicines; I crossed the way and rung at the bell, and I heard a groan on the other side of the way; and when I came cross the way Mr. Ball a surgeon, and another person, had lifted a woman up; Mr. Ball said, my dear, have you hurt yourself? she made no answer, but groaned very violently, and before we got her into the Horse Shoe Alehouse she bled at the eyes and nose, and all the parts of the head, and expired in about ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to charge the Prisoner with upon this?</p>
               <p>Haynes. I have nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner present at that time?</p>
               <p>Haynes. He was with his cart at Mr. Brooks's door when the deceased was killed, and I saw no other cart there but his.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not see her killed?</p>
               <p>Haynes. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how she came by the hurt?</p>
               <p>Haynes. The surgeon said her head was jammed between a post and the wheel.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give an account whether the deceased was hurt by this cart, or by any other?</p>
               <p>Haynes. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner present when the deceased was said to be jammed between the wheel and the post?</p>
               <p>Haynes. No, he went away with his cart.</p>
               <p>Q. I Suppose the last went away the usual pace?</p>
               <p>Haynes . I cannot say that, sometimes they go faster, and sometimes slower .</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun . Was not there a coach in the street?</p>
               <p>Haynes. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there posts between the cart way and the foot way?</p>
               <p>Haynes. There are not posts all along to part off the foot way from the cart way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go nearer to the wall than carmen generally used to do?</p>
               <p>Haynes. No, I do not think he went nearer than they used to do.</p>
               <p>Haynes. Did he leave room for people to go between the cart and the wall?</p>
               <p>Haynes . I do not know.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. How long afterwards was it that you saw the Prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240036"></xptr>Haynes . I saw him the next morning with some empty hogsheads .</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did he go a fast pace?</p>
               <p>Haynes. He went a pretty fast pace.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the horses seem to go faster than horses usually go?</p>
               <p>Haynes . No, my Lord, for they generally go pretty fast when they are empty.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any man taken notice of that night about it?</p>
               <p>Haynes . No, for there was nobody knew that any person was hurt that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you saw the Prisoner there at that time?</p>
               <p>Haynes . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner there when you crossed the way?</p>
               <p>Haynes. No, he was gone out of sight at the time I saw the deceased.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-41-person375">
                  William 
                  Ewin 
               <interp inst="t17480224-41-person375" type="surname" value="Ewin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person375" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of January the Prisoner called at Mr. Brooks's as usual for his loading; I told him there was no work for him that night, but he was to fetch five hogsheads out of Fell-street in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ewin. Yes, I have known him three or four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to charge him with with respect to the murder?</p>
               <p>Ewin. I know nothing of the murder.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he call at Mr. Brooks's?</p>
               <p>Ewin. I think it was a little before eight .</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark or light then?</p>
               <p>Ewin. I think it was dark: I understood the next morning that the Prisoner had killed a woman; I said I was sorry for it, for I believe I was the last person that spoke to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was you told so by?</p>
               <p>Ewin. My fellow servant, who took the hogshead in the next morning, and as I understood in the neighbourhood there was nobody knew that there was any person killed that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-41-person376">
                  Richard 
                  Hinman 
               <interp inst="t17480224-41-person376" type="surname" value="Hinman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person376" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am servant to Mr. Brooks; I know nothing of the murder; I know I received hogsheads from the Prisoner the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you the person that told Ewin there was a woman murdered?</p>
               <p>Hinman. I heard it, I do not know it myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480224-41-verdict226" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-41-verdict226" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Court reprimanded the Prisoner, and said it was plain that the King had lost a subject by him or somebody; and cautioned the Prisoner, and all other carmen, to be careful in driving their carts, and not to stay drinking in an alehouse while their horses are going forward, but to keep at the head of the thill horse: And charged the Prisoner and every one to take notice, that they have not the liberty of obstructing the passage of the King's subjects in the streets; and that there are proper places where they are to drive, and in which they are obliged to keep.</p>
            </div1>
