<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-12">
               <interp inst="t17400116-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-12" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-12" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-12-off62-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-defend117 t17400116-12-off62 t17400116-12-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>93. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-12-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Motte , alias <rs id="t17400116-12-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-defend117 t17400116-12-alias-1"></join>Moote</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-defend117" type="surname" value="Motte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-defend117" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-defend117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400116-12-defloc61">St. Brides</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-12-defloc61" type="placeName" value="St. Brides"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-12-defloc61" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-defend117 t17400116-12-defloc61"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-12-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 3 Five-Guinea Pieces, 4 Two-Guinea Pieces, 22 Guineas, a Portugal Piece of Gold, value 3 l. 12 s. a 36 Shilling-piece, 2 Half Guineas, a Piece of coined Gold, of King Charles the Second, value 23 s. 16 Crown Pieces, 36 gilt Six-pences, a Silver Box gilt, value 3 s. a Chrystal Stone engraved for a Seal, val. 3 s. and 4 Gold Mourning-Rings, value 30 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-12-victim119" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Gibbon 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-12-victim119" type="surname" value="Gibbon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-12-victim119" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-12-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-off62 t17400116-12-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17400116-12-viclabel63" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-victim119 t17400116-12-viclabel63"></join>, in his Dwelling-House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-12-cd64" type="crimeDate">December 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-off62 t17400116-12-cd64"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Gibbon. On Sunday the 16th of December I was robbed of every Thing mentioned in the Indictment, while I was at Church. I locked my Buroe in the Morning before I went out, and ordered my Servants to go to the Chapel before the Service began. The Prisoner had been my <rs id="t17400116-12-deflabel65" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-defend117 t17400116-12-deflabel65"></join>, and having been discharged for using me ill, I concluded he was the Person who had robbed me. I lost 3 Five-Guinea Pieces, 4 Two Guinea Pieces, and above 20 Guineas. Some Pieces of Portugal Gold; a 3 Pound 12 Shilling-Piece in particular, some Crown-pieces and gilt Six-pences, and a Piece of Gold of King Charles the Second, and a Piece of Chrystal cut for a Seal; some Mourning Rings, one pretty remarkable, because it hath not the Age of the deceased. Four of them are in the Indictment, but I lost more. The Prisoner was taken up in Essex, and the Things (taken from him) were described to me by the Constable, and afterwards were shewn me in Chelmsford Goal; when I had seen them, they were sealed up again in my Presence, and are here in Court. Here is a Two-Guinea Piece, which has a Mark on it, whereby I am pretty sure I can distinguish it from another. This Piece of King Charles's I believe is mine; and I verily believe this Guinea is mine. Here is the Ring that wants the Age of the Deceased. This is the Seal, and here is the Impression which I took off about two Years ago. The Prisoner has confessed the Fact, and the next Witness will inform you, the Things were found upon him. They were taken out of my Scrutore in my Study; the Lock of the Scrutore I found broke, and the Spring likewise, (tho' very strong) and part of the Molding that went over the Lock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-12-person120">
                  John 
                  Wasket 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person120" type="surname" value="Wasket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the Prisoner on the 30th of December, at Dunmow in Essex, and I found all these Things upon him, which are now Produced in Court. I am sure they are the same I found upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-12-person121">
                  Daniel 
                  Monk 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person121" type="surname" value="Monk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person121" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of December I received a Warrant from Colonel 
               <persName id="t17400116-12-person122">
                  De 
                  Veil 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person122" type="surname" value="Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person122" type="given" value="De"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person122" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , backed by Mr Justice Price of Illford, by Virtue of which we took the Prisoner. Upon searching him, we found the Things which have been now produced, and I heard him confess that he was guilty of the Fact, and that they were his Master's. After he had said this, he told us the Things were given him by one 
               <persName id="t17400116-12-person123">
                  John 
                  Linsley 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person123" type="surname" value="Linsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person123" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-12-person124">
                  John 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person124" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person124" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of December last, the Prisoner came and knocked at my Master's ( Mr Gibbon's) Door; I opened it, and his Brother William was with him. The Prisoner asked me, if my Master was gone to Church, and if we were going to Chapel? I told him yes. Then I went in to put on my Shoes, and when I came back I did not see the Prisoner. I asked his Brother William, where he was gone? William told me, he was gone out to speak to a Gentleman's Servant in the Yard. I left them<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160012"></xptr> both in the Passage, just within the Door, when I went to put on my Shoes.</p>
               <p>Jury. How far was this Passage from your Master's Study?</p>
               <p>Mr Gibbon. The Stairs which go to the Study, were in this Passage.</p>
               <p>Dawson. The Study is up one Pair of Stairs. William staid but a very little Bit; we went to Chapel, and he went out before us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-12-person125">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17400116-12-person125" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person125" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I made the Book Case for Mr Gibbon, which was afterward broken open. Mr Gibbon called upon me, and told me of this Disaster, - the Accident which had happened to my Work, and I called the next Day at his House, and saw it had been broke open. The Lock of the Desk had been very much strained; this is the Lock, and here is the Mark of the Instrument, with which it had been opened. Part of the Molding upon the Book-Case was tore off, to get at the Lock, and I reckon it must take up about a Quarter of an Hour, (not much less) in the breaking open.</p>
               <p>Mr Gibbon. When Mr Clark saw it, it was in the same Condition as I found it.</p>
               <p>Colonel Price produced the Prisoner's Confession, but as the Prisoner had sworn it, it was not read.</p>
               <p>Mr Ellis. I went to Chelmsford Goal to see the Prisoner. The Things which have been now produced, were found upon him, and he owned they were Mr Gibbon's.</p>
               <p>Mr Wasket. I heard him own in Chelmsford Goal, that the Things found upon him were Mr Gibbon's, and that Linsley gave them to him.</p>
               <p>Mr Gibbon. Some of the gilt Sixpences, I am informed he and his Brother paid away in the Country.</p>
               <p>Wasket. Mr Gibbon wrote to me, and desired me to get up these Sixpences if I heard of any being put off, and I went accordingly and gave Change for some which the Prisoner's Father had paid away for Half-Guineas; but I don't know of the Prisoner's putting them off himself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had all these Things, (which Mr Wasket took upon me) from John Linsley. <rs id="t17400116-12-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-12-punish67" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-12-punish67" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-12-defend117 t17400116-12-punish67"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
