<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-27">
               <interp inst="t17471014-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-27" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-27" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-27-off137-c286" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-27-defend333 t17471014-27-off137 t17471014-27-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>411 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-27-defend333" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Coppin 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-27-defend333" type="surname" value="Coppin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-defend333" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-defend333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17471014-27-off137" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-off137" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-off137" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two Pair of Grey Worsted Stockings, value 6 s. Two Pair of White Cotton Stockings, value 7 s. One Pair of White Thread Stockings, value 3 s.
            </rs> the Goods and Chattels of Persons unknown, <rs id="t17471014-27-cd138" type="crimeDate">September the 7th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-27-off137 t17471014-27-cd138"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-27-person334">
                  John 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17471014-27-person334" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person334" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a wholesale Hosier at the Three Kings in Fenchurch Street. The Prisoner at the Bar was my Porter, and has been for near a Twelve-month past. I have miss'd Goods for a considerable Time past. I can't positively swear to these Goods, but I have all the Reason in the World to believe they are mine, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-27-person335">
                  Rebecca 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17471014-27-person335" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person335" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Porter has often brought me Stockings to sell for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Smith. I live in Vinegar Yards. When he came to me he desired me to sell them, that he might have the Money. I sold the three Pair for 9 s. and he had every Farthing of it. He said he came honestly by them; and that he had them of a Shop keeper that had left off Business. Here is three Pair that I sold, but the People are not at home to whom I sold them. The other two Persons came to me, to desire me to go away, for there was no other Evidence against him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you to have any Thing for selling of them?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought them of a Hawker up and down the Streets with his own Hair.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner desired it might be ask'd, What Sort of Character this Witness had? and, What Sort of a House she kept?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Jones. I know nothing, but I bought this Pair of Stockings of Mrs Smith, and gave her 3 s. for them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-27-person336">
                  James 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17471014-27-person336" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person336" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Robbery, only as this Man has come frequently to me in the Vinegar-Yard, and Mrs Smith brought these Stockings to sell to my Housekeeper. She gave her 3 s. for them, I think they are 4 s. by the Gross. Mrs Jones said, I believe this Man has stole them. I watch'd, and he went into the Glass-house, and I goes and ask'd for half a Dozen of Glasses; and I says, Jack, What is that Hosier's Name that you live with? Says he, I live with one Mr Giles's a Brasier in Addle street. I went there in a Day or two, and not seeing of him. I describ'd the Man. With that they told me, he liv'd with one Mr Roberts in Fenchurch Street. I went there, and they told me, they had such a Man. Mr Roberts has a Gentleman that does his Business whilst he is in the Country; he said, do you know the Man if you see him? And he said, look down Lombard-Street. Upon that I saw him coming up Lombard-Street. I said, this is the Man. When I talk'd to him about Vinegar-Yard, and Mrs Smith, and those People, he deny'd he knew any Thing of us.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever hear any Thing against me?</p>
               <p>Gray. No, I never heard any Thing of you; but I believe you are the Thief that stole the Stockings.</p>
               <p>Mr 
               <persName id="t17471014-27-person337">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Figg 
               <interp inst="t17471014-27-person337" type="surname" value="Figg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person337" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lives with Mr Roberts, he only corroborated Gray's Evidence; he could not swear to these Stockings as Mr Roberts's.</p>
               <p>Mr 
               <persName id="t17471014-27-person338">
                  Benj 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17471014-27-person338" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person338" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He could speak nothing to the Fact, but only, that he talk'd with the Prisoner three Quarters of an Hour, and after all, the Prisoner told him they had no Evidence against him, and he would say nothing.</p>
               <p>Mr Huish, the Maker of the Stockings, he could swear to his Mark, but not that those Stockings were sold to Mr Roberts.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-27-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-27-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
