<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-34">
               <interp inst="t17430907-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-34" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-34" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-34-off177-c267" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-defend330 t17430907-34-off177 t17430907-34-verdict179"></join>
         
               <p>407. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430907-34-defend330" type="defendantName">
                     Silvester 
                     Ridge , otherwise called <rs id="t17430907-34-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-defend330 t17430907-34-alias-3"></join>John Connor</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-defend330" type="surname" value="Ridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-defend330" type="given" value="Silvester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-defend330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that he on the <rs id="t17430907-34-cd175" type="crimeDate">8th Day of July, in the 17th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-off177 t17430907-34-cd175"></join>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17430907-34-crimeloc176">St Martin in the Fields, in the County of Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-34-crimeloc176" type="placeName" value="St Martin in the Fields, in the County of Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-34-crimeloc176" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-off177 t17430907-34-crimeloc176"></join>, did <rs id="t17430907-34-off177" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-off177" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-off177" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seducingAllegiance"></interp>
               unlawfully and feloniously procure 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430907-34-victim332" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Ross 
                        <interp inst="t17430907-34-victim332" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-34-victim332" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-34-victim332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-off177 t17430907-34-victim332"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , being then a Subject of our Sovereign<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070016"></xptr> Lord the King, to enter into the Service of the French King, being a foreign Prince, as a Soldier, without Licence first had and obtained, under his Majesty's Sign Manual; in Contempt of our Lord the King, and his Laws, to the evil Example of others, against the Peace, &amp;c. and against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>And the Indictment further charged, that he the said 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person333">
                  Silvester 
                  Ridge 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person333" type="surname" value="Ridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person333" type="given" value="Silvester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise called 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person334">
                  John 
                  Connor 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person334" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person334" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the said 8th Day of July, &amp;c. did unlawfully and feloniously hire, and retain the said 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person335">
                  William 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person335" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person335" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c by giving him a Piece of foreign Silver Coin of the Value of 4 s. to enter into the Service of the French King, being a Foreign Prince as a Soldier, without the Leave, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Council fo r the Prosecution opened the Nature of the Offence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at the Battle of Dettingen, in the Regiment of Woolsenbuttle, in the Austrian Service. My Lord, I am informed that the Government have not thought fit to prosecute, I desire therefore to be inform'd who is the * Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>* A very proper Enquiry, as will presently appear; but it, unfortunately for the Prisoner, is fix'd on a Person not able to make him Satisfaction.</p>
               <p>The Court thereupon inquir'd, and the committing Justice being upon the Bench, named a Gentleman of Rank in the Army, who soon after acquainted the Court that he was not the Prosecutor; whereupon 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person336">
                  William 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person336" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person336" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was entered as Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-34-person337">
                  William 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person337" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person337" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of July last, on a Friday, I met the Prisoner near Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Never before.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you at that Time?</p>
               <p>Ross. He said to me, what Countryman are you? I said I was born in Holland.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you now?</p>
               <p>Ross. I belong to General Harrison's Regiment of Foot. - I am a common <rs id="t17430907-34-viclabel178" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-34-victim332 t17430907-34-viclabel178"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. If you were born in Holland, how then came you to be a Subject of Great-Britain?</p>
               <p>Ross. My Father was born in Scotland, he has a Company of Scotch Hillanders; they call them the Scotch Regiment; they are in the Service of Holland: My Father is now in Garrison at Art; He has been in Holland, near fifty Years.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know your Father was born in Scotland?</p>
               <p>Ross. I have heard him say several Times that he was born in the Shire of Ross.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in England?</p>
               <p>Ross. Three Months and a Half and better. - I have been enlisted in General Harrison's Regiment since the 25th of May. - I was enlisted when the Prisoner met me.</p>
               <p>Q. When you met together who spoke first?</p>
               <p>Ross. He spoke to me first in French, and said how do you do, do you understand French? Then I stopped and answered him in French; said he, I have seen you before; may be so, said I. Then I went with him to the House of one 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person338">
                  Miles 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person338" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person338" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Sign of the Green-Man at Charing-Cross. - I had never seen him before: Then he asked for a private Room, and the Man shewed him into a Fore-Room next the Street; he called for a Pot of Beer, and then for some Victuals. - He talked to me, thinking I was a Subject of the King of France; I never let him know that I could speak any English. There came a Drawer into the Room, and the Prisoner said to him, Here is a clever Man but he can talk no English at all, and he is afraid he should be taken up, because he is a 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person339">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person339" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person339" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q What Countryman did you tell him you were?</p>
               <p>Ross. I told him I was a Frenchman; says the Drawer to him, Explain to him in French that he need not be afraid, for I, and my Master and Mistress are all 
               <persName id="t17430907-34-person340">
                  Roman 
                  Catholicks 
               <interp inst="t17430907-34-person340" type="surname" value="Catholicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person340" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Drawer went out, and there came in a Chairman, I think his Name is Caibow; this Chairman thinking I could understand no English, said, if he would take him along with him he would go. - The Prisoner said it was a dangerous Thing to meddle with such Matters here; then the Chairman was called and went out, so the Prisoner came up to me, clapp'd his Hand upon my Shoulder, and said, I should be glad to have you for a Comrade, and you shall go with me to France; says he, I hope you are not against your own King and Country, meaning that I was a Frenchman: He said, if I would go with him, he would give me a Note under his Hand that I should be an Officer as soon as I came on the other Side of the Water; says he. I will give you 40 Livres. No says I, That is too little for such a Man as I am, I will have more as that - I spoke this in French. He put his Hand in his Pocket, and pulled out a French Crown. which I have here to produce, and said, he would make that 40 Livres more; (the French Crown was produced) this is worth<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070017"></xptr> about 4 s. 6 d. English Money; I took this Crown of him, and he called for a Pot of Beer; after we had drank the Beer, I was studying how to come out of that House, for fear of being knocked on the Head, as they were all his own Country People.</p>

               <p>Q. What were they Frenchmen?</p>
               <p>Ross. They all spoke French.</p>
               <p>Q. What Country People do you think they are?</p>
               <p>Ross. They are Irish People - the Prisoner is an Irishman; they talked both English and Irish; then I made a Proposal to him, that as he was a Man that understood English, and I could not, if he would go along with me down into Wapping to get my Goods, I would go with him where he pleased; he agreed to that, and pulled out half a Crown, and gave it to the People of the House, for a Lodging for me and himself, and for the Reckoning, which was Fifteen-pence Half-penny - we did not lie there; this was between five and six o'Clock; the Prisoner and I went to the Black-Boy and Trumpet at Tower-Hill, and I called for a Pot of Beer, I spoke to the Landlord, and desired him in Dutch to go to St Catharines, to get a File of Musqueteers, but he refused it, and said, I should go myself - the Landlord spoke Dutch - the Prisoner could understand some Words of what we said; then, I said, I would talk to him in English; and I told him he was my Prisoner, and I would hold him; I had no Money in my Pocket, but this Piece, that I had of the Prisoner, and the Landlord would not let us go without paying for the Beer; said I to the Landlord, keep this in your Custody till I come and pay for the Beer; then I took the Prisoner out of the House, and carried him before Justice Dennet.</p>
               <p>Court. This is all mispending of Time; for the Man took him to be a Frenchman; we will suppose this Man was a Subject of his Majesty, of which there is some doubt, if he pretends to be a Foreigner, and can't speak a Word of English, he is to be taken for what he pretends to be. <rs id="t17430907-34-verdict179" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-34-verdict179" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
