<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-38">
               <interp inst="t17430114-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-38" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-38" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-38-off191-c371" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-38-defend449 t17430114-38-off191 t17430114-38-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>113. + 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-defend449" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-defend449" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-defend449" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-defend449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-38-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17430114-38-victim450" type="victimName">
                        Thomas 
                        Osbourne 
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-victim450" type="surname" value="Osbourne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-38-victim450" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-38-victim450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-38-off191 t17430114-38-victim450"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the Highway, putting him in Fear , and taking from him a Hat, Peruke, a Pair of Buckles, a Muslin Neckcloth , three Guineas , and 26 Shillings in Silver
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-38-cd192" type="crimeDate">December 16th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-38-off191 t17430114-38-cd192"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-38-person451">
                  Thomas 
                  Osbourne 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person451" type="surname" value="Osbourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person451" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 16th of December I was going along the Strand, and went into a Cellar to call for a Pint of Twopenny-Purl; the Prisoner and another Woman were there: I staid no longer than the drinking my Purl, about twelve Doors from Drury-Lane ; the other Woman followed me, in order to pick me up, and the Prisoner laid fast hold of me in order to rifle me; they both held me, and endeavoured to pull me down. - I called out, Watch: Instead of the Watch, one 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person452">
                  Richard 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person452" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person452" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ( who I have a Warrant against) came up; one of the three hit me a Knock on the Face, that stunned me, and laid me on my Back; they robbed me of three Guineas, and 26 s. my Hat and Wig, Buckles out of my Shoes, and Neckcloth off my Neck; two Soldiers stood at a little Distance while I was robbed: They took hold of the Prisoner, and carried her up Drury-Lane. About a Minute after the Women were gone, Lucas says to me, Friend, you are rifled. I know I am, said I. He ran up the Lane, and said he would get me my Hat and Wig: I went to the Cellar where I had the Purl, and he brought me my Hat and Wig. I described the Women to the Watchmen, and they said it was 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person453">
                  Mary 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person453" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person453" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person453" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (or 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person454">
                  Welch 
                  Moll 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person454" type="surname" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person454" type="given" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person454" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , as they called her) and about a Week afterwards she was taken. I was sent for to the Watch-house in Lincoln's-Inn Fields, about five in the Morning, and the Prisoner confessed she was present, but the other Woman robbed me, and put the Money into her Lap. I went before Justice Deveil , she confessed the Thing, and desired to be admitted an Evidence.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-38-person455">
                  Edward 
                  Satchel 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person455" type="surname" value="Satchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person455" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. When the Prisoner was in the Round-house she fell a-crying, and told me she was taken up for a Robbery, and said, that as she was standing in Little Drury Lane, one 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person456">
                  Sarah 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person456" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person456" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             threw two Guineas and some Silver into her Apron, and told her, there lies a Fellow drunk, and she would go and see if she could get any more from him, but she did not bring any more; that they went to the White-Bear, Covent-Garden, and distributed that Money between them, and there was 9 s. 6 d. a piece; and they changed a Halfpenny into two Farthings, that every one might have alike; and the Prisoner desired I would speak early in the Morning to Col. 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person457">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person457" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person457" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , that she might be admitted an Evidence against the others; but I was obliged to wait on 'Squire Cook , in Lincoln's-Inn Fields, with two Pieces of Cloth, and so neglected to do it, which I am very sorry for: She said she was drawn in, and was very sorry for what she had done. When I spoke to the Colonel about it, he said it was too late, she had gone too far: I told the Colonel, I had given her some Hopes of it, but he did not take any Notice of it.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-38-person458">
                  William 
                  Rogie 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person458" type="surname" value="Rogie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person458" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Beadle, confirmed the Evidence of the Constable, with respect to the Confession that she made, and said, There was one 
               <persName id="t17430114-38-person459">
                  Richard 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person459" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person459" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another Soldier (I think his Name was Waters) there. - She gave this Account herself, I believe, in Hopes of being made an Evidence; she had some Hopes given her of it: The Constable, and I, and another, went into Parker's-Lane to see after this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140030"></xptr> Lucas and Berry, whom she had impeached, and we could not find them; she said that Lucas had two Shillings of the Money.</p>



               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-38-person460">
                  John 
                  Acton 
               <interp inst="t17430114-38-person460" type="surname" value="Acton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person460" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Watchman, said, he saw the Prosecutor come out of the Cellar very drunk, and would have seen him Home, but he said he could see himself Home; that he took the Prisoner about six Days afterwards, and agrees with the other Witnesses as to the Prisoner's Confession. Upon the whole, considering there was no other Evidence against her but her own voluntary Confession, (and that amounted only to the receiving Goods knowing them to be stole) on the Hopes she had of being made an Evidence, the Jury <rs id="t17430114-38-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-38-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> her.</p>
            </div1>
