<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490705-62">
               <interp inst="t17490705-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-62" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490705"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-62" type="date" value="17490705"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-62-off299-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-defend397 t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-verdict304"></join>
         
               <p>440. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490705-62-defend397" type="defendantName">
                     Anthony 
                     Dunn 
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-defend397" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-defend397" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-defend397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17490705-62-off299" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-off299" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-off299" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               he, together with two others not yet taken, in a certain field and open place, upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490705-62-victim399" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Crocket 
                        <interp inst="t17490705-62-victim399" type="surname" value="Crocket"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-62-victim399" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-62-victim399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-victim399"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, and put in corporal fear and danger of his life, one pair of leather shoes, val. 1 s. one pair of worsted stockings, one silk handkerchief, one pair of shoe-buckles, one half-guinea, and nineteen shillings and six-pence in silver, the goods of the said Thomas, from his person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>. <rs id="t17490705-62-cd300" type="crimeDate">June 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-cd300"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-62-person400">
                  Thomas 
                  Crocket 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person400" type="surname" value="Crocket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person400" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was come up to London from Kemsey, and in Smithfield these three boys came to me in the afternoon, on the 14th of June, they told me, if I would come along with them they would help me to a lodging, then they took me into the Fleet-market, then into Field-lane, there we bought some salmon for supper, then we went to the Golden-key on Saffron-hill, we had a pint of beer, which cost two pence, there we eat the salmon; then Edward Williams took me to his mother's house, the prisoner and the others went along with us; there they took three shirts that were tied up in a handkerchief, and said, they should be safe the next morning. I delivered them freely, and two pair of stockings: I observed, they locked the door while I was there, then Edward Williams's sister came in; then they said, they would not stay any longer; they took me into <placeName id="t17490705-62-crimeloc301">Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc301" type="placeName" value="Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc301" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-crimeloc301"></join> again, where, they said, I could not have lodging, but should go to Islington, there I might have lodging plenty for three half pence a night. We went along in order to go to <placeName id="t17490705-62-crimeloc302">Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc302" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc302" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-crimeloc302"></join>, and when we came to the <placeName id="t17490705-62-crimeloc303">Ass field</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc303" type="placeName" value="Ass field"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-62-crimeloc303" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-off299 t17490705-62-crimeloc303"></join>, it might be about ten o'clock, they said, they would go cross the field, and would be at Islington sooner. When we came into the middle of the field, Williams tripped up my heels; then the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17490705-62-person401">
                  John 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person401" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person401" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lay upon me, while 
               <persName id="t17490705-62-person402">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person402" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person402" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pulled my shoes, stockings and breeches off, with a silk handkerchief. 
               <persName id="t17490705-62-person403">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person403" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person403" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took my breeches, and the prisoner my shoes and stockings, cursing and swearing all the while. They ran away as fast as they could, and I got up, and ran after them; the prisoner dropped my shoes and one stocking, I stooped to take them up, and could not see them afterwards. I found out my uncle the next morning, and told him what had happened. We went and found the place where 
               <persName id="t17490705-62-person404">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person404" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person404" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived, the prisoner came into the yard, and we took him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-62-person405">
                  Hugh 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person405" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person405" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house on Saffron-hill. About three weeks ago the prisoner came into my house, I believe it was between eleven and twelve at night, he asked for a pint of beer, then he said, he wished it had been half a pint of cyder; I changed it, he paid me three half pence for it: then he begged to leave this with me till the next day; but I never saw him since till now. It was the prosecutor's breeches bundled up without any thing about them; the prosecutor swore to them as his property. The prisoner's mother called for them about a week ago; I am sure it was the same boy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-62-person406">
                  Thomas 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17490705-62-person406" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person406" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The boy that was robb'd is my own sister's son. A woman brought him to me about nine in the morning, on the 15th of June, saying, she found him crying in the Fleet-market, without breeches and one stocking; the boy telling the woman he had an uncle in town, and the place where he lived; she brings the boy to me, having bought, with the money she has got him, an old pair of breeches and an odd stocking.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050020"></xptr> After the boy had told me all his misfortune, I took him up Chick-lane to the turning into Black-boy-alley, I turned in, and came to a place where lay some rubbish, the boy observed some high steps, says he, I remember them, it goes into a court where Williams's mother lives, where I left my bundle. I set him foremost, he points with his finger, saying, that is the door. I went and fetched some persons to my assistance, and also a constable, and likewise sent to Justice Hole, to take out a Search-warrant. We found the house just as the boy had described it: we went to William's door; there was no-body at home. The landlord of the house living in the court, said, he could unlock the door; he did so, we searched, and found one shirt of the boy's under the woman's bed; this was in Black-boy alley. After the boy had described the thieves, said the landlord, come into my house, and they'll be all in the court presently; the prisoner was the first that came, said the boy, that is he that called himself the Jockey, (this was about 2 o'clock) he said, he wanted Ned. Williams, for he had stripped a country boy last night, saying they found him at Cow-cross; he also said before the Justice, he had six shillings of the money: then came Mrs. Williams very drunk, she was so noisy, that we could no longer keep her silent: her boy sent us wrong to find the others, viz. to the Golden-key in Rag-fair, and we found afterwards he was to have met them at the Golden-key on Saffron-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prisoner. How old are you?</p>

               <p>Prisoner. I am going into my fourteenth year.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-62-verdict304" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-verdict304" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-62-punish305" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-62-punish305" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-62-defend397 t17490705-62-punish305"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
