<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440404-27">
               <interp inst="t17440404-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-27" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440404"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-27" type="date" value="17440404"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440404-27-off154-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-defend296 t17440404-27-off154 t17440404-27-verdict157"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440404-27-off158-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-defend296 t17440404-27-off158 t17440404-27-verdict157"></join>
         
               <p>216. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-defend296" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Carberry 
                  <interp inst="t17440404-27-defend296" type="surname" value="Carberry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-defend296" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-defend296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of the <placeName id="t17440404-27-defloc153">precinct of St. Catharine's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-27-defloc153" type="placeName" value="precinct of St. Catharine's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-27-defloc153" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-defend296 t17440404-27-defloc153"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440404-27-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440404-27-victim298" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Milward 
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim298" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim298" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim298" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain open place called the <placeName id="t17440404-27-crimeloc155">Flemish church yard</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Flemish church yard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off154 t17440404-27-crimeloc155"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off158 t17440404-27-crimeloc155"></join>, near the King's highway, putting her in fear, and taking from her a silk handkerchief, value 12 d. a pocket, value 1 d. and six shillings in money
            </rs>, the property of Eliz. Milward, <rs id="t17440404-27-cd156" type="crimeDate">Jan. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off154 t17440404-27-cd156"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off158 t17440404-27-cd156"></join>.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Milward. About 8 or 9, or it may be 10 weeks ago, I cannot tell which, as I was coming over Flemish church yard, near Tower-hill (I lived there then) with a butter tub, about five o'clock in the evening, 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person299">
                  Dick 
                  Carberry 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person299" type="surname" value="Carberry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person299" type="given" value="Dick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knocked me down; then he tore my apron off my sides, and took my pocket with five or six shillings in it - I knew him when he came up to me - I have seen him several times - He had a room in the next house to my mother's, that came over her shop - It was pretty light, it was neither light nor dark - It was not so dark as to want the light of the lamps - I knew him after I got up again . I did not know him at first. After I got up I said , Pray Mr. Carberry don't meddle with me. And he beat me, and said, you B - h, I will knock your brains out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any resistance?</p>
               <p>Milward. No, Sir - I complained of it about three or four days afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you did not take him sooner?</p>
               <p>Milward. Because I could not take him - I had known him in that neighbourhood about three or four months - After he had robbed me he run away directly - He did return to his habitation again, but when I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it two days, or did he return the next day?</p>
               <p>Milward. I can't tell whether it was the next day, or the fourth day - I believe he was taken up upon the account of Justice Willoughby's being knocked down on Tower-hill; and there was a report that he did it - He went on board of ship after that - I complained to Justice Dennet three or four days after the robbery; and he sent a warrant for him, and he broke out backwards, and got away - He had been seen before that, but it was only in the night.</p>
               <p>Jury. Why did not you cry out stop thief?</p>
               <p>Milward. If I had, no body would have taken him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not do any thing to you. You run away as soon as I said to you, You B - h, you are one of them that robbed me last night.</p>
               <p>Milward. He did rob me - I knew him by the light of the day - There are several shops there.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did not you cry out?</p>
               <p>Milward. I made a great noise; but when the people saw who it was, they shut their doors, they were afraid of him, he is so desperate a fellow.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The night before this happened, another midshipman and I went into the bawdy-house which is kept by her or her mother, and we drank pretty freely. She took a laced hat and 2 guinea from this gentleman, and three shillings and six-pence from me. Said I, my girl, you have got a guinea from this gentleman, and a laced hat. She said she knew nothing of it. They had stripped us so, that we had not money to pay our reckoning. And then they and their bullies sell upon us so, that we had like to have been murdered. There were a matter of sixteen whores of them together. So the next day, about three o'clock, I met this girl, and said, You B - h, you are one of the whores that robbed me last night. And so she charges me with robbing her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174404040016"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person300">
                  Sarah 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person300" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person300" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person300" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the neighbourhood, 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person301">
                  Catharine 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person301" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person301" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person301" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , the Prosecutrix's mother-in-law, kept a vile house. The Prisoner goes to sea, I never saw any harm of him, I saw him run after the daughter and throw her down. - About two o'clock in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What character has the Prisoner, has he the character of a thief?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I never heard any such character of him, he is reckoned a civil man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she complain then that he had robbed her?</p>
               <p>Cooper. She did not complain of any thing, she sat down upon the bench a little, and then walked home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person302">
                  Sarah 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person302" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person302" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has lodged with me several times when he came from sea, he lodged with me about three weeks ago. - I never heard that he had the character of a thief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person303">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Studly 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person303" type="surname" value="Studly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person303" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person303" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to his robbing her, I believe he robbed her of nothing, for I believe she had not a farthing in the world. - I never heard any harm of 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person304">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person304" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person304" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - the mother has the character of keeping a disorderly house. <rs id="t17440404-27-verdict157" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-verdict157" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>217. 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person305">
                  Richard 
                  Carberry 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person305" type="surname" value="Carberry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person305" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17440404-27-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440404-27-victim307" type="victimName">
                           Catharine 
                           Milward 
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim307" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim307" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-27-victim307" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in the night time, and stealing one silk gown, value 5 s. four cambrick aprons, value 10 s. six handkerchiefs, value 5 s. five suits of cambrick headclothes, value 10 s. fourteen guineas and seventeen shillings in money
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person308">
                  Catharine 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person308" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person308" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person308" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17440404-27-cd159" type="crimeDate">January 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off154 t17440404-27-cd159"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-27-off158 t17440404-27-cd159"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person309">
                  Catharine 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person309" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person309" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has lodged in a room over my head since last Michaelmas, he came into my house in the middle of the day, with a woman he calls his wife, and he and my daughter had some words; he came bodily into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by bodily?</p>
               <p>Milward. He came with a great stick, and he gave me a blow upon my arm, that I had like to have lost the use of it - it was the day the warrant was taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. What upon your daughter's affair?</p>
               <p>Milward. No, that was the last thing he did, it was upon the account of a quarrel, it was all within a day or two of one another; he came again about six or seven at night. I asked who was there, I believe he changed his voice, said my daughter, that's Carberry's voice. God forbid, said I, but I opened the door, in he came with two pistols in his hands , and a cuttean cross his month. My daughter hid herself behind the back door, and I got out of his fight, but I stood so that I could see what he did. He was in a great passion, and broke the chairs, shelves and things to pieces: there was a lad going by with a link, he got the link from the lad, laid about with one of the pistols, and broke the windows till he was tired with that. Then he took his stick and laid about with one and the other, and broke all the glasses and several bottles of small beer. And at the same time there was a mob of 100 people about the door. - There was a great mob, he threw the goods out into the street, and I went and picked up what I could, for I thought I had better have them than not, and he came out several times before all the people, and no body dared to meddle with him. Then he searched for my daughter and found her, he put a pistol to her breast and said, D - n you you B - h, if you speak a word you are a dead woman. Then he took a box with all these goods and money in it, and put it out at the window, his wife and the landlady he lives with were at the outside of the window, and took the box entirely away, and they carried it up stairs into his own house. And he not only took away all my things, but cut my clothes off my back in the street. The next day I got a warrant from Justice Jones, and I told the Constable what a dangerous man he was, but he could not take him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you got the Constable here?</p>
               <p>Milward. No; Justice Dennet said there was no occasion for him. The Governor of the Tower (I think it was the Governor) sent the whole grand guard, and as they came into the house he got over Esquire Willoughby's garden. - One that he was supposed to be a highwayman about, and so got off. - How he came to be taken I cannot tell, but I think he was taken upon suspicion of robbing Capt. Pidgeon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person310">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person310" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person310" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person310" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , confirmed the evidence of her mother in many particulars. She adds, that after he had done a great deal of mischief, in beating and abusing them and breaking the windows, he asked if they had any thing to drink, that not having any thing he went up into his own room, came down again, and then broke the shelves and every thing all to pieces. She says, that the people were afraid of him, that she sent to the Constable and Watchmen too and they would not come, and that the watch was not set; that she could have brought a great many people to have proved this, but the Justice said there was no occasion for any body but her mother and herself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her how she gets her living?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person311">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person311" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person311" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person311" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I deal in Rag-Fair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person312">
                  Jonas 
                  Ogden 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person312" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person312" type="given" value="Jonas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived in the parish these twenty years, and the Prisoner about three years, when he or I went out, he used to pull his hat off<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174404040017"></xptr> to me in a very reverend manner. He is a very civil man, but Milward kept a very disorderly house. They swore another time before this, that I broke the windows, and I paid 3 s. 6 d. for what I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person313">
                  Sarah 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person313" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person313" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person313" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - I don't believe the Prisoner took the value of this bit of paper away, for all the neighbourhood believes they were not robbed of a pin.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think they would perjure themselves upon oath?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I cannot tell that; the daughter was tried here a little before Christmas, for robbing a * man of his watch. </p>
               <p> * Elizabeth Milward was tried last December Sessions for privately stealing a watch from the person of 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person314">
                  George 
                  Coombs 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person314" type="surname" value="Coombs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person314" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and acquitted, page 6. trial 13.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person315">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person315" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person315" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am landlady to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of a box or trunk that was delivered to you by the Prisoner out of Milward's house?</p>
               <p>Mills. I was in bed, I don't know what they did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think they would forswear themselves?</p>
               <p>Mills. Yes, I believe they would, I believe they don't care whose life they swear away .</p>
               <p>Eliz. Studly. I lodge in the house with the Prisoner, he owned that night that he had been fighting with them and beating them, he was drunk and quarrelsome. - I did not see he had any pistols or a cutteau.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any soldiers coming from the Tower to take the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Studly. Mrs. Milward did bring them down, but they did not take him; he was there when they first came down, but they would not meddle with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he make his escape then?</p>
               <p>Studly. He went away then, but he came again two or three days afterwards, and appeared publickly every day. - 
               <persName id="t17440404-27-person316">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person316" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person316" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             complained to Justice Jones and wanted a warrant, but that was only for beating her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that they would swear falsely?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-27-person317">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Studly 
               <interp inst="t17440404-27-person317" type="surname" value="Studly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person317" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-person317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe they would not stick at it in order to obtain their ends. <rs id="t17440404-27-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-27-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
