<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451204-23">
               <interp inst="t17451204-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-23" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-23" type="date" value="17451204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451204-23-off116-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-defend249 t17451204-23-off116 t17451204-23-verdict122"></join>
         
               <p>23. 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-defend249" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-defend249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17451204-23-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17451204-23-victim251" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Brooks 
                        <interp inst="t17451204-23-victim251" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451204-23-victim251" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451204-23-victim251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-off116 t17451204-23-victim251"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; in a certain Passage in or near the King's Highway, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17451204-23-crimeloc117">St. Dunstan's the West</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-crimeloc117" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan's the West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-crimeloc117" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-off116 t17451204-23-crimeloc117"></join>, putting him in Fear of his Life, and taking from him seventeen Guineas and a Half in Money, a Hat and Wig, value 10 s. 6 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17451204-23-cd118" type="crimeDate">Sept. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-off116 t17451204-23-cd118"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person252">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person252" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person252" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-person253">
                  Robert 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person253" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person253" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Brooks. Yes, very well; I have cause to know him; I have suffered very much by him, my Lord. I was coming home to my House, the 8th of Sept. in <placeName id="t17451204-23-crimeloc119">Bolt in Tun Court in Fleet-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-23-crimeloc119" type="placeName" value="Bolt in Tun Court in Fleet-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-23-crimeloc119" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-off116 t17451204-23-crimeloc119"></join>: It was about Nine o'Clock at Night; I did not perceive any Body to follow me. There was a Quarrel in the Street between two Women, and I came by, put my Hand into my Pocket, to see if my Money was there, and it was all safe. I walked homewards, and turned into the Court, and when I came within about thirty Yards of my Door, a Man came behind me, and said, d - n you, you Brooks, you are a Rogue and a Villain: And before I could turn to look unto the Man, he knocked me down, and with the second Blow he cut me in this Place; and I had a great many Blows when I was down, and I felt his Hand in my Pocket, and he drew the Money out of my Pocket, and there was seventeen Guineas and a Half Guinea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person254">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person254" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person254" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner at the Bar) Do you know him?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have known him about three Weeks.</p>
               <p>Brooks. I am sure he is the very Man. I never drank with him in all my Life; but he came by my House one Night, and made me a Visit against my Will.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of Night?</p>
               <p>Brooks. About Eleven or Twelve o'Clock at Night; as he was passing by my Door, he said that he thought he heard Murder cried out in my House.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174512040013"></xptr>Q. Pray, what are you?</p>
               <p>Brooks. I am an Appraiser of Goods, and lend Money upon Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. You take upon you to swear that he is the Man that knockt you down: Was you quite sober then?</p>
               <p>Brooks. Yes, my Lord; I had drank but Part of two Pots of Beer with a Man, his Wife and Children.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, before he struck you, he called you Rogue and Villain?</p>
               <p>Brooks. I pursued him that Night, and I said, that I had lost seventeen Guineas and a Half, a Hat, and Wig which was found at the Barber's Door: I pursued him; he lodged at the Bolt-in-Tun Inn. After this I got a Search Warrant, in order to apprehend him, and I searched the Inn several Times, but never found him. At last I was told by one of my Acquaintance, that he was in a safe Place, for he had seen him in the Counter? With that I went to the Poultry Counter, and there I found him.</p>
               <p>Q. Are not you lame?</p>
               <p>Brooks. Yes, I have one Leg shorter than the other, and it cost me 40 l. to cure it, and it was a good Cure too.</p>
               <p>- Chainey. I know nothing of the Robbery. I saw a Quarrel one Sunday Night between Nine and Ten o'Clock, on the 8th of September. I was at my Door in Bolt-in-Tun Court, and saw the Prosecutor and the Prisoner a little before. The Prisoner comes down the Passage, and when he comes up to the Prosecutor, he says, D - n you for a Scoundrel Dog, your Names is Brooks. With that the Prosecutor said, D - n you for a Scoundrel Dog, who do you call Scoundrel? I stepp'd up and desir'd that they would not quarrel; but one Word begat another, and the Prisoner struck Mr. Brooks, and they both went to Fighting; and as soon as the Scuffle was over, the Prisoner walk'd down to the Bolt-in-Tun Inn, and Mr. Brooks came up to me; in the Scuffle his Wig came off. Then Mr. Brooks went Home, and after a few Minutes he came out again, and said that the Villain had robb'd him of 17 Guineas and a Half. Nothing more, my Lord; I saw no more. I heard after, that he went in Pursuit of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner have his Hand in his Pocket?</p>
               <p>Chainey. No, it was dark, I could not see.</p>
               <p>- Molloy. I was going to Bed, and had just put the Candle out; I heard the Prisoner at the Bar say, You are a Scoundrel. I stood at the Step of my Door, and I saw Mr. Chainey with a Pipe in his Hand, and the Prisoner at the Bar knock'd Mr. Brooks down. I was naked, I did not care to go out naked. I saw the Prisoner upon him. I then being sorry to see my Friend ill us'd, I said, What are you going to rob my Neighbour? And I am about 10 Yards, altho' I was naked, but I return'd back again. Mr. Brooks put his Hand into his Pocket, and said, I am robb'd of all my Gold; he said he was robb'd of 17 Guineas and an Half. I still continu'd in my Shirt. Mr. Chatney went into his House.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Molloy. I am a Weaver, and work for 'Squire Turner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person255">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person255" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person255" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-person256">
                  Mary 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person256" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person256" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you?</p>
               <p>Porter. I am a Washer-Woman; I take in Washing; I live opposite to Mr. Brooks. I heard a Scuffle in the Court; I went to the Window, and I saw Mr. Molloy in his Shirt and Cap helping Mr. Brooks off the Ground, and he brought him to his own Door. I heard him myself say, that he was robb'd; I was near althought I was up two Pair of Stairs, and he said that he was robb'd of 17 Guineas and a Half.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person257">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person257" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person257" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-person258">
                  John 
                  Dowell 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person258" type="surname" value="Dowell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know for what Reason, in August last, that Brooks was going to destroy his Wife and Child, and came down with a naked Hanger in his Hand; and that the Constable, with others, brought the Woman down Stairs; and that the Prisoner should say, that he was a very dangerous Fellow, and the Constable took Charge of him?</p>
               <p>Dowell. Brooks, speaking of the Prisoner at the Bar, said he was a Gentleman-Thief, and charg'd a Constable with him; and they went to the Watch-House, and when Brooks came there, he did not know what he had lost, but he talk'd of a Piece of Lace that he had he lent 22 Guineas upon that Day; and I saw both the Prisoner and Mr. Brooks going -</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any Thing of the Gate-Way Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Dowell. I believe it was the Beginning of September. It was on a Sunday Night, about Nine or Ten o'Clock. I heard the Voice of the Prisoner, and Mr. Brooks: I heard that Brooks was roul'd in the Kennel, and dawb'd his Coat. I heard one Molloy ask, if he had lost any Thing? Upon which Brooks said, he had lost some Money; and I heard Mr. Chainey say, There's your Wig. After this I went in a-Doors; and some Time after that he came out of his Door, and he said that he lost 17 Guineas and a Half Guinea; upon which I had a Piece of Flamboy in my Hand, and I light it to look for the Money; but Mr. Brooks call'd me holping<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174512040014"></xptr> Dog: The Neighbours were all about; I found none. He said before, that he had lost five Guineas; and after he came out of his House he said, he had lost 17 Guineas and a Half.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person259">
                  Robert 
                  Money 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person259" type="surname" value="Money"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person259" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the Constable. Between Eleven and Twelve o'Clock at Night there was an Uproar in Mr. Brooks's House, and the Neighbours were afraid to break the Door open, and Mr. Brooks asked if I was there? and he came down with a Hanger in his Hand, and gave it to me. He had made several Notches and Cuts in the Wood of the Bedstead. Accordingly I took Mr. Brooks and the Prisoner at the Bar to the Watch-House, and I could not persuade Mr. Brooks to let him go, but he insisted upon his going to Court, and the Prisoner at the Bar was honourably acquitted.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed between Mr. Brooks and the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Mony. Why, Mr. Brooks asked him what he was, and he said, a Gentleman; and Mr. Brooks said, I suppose a Gentleman-Thief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person260">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person260" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person260" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-person261">
                  Mary 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person261" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person261" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know any Thing of the Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, no further than hearing of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person262">
                  John 
                  Atkinson 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person262" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Bolt in Tun Inn; I have kept it twenty Years.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of the Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. That it was on the 8th of Sept. The Prisoner at the Bar came in and said, that he had had a Roul and a Tumble with Mr. Brooks. It was on a Sunday Night, about Ten or Eleven o'Clock at Night. He told me that in the Fray he had gotten Mr. Brooks's Hat, and beg'd that I would get it sent Home to him. So I ordered the Chamberlain to carry it, but he did not care to have any Thing to do with him: Then I ordered the Cook to carry it, and he ( Brooks ) would not take it of her; she brought it back again. Then I went myself and carried it, and he would not take it of me in any Shape. And then Mr. Molloy went in and said, Mr. Brooks, han't you lost something? and he said after that, that he had lost seventeen Guineas and a Half, a Hat and Wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. F - , the Prisoner at the Bar? What Character does he bear?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. A very honest Character. He always paid me very honestly and justly, and was unto me a good Customer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Brooks come and search your House?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. Yes; I have had my People taken out of their Beds; and he said, that he would search every Room in my House for seven Years together Night and Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Of what Business is the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. He has been Abroad on board that Ship which the Lieutenant of was shot for Cowardice; and as I found that Mr. Brooks was so troublesome to search my House, I beg'd him to get another Lodging.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person263">
                  Jacob 
                  Ferdinando 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person263" type="surname" value="Ferdinando"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person263" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember one Sunday in November Mr. Brooks and Mr. Molloy came into the Green-Dragon, and said, that they had been at the Counter, and had seen the Prisoner at the Bar; and he said, God d - n it, I have gotten the F - at last; and he said, that he would hang him and two or three more, and then he should be reveng'd on the Inn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person264">
                  Rachel 
                  Corbet 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person264" type="surname" value="Corbet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person264" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the Green-Dragon in Fleet-Street I heard him say, that he would hang the Prisoner out of Spite, and he would hang three or four more, and then he should be reveng'd of the Inn. This was spoke in a publick Room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person265">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person265" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person265" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-23-person266">
                  David 
                  Cumberland 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person266" type="surname" value="Cumberland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person266" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar, Mr. F - .</p>
               <p>Cumberland. I have known him about four Months; he has the Character of an honest Man; he was a <rs id="t17451204-23-deflabel120" type="occupation">Midshipman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-defend249 t17451204-23-deflabel120"></join> in the Anglesea; he is a <rs id="t17451204-23-deflabel121" type="occupation">Gentleman of an Estate</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-23-defend249 t17451204-23-deflabel121"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-23-person267">
                  Daniel 
                  Arthur 
               <interp inst="t17451204-23-person267" type="surname" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person267" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven Years, a Man of strict Honesty; he is a Man of Substance.</p>
               <p>- , I have known him fifteen or sixteen Years; I knew his Father and Mother; Mr. Hutton of Gainsborough has given him several Dranghts upon my Lord-Mayor. There is an Estate in Lincolnshire, more than 200 l. a Year.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilson. I know him, and his Mother before he was born. His Father was a very great Trader, and traded for as much as any Man in the County.</p>
               <p>After such a Cloud of Witnesses appearing in Behalf of the Prisoner at the Bar, his Innocence was manifested with peculiar Glory, and Gladness was seen in every Countenance; and, in Consequence, he was honourably <rs id="t17451204-23-verdict122" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-23-verdict122" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, and had a Copy of his Indictment granted him by the Court.</p>
            </div1>
