<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480907-14">
               <interp inst="t17480907-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-14" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-14" type="date" value="17480907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480907-14-off59-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-defend116 t17480907-14-off59 t17480907-14-verdict64"></join>
         
               <p>397 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480907-14-defend116" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Dayley 
                  <interp inst="t17480907-14-defend116" type="surname" value="Dayley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-defend116" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-defend116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17480907-14-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 2 pieces of Portugal gold coin, 36 s. each, one moidore, a half moidore, 8 guineas, 12 half guineas,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070006"></xptr> and 7 s. 6 d. in money; the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480907-14-victim118" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Pearce 
                        <interp inst="t17480907-14-victim118" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-14-victim118" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-14-victim118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-off59 t17480907-14-victim118"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480907-14-cd60" type="crimeDate">August 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-off59 t17480907-14-cd60"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-14-person119">
                  James 
                  Pearce 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person119" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person119" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17480907-14-viclabel61" type="occupation">victualler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-victim118 t17480907-14-viclabel61"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17480907-14-crimeloc62">Great Marlborough-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-14-crimeloc62" type="placeName" value="Great Marlborough-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-14-crimeloc62" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-off59 t17480907-14-crimeloc62"></join>. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17480907-14-deflabel63" type="occupation">cobler and shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-14-defend116 t17480907-14-deflabel63"></join>, and lodged in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any money on the 23d of August?</p>
               <p>Pearce . I lost two 36 s. pieces, a moidore, and a half moidore.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any guineas?</p>
               <p>Pearce. I had a great many guineas, but I am certain to 8 guineas, and 12 or 14 half guineas, that I lost: my wife miss'd the money, and that night the prisoner was brought home in a chair, very drunk.</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. Did you see the prisoner offer your wife any money?</p>
               <p>Pearce. I was busy, and did not see it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think any thing of that being your money?</p>
               <p>Pearce. I did not suspect it at that time; and my wife was persuaded to get more money from him, in order to keep it for him; but he was very obstinate , and would not part with any. My wife seeing him have so much money, said she was afraid the cobler had robb'd us; and I found I was robbed, and got a warrant to take him up on suspicion on the Tuesday, and carried him before a justice; and he was very rude and faucy to the justice; and on the Friday following he was ask'd how he came by the money, and he said, where's the letter the constable took from me when he took the money? And the constable said, he did not take any letter or paper from him. He was asked again how he came by the money. At first he said he had it sent him for the use of his sister, and afterwards he said, how do you know but I earn'd it? for I have got 6 s. a day in my stall. My wife said, the more rogue you, that you did not pay your way as you went. I never before saw him master of a guinea in my life; and he said before he would say any more, he would do thus [making a motion with his hand, as if he would be hang'd if he did] and his sister brought my wife half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Where was it you kept this money?</p>
               <p>Pearce. It was in a chest of drawers in the room where we lay, and the drawers were lock'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mark your money?</p>
               <p>Pearce. No; I never mark any money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the prisoner give a moidore to your wife, in order to keep it for him, after he had paid the rent?</p>
               <p>Pearce. He did not know whether he had given it to her, or not; and he did not know it the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not he bear a good character in the neighbourhood?</p>
               <p>Pearce. His neighbours will give him a good character.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character , to your knowledge ?</p>
               <p>Pearce. He will stick to his work sometimes , and sometimes he will run out, and lie out o'nights.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Pearce. The day I was robb'd, in the morning, I put two 36 s. pieces, and other money, into a purse; the whole was 20 l. and upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when the prisoner was brought home?</p>
               <p>Pearce. Yes; and he had a great deal of gold and silver. I ask'd him for my money, and he put his hand in his pocket, and gave me a guinea; and I robb'd the guinea off, and said there was 14 s. 3 d. halfpenny remaining; and he put his hand in his pocket, and gave me a 27 s. piece, and afterwards he gave me a guinea more, for he had forgot that he had given me the moidore. I went up to look for the money, and the purse and all was gone. I said to my husband , I am afraid the cobler has robb'd us; because he had not a farthing in the morning, and was so flush of money then: he said, God forbid; and we went up, and it was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say, with respect to how he came by the money?</p>
               <p>Pearce. He said a staymaker brought his sister 12 l. out of Ireland.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any more?</p>
               <p>Pearce. He said he would hang before he did: and he said afterwards, how do you know but what I earn'd it? for he had got 6 s. a day in the place. And I said, the more shame for you, not to pay your debts.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lyne (Constable .) Mrs. Pearce came to me, and begg'd I would go with her to take up the prisoner, which I did; and I search'd him, and found in his breeches a 36 s. piece , 1 guinea, 3 half guineas, and some silver. I examined his thighs, and felt a bunch; and I opened the knees of his breeches, and cut a hole, and took some money out which was sewed up; and I cut open another part of his breeches, and took money out of that. I ask'd him how he came by the money, and he bid me set down a person's name, and that person could tell me how he came by the money; but he said the man was a stranger, and just come out of Ireland, and he could not find him: and he said, the letter that I took from him would give an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070007"></xptr> account how he came by the money, and that the money was sent to his sister ; but I did not take any letter from him. I asked him before the Justice , how much money was sent to his sister; and he said about 12 l. or 12 guineas. Said I, you have given an account of more than that already, with what you have paid; and he said he would say no more; if he did, he would come here [ making a motion, as if he would sooner be hang'd] and 3 or 4 days before he had not money to buy a pint of beer, and I gave him a pint of beer my self .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-14-person120">
                  Peter 
                  Crawford 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person120" type="surname" value="Crawford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person120" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 23d of August the prisoner came to my house with a pair of pumps for my servant: I asked him what he was doing there; he said he was taking the pretty girl by the foot: I asked him what the price of them were; he said they were worth 5 s. I said they were not worth 9 d. and she paid him 3 s. 6 d. and he said it was very lucky, and swore that he had not a farthing in his pocket before, and hoped it would be good luck.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-14-person121">
                  Isaac 
                  Chissell 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person121" type="surname" value="Chissell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person121" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17480907-14-person122">
                  Isaac 
                  Dove 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person122" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person122" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17480907-14-person123">
                  Thomas 
                  Connell 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person123" type="surname" value="Connell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person123" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17480907-14-person124">
                  Matthew 
                  Finglass 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person124" type="surname" value="Finglass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person124" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               <persName id="t17480907-14-person125">
                  Mary 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person125" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person125" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17480907-14-person126">
                  Mary 
                  Ingoldsby 
               <interp inst="t17480907-14-person126" type="surname" value="Ingoldsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person126" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-person126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , appeared to the prisoner's character : they said they had known him 3, 4, or 5 years, and never heard but he was a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480907-14-verdict64" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-14-verdict64" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
