<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440510-8">
               <interp inst="t17440510-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-8" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-8" type="date" value="17440510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440510-8-off42-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-defend119 t17440510-8-off42 t17440510-8-verdict45"></join>
         
               <p>251. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-defend119" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Terry 
                  <interp inst="t17440510-8-defend119" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-defend119" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-defend119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440510-8-defloc40">St. Giles's in the Fields , in the County of Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-8-defloc40" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields , in the County of Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-8-defloc40" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-defend119 t17440510-8-defloc40"></join>, single woman, was indicted for that she on the <rs id="t17440510-8-cd41" type="crimeDate">24th of April, in the 17th year of his present Majesty</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-off42 t17440510-8-cd41"></join>, <rs id="t17440510-8-off42" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-off42" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-off42" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               being big with a female child, on the said 24th day of April, &amp;c. she the said 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person120">
                        Ann 
                        Terry 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person120" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person120" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said female child by the providence of God from her body did bring forth alive, which said female child being so brought forth alive, by the laws of this land is a bastard; and that she the said 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person121">
                        Ann 
                        Terry 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person121" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person121" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not having God before her eyes, &amp;c. on the said 24th day of April, &amp;c. after the said female bastard child was born, upon the said female bastard child being then alive in the peace of God, &amp;c. feloniously, wilfully, and of her malice aforethought, did make an assault, and the said female bastard child feloniously, wilfully, and of her malice aforethought, in both her hands did take, and the said female bastard child with both her hands, out of a certain window in a lodging room belonging to the said 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person122">
                        Ann 
                        Terry 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person122" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person122" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   three stories high, in a dwelling-house belonging to 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person123">
                        Esther 
                        Bird 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person123" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person123" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Widow, in a place called <placeName id="t17440510-8-crimeloc43">Whetstone Park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-crimeloc43" type="placeName" value="Whetstone Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-crimeloc43" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-off42 t17440510-8-crimeloc43"></join>, into a paved yard, did cast and throw down, by which casting and throwing down into the said paved yard, she the said 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person124">
                        Ann 
                        Terry 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person124" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person124" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   the said female bastard child several mortal wounds and bruises upon the head, back, belly, and sides, did give, of which said mortal wounds and bruises upon the head, back, belly, and sides, of the said female bastard child, the said female bastard child instantly died; and therefore the Jurors do say, that she the said 
                     <persName id="t17440510-8-person125">
                        Ann 
                        Terry 
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person125" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person125" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-8-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said female bastard child, feloniously, wilfully, and of her malice aforethought, did kill and murder, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the same murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person126">
                  Mary 
                  Ditcher 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person126" type="surname" value="Ditcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person126" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of April I happened to be abroad, and when I came home I was told the Prisoner was in a violent fit of the colic; I said, Nanny, you being something in years may have some disorder. She had a Miss a little before Christmas. I sent her some penny-royal water, and when I came up again I saw some further disorder, but no appearance of the birth of a child. I asked her what ailed her. [The witness expressed herself so as to show the nature of the Prisoner's disorder.] I sent for her aunt, and gave her that which was proper. In the morning the child was found in the yard. Her aunt came to me, and said, Mrs. Ditcher, Nanny has thrown it out. Said I, what has she thrown out? Why, a child, said she. Said I, you frighten me to death. I said, oh Nanny! how could you be so barbarous as to throw it out? Said she, Mrs. Ditcher, I did it to hide my shame, and for fear you should see it. I asked her, whether the child was alive when it was born, and she said it was not. I did not see it till next morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person127">
                  John 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person127" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between five and six the 24th of April in the morning as I was going to my work, I saw a dead child lye upon the pavement in the yard upon it's back, so I went and alarmed the people of the house where the Prisoner lives - I live on the ground floor in the same house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any observation upon the child?</p>
               <p>Phillips. No more than to see that it was a child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person128">
                  Ann 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person128" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person128" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of April I was called to the Prisoner at the bar. I found she had been delivered of a child. [She said she performed the business of a midwife.] I asked her how she could do such a barbarous action as to throw her child out of the window? She said she did it to hide her shame. Whether the child that was found was the child she was delivered of, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child?</p>
               <p>Tanner. Yes - it was a female child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether the child was born alive or dead?</p>
               <p>Tanner. I cannot judge whether it was or not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person129">
                  Edward 
                  Kelleck 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person129" type="surname" value="Kelleck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person129" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was called by the Coroner in order to examine this child, and upon examination of the child, I found it in the first place entirely free from all cleansing, but naturally as it came from the body. Upon examination, after they had cleansed it, I found there was a large contusion on the left cheek by the Os Temporum, there was a confraction of that and the jaw bone. I opened the Thorax to make an experiment upon the lungs, and some part of the lungs would swim, and some would not: she tore it away I suppose from her body. I saw upon opening the lungs that part of them were a little inflated, and would swim; this is a common experiment upon this subject, but by the tearing it away from her body, there was not time to inslate the lungs, and make them hollow. The child was blackish, which shows it was in a fluid slate while it was in the mother's body; but whether it had breathe or no after it came out of the body, I cannot pretend to say.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your general observation in cases of this nature?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100012"></xptr>Kelleck. There is no role without an exception, sometimes, they may breathe before they come really into the world; I have tried that experiment many a time, but I cannot be downright certain and positive of it; but if you take an infant out of a woman's body (before it breathes) these lungs will never swim. Suppose a woman was six or seven months gone with child, and the child was dead within her, those lungs will never swim; but as children come forward in the birth, they may breathe before they are really born.</p>
               <p>Q. If a child is still-born, and dies before the delivery, the lungs will never swim; but if a child should die in the delivery, will they swim?</p>
               <p>Kelleck. It is possible they may, but I believe she was so hasty in the birth, that I apprehend she did not give time to let it breathe.</p>
               <p>Q. If the child had any respiration, would not the whole lungs be inflated with the first respiration?</p>
               <p>Kelleck. No; there must be several respirations before the whole lungs come to be inflated.</p>
               <p>Q. Now as to the contraction or expansion of the lungs, I would ask you, whether, if the actual respiration from which the blood circulates is performed for three or four seconds, all the lungs are not expanded?</p>
               <p>Kelleck. No; I believe not in so short a space.</p>
               <p>Q. Now in the case of a still-born child, will part of the lungs swim, and part sink?</p>
               <p>Kelleck. There have been experiments both ways.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a child is suffocated in the delivery, in that case does it occur to you, that part of those lungs have swam, and part have sunk?</p>
               <p>Kelleck. Sometimes they have partly done so, and partly not, that is to say, if it was suffocated in the birth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person130">
                  Thomas 
                  Noakes 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person130" type="surname" value="Noakes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person130" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is a very quiet honest woman, only very foolish. <rs id="t17440510-8-deflabel44" type="occupation">She used to close upper leathers for shoes</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-defend119 t17440510-8-deflabel44"></join>; she has worked for my father and me upwards of six years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person131">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stendrup 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person131" type="surname" value="Stendrup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person131" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner thirty seven or thirty eight years, I have reputed her a very silly foolish girl, not capable of taking care of herself. I never heard any ill of her, nor nobody can say any harm of her. I believe sometimes she is not compos mentis.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she is capable of knowing whether she is with child, or not?</p>
               <p>Stendrup. I cannot tell what to say to that; I believe she might be so far non compos mentis as not to know the danger there might be attending the want of care.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-8-person132">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Eden 
               <interp inst="t17440510-8-person132" type="surname" value="Eden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person132" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-person132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All I know of the Prisoner is, that she is a hard working body, and I never knew of any man that followed her.</p>
               <p>Q. Mrs. Ditcher, when you ordered her some pe royal water was she in her senses?</p>
               <p>Ditcher. I cannot tell; as to the questions I asked her, she did not answer as if she had any sense.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so?</p>
               <p>Ditcher. Because she said when she flung it out at the window it was to hide her shame; and I asked her as to the other matters that belonged to the child, and she did not know what I meant. I asked her several questions afterwards, and she answered me as if she was delirious, particularly with relation to the manner of her delivery. And I asked her who was the father of it, she hammered a good while, and at last she said it was one that was apprentice to her brother. I saw the lad she laid the child to, the morning it was found, and he said he would have taken care of it, if he had known she had been with child by him. <rs id="t17440510-8-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440510-8-punish46" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-8-punish46" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-8-defend119 t17440510-8-punish46"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
