<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-15">
               <interp inst="t17431012-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-15" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-15" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-15-off63-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-15-defend159 t17431012-15-off63 t17431012-15-verdict65"></join>
         
               <p>476. + 
               <persName id="t17431012-15-defend159" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Kill 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-defend159" type="surname" value="Kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-defend159" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-defend159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17431012-15-defloc62">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-15-defloc62" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-15-defloc62" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-15-defend159 t17431012-15-defloc62"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17431012-15-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17431012-15-cd64" type="crimeDate">6th of October, in the 17th Year of his present Majesty</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-15-off63 t17431012-15-cd64"></join>. upon 
                     <persName id="t17431012-15-victim160" type="victimName">
                        Elizabeth, the Wife of 
                           <persName id="t17431012-15-person161" type="victimName">
                              John 
                              Berry 
                           <interp inst="t17431012-15-person161" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17431012-15-person161" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17431012-15-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-15-off63 t17431012-15-person161"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17431012-15-victim160" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-15-victim160" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-15-victim160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-15-off63 t17431012-15-victim160"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , did feloniously make an Assault; and her, the said Elizabeth, against her Will, did ravish, and carnally know against the Peace of the King, &amp;c. and against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person162">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person162" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person162" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday Sev'nnight, at Night, I went out of my own House just after the Clock struck nine, to see for my Husband; and I found him at one 
               <persName id="t17431012-15-person163">
                  Rowland 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person163" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person163" type="given" value="Rowland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, at the Turnpike, in the King's Road at Chelsea - my Husband is a Labourer in Chelsea, he has been a good Husband; he had another Man drinking with him; I staid about a Quarter of an Hour; they had a full Pot of Beer before them; but when I came away, there was not above a Quarter of a Pint in it; and, he said, he would come presently - I saw he was a little in Liquor: When I came to the White Stiles, facing Burton's Court, it was very dark - (I believe it was then half an Hour after nine) I found that my Husband, who I expected to go with me, did not follow me (for he turned down from me into Chelsea-Common, being in Liquor). I heard the Tread of Feet, and thought it was my Husband; and my Spade-Bitch was with me; I found him lying upon the Ground, and he was so suddled, that he could not get up; I saw a Light coming over the Common from the Sign of the Cow and the Two Calves; and when the Man came near me, I asked him if he would be so kind as to help my Husband up, and try to get him Home; with that, the Man with the Light came to help my Husband up; and the Prisoner was with him; they hope my Husband up, as they said; and they said, he could not stand; and I believe he could not; the Man said, If you will not go Home with your Wife, lie there, and be d - d; and the Man went away with the Light, and the Prisoner with him; I went a little Distance from my Husband, and thought he would come after me; I took his Hat and Wig off, thinking he would be cold, and follow me; he not coming, I went back again; but he was not in the Place where I left him; he was moved farther; with that I saw a Light by the Sign of the Cow and the Two Calves; I went thither, and then the Light was out; so I did not knock, but came back again, and was going Home; when I was got about half way over the Common; the Prisoner came up, and laid hold of my Shoulder; with that I was surprized (I had got my great Spade-Bitch with me) says he, Have you found the Man on the Common? Is he gone Home? With that, I said, What makes you ask that Question; said he, By Reason I do ask you the Question; then, said I, If you do ask me the Question, I will not resolve you; with that, he said, I should go no further; said I, Why shall I not go any further? He said, You shall go no further, you shall stop here, for you want a Bed fellow; and I'll be your Bedfellow; I said, I do not want a Bedfellow; yes, you do, said he, and you shall not go any further; he said, if you make any Noise. I will knock you down; said I, but you shall not, Fellow; you had better be quiet, for I know you; though I did not, for I had never seen him before in my Life; with that he got fast hold of me, and said. D - n you for a Newgate Bitch, do you know me? With that he strove to get me down, and struck me on the Side of the Head; I got fast hold of his Coat, and his Shirt, with that he shoved me, and did all he could to get me down, and then struck me on the other Side of the Head; I kept hold of him, so that his Shirt and Coat tore with my holding him, with which my Hand gave way; with that he put his Feet some how or other to my Heel, and got me down; then I cried out Murder; he said, it I cried out Murder again, he would cut my Throat; said I For God's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120010"></xptr> Sake, Show Merey on me, and don't kill me; he said, if I spoke one Word more he would; then, I said, to my Spade-Bitch, which I thought would seize any Body, seize him; with that, says he, Do you say seize me, to your Dog; I do not value you nor your Dog; with that I begged of him to let me alone; he said, If you will not let me have my Will of you, I will keep you here till one o'Clock in the Morning, if I do not murder you - he said, I will either keep you here till one o'Clock, or else murder you; then, I said, he should not have his Will; with that he began to use his Violence in his nasty Way; then he asked me whether I would or not; I told him I would not - I am not a young Girl; for I am Mother of twelve Children - then he lay with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by lying with you?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person164">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person164" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person164" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I mean that he had carnal Knowledge of me - he forced me; I held out against him, till I had no Strength in me - he pulled my Legs open with his Hands [there being a little Laugh about the Court, she said] I knew these Things before I came here; I expected to be laughed at, but it is not a laughing Matter - he abused me till I was so saint that I could speak no longer, and then he had his Will of me for a great while; I am sure I thought it so - he had not done with me, in that way, I believe for the Space of half an Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his private Parts in your's?</p>
               <p>Berry. Yes, he had - not for all that Time - he had to do with me twice; I thought he had done with me the first Time, but he had not - I believe it was half an Hour both Times put together - I cried out, and struggled all I could; for I thought, at that Time, of Mr Smith, who was murdered in the Five Fields - it is a large Common that goes into the King's Road near Chelsea Common.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there any Houses near the Place where he did this?</p>
               <p>Berry. There's the Cow and the Two Calves.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from that? Is it a hundred Yards?</p>
               <p>Berry. Yes, a great deal more than that - I do not think it was above a Quarter of a Mile - as near as I can guess, it was between ten and eleven o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Jury. It is a very bye Common; there's a Foot Path cross it; but very few People care to go that way.</p>
               <p>Berry. It was as dark a Night, I think, as ever I saw from Heaven.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you part afterwards?</p>
               <p>Berry. I said, you have used me very barbarously; I hope as it is so late you will see me a little Way over the Common; with that he said, I would see you over the Common, if I thought you would not raise any body upon me, or below me; he said it was his Way home; with that I told him I would not; Said he, How shall I take your Word for that; says he, You are going to betray me: I said no, I will not, as you have done such an Action as this, and as I have Children of my own, I would not have the Thing known.</p>
               <p>Q. You say he had carnal Knowledge of you, where you sensible of any Thing coming from him?</p>
               <p>Berry. Yes, there did. - Moreover, some People said the Prisoner was not a clean Man, - I hope I shall not find it so; we came together over the Common as far as the Fighting Cicks, and there was a Light up Stairs as if they were going to Bed; the Gate was fastened up or else I would have apprehended him there; then I came over by the Chesnut-Tree-Walk, by the White Stiles, and Burton's-Court was locked up; said he, I doubt you are going to have me apprehended; Where do you live? I told him my House was on the far Side of the five Fields, (which is a great Way off my House) then he was very well contented to go along with me. They were all in Bed at the seven Houses: I passed by Mr Desborough's the Constable, and they were in Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you after he had done what he did to you?</p>
               <p>Berry. After I got off the Bed -</p>
               <p>Q. Off the Bed!</p>
               <p>Berry. Off the Ground; then he said, Now let me see what Money you have got, I told him I had none; said he, Let me feel, with that he did feel in this Pocket I have on now; says he, There is none in this Pocket sure enough; said he, let me feel in the other Pocket, I said, I never wore but one Pocket. (To return to the Story,) After I passed by Mr Desborough's, I turned to my own Door and gave a Rap; my Daughter was in Bed and thought it had been her Father and me, so she came down in her Shift and open'd the Door; when the Door was opened he stepped just within the Threshold; Oh, says he, there's a Spinning-Wheel; I then shut the Door in order to keep him in; there are two Bolts and a Lock to the Door which I fastened, and set my Back against the Door; said he, What am I come here for, I said I will tell you presently what you came here for, and I called out for Mr Tovey, a Man that lives in the House; Mr Tovey put on his Cloaths as fast as he could, and came down; says Tovey, What does this Fillow do here; I told Mr Tovey how he had used me, and desired him to go for Mr Desborough the Constable; Mr Tovey had not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120011"></xptr> been down long before my Husband came. I said to the Prisoner, you would not let me go when I was upon the Common, and I will keep you here now, and I made him sit down in the Chair by my Desk; and he told me he would make me sutter for keeping him.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you sent for the Constable?</p>
               <p>Berry. I went for the Constable, but he did not come that Night; he was in Bed and said he could not get up, and could not find the Key of the Cage; afterwards Mr Tovey went for the Constable, and left my Husband and I with the Prisoner; - my Daughter was in Bed; and he told Mr Tovey he could not come till Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with you when you made him sit down in the Chair?</p>
               <p>Berry. My Daughter, who is 21 Years of Age, and Mr Tovey: As soon as he saw that we would send for a Constable, he down'd on his Knees over and over, and begg'd us to let him go, and offered to make Satisfaction. I told him before my Husband and Mr Tovey, what he had done; he at first denied it, but he afterwards owned that he had done the Thing. - He owned he had Knowledge of me, that he felt in my Pocket, and that he would have robbed me if I had any Money. - I never saw him before he committed the Fact, and he owned that he never saw me before. I asked him his Name as I was coming Home, and he said his Name was Johnson. He owned before Mr Dunmore the Brewer - or Malster; I cannot tell which he is, he lives hard by Chelsea, and before Mr Gill the Apothecary, that he had done the Thing.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was you by when he owned it to Dunmore, and the other?</p>
               <p>Berry. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Council. Did not you ask the Prisoner to go Home with you?</p>
               <p>Berry. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Council. What; did not you say just now that you did?</p>
               <p>Berry. I asked him to go Home in order to get him secured. - I did not ask him before he had done the Thing - I had not been drinking with the Prisoner. - I was very sober.</p>
               <p>Council. You say the Prisoner was apprehensive you were going to apprehend him; how came he to go home with you after he had that Mistrust?</p>
               <p>Berry. Because I desired him to see me Home, and I told him I lived by the five Fields, tho' I did not live there.</p>
               <p>Council. I think you said the Bitch was always ready to assist you if you cried out; how came this Bitch to let this Man do all this to you?</p>
               <p>Berry. She used to assist me, but the Prisoner had worked at one Douse's a Basket-Maker's, and the Dog used to lie at the Door, and I believe she knew the Prisoner's Voice, for we lived that Way about a Quarter of a Year ago; I think he must know the Bitch because she did not fly upon him.</p>
               <p>Council. How long might he be penetrating your Body?</p>
               <p>Berry. Longer than I desired, as I told you before.</p>
               <p>Council. What did he penetrate it with?</p>
               <p>Berry. With what other People do, and with what you do other People with.</p>
               <p>Council. How long was he in you the first Time?</p>
               <p>Berry. I told you half an Hour in all; how long Time would you have had me have said?</p>
               <p>Q. After he had done the first Time; how did he get you down again?</p>
               <p>Berry. I never was up; he would not let me get up; he said he had not done with me.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, how long did he lie with you the first Time, when he first penetrated your Body?</p>
               <p>Berry. I believe about a Quarter of an Hour. - I do not know whether he called to the Bitch or no.</p>
               <p>Q. You seem to be a stout strong Woman and kept him for some time in your House by yourself, how long did you keep him there?</p>
               <p>Berry. No longer than the Time that Tovey was putting his Cloths on?</p>
               <p>Q. Was it owing to your Fear or what, that you submitted to him so as to let him be Master of you for half an Hour together?</p>
               <p>Berry. I did not submit at all, for when he pulled me open by Violence, I had not Power to resist. - I do not know where the Prisoner lives any otherwise, than that he is a Basket-Maker, and works with Mr Sadler; Mr Sadler said if I would take Half a Guinea, he would give it me to make it up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person165">
                  John 
                  Tovey 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person165" type="surname" value="Tovey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As near as I can guess, between twelve and one o'Clock, Mrs Berry's Daughter called me out of my Bed, and said, For God's-Sake come down, for here is a Man threatens to cut my Mother's Throat; when I came down Mrs Berry said, Mr Tovey, this Fellow has abused me very much, and I desire you would lend us your Assistance to keep him till we can charge a Constable with him. Mrs Berry would have gone for a Constable, but I did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120012"></xptr> not care to say in the House with the Man by myself; after I had said some Time, I said you had better let the Fellow go about his Business, for it will cost you a great deal of Trouble and some Expence if you swear this Thing against him; she said he should answer for his Offence; then the Prisoner dropped upon his Knees and begged to go home, and said he would make any Satisfaction. Mrs Berry made Answer. No you shall not go as you have threatned to cut my Throat and to rob me: Said she, You never offered to cut my Throat did you? No, said he, You did not search my Pocket neither, did you? Yes, said he, my Hand was in your Pocket, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she charge him with any particular Matter?</p>
               <p>Tovey . She said he had lain with her twice by Force, or against her Will, or something like that.</p>
               <p>Q. Before you came down was the Woman's Husband with her?</p>
               <p>Tovey. He really was with her. - I never saw the Prisoner to my Knowledge before that Night. I know nothing of his Character; I have heard of his Name, and where he worked.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person166">
                  John 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person166" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person166" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It is true enough (as my Wife says) that I was suddled; I was so suddled that I could not stand, and my Wife took my Hat and Wig off; the Prisoner and another Man came over the Common, and the Man said, if I would not go home with my Wife I might lie there and be d - n'd; at last I fell asleep, and slept till twelve o'Clock or thereabout, and when I came Home I found the Prisoner and my Wife within my own Door; says she, This Man has forced me against my Will, and has ruin'd me; said I, I am sorry to hear that, I wish I had gone Home at first if that's the Story; - She said he had lain with her twice, till she had hardly any Breath in her Body; said I, are you not a vile Rogue to do so? - He said he could not deny but he did it, and dropped down on his Knees and asked Pardon; I told him, Fellow, you have done enough to bang you, and when you have done that to be betrayed Home by the Woman! you foolish ignorant Blockhead. I said his asking Pardon would not do now, for he should be brought to Justice. - I did tell him he had ruined my Wife; said I, Are you a clean Man; he said he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found that he was not?</p>
               <p>Berry. I dare not come there yet for Fear.</p>
               <p>Council. Don't you apprehend your Wife to be given to be in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Berry. She will scold a little now and then, that is nothing at all to the Purpose. - I cannot say but she may drink too much; - I have been married to her 32 Years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. An't please you my Lord, Mrs Berry asked me to go Home with her; said she, young Man, do go along with me over the Common to look for my Husband, and I will treat you with any Thing if you will go along with me; which I did, and she persuaded me to go Home to her House. - I never did any such Thing to her, nor nothing like it; I am as innocent of it as the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person167">
                  George 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person167" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person167" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr Berry did send a Person from Mr Hopkins's, who lives over-against me in Petty-France, Westminster, to acquaint me that he wanted to speak with me; he made great Complaints of his Wife, and said she was a terrible drunken Creature, and he wanted to consine her, that he was an unfortunate poor Man, and had an unfortunate Wife. He said, when she is drunk she is in such Fits that I am afraid she will do me a Mischief some Time or other. - I keep a House to cure Lunaticks, - I pay 60 l. a Year Rent. Says he, if you will take her into you House she may make you a good Servant; I said, I will have nothing to do with such a Creature, I will not take her into my House. - She is very bad as to drinking, I cannot say what she is as to any Thing else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person168">
                  Thomas 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person168" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person168" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prosecutrix very well; her Husband was a Coachman and lived at Chelsea, and kept the Stage, but what with her drinking and going to Law, I believe brought him very low; that she used to get drunk and abuse him, and he has said he could not go home with Safety for her - I take her to be a Person that is not to be credited, I would not believe any thing she say. I keep the Black Horse Inn, in Petty-France, Westminster.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person169">
                  John 
                  Figg 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person169" type="surname" value="Figg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person169" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs Berry's Character is, that she is a vile, fottish, drunken Woman, and a great lieprobate; I have heard her Husband upbraid with whoring and drinking. - I would not hang a Dog upon her Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person170">
                  William 
                  Sadler 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person170" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person170" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the Prisoner at twelve Years of Age, and have known him 13 Years. I never had a faithfuller Servant in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he as to his Modesty, or Immedesty?</p>

               <p>Sadler. I never found him immodest in my I have three or four Daughters at Home, and some of them marriageable; and if I thought he was given that Way he should not come into my House. I would trust my own Daughter with him, and if he was at Liberty I would employ him again.</p>
               <p>Council. There is a Reflection cast upon you that you should offer the Prosecutrix a Consideration to make this Affair up; did you make any such Offer?</p>
               <p>Sadler. I did offer half a Guinea Yesterday; and To-day they would have taken it, but it was too<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120013"></xptr> late. - I offered it out of my own good Will to the Prisoner. - The Prisoner knew nothing of it indeed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person171">
                  Joseph 
                  Toone 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person171" type="surname" value="Toone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person171" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner between ten and twelve Years; he is always in his Work, and always behaved well. - I do not know that he would be guilty of any such Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person172">
                  John 
                  Hornsby 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person172" type="surname" value="Hornsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 13 Years; he has the Character of a very honest Fellow for what I know. - I never heard that he had the Character of an immodest Man, and do not think he is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person173">
                  Thomas 
                  Walter 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person173" type="surname" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person173" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him nine Years, and never heard but that he bore the Character of an honest modest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-15-person174">
                  Martha 
                  Cufford 
               <interp inst="t17431012-15-person174" type="surname" value="Cufford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person174" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-person174" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (called by the Prosecutrix) I have known Mrs Berry about 13 Years, and I never heard any thing amiss of her: I have often employed her, and her Husband; they were always very honest People. - I do not know that she is given to drinking - I have heard some People say so as they do now, but I never found her so. <rs id="t17431012-15-verdict65" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-15-verdict65" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
