<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-46">
               <interp inst="t17470909-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-46" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-46" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-46-off194-c337" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-46-defend418 t17470909-46-off194 t17470909-46-verdict196"></join>
         
               <p>363. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-46-defend418" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Kenward 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-46-defend418" type="surname" value="Kenward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-defend418" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-defend418" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470909-46-off194" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-off194" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-off194" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing on the <rs id="t17470909-46-cd195" type="crimeDate">3d of Sept.</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-46-off194 t17470909-46-cd195"></join> two fine Holland Sheets, value 19 s.
            </rs> the Goods of Persons unknown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-46-person419">
                  Jonathan 
                  Beasley 
               <interp inst="t17470909-46-person419" type="surname" value="Beasley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-person419" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to my House and offered a Pair of Sheets to Pawn. I ask'd her whose they were? She said her own. I observed one of the Sheets was extremly fine, and very large, at the Corner there was a Mark pick'd out, and a Coronet over the Letters. I ask'd her if she was a Housekeeper? She said, Yes. Then she deny'd that, and said, she was a poor Servant out of Place. I ask'd her, where she liv'd? She said, she liv'd some time ago at Mr Miles's in Soho Square. I ask'd her, what Place she liv'd in last? She said in some Place near Grosvenor-street. I said, where? Then she reply'd, I will tell you the Truth, they were given me by my Aunt, who lives at Maidstone. I ask'd her her Aunt's Name. She said she would not tell me, perhaps I would write to Maidstone. She told me where she lodged. She went out of my Shop to go Home. My Man followed her and brought her Back. She would not go Home when she found he follow'd her. I sent for a Constable; she was committed to the Round-House all Night. I advertiz'd the Sheets, but no Owner appear'd, upon which I appear'd, for I am certain they are stole. One of the Sheets is fit for any Nobleman. One Wright, Servant to this Witness, confirm'd the above Account, of his Master.</p>
               <p>No Owner appearing, nor Proof of the Prisoner's stealing of them, she was <rs id="t17470909-46-verdict196" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-46-verdict196" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, and had the Sheets again.</p>
            </div1>
