<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-27">
               <interp inst="t17420428-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-27" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-27" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-27-off126-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-27-defend265 t17420428-27-off126 t17420428-27-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-defend265" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Page 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-27-defend265" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-defend265" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-defend265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17420428-27-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-27-victim267" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Bean 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-27-victim267" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-27-victim267" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-27-victim267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-27-off126 t17420428-27-victim267"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   (with another Person unknown) in a certain Street, putting him in Fear, and taking from him 13 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420428-27-cd127" type="crimeDate">March 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-27-off126 t17420428-27-cd127"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person268">
                  Daniel 
                  Bean 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person268" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person268" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             On the 14th of March last I had been into Spittle Fields, and between One and Two in the Morning as I was returning Home through <placeName id="t17420428-27-crimeloc128">Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-27-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-27-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-27-off126 t17420428-27-crimeloc128"></join>, near the Half-moon Tavern, I stood up to make Water, and then the Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280019"></xptr> and another Man in his Company, stopp'd me as I turn'd about to go Home. The Prisoner hit me a Blow with his double Fist, right against my Heart, and knock'd out my Breath for sometime. Then the other Man knock'd me down with a short Staff, or Truncheon, and the Prisoner put his Hand into my Pocket, and took out what little Money I had, which amounted to 13 or 14 d. or something more. After this, they beat me most terribly as I lay down, - they did not tell me what was their Reason for it. When they had us'd me in this Manner, they made off, upon which I call'd Watch! and then they turned back, and knock'd me down again, and left me bleeding. They beat this Eye out, so that I shall never see out of it, and I spit Blood for two Days. I know very well that the Prisoner was one of them, because he stoop'd down towards me; besides it was a Moon-light Morning, and there are 4 or 5 large Lamps just by; there was nobody with me but my Boy.</p>
               <p>Pris. Please to enquire into his Character.</p>
               <p>Bean. I am a Silk Weaver, and live in Baldwin's Gardens, by Leather lane, at the Sign of the Cradle My Wife is a Midwife, and I have work'd for Mr. Jackson, at the Golden-Head in Moorfields, these 17 Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person269">
                  William 
                  Attley 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person269" type="surname" value="Attley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nothing to say against the Prisoner, no farther then that I took him just by St. Andrew's Church in Holborn; there were 4 or 5 Thieves with him. I can't say what Time it was exactly; but I believe it was about a Fortnight or three Weeks ago; Bean was with me, and as soon as he saw the Prisoner, he said that was the very Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person270">
                  Timothy 
                  Bean 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person270" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person270" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 13 Years old last Michaelmas, being examin'd as to his Knowledge of the Nature of an Oath, was admonished to speak the Truth, and gave the following Evidence.</p>
               <p>That is the Man who came up to my Father first, and the other Man who was along with him, knock'd my Father down: I remember it was the 14th of March, because my Father set it down, but I can't tell the Day of the Week. My Father and I went to see for some Money, and coming Home, the Prisoner made up to him just by the Half moon Tavern in Cheapside, and struck him on the Stomach, and the other knock'd him down with a short Staff. Then they stood over him, and threaten'd his Life, if he made a Noise, and he said they had taken 13 or 14 d. from him, I can't tell which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they do any Thing to him while he was down?</p>
               <p>Bean. No, they did not strike him; they only stood swearing over him. My Father made shift to get up, and when he call'd the Watch, they came back, and knock'd him down again, and then made off.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that the Prisoner was one of the Men that robb'd your Father?</p>
               <p>Bean. Because I have seen him three Times; twice when he knock'd my Father down, and once since that, by Honey lane Market.</p>
               <p>Pris. I was standing at St. Andrew's Church, and Attley the Thief-catcher gave a young Man a Half-penny to get some Tobacco, and I ask'd him for a Bit of it. Then I went to Field lane, to get a Sheep's-Head for my Supper, and he came there after me, and took me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person271">
                  Wm 
                  Doleman 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person271" type="surname" value="Doleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person271" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard a Man ask the Prosecutor's Son whether his Father had sworn to the Prisoner; and he said, no, - he could not be sure. I am a Salesman at the Red cross in Chick-lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person272">
                  John 
                  Raymond 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person272" type="surname" value="Raymond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All that I have to say is, that about three Weeks or a Month ago last Friday, I happen'd to hear that a Man was taken up for this Robbery, and seeing the Prosecutor's little Boy go by, I ask'd him if his Father knew the Man? He said, no, his Father could not be sure.</p>
               <p>Attley This Man shaves all the Thieves in Thatch'd-Alley, and his Mother keeps a Brandy-Shop.</p>
               <p>Raymond. I live in Chick-lane, and am a Barber and Peruke-maker, I know the Prosecutor very well; he always pass'd for a very honest Man, and I have shav'd him a great many Times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person273">
                  Edward 
                  Craft 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person273" type="surname" value="Craft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person273" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 5 or 6 Years; I never knew no harm of him in my Life: He runs on Errands, cleans Shoes, or does any Thing in an honest Way. He has no settled Lodging, but lives at any Place he can pay for. I never heard but that he bore a good Character, and I bless God my Character is unstain'd if you please to examine into it. Out of good Will to the Prisoner (who I believe is as innocent as I am, and I desie the World to say otherwise of me) I took an Opportunity to examine the Prosecutor's Character through his Neighbourhood, and every House-Keeper gave him a very bad Character.</p>
               <p>Maary Craft. I am related to the former Witness, and live in Beach-lane. I have known the Prisoner ever since he was a little Boy, and never heard any Harm of him; but was always<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280020"></xptr> willing to do any Thing in an honest Way for a Bit of Victuals.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person274">
                  Jane 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person274" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person274" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him and his Family a great many Years. His Father was a Porter, and carried a Basket in the Market. I have reliev'd him with a hard Crust, and he was very thankful for it. I never heard that he was a Thief, but always believ'd him to be very honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-27-person275">
                  Rebecca 
                  Bristol 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person275" type="surname" value="Bristol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person275" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known all his Family a great many Years, and always took him for a harmless young Man. I liv'd 24 Years in one House, and I am almost forty Years of Age.</p>
               <p>Joseph Green. I have known him between 3 and 4 Years, and for the general Part, or altogether, he always was an honest, endeavouring Man, willing to get a Penny in an honest, tho' a mean Way. But I have one Thing more to say, - the Prosecutor, since the Company have been here, said to this Man, you Rogue you have said what you can't answer, and I will do for you when I get out of Court.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17420428-27-person276">
                  Timothy 
                  Bean 
               <interp inst="t17420428-27-person276" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person276" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you tell Raymond that your Father could not swear to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bean. No, he never ask'd me that.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-27-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-27-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
