<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460409-47">
               <interp inst="t17460409-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-47" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-47" type="date" value="17460409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460409-47-off197-c595" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-47-defend695 t17460409-47-off197 t17460409-47-verdict199"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090039"></xptr>190. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-defend695" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Hayes 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-47-defend695" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-defend695" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-defend695" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             
                  <rs id="t17460409-47-off197" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-off197" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-off197" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               being big with a certain Female Child, by the Providence of God; did cast this Child into a Privy, whereby it was suffocated
            </rs>, the <rs id="t17460409-47-cd198" type="crimeDate">26th of February</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-47-off197 t17460409-47-cd198"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person696">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person696" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person696" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-47-person697">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Troughton 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person697" type="surname" value="Troughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person697" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person697" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Troughton. Please you, my Lord, she came out of Service to my House for a Lodging, 'till she got into Place: She was about a Fortnight and two Days at my House before she was brought to Bed. Sir, the young Woman in the House happen'd to go up to her Room to put a larger Bed there in order that she might lie with her; but taking the Bed off the Bedstead they call'd me up, and we saw a Child had been born. The Prisoner said there had not; but I said I was sure there had: She said she was about six Months gone with Child, and had miscarry'd; that she had left the Child in a Place where she could have it again; and afterwards, that she had dropp'd it in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields; but upon Enquiry there was no such Thing. Her Mistress and I went to the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is her Mistress?</p>
               <p>Troughton. Mrs. Moseley. She told her Mistress, after some time, that she had thrown the Child down the Vault in Woodstreet-Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Child?</p>
               <p>Troughton. I saw it after it was taken out of the Vault, but never before. She carried it out of my House in a Handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive that she was with Child?</p>
               <p>Troughton. She always had her Apron tuck'd up that I never minded it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that you perceiv'd it?</p>
               <p>Troughton. On Friday between Ten and Eleven o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Woman appear?</p>
               <p>Troughton. As well and as hearty as she was before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you look upon it she was deliver'd?</p>
               <p>Troughton. She was deliver'd between Two and Three o'Clock on Wednesday Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she was deliver'd on Wednesday Morning?</p>
               <p>Troughton. She said so herself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she kept House from that Time to Friday?</p>
               <p>Troughton. No, my Lord; she went out on Wednesday Morning about Eight o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she keep out all Day?</p>
               <p>Troughton. 'Till about Eight o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lodge near to her ?</p>
               <p>Troughton. She could not go to her Bed without going thro' my Kitchen, and she went out on Thursday Morning as usual.</p>
               <p>Q. And did she go out on Friday Morning?</p>
               <p>Troughton. Yes, and back again at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go up in her Room on Friday Night?</p>
               <p>Troughton. The young Woman took her Bed off from her Bedstead, to put a bigger Bed on to lie with her, or we should not have found it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to let this Woman out of a Morning? Did she use to carry out something?</p>
               <p>Troughton. I saw her carry out something on Wednesday Morning in a Handkerchief, that look'd very full; but I had no Suspicion of any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there appear any Provision she had made for the Child? Any Childbed Linnen?</p>
               <p>Troughton. No, my Lord; but she said she had some a making.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married Woman?</p>
               <p>Troughton. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. So you never had a Suspicion of this Thing 'till Friday?</p>
               <p>Troughton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never keep her Company, nor converse with her?</p>
               <p>Troughton. But little; she generally had her Apron tuck'd up, that I never minded her.</p>
               <p>Court. So you say this Child was taken out of the Compter Vault.</p>
               <p>Troughton. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any Marks of Violence upon the Child?</p>
               <p>Troughton. I can't say that I could. The Rats had eaten one of the Arms and Hands, and one of the Arms was left whole.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person698">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person698" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person698" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-47-person699">
                  Mary 
                  Prichard 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person699" type="surname" value="Prichard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person699" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person699" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do know of this Affair?</p>
               <p>Prichard. Please you, my Lord, I know no more of it, than that I lay in the next Room to hers that Night, and the Night following she was to lie along with this Woman; and when they went to make her Bed, this Woman call'd to me, and shew'd me the Things that I thought was usual on those Occasions; upon which I went down to call my Landlady: When she came up Stairs, she said there had been a Child born.</p>
               <p>Q. What Things?</p>
               <p>Prichard. I don't know, Sir; Things as usual at such Times. When the Prisoner came up there was Company in the House, and she tax'd her with having a Child. She said, there was no such Thing. The Landlady said, as sure as ever she had a Child<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090040"></xptr> in her Life, she had one. Then she confess'd that she had miscarried; and the Landlady insisting to know what was become of it, she said it was very safe. The Landlady desired to know where it was. She said, if she would give her Leave, she would go and fetch it. My Landlady said she did not chuse she should go to fetch it; but if she'd tell, she would send for it. With a great deal to do, she said she had left it at the Duke of Newcastle's House. My Landlady said, she could never leave such a Thing there in the Morning. She desired the Landlady to let her go; for the Prisoner still insisted she had left it on the Stone Wall at the Duke of Newcastle's that Morning. They charg'd the Constable with her, and they sent the Beadle of the Parish to enquire if there was any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the House during the whole Time of the Prisoner's being there?</p>
               <p>Prichard. Yes, the whole Time, I believe. She was about a Fortnight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person700">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person700" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person700" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-47-person701">
                  Mary 
                  Moseley 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person701" type="surname" value="Moseley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person701" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person701" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Moseley. The Prisoner was my Servant, my Lord; she lived about 14 Months with me, my Lord; I perceived she was with Child, and I turn'd her away upon the same Occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you turn her away?</p>
               <p>Moseley. About a Fortnight before she was brought to-bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that all you have to say?</p>
               <p>Moseley. I went to see her at the Compter. I asked her what she had done with the Child; she said it was in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields; but I told her it was a Story, and she should tell me; then she took hold of my Cloaths, and said it was here: I ask'd where; she pointed to the Vault, and it was taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it any Marks of Violence?</p>
               <p>Moseley. The Arm and Leg, and the bottom Part was knowed with Rats, and sadly mortify'd, that we could not tell what it was; but as she said herself that it was a Girl, for no-body could tell what it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Thing further ?</p>
               <p>Moseley. No, my Lord.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person702">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person702" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person702" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460409-47-person703">
                  Mary 
                  Jane 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person703" type="surname" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person703" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person703" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Jane. I live just by the Compter. The Church-warden and the rest of the Gentlemen were pleas'd to send for me, and when I came, there was a little Bandbox stood upon the Table, and the Coroner swore me; they took off the Lid of the Box, and it was such a shocking Sight, that it almost took away my Senses: After I was recover'd, I examined it as well as I could, but it seemed to be so knawed and destroyed by Vermin, that it was not to be discerned. Whether it was Male or Female, I don't know, but she said it was a Female Child.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Child you saw in the Bandbox, the same that was taken out of the Vault? Did this appear to be a full-grown Child?</p>
               <p>Jane. I cannot tell, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Opinion?</p>

               <p>Jane. I really can't say, my Lord, whether it was or was not; if it was not at its Time, I believe it must be very near, it was wasted, there was but one Hand left.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there Nails upon the Hand?</p>
               <p>Jane. Small Nails, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Hair?</p>
               <p>Jane. No, my Lord, I did not apprehend any Thing of that; but I was so shocked with the Sight of it, that I was almost dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Who carried the Woman to the Compter?</p>
               <p>Jane. She used to go to a Man that she had lived with, and had three or four-Children by.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person704">
                  Aaron 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person704" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person704" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person704" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know concerning the Prisoner at the Bar coming to the Compter?</p>
               <p>Levi. She was committed by my Lord Mayor to our Place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she use to come there before?</p>
               <p>Levi. Yes, my Lord, she came to a Man that she pretended was her Brother; but I find it was a Man that she had lived with before, and had some Children by him.</p>
               <p>Court. She called this Man her Brother, did she? Do you know any Thing to the contrary that he was not her Brother?</p>
               <p>Levi. I believe he was not; the Prisoner confessed that she had thrown the Child into the Vault, and she brought it there in a Handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you whether the Child was alive when she threw it in?</p>
               <p>Levi. No, my Lord, for I did not ask her that Question.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to you to be a full-grown Child?</p>
               <p>Levi. I can't say, my Lord, I have very little Judgment in it.</p>
               <p>Court. (to the Prisoner.) Now is your Time to make your Defence: You hear what has been sworn against you, that you threw a Child into the Vault in the Compter, and you confessed it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, I was brought to-bed half an Hour after Two o'Clock on Wednesday Morning; I went out about Nine in the Morning,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090041"></xptr> I went to Wood-Street Compter, and threw it down; it was born dead, and had been so for two or three Days before, by a Hurt I got.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to give some Notice ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, I was a Servant, and would not disgrace myself: I was making Prepara tions for it: I did it to hide Shame, and to be sure I got more. I got a Hurt on Saturday as I was Washing, and the Child was dead-born, it was never born alive.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any to prove that you got any Hurt?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, I never spoke of it to any Body. I had made some Preparations, but the Woman that made them for me is now sick a-bed, and sent them to me Yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get this Hurt?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, I was hanging up of Cloaths, and the Stool I stood upon, slipt from under me, and I had my Arms up, and I fell down on Saturday in the Afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you washing?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was washing in the Compter, please you my Lord; I used to go there every Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-47-person705">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person705" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person705" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-47-person706">
                  Mary 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17460409-47-person706" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person706" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-person706" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) You lodged in the next Room, did you hear any Cry?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. No, I never heard any Cry, nor my Sister did not hear any Thing of it. <rs id="t17460409-47-verdict199" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-47-verdict199" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
