<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-6">
               <interp inst="t17431012-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-6" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-6" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-6-off22-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-6-defend91 t17431012-6-off22 t17431012-6-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>467. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-6-defend91" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Orr 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-6-defend91" type="surname" value="Orr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-defend91" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-defend91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17431012-6-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a black Gelding, value 7 l. 7 s.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-6-victim93" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Darnel 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-6-victim93" type="surname" value="Darnel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-victim93" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-victim93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-6-off22 t17431012-6-victim93"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17431012-6-cd23" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-6-off22 t17431012-6-cd23"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-6-person94">
                  John 
                  Darnel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-6-person94" type="surname" value="Darnel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-person94" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of September, I had a Horse stole out of Hackney-Marsh, and I found the Horse in Smithfield, in Mr Orr's Man's Hand, leading him to be sold; he was in the Marsh the 14th, between five and six in the Evening; Mr Orr said before my Lord Mayor that he bought him at his own House for 50 s. that he was brought to his House on Wednesday the 14th, but that he would not buy him till next Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Person to the Fact?</p>
               <p>Darnel. I can bring half the Parish if you please.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I deal in Hay and Straw, &amp;c. and live in Whitechapel; a Man brought the Horse to me and asked me if I could help him to a Chap to sell it, and he should be obliged to me; I said if he came to me To-morrow I would either buy him or help him to a Chap for it; it was an old Thing worth about 50 s. I bid him put him into the Stable among the rest of the Horses; which he did, and he came again the next Morning, and then I cheapned him before Mr Sweeting, at the Red Cow, and some other Persons. I paid the Fellow 50 s.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120006"></xptr> for the Horse, and gave him one Shilling for himself, and told him, if I made 10 s. or more Profit of it. I would give him something more; the Horse was owned in Smithfield by the Prosecutor; I told him, if the Horse is stole I must be the Sufferer. I delivered him the Horse, and lost my Money and Charges.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-6-person95">
                  Richard 
                  Alexander 
               <interp inst="t17431012-6-person95" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-person95" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner keeps the Elephant and Castle in Whitechapel; I have a House in that Yard, and as I came out on Thursday in the Morning, I saw Mr Orr buy this Horse, and pay the Man 50 s. for him; he sent him to Smithfield on Friday, and offered him to be sold for 3 l. 10 s.</p>
               <p>- Askew. I live at the George in Smithfield; Mr Orr has the Character of a very honest Man; I believe there are a great many Innkeepers would have appeared to his Character if he had desired them; any Person may happen to buy a Horse that is stole if he is never so careful. <rs id="t17431012-6-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-6-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
