<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410405-12">
               <interp inst="t17410405-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-12" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-12" type="date" value="17410405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410405-12-off51-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-defend89 t17410405-12-off51 t17410405-12-verdict54"></join>
         
               <p>12. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-defend89" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17410405-12-defend89" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-defend89" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-defend89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17410405-12-defloc50">St. Dunstan in the West</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-12-defloc50" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan in the West"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-12-defloc50" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-defend89 t17410405-12-defloc50"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410405-12-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410405-12-victim91" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hambler 
                        <interp inst="t17410405-12-victim91" type="surname" value="Hambler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-12-victim91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-12-victim91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-off51 t17410405-12-victim91"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   about 10 at Night, and stealing 2 Linen Shifts, Value 12 s. 1 Suit of Cambrick Headclothes laced, Value 12 s. 2 Linen Caps, Value 2 s. 2 Linen Handkerchiefs, Value 3 s. 2 Towels, Value 8 d. 1 Pair of Worsted Stockings, Value 2 s. 2 Aprons, Value 3 s. 2 Guineas , 1 half Guinea and 8 s. 6 d. the Goods and Money of the said Hambler
            </rs> , <rs id="t17410405-12-cd52" type="crimeDate">March 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-off51 t17410405-12-cd52"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person92">
                  John 
                  Hambler 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person92" type="surname" value="Hambler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person92" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am an <rs id="t17410405-12-viclabel53" type="occupation">Officer of the Marshal's Court</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-victim91 t17410405-12-viclabel53"></join>. On the 11th of March, I took the Prisoner with me to arrest a Person in Rag-Fair, but not having an Opportunity to do it, we drank a Pint of Beer at the King Harry the 8th, and then I dismissed him, and desired him to come to me the next Morning at 4 o'Clock. This was about 9 o'Clock at Night, and in about an Hour's Time I went Home, and found my Window wide open; there had been a Pane of Glass taken out to open it, and put in again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave any Person in your House when you went out?</p>
               <p>Hambler. No, the Prisoner, I, and my Wife, all went out together. When I came Home and saw the House in this Condition, I desired my Wife not to go in, so I drew my Hanger and went in, and saw that a Box had been broke open, and the Goods mentioned in the Indictment taken out. The next Morning the Prisoner came to me at 6 o'Clock and told me he could not go with me; I then went about the Neighbourhood to enquire for disorderly Persons, and was informed by a Woman that a tall thin Man ran by with a Bundle and dropp'd a Cap which proved to be mine. Upon this I suspected the Prisoner, and got a Warrant to search for my Goods, and found one of my Shirts on the Prisoner's Bed, at the Elephant and Castle in Drury-Lane. I then apprehended him, and he carried me to another Alehouse and delivered me some more of my Things. After this I carried him before Justice Poulson, and imagining he had got my Stockings on his Legs, I said it they were mine they were darred in the Toe with light grey Worsted, and on their being pulled off they appeared to be mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person93">
                  Mary 
                  Hambler 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person93" type="surname" value="Hambler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person93" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Husband, the Prisoner and I went out together to Rag-Fair, about 6 in the Evening. The Prisoner parted from us in Redlion-street, Whitechappel , about 9, and at 10 my Husband and I went Home to our House which is in Sheer-Lane, and found the Window of the Ground-Floor wide open. I had been washing some of these Things that Afternoon and they were taken away wet.</p>
               <p>Q. How is this Window fastened ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person94">
                  Mary 
                  Hambler 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person94" type="surname" value="Hambler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person94" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There is an Iron Masp to fasten it, but the Window Shutters were not put up, and this Pane of Glass which was taken out was just against the Hasp of the Window.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was the Window shut when she went out?</p>
               <p>Hambler. Yes, I am very sure it was, and when I came back it was wide open.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person95">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person95" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person95" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor brought a Warrant to me to search the Prisoner's Quarters, at the Elephant and Castle in Drury-Lane. As soon as he saw me he ran backwards , but I took him, and found one of Hambler's Shirts on his Bed. After I had found this Shirt, the Prisoner said he would carry us to the Place where the rest of the Things were, and accordingly I went with him to the Bear and Ragged staff, and a Woman delivered these Things to me. These Stockings I took off the Prisoner's Legs, and they were owned by the Prosecutor Hambler.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person96">
                  Martha 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person96" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person96" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner came to me the Day after the Robbery was committed, and said he had an Apron for me! I asked him how he came by it? and he said he took these Things from a Woman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174104050005"></xptr> man that kept him Company while he was at Camp, on Account of her detaining some white Stockings of his, which she had to wash. He came soon afterwards and left the rest of the Things with me, and then said, that he picked them up in a Bundle between Ludgate-Hill and Temple-Bar. This is the Apron which he brought first, and it was quite wet.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hambler . I washed this very Apron, and left it wet when I went out.</p>
               <p>- Cooper. The Prisoner parted with Hambler and his Wife about 9 at Night, at my House in Red-Lion Street, Goodmans Fields .</p>
               <p>Jury. How long did the Prosecutor stay after the Prisoner was gone?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Hambler and his Wife staid 'till near 10 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That Night that he (the Prosecutor) carried me to Rag-Fair, he said I should have Diversion, and at last I found that he was going to arrest some Body; but I not being willing to be guilty of any such Thing left him, and as I was going Home, my Foot struck against this Bundle, and I carried it Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person97">
                  Susan 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person97" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person97" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by the Duke of Newcastle in Drury-Lane at the same Time that Rhodes took the Prisoner, and I heard him (the Prisoner) say, if Rhodes would make it up with the Prosecutor he would give him the Clothes and Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person98">
                  Catherine 
                  Hinton 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person98" type="surname" value="Hinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person98" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 2 Years and never heard but that he was an honest Man. The Prosecutor came to Mr. Haines a Printer, who is a Prisoner in the King's Bench, and Mr. Haines asked him in my Presence what he designed to do with the Prisoner: Hambler replied, I shall have a Tyburn-ticket which is worth 20 l. and part of a Reward, and if he does not give me an Equivalent, I will prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person99">
                  John 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person99" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Serjeant. The Prisoner has been in our Regiment about a Year, and always behaved well. On Saturday was 3 Weeks a Man came to me, and said if my Officer would give the Prosecutor 5 l. he would make up the Matter, and throw in such a Bill that the Prisoner should not be hurt. This Man came in the Name of Hambler's Brother, but I take Hambler to be the Person himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person100">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodman 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person100" type="surname" value="Woodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person100" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner these 2 Years and always took him to be an honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person101">
                  Catherine 
                  Woodman 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person101" type="surname" value="Woodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person101" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 2 Years, and never heard any Thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person102">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person102" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person102" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten Years, and never heard that he was dishonest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-12-person103">
                  James 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17410405-12-person103" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person103" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 2 Years, and never heard any Thing to his Mis-conduct before. <rs id="t17410405-12-verdict54" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-verdict54" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17410405-12-punish55" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-12-punish55" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-12-defend89 t17410405-12-punish55"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
