<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440912-27">
               <interp inst="t17440912-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-27" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-27" type="date" value="17440912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440912-27-off138-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-27-defend235 t17440912-27-off138 t17440912-27-verdict142"></join>
         
               <p>378. + 
               <persName id="t17440912-27-defend235" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17440912-27-defend235" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-defend235" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-defend235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17440912-27-defloc137">St. Mary le Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-defloc137" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-defloc137" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-27-defend235 t17440912-27-defloc137"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440912-27-off138" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-off138" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-off138" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing from the person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440912-27-victim237" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Thorn 
                        <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim237" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 6 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-27-victim239" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Burridge 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim239" type="surname" value="Burridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim239" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-27-victim241" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Tollman 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim241" type="surname" value="Tollman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim241" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-victim241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17440912-27-cd139" type="crimeDate">July 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-27-off138 t17440912-27-cd139"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-27-person242">
                  William 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17440912-27-person242" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17440912-27-viclabel140" type="occupation">porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-27-victim237 t17440912-27-viclabel140"></join> to Messrs. Burridge and Tollman. I came from home with a load of goods upon my shoulder, and went into the sign of the Anchor in <placeName id="t17440912-27-crimeloc141">Dudgy-Lane , by Somerset-House</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-crimeloc141" type="placeName" value="Dudgy-Lane , by Somerset-House"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-27-crimeloc141" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-27-off138 t17440912-27-crimeloc141"></join>; I set my basket down by me and called for a pint of beer, there were three young women in the house, and one of them asked me to be three halfpence with them; I refused it, and went into the yard and took my basket with me; there were several more gentlemen in the house; then I went into the house again - I did not go out of the house I went into the yard - I was obliged to go through the house to go into the yard, and to come through the yard to come into the house again - I staid and drank a pot of beer with the women, and they said they would drink with me; I set my basket down by the side of me, there were two of the women sat down by me, and the other sat on the other side of the table, they asked me to pay for the whole pot, I refused it at first, but they said if I would pay for that, they would treat me with a dram of gin: I refused it, for it was liquor I did not care for - I believe I did just taste of it. I got up upon my legs and pulled out 9 s. 9 d. (for I had just before received 9 s. 9 d. at the Civet Cat in the Strand,) and paid 3 d. for the pot of beer. During the time they were drinking these three glasses of gin, which I don't think could be above two minutes, the money was gone - I turned round to take up my basket , and missed the money. - I did not feel any body's hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the young women?</p>
               <p>Thorn. They rose and went out of doors.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before you took up your basket or after?</p>
               <p>Thorn. I had just got my basket on my arm ready to go out as they went out - The other two went out first , and the Prisoner followed ; then I put my hand in my pocket, and the money was gone. I asked the women of the house if she know them, and she said she did not; I got one to go after them, and I went down to the water-side, and saw them all three in the boat together; I called out to the waterman, thieves! one of them had thrown sixpence into the boat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the waterman seize them?</p>
               <p>Thorn. No, he did not; he pulled them away [rowed away] as fast as he could. I took a boat and rowed after them - There were some lighters a little way off, and some boats faitened to them, and I took one of them and rowed after them. When they came on shore I jumped upon a lighter, got on shore and took hold of the Prisoner and kept her. - I could not take them all for I had not a Constable?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing upon her?</p>
               <p>Thorn. I did not examine her as to that; the Justice asked me whether I could swear to the money in my pocket? I said, I could not; but it was small silver - I believe the Prisoner took it because she was by me.</p>
               <p>Q. They were all three by you, why might not one of the others take it?</p>
               <p>Thorn. The other two did not come near me after the money was lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side of the table did the other women sit on?</p>
               <p>Thorn. They sat on the off side of the table.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner near enough to touch you after you pulled out the money to pay the reckoning?</p>
               <p>Thorn. Yes, I believe she was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you the other two women in custody as well as this?</p>
               <p>Thorn. After I got on shore I had them all three in custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you keep them?</p>
               <p>Thorn. Because I could not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I go voluntarily with you before the Justice?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174409120013"></xptr>Thorn. I can't say you did voluntarily, because we laid hold of you .</p>
               <p>Q. Who is we?</p>
               <p>Thorn . There were some others took my part, that they did not mob me off.</p>
               <p>Jury . When you took her did you charge her with robbing you?</p>
               <p>Thorn . I said she had picked my pocket.</p>
               <p>Jury . What did she say?</p>
               <p>Thorn . She laughed at me. <rs id="t17440912-27-verdict142" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-27-verdict142" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
