<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-30">
               <interp inst="t17421208-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-30" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-30" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-30-off161-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-30-defend277 t17421208-30-off161 t17421208-30-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-30-defend277" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Murphey 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-30-defend277" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-defend277" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-defend277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17421208-30-defloc160">St James, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-30-defloc160" type="placeName" value="St James, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-30-defloc160" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-30-defend277 t17421208-30-defloc160"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17421208-30-off161" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-off161" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-off161" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing six Linnen Aprons, two Linnen Shifts, a Linnen Gown, one Cambrick Handkerchief, one Pair of Cambrick Russles, one Silk Hood, one Silver Tooth-pick Case, and other Things
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-30-victim279" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Spicer 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-30-victim279" type="surname" value="Spicer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-victim279" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-victim279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-30-off161 t17421208-30-victim279"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             , Widow, <rs id="t17421208-30-cd162" type="crimeDate">October 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-30-off161 t17421208-30-cd162"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-30-person280">
                  John 
                  Spicer 
               <interp inst="t17421208-30-person280" type="surname" value="Spicer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-person280" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came Home in the Queen Caroline from the East-Indies , the 1st of October, and my Mother died the 5th. I had been informed that the Prisoner had wronged my Mother very much, and was advised to look into it. I said to her, Mrs Murphey, you have wronged my Mother of a great many Things, as I have been informed: After some<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080020"></xptr> Conversation, she owned, she had pawned some trifling Things, particularly one Pair of Sheets, and a Couple of Aprons; said I, Mrs Murphy deal ingenuously with me, and I will not trouble you: She said, she would deal no otherwise with me: but every Time I saw her, she always told me of more and more, so that I thought she only deceived me: I was advised by my Mother's Friends to prosecute her, and they told me, if I did not, they would never regard me, while they lived. I delayed prosecuting her, thinking she would tell me where the Things were; but I found she would not, so I commenced this Prosecution.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you promise her over and over again, that you would not prosecute her, if she would be ingenuous?</p>
               <p>Spicer. I promised her so; but she never would be ingenuous. I went to Mr Kates a Pawnbroker, and enquired for such and such Things; and the Goods mentioned in the Indictment, were brought down to me; they were pawned in her Name; as to the Tooth-pick-Case, I can swear to that: I know the Mark of her Linnen, it was always marked with an (S) in White. There is no Mark upon this Case, but I know it by a little Bruise there is in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this your's?</p>
               <p>Spicer. It was mine originally, but I left it with my Mother when I went to Sea.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you give it your Mother?</p>
               <p>Spicer. I gave it to my Mother before I went to India. <rs id="t17421208-30-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-30-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
