<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-8">
               <interp inst="t17470225-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-8" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-8" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-8-off31-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-8-defend131 t17470225-8-off31 "></join>
         
               <p>139. 
               <persName id="t17470225-8-defend131" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas M 
                  Lane 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-defend131" type="surname" value="Lane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-defend131" type="given" value="Thomas M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-defend131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-defend131" type="age" value="eleven"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-8-off31" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-off31" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-off31" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing one Pair of Silver Buckles
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-8-victim133" type="victimName">
                     Jane 
                     Gorden 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-8-victim133" type="surname" value="Gorden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-victim133" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-victim133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-8-off31 t17470225-8-victim133"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470225-8-viclabel32" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-8-victim133 t17470225-8-viclabel32"></join>, <rs id="t17470225-8-cd33" type="crimeDate">December 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-8-off31 t17470225-8-cd33"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-8-person134">
                  George 
                  Overton 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-person134" type="surname" value="Overton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person134" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Mistress, 
               <persName id="t17470225-8-person135">
                  Jane 
                  Gorden 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-person135" type="surname" value="Gorden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person135" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person135" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of Russel court, lost a Pair of Silver Buckles: The Constable at Spitalfields, in a disorderly House finding some Rogues, they found some Buckles and other Things, and the Constable enquired of my Mistress if she had lost a Pair of Buckles; and she said she had lost a Pair of Silver Buckles in the Month of December; it was reported that they were pawned at the End of the Hay-market, in Piccadilly. I saw a Pair<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250013"></xptr> that was as near to them, as ever any thing could be. My Mistress told the Constable what they weighed, that was three ounces and one penny weight. My Lord, she is not here; she is not well; I can swear to them, as much as my Mistress can; the Minute I saw them, I said they were the Buckles that were taken out of my Mistress's Show-glass: When the Pawnbroker brought them to my Mistress, my Mistress weighed them; when she came to weigh, they weighed three Ounces and one Penny-weight to a Hair, as my Mistress mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-8-person136">
                  Moses 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-person136" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person136" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know about the Matter?</p>
               <p>Holloway. My Lord, the Prisoner at the Bar and I went out one Day to see what we could get, and we saw this Show-glass something loose, and the Prisoner at the Bar hoisted up the Show-glass, and took out these Buckles.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the Prisoner, that Boy, took out the Buckles?</p>
               <p>Holloway. Yes, my Lord; and I saw them in his Possession; and I had them in my Possession, and pawned them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Show-glass?</p>
               <p>Holloway. It was in Russel-court, near Drury-lane; there was the Place where we took the Buckles.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the Buckles ? Did you go with him to pawn them?</p>
               <p>Holloway. Please you, my Lord, I gave him eight Shillings for my Share, and so wore them for a long while; and last Monday was Se'nnight I pawned them at the Sign of the three Blue-balls in the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hollingsworth the Constable. What do you know about the Matter?</p>
               <p>Hollingsworth. The second Time this Chap was examined, he said he thought of this afresh, and said he had pawned the Buckles at such a Place in the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>Q. What, Holloway the Accomplice said so?</p>
               <p>Hollingsworth. Yes, Sir; when I went to the Pawnbroker, I told him our Warrant; then he said he would prosecute; however, afterwards he gave me the Buckles; his Wife thought it more safe to deliver them to me, being the Constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-8-person137">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Moor 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-person137" type="surname" value="Moor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person137" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was an Apprentice-Girl to one Mr Jones, and this little Boy used to be an Errand-Boy there; and I never knew an ill thing of him in my Days; he used to work hard with his Father in bottoming of Chairs; he lives in Gray's-Inn lane.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-8-person138">
                  Mary 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17470225-8-person138" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person138" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew him to wrong Man, Woman, or Child.</p>
               <p>[It was said in Court, the Father of this Boy was without, but would not come in; but the Court ordered him to be brought in, and was asked how he kept the Boy; whether he allowed him Victuals enough; and he said he did; but he could not make him stay with him]</p>
               <p>The Prisoner, though but about eleven Years of Age, yet it appears he has been very notorious in Thefts and Robberies, and was no Stranger to the Court.</p>
               <p>Before Judgment for Transportation was given up on him, the Court was petitioned to have him put a board a Man of War; which was granted.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-8-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-8-punish34" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-8-defend131 t17470225-8-punish34"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
