<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-15">
               <interp inst="t17420428-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-15" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-15" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-15-off74-c128" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-15-defend161 t17420428-15-off74 t17420428-15-verdict77"></join>
         
               <p>17 +
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-15-defend161" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Birk 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-15-defend161" type="surname" value="Birk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-defend161" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-defend161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of St. Mary Whitechappel, was indicted for <rs id="t17420428-15-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-15-victim163" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-15-victim163" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-15-victim163" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-15-victim163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-15-off74 t17420428-15-victim163"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17420428-15-person164">
                        John 
                        Murray 
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person164" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-15-person164" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-15-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , putting him in Fear, and taking from him a cloth Coat, value 15 s. a pair of cloth Breeches, val. 6 s. a Calamancoe Waistcoat, val. 10 s. a linnen Shirt, val. 5 s. a Wig, val. 21 s. a Hat, val. 7 s. 6 d. a pair of Silk Stockings, a pair of Thread ditto, a pair of Shoes, and a gold Ring
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420428-15-cd75" type="crimeDate">August 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-15-off74 t17420428-15-cd75"></join>.</p>
               <p>Robert Davis. Some time in August, I was coming from Hackney, and in <placeName id="t17420428-15-crimeloc76">Well-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-15-crimeloc76" type="placeName" value="Well-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-15-crimeloc76" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-15-off74 t17420428-15-crimeloc76"></join>, just by the Sugar-Baker's, the Prisoner push'd me into a House; - I can't tell the Day, for I never design'd to trouble my Head with her, if she had not made her Binggs that she had robb'd me. One end of th is Well-street, comes into Rosemary-Lane, the other into Rag-fair, and there the Prisoner and another Woman pick'd me up, and would have had me into a House with them, but I being unwilling, they push'd me in. It was between 9 and 10 at Night - I have belong'd to the Tower these 30 Years, and she used me very barbarcusly and threatened my Life, - there she is, and she has made her Brags that she robb'd me of every Thing, and has made me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280013"></xptr> me scandalous all over the Tower. I believe it was Mrs. Murray's House, but nobody lives in it now, for it is knock'd all to Pieces. When I came in Doors, there were three Men in the Room and two Women, they had got a Stinkabus of Gin, and I would have given them a Gold Ring to let me go, but that would not satisfie them, for they stripp'd me stark naked. The first Things they took were my Hat and Wig, which were better than those I have on now, and my Shoes I have now at Home, - I wish I had brought them with me. After they had taken my Cloaths, they all ran away, and I was forc'd to send for more, for I could not go home naked. They put me into a sad Fright, for they threaten'd my Life, and if I offer'd to stir or speak a Word, they would, &amp;c I was in so much Fear, that I cry'd and look'd out of the Window like a Madman; they stupified me, and burnt Liquor under my Nose; but I can't imagine how they got my Shirt off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-15-person165">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17420428-15-person165" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person165" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know that Man, (Davis) very well; he was robb'd in Well-street. I saw them take the Clothes away, - that Woman at the Bar was one of them. I was looking out of my Mother's Window, and saw the Prisoner go up to the Place where the Sugar Bakers put their Liquors, and put them in there.</p>
               <p>Q. Who lives in the House where this happen'd?</p>
               <p>Moore. Nobody lives there now; Mrs. Murray liv'd in it then, - she has a Husband, but I can't tell his 
               <persName id="t17420428-15-person166">
                  Christian 
                  Name 
               <interp inst="t17420428-15-person166" type="surname" value="Name"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person166" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know what the Prisoner carried?</p>
               <p>Moore. I never saw the Clothes afterwards, but I took Notice that they were Mouse Colour.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My Clothes were Mouse Colour.</p>
               <p>Pris. Did he ever see me before.</p>
               <p>Davis. I never saw her before she robb'd me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-15-person167">
                  Ann 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17420428-15-person167" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person167" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to my House about a Month ago, I ask'd her where she had been? She said, she was just come out of Bridewell. My Husband told her she would certainly come to be hang'd; she said, she should not, for she would never do so any more, and Newgate had groan'd for her a great while; for sometime ago (said she) I stripp'd a Man stark naked, and sold his Clothes. What (said I) was he an old or a young Man? she answer'd, that he was a good middling working Man, but an old foolish Son of a B -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lodg'd in this Woman's House, and she is an Evidence against me out of Spite.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-15-person168">
                  Sarah 
                  Oakley 
               <interp inst="t17420428-15-person168" type="surname" value="Oakley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person168" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and I were talking of her Robberies, and she said, she had pick'd up a Man in some Place by Well-Close Square, and carry'd him to a Bawdy-House, where she stripp'd him of his Watch and all his Clothes, and left him naked. I ask'd her whether he was a Gentleman or a young Man? She said, he was not a Gentleman, but an old foolish Son of a B - .</p>
               <p>Pris. They are welcome to say what they please, I know nothing of it. <rs id="t17420428-15-verdict77" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-15-verdict77" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
