<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-16">
               <interp inst="t17400227-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-16" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-16" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-16-off97-c136" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-16-defend180 t17400227-16-off97 t17400227-16-verdict102"></join>
         
               <p>170. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-16-defend180" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Holden 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-16-defend180" type="surname" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-defend180" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-defend180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-16-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously making, forging, and counterfeiting, and causing to be made, forged, and counterfeited, a Receipt for 12 s. and 6 d. with Intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-16-victim182" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Little 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim182" type="surname" value="Little"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim182" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   of the said Sum. Jan. 11. And the Indictment farther charged the said Holden, as above, with Intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-16-victim184" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Allen 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim184" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim184" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-16-victim184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   of the said Sum. The Indictment farther charged the said Holden with uttering and publishing the said forged Receipt
            </rs>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400227-16-crimeloc98">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-16-crimeloc98" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-16-crimeloc98" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-16-off97 t17400227-16-crimeloc98"></join>, <rs id="t17400227-16-cd99" type="crimeDate">Jan. 11. 1739</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-16-off97 t17400227-16-cd99"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Little appearing to be concerned in Point of Interest, was not permitted to give Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-16-person185">
                  Nicholas 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17400227-16-person185" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person185" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Little is a <rs id="t17400227-16-viclabel100" type="occupation">Brewer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-16-victim182 t17400227-16-viclabel100"></join>; and I have dealt with him ever since last May. The Prisoner was his <rs id="t17400227-16-deflabel101" type="occupation">Drayman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-16-defend180 t17400227-16-deflabel101"></join>, and by Mr. Little's Order, I have paid the Drayman every Month for the Beer I have had in. I know this Note; it is a Bill for 5 Quarter Barrels of Beer, and the Receipt at the Bottom of it is for 12 s. and 6 d. which the Beer comes to. I paid the Money to him for the Use of Mr. Little in full of all Demands. About a Fortnight before this Receipt was given me, Mr. Little's Clerk brought me a Bill for Beer which I knew nothing of; I told the Prisoner of it the next time he came, and he told me it was a Mistake, and that the Bill was intended for one Allen who lives at Westminster. However, to prevent Mistakes, I told him I would have a Receipt from his Matter, in full of all Demands, the next Money I paid him. Accordingly he brought me this Receipt, and said it came from his Master. I afterwards observed the Receipt was not dated, and in about three Days time the Prisoner coming again, I asked why it was not dated? He told me his Master did not use to make such Mistakes, so he took a Pen and put a Date to it, telling me he believ'd he could not write so well as his Master. He told me the Receipt was signed by Mr. Little, and I had never seen Mr. Little's Hand-writing in my Life, as I know of, so I took it as a Receipt from his Master, who had given me Orders to pay the Prisoner, and had told me he was an honest Man: So I used to pay him, and take his Receipts for the Money, for the Use of Mr. Little. I have six other Receipts which the Prisoner has given me at different Times, and Mr. Little never saw any of them, till I demanded this Receipt in full from him. The Bill was read.</p>
               <p>Mr. Allen, Debtor. Dec. 7. 1739. 1/4. the 14th 1/4, Xt (for Dec. the 19th) 1/4. Jan. 2. 1/4. the 9th 1/4. B. (as if it was cast up) 5 quarters. Sum 12 s. and 6 d. Jan. 11. 1739. Receiv'd the full Contents of this Bill, and all Demands, per John Little. Sum 12 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-16-person186">
                  George 
                  Hanna 
               <interp inst="t17400227-16-person186" type="surname" value="Hanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person186" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to Mr. Little; and as we make out our Bills about Christmas, I carry'd one to Mr. Allen. He told me he did not owe so much Money, for he had paid the Drayman every fourth Barrel, and he shew'd me some of his Receipts. I said I would speak to the Drayman about it. I did so; and the Prisoner then told me, he had seen Mr. Allen, and he (Allen) was now satisfy'd that my Bill was right, and he would pay me whenever I went that Way. The whole Account of Mr. Allen, as charged in our Ledger, and in the Runner at Home, is 1 l. 17 s. 6 d. 27 Shillings of which is still due, by our Books, from Mr. Allen: for we have receiv'd no more than 10 s. since he dealt with us. This Receipt, now in question, is none of Mr. Little's Writing, nor any Part of the Note; nor is this 12 s. and 6 d. discharged in our Books, and the House-Clerk always enters the Money that is receiv'd. When the Prisoner was examin'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17400227-16-person187">
                  Edward 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17400227-16-person187" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person187" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he owned he wrote the Bill, and the Receipt, and sign'd it with Mr. Little's Name, and he had nothing to say for himself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270015"></xptr>Prisoner. When I told him Mr. Allen was satisfied, both he and my Master order'd me to receive the Money, and give Mr. Allen a Receipt for it.</p>
               <p>Hanna. I did give him Orders to take the Money, if Mr. Allen was satisfy'd; but I did not give him Orders to write my Master's Name to it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I say before the Justice, that I did not intend to forge my Master's Hand, nor to defraud him?</p>
               <p>Hanna. I imagine he did it with Intent to defraud my Master; for he has received more Money than ever he brought to Account, and more than ever he charg'd Mr. Allen with in our Books. - I have seen the Prisoner write several Times, and I believe he endeavoured to imitate my Master's Hand, in this Receipt; but it is not well done; it is pretty much like his own Handwriting.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-16-person188">
                  Thomas 
                  Baylis 
               <interp inst="t17400227-16-person188" type="surname" value="Baylis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person188" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I heard the Prisoner acknowledge before Sir Edward Hill, that both the Bill and the Receipt were his own Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not deny what I had done, before Sir Edward Hill, because I knew I did not do it with a Design to forge any Thing, but to serve my Master, because Mr. Allen desired a Receipt in full, and I thought my own Name might not be a Discharge in full.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17400227-16-verdict102" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-16-verdict102" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
