<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-41">
               <interp inst="t17441205-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-41" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-41" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-41-off259-c415" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-defend516 t17441205-41-off259 t17441205-41-verdict265"></join>
         
               <p>69. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-defend516" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Goodman 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-41-defend516" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-defend516" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-defend516" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17441205-41-defloc258">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-41-defloc258" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-41-defloc258" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-defend516 t17441205-41-defloc258"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17441205-41-off259" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-off259" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-off259" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17441205-41-victim517" type="victimName">
                        Mary, the <rs id="t17441205-41-viclabel260" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-victim517 t17441205-41-viclabel260"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17441205-41-person518" type="victimName">
                              
                                 <persName id="t17441205-41-victim519" type="victimName">
                                    Thomas 
                                    Footman 
                                 <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim519" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim519" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           </persName>
                               
                           <interp inst="t17441205-41-person518" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17441205-41-person518" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17441205-41-person518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim517" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim517" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-41-victim517" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the King's highway, putting her in fear, and taking from her a linen pocket, value 3 d. a gold ring, value 21 s. a cambrick handkerchief, value 12 d. a fan, value 2 s. a snuff-box, value 6s. twelve keys, value 1 s. a pair of brass nutcrackers, value 2 d. a penknife, value 2 d. and 3 s. in money, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17441205-41-person520">
                        Thomas 
                        Footman 
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person520" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-41-person520" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-41-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-41-cd261" type="crimeDate">April the 10th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-off259 t17441205-41-cd261"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person521">
                  Mary 
                  Footman 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person521" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person521" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person521" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of April, I was at Drury lane play-house, and when I came into <placeName id="t17441205-41-crimeloc262">Bridges street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-41-crimeloc262" type="placeName" value="Bridges street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-41-crimeloc262" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-off259 t17441205-41-crimeloc262"></join>, the Prisoner, and I believe five more laid hold on me; the others held me, while the Prisoner cut off my pocket, and I was glad to get away with my life - I remember the Prisoner perfectly well, and looked at him thoroughly while he was robbing me, and remember him, I saw him by the light of a lamp.</p>
               <p>Coun. When was the Prisoner taken up?</p>
               <p>Footman. Upon the 10th of Nov.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before that time?</p>
               <p>Footman. I believe not.</p>
               <p>Coun. Have you seen him since?</p>
               <p>Footman. Yes, a great many times.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050035"></xptr>Coun. Why did you not take him up?</p>
               <p>Footman. He had such a crew about him that every one I spoke to of it, were afraid of him.</p>
               <p>Coun. Did you see him in the day time?</p>
               <p>Footman. Yes, but what could I do when there were twenty people about him?</p>
               <p>Coun. Where have you seen him in the day time, and never took him up?</p>
               <p>Footman. In Lincoln's-inn-fields - about six o' clock in the afternoon (he had somebody with him) and he asked me how I did; I said I would do my self and him justice, and would let him know how I did.</p>
               <p>Coun. Had he the impudence to speak to you, when he had robbed you?</p>
               <p>Footman. If he had the Impudence to rob me, he would have the impudence to speak to me - I had my child with me, a little boy about nine years of age.</p>
               <p>Coun. Was it broad day light?</p>
               <p>Footman. Yes, 'tis broad day light in summer time about six o'clock.</p>
               <p>Coun. When did you see him again?</p>
               <p>Footman. A great many times.</p>
               <p>Coun. And you had not courage to take him up?</p>
               <p>Footman. I question if he had robbed you, whether you would have had courage to have spoke to him or no. I saw him one night where he cut three ladies pockets off.</p>
               <p>Coun. Why did you not discover him?</p>
               <p>Footman. I had a greater regard for my life.</p>
               <p>Coun. When did you see him besides?</p>
               <p>Footman. At other times, with twenty people round him with cutlasses - twenty together - may be it might be about four o'clock, when I saw him with twenty.</p>
               <p>Coun. I desire you would answer my questions.</p>
               <p>Footman. I am very willing to answer a gentleman any question.</p>
               <p>Coun. What time o'night was you robbed?</p>
               <p>Footman. About half an hour after ten.</p>
               <p>Coun. And could you remember his face from that time to this, at that time of night?</p>
               <p>Footman. Yes, and so I could your's, if I should see you seven years hence.</p>
               <p>Coun. This man's life lays at stake, you ought to be very careful what you say.</p>
               <p>Footman, 'Tis himself is the occasion of it, 'tis not me, if he would let me alone, I would not meddle with him.</p>
               <p>Coun. When did you take out a warrant?</p>
               <p>Footman. As soon as I heard he was to be taken with ease.</p>
               <p>Coun. 'Tis for the sake of the great reward, I suppose that you do this?</p>
               <p>Footman. No, Sir, you are mistaken; this thing was done before the time of the reward being promised, if you please to look back.</p>
               <p>Coun. So you say you have seen him frequently, and yet would not take him?</p>
               <p>Footman. Yes, so I have; but I have so great a regard to my own life, and the life of my friend, that I would not venture to take him; for no body would run into the mouth of a lion, with twenty thieves round him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person522">
                  Alexander 
                  Langdell 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person522" type="surname" value="Langdell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person522" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came down to Mrs. Footman's house on the fast day, the 11th of April last: and she said, she was robbed by such a man, and knocked down; she said, she was sure to the man, and that she should know him again if she saw him. I said, I knew them all, and I would go and see; and he was one of them that were there, when the pressed men were rescued.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am a <rs id="t17441205-41-deflabel263" type="occupation">Cooper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-defend516 t17441205-41-deflabel263"></join> at a brew house. Did not you see me in the street, about three weeks before I was taken up?</p>
               <p>Langdell. Yes - he was taken up Wednesday was fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not take him up sooner?</p>
               <p>Langdell. I went to Mrs. Footman and told her, I knew where he was, and I said come and see him being it's a dangerous case for the man's life is at stake, and she was positive to his person.</p>
               <p>Q. You said you knew him, and saw him three weeks before, why did you not take him up?</p>
               <p>Langdell. I did not know I could take him up without a warrant, and I thought it was the safest way to take him with a Constable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has seen me twenty times since.</p>
               <p>Langdell. Yes, so I have, with a great many gamblers and thieves; he was there when the man was shot.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know Mrs. Footman?</p>
               <p>Langdell. Her husband <rs id="t17441205-41-viclabel264" type="occupation">keeps a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-person518 t17441205-41-viclabel264"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-victim519 t17441205-41-viclabel264"></join> at the black boy in Milford lane.</p>
               <p>Coun. What sort of a house is it?</p>
               <p>Langdell. I think 'tis a very good house.</p>
               <p>Coun. Is it not a night-house?</p>
               <p>Langdell. I never heard that it was, and I have drove about five years into the next yard - I am a hackney coachman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person523">
                  Thomas 
                  Footman 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person523" type="surname" value="Footman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person523" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to the Prisoner's Council. Mr. T - knows me very well. I was not with my wife when she was robbed, but I am certain she lost the goods: she shewed the Prisoner to me a little afterwards.</p>
               <p>Coun. How came you not to take him then?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050036"></xptr>Footman. It was on a Sunday night, there was a great disturbance in the Strand; there was a gentleman had lost his watch; there were several robberies committed in half an hour, and the Prisoner was among the rest : there was a boy about ten years of age, who was very Cute in that.</p>
               <p>Coun. When was the Prisoner taken?</p>
               <p>Footman. I think it was the 21st of November, at Mr. Smith's brewhouse; he thought it had been an arred: he had an adze in his hand : and when they told him it was not an arrest, it was for a street robbery, for robbing Mrs. Footman; then he swore he was a dead man : and going along he desired not to be carried before such a Justice, because if he went before him, he said he should soon be committed. So when we went in, the Justice said to him, Oh my old Friend, where have you been all this while; what an't you hanged yet?</p>
               <p>Coun. Did not you know of the reward which is promised for taking of street robbers?</p>
               <p>Footman. I did not take him for the sake of the reward, but to justify my wife and my country. I shall call at your chambers one day or other, and let you know whether I keep a night-house or no: you have done business for me, and I have paid you very honourably.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person524">
                  William 
                  Wootton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person524" type="surname" value="Wootton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person524" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I served this warrant upon the Prisoner the 21st of November, at Mr. Smith's brewhouse by Hide-park-corner: I took one Gardner to assist me. When I took him, he said he had no friends to help him, but he would pray for the woman.</p>
               <p>Coun. Do you know this Footman, who is so well acquainted with every body?</p>
               <p>Wootton. I never saw him before he brought the warrant, to my knowledge - I never heard any thing for or against him - I never saw the Prisoner before I took him.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did you hear him say, when he was taken, that he was a dead man?</p>
               <p>Wootton. I did not hear him say that.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did you hear the Justice say, his old friend was come?</p>
               <p>Wootton. Yes, I heard him say that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person525">
                  William 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person525" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person525" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say he was a dead man?</p>
               <p>Carter. I did not hear him say that; he said he would pray for the woman.</p>
               <p>Coun. My Lord, I think 'tis a very stale demand, from the 10th of April till November, and never to prosecute till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-41-person526">
                  John 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person526" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person526" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Cooper, the Prisoner is my own brother; he came with Admiral 
               <persName id="t17441205-41-person527">
                  Cavendish
               <interp inst="t17441205-41-person527" type="given" value="Cavendish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             from the West-Indies about two years ago, and has worked with me, on and off, ever since; I recommended him to the Brew-house, and he had worked there three weeks when he was taken. <rs id="t17441205-41-verdict265" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-verdict265" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17441205-41-punish266" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-41-punish266" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-41-defend516 t17441205-41-punish266"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
