<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470116-47">
               <interp inst="t17470116-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-47" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-47" type="date" value="17470116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-47-off191-c421" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-47-defend523 t17470116-47-off191 t17470116-47-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>125. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-47-defend523" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-47-defend523" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-defend523" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-defend523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-47-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Hand Saw, value 5 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-47-victim525" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Presgrove 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-47-victim525" type="surname" value="Presgrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-victim525" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-victim525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-47-off191 t17470116-47-victim525"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             . <rs id="t17470116-47-cd192" type="crimeDate">December 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-47-off191 t17470116-47-cd192"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-47-person526">
                  Thomas 
                  Presgrove 
               <interp inst="t17470116-47-person526" type="surname" value="Presgrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person526" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came and took a Saw out of my Shop, on the First of December.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Presgrove. I missed the Saw, when I came Home; I enquired of my Wife, when I came Home; the Man that was at work there, he said that Williams had been there, and he had a Suspicion he had taken it away; so I went to William's House, and I saw the Saw, and I said it was mine; he afterwards pawned it in Chiswell-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any thing further to say? Did you carry him before a Justice of the Peace?</p>
               <p>Presgrove. He made an Excuse that I lent him the Saw before the Justice, but he afterwards denied it; he used me very ill; when I went to take the Saw away, he would have stabbed me.</p>
               <p>Court to Presgrove. He says that you lent him the Saw?</p>
               <p>Presgrove. That was a Fortnight before that he worked for me.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470116-47-person527">
                  John 
                  Urwin 
               <interp inst="t17470116-47-person527" type="surname" value="Urwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person527" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Pawnbroker. What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Urwin . I never saw the Man in my life, it was his Wife brought the Saw.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. What have you to say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Williams. Sir, he lent me the Saw and the Stuff at the same Time, it was to make Boards for a Hot-presser ; that Saw was pawned for two Shillings; I got my own Saw out that was pawned for one Shilling. When he came up and saw me at work for a Customer, then he said I had stolen the Saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-47-person528">
                  Abraham 
                  Holding 
               <interp inst="t17470116-47-person528" type="surname" value="Holding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person528" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-person528" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, some Months ago I happened to meet the Prosecutor, I asked him if he could recommend me to some honest Journeyman Carpenter, the Prosecutor recommended to me the Prisoner at the Bar; I employed him about three Months making up Clothes Presses, the Fellow always behaved very honestly; I believe I had some hundred Pounds Worth of Work done in my House afterwards. I was to make a considerable Alteration in my Estate.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174701160039"></xptr>Court. I ask if Presgrove recommended the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Holding. Yes, and during the Time they worked for me, the Prosecutor found the Prisoner Tools: When I huffed the Prosecutor for being so long about it, I said, if you do not go on better, I must contract with somebody else; with that he went about his Business, and when I spoke to Williams, the Prisoner, he said I cannot work if he does not find me Tools, and I believe he did frequently lend him Tools; and if he did take it out of the Shop, it was common.</p>
               <p>Q. to Quincey . What have you to say about this?</p>
               <p>Quincey. This Fellow, the Prisoner, has worked for me four or five Years at a Time; he sent me a Letter, that a Fellow had swore a Saw against him. I think he is a very honest Fellow, I know nothing of the Fact.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470116-47-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-47-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
