<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450424-34">
               <interp inst="t17450424-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-34" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-34" type="date" value="17450424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450424-34-off211-c341" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-defend405 t17450424-34-off211 t17450424-34-verdict216"></join>
         
               <p>231. + 
               <persName id="t17450424-34-defend405" type="defendantName">
                  Stephen 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17450424-34-defend405" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-defend405" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-defend405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17450424-34-defloc210">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-34-defloc210" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-34-defloc210" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-defend405 t17450424-34-defloc210"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450424-34-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver chocolate pot, value 7 l. 10 s. a pair of silver snuffers, value 15 s. a pair of silver tea-tongs, value 8 s. a silver stockbuckle, value 4 s. the goods of <rs id="t17450424-34-viclabel212" type="occupation">Sir</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-victim407 t17450424-34-viclabel212"></join> 
                  
                     
                        <persName id="t17450424-34-victim407" type="victimName">
                           Simeon 
                           Stuart 
                        <interp inst="t17450424-34-victim407" type="surname" value="Stuart"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-34-victim407" type="given" value="Simeon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-34-victim407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-off211 t17450424-34-victim407"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in his dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450424-34-cd213" type="crimeDate">Octo. 10th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-off211 t17450424-34-cd213"></join>.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17450424-34-person408">
                  Simeon 
                  Stuart 
               <interp inst="t17450424-34-person408" type="surname" value="Stuart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person408" type="given" value="Simeon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have a dwelling house in <placeName id="t17450424-34-crimeloc214">York Buildings</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-34-crimeloc214" type="placeName" value="York Buildings"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-34-crimeloc214" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-off211 t17450424-34-crimeloc214"></join>. I was in Suffolk when this accident happened. The prisoner had been a late <rs id="t17450424-34-deflabel215" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-defend405 t17450424-34-deflabel215"></join> of mine: I had notice sent me, that my house had been robbed, and that some of my pieces of plate were found at a pawnbroker's. The plate was locked up by me when I went out of town in a strong box, and left in my dining room window; the brass hinges were taken off, which was done by a person of judgment. I am very well satisfied these pieces of plate are my own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-34-person409">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17450424-34-person409" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person409" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person409" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Sir Simeon, the prisoner lay in my master's house, when he was out of town.</p>
               <p>Sir Simeon. That was after he was discharged out of my service; I discharged him in Suffolk, without a livery, or any badge belonging to me.</p>
               <p>Warwick. I did not know that, for he came to the house, and said, he came to town upon business of his master's, and I let him lye in the house about three nights. I can positively swear the box was very safe when he came into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss the plate?</p>
               <p>Warwick. Mr. Reason a silver-smith discovered it to me; he came and asked me, if I had not lost something; I looked in the dining room, and found two boxes broke open, and plate and wearing apparel gone. The prisoner went away in the morning; and Mr. Reason sent to me about the chocolate pot, with Sir Simeon's coat of arms, about five in the evening, and I found it there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-34-person410">
                  William 
                  Reason 
               <interp inst="t17450424-34-person410" type="surname" value="Reason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person410" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of October last, about three o'clock in the afternoon, the prisoner came to me, put his hand in his pocket, and pulled out the lid of a chocolate pot: I asked him where the other part was; he said, there was a coat of arms upon that, and he did not care to sell it. I thought there might be some weightier concern than that; and he said, if I would buy this, he would return in two hours; so I weighed it, bought it, and paid for it, and then he pulled out the snuffers and tea tongs. He not coming that evening, I directed my wife that if any person came with any plate, to secure him; and the next day the prisoner brought the chocolate pot. I advertised it, and my brother-in-law, an engraver in arms, having the honour to work for Sir Simeon, he directed me to go to York Buildings, and there I saw Mrs. Warwick, and asked her if she was robbed; she said she was not; I said, I am sure Sir Simeon is, for I have some of his plate; then she went to look, and missed it: she said, there was a raw boned young fellow, who had been servant to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174504240031"></xptr> Sir Simeon, lay in the house; and she was sorry, as she recommended him, that he should be the thief. The Prisoner is the person who brought the lid of the chocolate pot, the tea-tongs, and stock-buckle.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-34-person411">
                  Mary 
                  Reason 
               <interp inst="t17450424-34-person411" type="surname" value="Reason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-person411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of October the Prisoner brought this chocolate pot to me to sell. I put it into the scale, and weighed it, sent for assistance, and secured him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If you say this, you will say a thing that is wrong, for I am not the person that brought the things to your house. My master discharged me in the country, and I came to the housekeeper, and told her, my master had turned me away, and would not give me a character. She let me lie there two or three nights, but I know nothing of these things. I went to work in a rope-yard, and afterwards enlisted myself as a drummer in the first regiment of guards. <rs id="t17450424-34-verdict216" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-verdict216" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17450424-34-punish217" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-34-punish217" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-34-defend405 t17450424-34-punish217"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
