<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480706-45">
               <interp inst="t17480706-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-45" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-45" type="date" value="17480706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480706-45-off207-c307" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-45-defend395 t17480706-45-off207 t17480706-45-verdict210"></join>
         
               <p>369. 
               
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-defend395" type="defendantName">
                     Frederick 
                     Hamilton 
                  <interp inst="t17480706-45-defend395" type="surname" value="Hamilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-defend395" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-defend395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17480706-45-off207" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-off207" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-off207" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a gold ring, value 10 s. a guinea, and two shillings and sixpence in silver
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-victim397" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Peterson 
                  <interp inst="t17480706-45-victim397" type="surname" value="Peterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-victim397" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-victim397" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-45-off207 t17480706-45-victim397"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , widow, <rs id="t17480706-45-cd208" type="crimeDate">May 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-45-off207 t17480706-45-cd208"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person398">
                  Ann 
                  Peterson 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person398" type="surname" value="Peterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person398" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday before Whitsunday the Prisoner took a gold ring, a guinea, and half a crown, out of my own lap, upon the bed in my chamber. I am but a <rs id="t17480706-45-viclabel209" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-45-victim397 t17480706-45-viclabel209"></join>, I lived at my Lord Lisburne's.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any company in your bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>Peterson. No body, but the Prisoner and I; he came with an intent to marry me.</p>
               <p>Q. So he came with your free consent to pay his addresses to you?</p>
               <p>Peterson. I cannot say but he did, and he desired I would promise him marriage on the Saturday; for he said I might as well do that, as remain single. First he told me he was a Hampshire man, and then he told me he was an Irishman.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060030"></xptr>Q. How long had he been with you?</p>
               <p>Peterson. About a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he take them?</p>
               <p>Peterson. He took them feloniously out of my lap.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire any body to stop him?</p>
               <p>Peterson. I did not cry out stop thief, for I did not think he would have served a person so, that he pretended to have a value for.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you to have been married?</p>
               <p>Peterson. That evening, at May-Fair Chapel. I was suspicious of his leaving me, and I went out along with him; he took me to the Red Lion in Silver-Court (I lived in Paradise-Row) and he dropped me in that strange place, and left me with one of his countrymen.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take him?</p>
               <p>Peterson. On Whitsunday, when he was going to dine on a pigeon pye, with all his company at his lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been at his lodging?</p>
               <p>Peterson. Yes, once.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say, when you took him?</p>
               <p>Peterson. He made a great many out of the way speeches, that were not agreeable, to be, and he owned he took the ring and the money.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did you make any objection, when he took the money out of your lap?</p>
               <p>Peterson. Yes, and I desired he would return it me again.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you know Mrs. Barnes?</p>
               <p>Peterson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you borrow a ring of her, in order to accommodate you for your marriage?</p>
               <p>Peterson. I bought a ring of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the hour six o'clock fixed upon for you to be married?</p>
               <p>Peterson. No, Sir, it was seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he come to you between five and six o'clock, in order to go with you to be married?</p>
               <p>Peterson. Not with my ring. Must a person come to rob me? Gentlemen, take this into consideration. He run away before the Justice, and that looked very unhandsomely. There was one 
               <persName id="t17480706-45-person399">
                  Elias 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person399" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person399" type="given" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bid him run away, and the Justice said he would commit any body that should rescue him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask her what place we went to?</p>
               <p>Peterson. We went to the Red Lion, in Silver-Court, and he left Mr. Macguire with me; he said, my love, I will come to you presently; and Mr. Macguire said, He does not use you well, nor does he use me well, to leave you in this manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Consider, madam, you are upon your oath, were not all these things taken by your consent?</p>
               <p>Peterson. No, he took them, all together, out of my lap, without my consent. I was doubtful of him, because he first said he was a Hampshire man, and then he said he was an Irishman; but I was glad I missed of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person400">
                  Ann 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person400" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person400" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person400" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The gentleman came as a courtier to Mrs. Peterson, and he owned before the Justice that he robbed the woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he robbed the woman?</p>
               <p>Barnes. He said he took the things from her, and that he had the ring in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any excuse before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Barnes. He said he got a little in liquor, and forgot it; she followed him till twelve o'clock at night, and he could not be found.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she buy a ring of you?</p>
               <p>Barnes. Yes; she bought it about a fortnight or three weeks before, and she gave me seventeen shillings for it; the Prisoner went out of my house to the Red Lion along with her, and he said, Mrs. Barnes, I will be back again immediately.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Were not Mr Hamilton and Mrs. Peterson often together?</p>


               <p>Barnes. They were sometimes, there is no harm in a person's coming in an honourable way, if they come frequently; and there is nothing to the disreputation of the woman. I think it is a barbarous thing to see a person abused in this manner, and by an Irish fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person401">
                  Samuel 
                  Cracknell 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person401" type="surname" value="Cracknell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person401" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the Prisoner say he had the money, and own he took the ring, and that he would return it, if she would make it up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person402">
                  Thomas 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person402" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person402" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (constable). Between eleven and twelve o'clock in the morning the Prisoner was brought to me, and I had him before Justice Fraser; after he was committed, he pretended to go to make water, and run away, but I run after him, and took him again. She said before the Justice, that he had robbed her of a guinea, half a crown, and a ring, but he said she gave them to him, which she denied.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Peterson. Is that your ring?</p>
               <p>Peterson. I cannot say, because there is no mark upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Barnes. Is that the ring you sold to Mrs. Peterson?</p>
               <p>Barnes. It is like mine, but there is no stamp upon it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060031"></xptr>[The Prisoner, in his defence, said she gave him the guinea and the ring, in order to their being married.]</p>
               <p>Mrs. Biggs. I live in Tyburn-Road, and keep a publick house in the Parish of St. George, Hanover-Square. I kept a house several years there.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it any sign?</p>
               <p>Biggs. It was the sign of the Bricklayers-Arms, but I put up my sign, which I had at the house I came from; which was the sign of the Red Lion, but the sign was put down.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any sign at all?</p>
               <p>Biggs. There is no sign at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mrs. Peterson ever at your house?</p>
               <p>Biggs. Yes, she was there the Saturday before Whitsunday; I believe she came about eight o'clock at night, and asked for Mr. Hamilton, and said her case was very deplorable, that she had given him a guinea and half a crown, and that she had given him a ring, that she borrowed of her landlady, in order to be married to her at May-Fair Chapel.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say when she was to be married?</p>
               <p>Biggs. She said she was to be married that night, but that she was not married to him; she lay with the Prisoner all night at my house, and I would have turned her down stairs, or charged the watch with her.</p>
               <p>Q. It is a very extraordinary thing, that a woman should come and tell you, that she was going to be married, and yet he with he man all night; you know you are upon your oath?</p>
               <p>Biggs. I think I am not a child; I am an honest woman.</p>
               <p>Peterson. I desire she may be asked how long it is since she was cook at the Fountain-Tavern on Ludgate-Hill?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person403">
                  William 
                  Weaver 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person403" type="surname" value="Weaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person403" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She lived at the Fountain-Tavern on Ludgate-Hill, and at an alehouse, the Bull and Gate, by Fleet-Ditch.</p>
               <p>Q. You said you was not a child, but I believe you are old in wickedness.</p>
               <p>A Juryman. She kept a house in St. Ann's parish a little above a twelvemonth ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person404">
                  Roger 
                  Kellock 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person404" type="surname" value="Kellock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person404" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the first troop of horse guards. The Prisoner was a private man in the marines, on board Admiral 
               <persName id="t17480706-45-person405">
                  Anson
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person405" type="given" value="Anson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person405" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's ship.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Has he no wound that renders him incapable of serving his country?</p>
               <p>Kellock. I believe he has a pension from Chelsea. I never heard but what he behaved well.</p>
               <p>Mr. Turner. The Prisoner is a shoemaker by trade; he lodged in one of my houses about six months, till the time he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not he a lodging at Mrs. Bigg's?</p>
               <p>Turner. Mrs. Biggs had a lodging at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not the Bricklayers-Arms?</p>
               <p>Turner. It was about a year and a half ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a sign to the house before Mrs. Biggs came to it?</p>
               <p>Turner. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any for a year, or a year and a half?</p>
               <p>Turner. I believe not. The Prisoner has been in the army and navy, and I believe he has had a pension about half a year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person406">
                  Richard 
                  Whittingham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person406" type="surname" value="Whittingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person406" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the second troop of horse-guards; I have known the Prisoner five months, and never heard any thing against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-45-person407">
                  Priscilla 
                  Bryan 
               <interp inst="t17480706-45-person407" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person407" type="given" value="Priscilla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-person407" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Peterson said the Prisoner was a rogue, and had disappointed her, and that he should never marry a woman in England, if he did not marry her, for she would either hang him, or transport him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-45-verdict210" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-verdict210" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-45-punish211" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-punish211" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-45-punish211" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-45-defend395 t17480706-45-punish211"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
