<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-37">
               <interp inst="t17431207-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-37" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-37" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-37-off201-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-defend309 t17431207-37-off201 t17431207-37-verdict204"></join>
         
               <p>+ 44. 
               <persName id="t17431207-37-defend309" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-defend309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of the <placeName id="t17431207-37-defloc200">Precinct of Bridewell in the Parish of St. Bride</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-37-defloc200" type="placeName" value="Precinct of Bridewell in the Parish of St. Bride"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-37-defloc200" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-defend309 t17431207-37-defloc200"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17431207-37-off201" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-off201" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-off201" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431207-37-victim311" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Baker 
                        <interp inst="t17431207-37-victim311" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-37-victim311" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-37-victim311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-off201 t17431207-37-victim311"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , by giving him a mortal Bruise with his Hand, on the right Side of the Head, above the Ear, of which he soon after died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17431207-37-cd202" type="crimeDate">Nov. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-off201 t17431207-37-cd202"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was likewise indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-37-person312">
                  Charles 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17431207-37-person312" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person312" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of November in the Evening, 
               <persName id="t17431207-37-person313">
                  Thomas 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17431207-37-person313" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person313" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Prisoner a Challenge to fight him the next Morning - He delivered the Challenge to me himself, and desired that I would tell the Prisoner to meet him the next Morning in the Church-Yard (or Burying-Ground) belonging to <placeName id="t17431207-37-crimeloc203">Bridewell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-37-crimeloc203" type="placeName" value="Bridewell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-37-crimeloc203" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-off201 t17431207-37-crimeloc203"></join>, between 7 and 8; and he that did not come at the Time was to forfeit Six-pence: Accordingly I delivered the Challenge, and they both came into the Church-yard - I believe Baker was there first; they both stripped, and went to fighting - They were both Bridewell-Boys, and knew one another as well as any two Boys in the Hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they Friends before this?</p>
               <p>Child. They were not Friends, or they had not fought; but they fought in order to be Friends with one another; they had fought twice before, and were parted both Times. Baker had given the Prisoner Challenges several Times - Baker had the better both Times, and that was the Reason he gave him the Challenge, because he thought himself to be a better Man than the other. I was the Deceased's Second, and took him up when he was down.</p>
               <p>Q. How often had he been down?</p>
               <p>Child . I believe about a Dozen times; they fought near half an Hour - Baker was down oftenest ; the Prisoner had the Advantage in the Falls, but as to the Blows, I cannot tell who had the Advantage.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they part at last?</p>
               <p>Child. No; Baker was down, and I said, they should fight no more. As soon as the Words were out of my Mouth, they both went away; and Baker being asked by the Prisoner, whether he would drink, he said, he could not drink, but he would fight him another Time - I am very certain this fight was to make Things up; for there was a Difference between several of us besides.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the deceased appear to be ill?</p>
               <p>Child. He was ill in about five Minutes after I said he should not fight any longer; in about five Minutes after that he dropped down, and had not Strength to put hi s Shirt on; I got him up, but he could not stand long.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think to be the Occasion of his Death?</p>
               <p>Child. He might over-strain himself in the Fight, but I don't think the Blows were the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Malice?</p>
               <p>Child. There was no Malice. There have been greater and harder Fights than this - When they cannot agree, they commonly fight it out; and it is done in order to be Friends.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character has the Prisoner among you? Is he good natured?</p>
               <p>Child . He is as good a natured Boy as any in the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-37-person314">
                  Robert 
                  Radless 
               <interp inst="t17431207-37-person314" type="surname" value="Radless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person314" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About 10 o'Clock the Night before they fought the Prisoner desired me to be in the Church-yard at 7 o'Clock in the Morning: I was to be the Prisoner's Second. They met and fought. I cannot say there was any foul Play - The Deceased did not express any Dissatisfaction; the last Word I heard him say, was, I will fight you another Time.</p>
               <p>Child. He never spoke any more after he said he would fight him again another Time, but he groaned very much - It was a fair Fight.</p>
               <p>Jeffery Gillingham . I am one of the Arts Masters; the Prisoner is as good a natured Boy as any Man ever had, or as ever came into a House.</p>
               <p>- Ray. I am one of the Arts-Masters; the Character of the Prisoner is, that he is as good a tempered Boy as ever was in the Hospital. <rs id="t17431207-37-verdict204" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-verdict204" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-verdict204" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17431207-37-punish205" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-punish205" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-37-punish205" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-37-defend309 t17431207-37-punish205"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
