<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480224-27">
               <interp inst="t17480224-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-27" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-27" type="date" value="17480224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-27-off154-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-defend266 t17480224-27-off154 t17480224-27-verdict158"></join>
         
               <p>149. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480224-27-defend266" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Bellebee 
                  <interp inst="t17480224-27-defend266" type="surname" value="Bellebee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-defend266" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-defend266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17480224-27-defloc153">St. John the Evangelist</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-27-defloc153" type="placeName" value="St. John the Evangelist"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-27-defloc153" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-defend266 t17480224-27-defloc153"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480224-27-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one gold ring, value 10 s. 6 d. and 14 s. in money, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480224-27-victim268" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Stacey 
                        <interp inst="t17480224-27-victim268" type="surname" value="Stacey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-27-victim268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-27-victim268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-off154 t17480224-27-victim268"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs> , <rs id="t17480224-27-cd155" type="crimeDate">Feb. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-off154 t17480224-27-cd155"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-27-person269">
                  William 
                  Stacey 
               <interp inst="t17480224-27-person269" type="surname" value="Stacey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner picked my pocket of fourteen shillings in money, and took a gold ring off my finger.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Stacey. In <placeName id="t17480224-27-crimeloc156">St. Ann's-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-27-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="St. Ann's-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-27-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-off154 t17480224-27-crimeloc156"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Stacey. About five o'clock in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What business had you at that time of the day in that place?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Speak a little louder that I may hear you, I do not know what you say.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see her first?</p>
               <p>Stacey . The first time was at Charing-Cross, and we went to a night cellar to drink a pint of beer, and we had three halfpennyworth of bread and cheese; she went up stairs and fought with a woman, then she came down again, and she wanted me to go along with her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Speak your words properly, pray.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the Prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Stacey . In St. Ann's-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Stacey . I am a <rs id="t17480224-27-viclabel157" type="occupation">chairman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-27-victim268 t17480224-27-viclabel157"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her home?</p>
               <p>Stacey . Yes, I saw her quite to the house, and she said she would make me amends: she went up one pair of stairs, and I went after her; I had been up all night, and was very heavy; I sat upon the bed's feet, and fell fast asleep.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What did you do upon the bed? [There was no answer.]</p>
               <p>Stacey . She fumbled about something, and she picked my pocket, and took my ring off my finger, and put it into her mouth; I said if she would give me my money and ring again I would not do any thing to her; she said I might kiss her a - e, and do what I would; I called out watch, and a man came and bid me go out, and if I would not go out he would lick me away: I got a warrant for the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240020"></xptr> man, and took him before a Justice; he said as to the money he knew nothing of it, but the ring I should have; and the man gave the ring to the Justice, and the Justice gave it to the constable: the Prisoner owned she had the ring, and had given it to her landlord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Pray what did you do when you went into the room ?</p>
               <p>Stacey. I sat down upon the bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did nobody lie down by you?</p>
               <p>Stacey. No. Was you on the bed along with me?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes, I was, and you gave me this face. You made me lie down along with you. Pray, Sir, did not you ft - h me? [The Prosecutor made no reply.]</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any familiarities with her?</p>
               <p>Stacey. No, my Lord, I do not know whether she is a man or a woman but by her clothes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-27-person270">
                  Lewis 
                  Farbes 
               <interp inst="t17480224-27-person270" type="surname" value="Farbes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-person270" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (constable.) I was sent for by the man of the house to take this man and woman up, and I carried them before Justice Ellis: the ring was delivered to the Justice by a corporal, and it was delivered to me by his Worship. The Prisoner owned she had the ring, and that she gave it to her landlord, and the landlord gave it to the corporal .</p>
               <p>[ Forbes gave the ring to the Prosecutor, and bid him look at it .]</p>
               <p>Stacey . This is the same ring the Prisoner took off my finger,</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had been to see a young woman an acquaintance of mine who was very ill: I went into this cellar and had a pint of beer; I had not been there long before this chairman came down; he sat down, and said I should drink with him ; I said I would not; he said if you will not drink part of a pint of beer, you shall drink part of a pint of hot: he sat me down upon a bench, and called for some bread and cheese, and then another pint of hot . He asked me whether I could help him to a lodging , for he was locked out of doors; I said I could not say but I had a bed, and he said, my dear , let me go along with you; I said I did not care that any body should lie in my room, but as he was destitute of a bed, he should lie in my bed, and I could lie with a young woman in the next room, and he lay in my bed; he let me have the ring for a shilling that he had of me: he asked for the ring, and I said I will not give you the ring till you give me the shilling, for he had not a halfpenny piece to show after he came out of the cellar. He threw me against the door of my lodging, and broke the door open by throwing me against it; and I said, young man, give me the shilling, and you shall have your ring; he went away, and I never saw him again till he brought the constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any body to prove any thing of this?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have none here now, but I have very good housekeepers to appear to my character; it will go very hard on my side if I have them not here.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480224-27-verdict158" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-27-verdict158" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
