<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440113-15">
               <interp inst="t17440113-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-15" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-15" type="date" value="17440113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440113-15-off80-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-15-defend218 t17440113-15-off80 t17440113-15-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>119. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440113-15-defend218" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17440113-15-defend218" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-defend218" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-defend218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440113-15-defloc79">Christ-Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-15-defloc79" type="placeName" value="Christ-Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-15-defloc79" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-15-defend218 t17440113-15-defloc79"></join>, London, was indicted for <rs id="t17440113-15-off80" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-off80" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-off80" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 8 yards of Irish linen, value 8 s. 
            </rs>the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440113-15-victim220" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Clavey 
                  <interp inst="t17440113-15-victim220" type="surname" value="Clavey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-victim220" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-victim220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-15-off80 t17440113-15-victim220"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             , <rs id="t17440113-15-cd81" type="crimeDate">Sept. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-15-off80 t17440113-15-cd81"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-15-person221">
                  Charles 
                  Clavey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-15-person221" type="surname" value="Clavey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person221" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the bar is an accomplice with 
               <persName id="t17440113-15-person222">
                  William 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17440113-15-person222" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a footman of mine whom I have in custody, I have lost several goods at different times, but this in particular I found in the Prisoner's custody.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you miss this first?</p>
               <p>Clavey . I cannot swear to the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it found?</p>
               <p>Clavey. It was found at a pawnbroker's, pawned by the Prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you find it?</p>
               <p>Clavey. I found it the 29th of December.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it to be your's?</p>
               <p>Clavey. I know it by my mark, 'tis marked in three places that I can swear to.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to find it out?</p>
               <p>Clavey. I had an information from a person that the Prisoner at the bar was an accomplice with a servant of mine, who is indicted for the like offence , and suspected that he had pawned some of my goods: upon this information I desired my apprentice to go to Mr. Price's and enquire whether there was any such thing pawned to him; this Gentleman came to me very handsomly the next morning, and told me that he had such a thing, and the Prisoner was taken up directly; as to his character it is very notorious.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to give him his oath whether I ever pawned any thing to that gentleman.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174401130014"></xptr>Liscomb Price. On or about the 29th of last month, Mr. Clavey sent his servant to me to enquire if I knew one 
               <persName id="t17440113-15-person223">
                  Thomas 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17440113-15-person223" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person223" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and whether he had at any time pawned any linen at our house. I had some company at my house then, it being in the Christmas week, so I sent my servant to acquaint him that I would let him know in the morning. I examined, and found that there was a parcel entered in my book in the name of Parker; a coat and a remnant of linen, which the Prisoner pledged in the month of September last; I went to him the next morning and told him there was a little remnant of a coarse piece of Irish linen, and that I apprehended it to be the fag end , and thought by that he might satisfy himself whether it was his, and desired him to come to our house to see it; he came to our house, looked upon, and saw some marks by which he knew it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who pledged that to you?</p>
               <p>Price. This was pledged at our house by the Prisoner, he delivered it to me himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Price. I have known the man some time, he bought a watch of me within these twelve months and paid for it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own I pawned the things about five months ago: Mr. Clavey's servant came to me with a coat and a piece of cloth, and he said Mr. Clavey gave him the coat; he said he was going out of town and wanted a little money, and if I could get him half a guinea upon them it would be of some service to him. I told him I would try, and I carried them to Mr. Price's, as I had pawned some things of my own there before, and I pawned them for him to this gentleman, and gave him the half guinea.</p>
               <p>Clavey. There's another material witness, but we think he is sent out of the way.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Clavey. Have you seen the Prisoner frequently about your shop?</p>
               <p>Clavey, Yes, he has been in the shop frequently, and I believe oftner than I knew of.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have no other witness but Mr. Clavey's man 
               <persName id="t17440113-15-person224">
                  William 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17440113-15-person224" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person224" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he can clear me of this.</p>
               <p>[The Prisoner was informed, that he might choose whether he would be sworn or not, because he was not obliged to answer any questions that might tend to accuse himself; he paused some time, and then consented to be sworn.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-15-person225">
                  William 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17440113-15-person225" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took up nine pounds worth of goods of my master, I have a bill of parcels of them here; this is part of them.</p>
               <p>Clavey . He had some goods of me, but this is no part of them. I can prove when this piece of goods came into the house.</p>
               <p>Randall. I bought it of my master, and desired the Prisoner to pawn it for me. [The bill of parcels was produced.] This is the piece, it is charged to me the 21st of June.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you bought that of Mr. Clavey?</p>
               <p>Randall. I believe it was about seven months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you buy it of?</p>
               <p>Randall. I bought it of Mr. Hodgkins the youngest apprentice but one, and my master said he could afford to sell this at 1 s. 9 d. a yard, and he charged me two shillings for it. <rs id="t17440113-15-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-15-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
