<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460226-16">
               <interp inst="t17460226-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-16" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-16" type="date" value="17460226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460226-16-off55-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-16-defend197 t17460226-16-off55 t17460226-16-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>104. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Cardwell 
                  <interp inst="t17460226-16-defend197" type="surname" value="Cardwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-defend197" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460226-16-off55" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-off55" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-off55" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing seven Linnen Sheets, value 10 s. two Linnen Table-Cloths, value 7 s. one Linnen Shift, value 2 s. four Silver Tea-Spoons, value 6 s. four Towels, value 1 s. a Hat, value 4 s. a Pillowbear, value 6 d. a pair of Silk Stockings and a Copper Pot, &amp;c.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-victim199" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Coply 
                  <interp inst="t17460226-16-victim199" type="surname" value="Coply"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-victim199" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-victim199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-16-off55 t17460226-16-victim199"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , on the <rs id="t17460226-16-cd56" type="crimeDate">14th of September</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-16-off55 t17460226-16-cd56"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person200">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person200" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person200" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply ) Did you lose any Goods at any Time ?</p>
               <p>Coply . Yes, I lost two Linnen Table-Cloths, a laced Apron , a Cotton Gown, two Cloth Coats, a Silk Waistcoat, three pair of Worsted Stockings , a pair of Silk Stockings , a Copper Pot and a Silk Gown.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these all your Goods?</p>
               <p>Coply. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose them?</p>
               <p>Coply. At different Times.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell when you miss'd them?</p>
               <p>Coply. The 14th of September .</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose these Goods ?</p>
               <p>Coply. Out of my Dwelling-House .</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your Dwelling-House ?</p>
               <p>Coply. In Chancery-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the Prisoner been your Servant ?</p>
               <p>Coply. She came to me Valentine Day last was 12 Month.</p>
               <p>Q. Having lost all these Things, How came you to suspect the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Coply. By her eloping from me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this? Did she go without Notice?</p>
               <p>Coply. Without Notice, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done upon that?</p>
               <p>Coply. A Friend of mine took her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she taken?</p>
               <p>Coply. In Eagle-Street, my Lord. I saw her there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge her with taking these Things?</p>
               <p>Coply. Yes, my Lord. She acknowledg'd the taking of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention all the particulars?</p>
               <p>Coply. I can't say I did mention all of them. She own'd she took them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any Excuse for herself?</p>
               <p>Coply. She said she had a Lawyer she ow'd four Guineas to, and she wanted to raise Money to pay him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry her before any Magistrate ?</p>
               <p>Coply. Yes. Before Justice Burdus .</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any other Excuse there ?</p>
               <p>Coply. The same Excuse.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the Things again?</p>
               <p>Coply. I have had part, and the Pawnbroker the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. What's the Pawnbroker's Name?</p>
               <p>Coply. Johnson .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person201">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person201" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person201" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to Johnson ) What do you know of the Prisoner's having these Goods? Are they here?</p>
               <p>Johnson . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner at the Bar bring these Things to you to pawn?</p>
               <p>Johnson . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it she brought them?</p>
               <p>Johnson. she came to us at different Times for eight or nine Years. The first part of these Goods came in July 44 .</p>
               <p>Court. ( to Coply ) You say she came to you but about a Year ago, then these Goods that were brought in July 44, could not be your Goods.</p>
               <p>Court. ( to Johnson ) Give an Account of what was brought to you from Valentine Day was 12 Month .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260012"></xptr>Johnson. The major Part of them was since that.</p>
               <p>Q. Then first, is there any Table-Cloth, is there any Linnen Shift ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there six Tea-Spoons, a Cambrick Handkerchief, or a laced Apron?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. A Napkin?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. How many?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Two.</p>
               <p>Q. A Woman's Hat?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. A Pillowbear, two Cloth Coats?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. A Silk Waistcoat, Worsted Stocking</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How many ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Two pair.</p>
               <p>Q. A Copper Pot?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. A Silk Gown ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Are these Things that were mention'd, brought here?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Let the Prosecutor look upon them .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person202">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person202" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person202" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Johnson) Have you any more to say?</p>
               <p>Johnson. This Gentleman, the Prosecutor, ask'd me if I had such and such Things. I shew'd him some Things that he did not know he had lost. He did not chuse to prosecute at this Time, but took out a Warrant by Justice Burdus against me for receiving Goods known to be stolen. So he brought an Action against me for the Goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person203">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person203" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person203" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply) What became of the Action; Is the Action depending?</p>
               <p>Coply. I order'd the Attorney to stop it . I thought I had got into bad Hands, it is not yet determin'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person204">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person204" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person204" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner ) What have you to say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord. Part of the Money I had for these Things, I had for my own Use, and some my Master had at different Times. I laid out the Money for Fish, Liquors, &amp;c. Please you my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person205">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person205" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person205" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply) She liv'd with you near a Year, did you pay her any Wages?</p>
               <p>Coply. I lent her 13 s. 9 d. and 5 s my Wife lent her unknown to me. And I engag'd for a pair of Shoes for her. But there was more due than this.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, my Mistress had a Quilted Petticoat of mine, she wore it most part of the Summer .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person206">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person206" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person206" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply) Had your Wife a Petticoat of her's?</p>
               <p>Coply. She told my Wife she had a Petticoat at pawn, at such a Place, and it my Wife said it, she should have it .</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Wife wear it?</p>
               <p>Coply. I don't know, she might wear it for ought I know.</p>
               <p>Court. The Prisoner says, she wore it for the whole Summer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person207">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person207" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person207" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) What was she to pay for it?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It cost 13 s. 9 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person208">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person208" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person208" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply) Then you have paid her no Wages.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, I have had 9 s. of my Master. My Master had of me, a Shilling he borrow'd , and sometimes he had 18 d. and sometimes when he wanted Change, he would ask for 2 d. or 3 d . and I take it to be 3 s. in all .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person209">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person209" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person209" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Coply) At the Time the pretended to take these Things, were you indebted to her the Value of them?</p>
               <p>Coply. My Lord, I can't say any Thing to that. If she went away I could not have paid her. I never turn'd a Servant away without their Wages in my Lifetime.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-16-person210">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-16-person210" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-person210" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Have you any Witnesses?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Master, who is a Distiller upon Snow-Hill, and my Mistress, have sent to me twice , and promiss'd to come to appear for me when my Trial was to come on.</p>
               <p>Court. Send for your Master and Mistress .</p>
               <p>They were sent to, but were gone out to Supper .</p>
               <p>Her Master was desir'd by the Court to pay her her Wages, upon receiving the Things.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460226-16-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-16-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
