<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411204-28">
               <interp inst="t17411204-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-28" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-28" type="date" value="17411204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-28-off122-c176" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-28-defend235 t17411204-28-off122 t17411204-28-verdict125"></join>
         
               <p>40. 
               <persName id="t17411204-28-defend235" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-defend235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of - , was indicted for that <rs id="t17411204-28-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17411204-28-cd123" type="crimeDate">23d of Sept.</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-28-off122 t17411204-28-cd123"></join> on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411204-28-victim237" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Herne 
                        <interp inst="t17411204-28-victim237" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-28-victim237" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-28-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-28-off122 t17411204-28-victim237"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously, &amp;c. did make an Assault, and that 
                     <persName id="t17411204-28-person238">
                        Christopher 
                        Shotton 
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person238" type="surname" value="Shotton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-28-person238" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-28-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   on the Head, Back, Breast, Belly, and Ribs of the said Herne, did strike and beat, giving him several mortal Bruises, of which from the said 23d of Sept. to the 14th of Oct. he languish'd and then died, and that the Prisoner was present, aiding and abetting, &amp;c. the said Shotton the said Murder to commit, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a second Time charg'd by Vertue of the Coroner's Inquisition for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person239">
                  Charles 
                  Pelton 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person239" type="surname" value="Pelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person239" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of Sept. last, there was a Cricket-Match at <placeName id="t17411204-28-crimeloc124">Staines Moor</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-28-crimeloc124" type="placeName" value="Staines Moor"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-28-crimeloc124" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-28-off122 t17411204-28-crimeloc124"></join>, between the Men of Staines and Brentford. I saw the Prisoner pulling Herne among the Croud, and I saw Shotton strike him twice, while he had hold of him. The Deceased was presently taken ill, and after that, I saw him no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Deceased engage in the Play after this ?</p>
               <p>Pelton . Yes, he play'd till he was bowl'd out, and whether he ran once or twice I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. For what Reason do you think the Prisoner took hold of the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Pelton . I took it to be to get him in to play. - I saw nothing more done by the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person240">
                  Thomas 
                  Herne 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person240" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner take hold of my Brother's Collar, and pull him to force him to o la . In the forcing he chuck'd him on the Throat, and I saw Shotton strike him two or three Blows on the Breast, and it is my Opinion they were the Death of him. He lived but Weeks afterwards, and always complain'd of his Stomach and Throat.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any Thing said to your Brother before the Prisoner laid hold of him ?</p>
               <p>Herne. I did not hear him asked to play before by any Body: the laying hold was the first that I saw.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he complain while he was playing, that he was any way affected by those Blows?</p>
               <p>Herne. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Prisoner laid hold of him, did he do it to help off his Coat?</p>
               <p>Herne. No, to pull him in to play.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I saw the Prisoner take hold of this Man by the Coat, in order to carry him up to the Wicket to play. Shotton hit him 2 Blows, one over the Prisoner's Arm, and one under it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he complain of any Injury afterwards?</p>
               <p>Witness. He said, he believ'd those Rogues had given him his Death. I saw nothing done by the Prisoner but the laying hold of his Collar to make him play.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he play long after this?</p>
               <p>Witness. He got one Notch according to the Rule of the Play.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person241">
                  John 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person241" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person241" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw 
               <persName id="t17411204-28-person242">
                  John 
                  Herne 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person242" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person242" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next Day: he told me that the Prisoner took him by the Collar to lead him to the Wicket, and that Shotton gave him some Blows on the Breast. He complained that his Breast and his Throat were very sore, and said, that the Prisoner in pulling him along chuck'd his Throat so that he could not tell how to swallow any Thing. He lived about 3 Weeks afterwards, and always complained of the Blow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person243">
                  William 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person243" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Morning after the Cricket-Match I went down to 
               <persName id="t17411204-28-person244">
                  John 
                  Herne 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person244" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Boat and called him. He answer'd me in a very low Voice, and said he had been used so barbarously at the Cricket-Match, that he was murder'd. He went with me to my House, and my Servant drew him some Beer , but he could not drink it. He said he knew one of the Persons that had used him ill, and mention'd the Prisoner's Name.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not the Deceased lie in his Boat all Night?</p>
               <p>Banks. Yes, I believe he did, and it is as common for them to lie in their Boats , as for us to lie in our Beds.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Can you tell where he had been before he went to his Boat?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040015"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>Banks . At the Three Pidgeons .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person245">
                  Ann 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person245" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person245" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Nurse to him in his Illness. He had a violent Fever and Convulsions, and all his Complaint was of his left Side, so that he could not lie upon it . I used to ask him his Complaint, and he said, those Rognes that beat one have killed me , and hang them, hang them: These were his Words. I saw him open'd, and he was all black on the Heart, and one of his Ribs was broke, but the Surgeon can give a better Account of that than I can.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person246">
                  Joseph 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person246" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person246" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I stood Umpter (Umpire) at the Wicket, and there was a Sort of a Demur about a Man's coming in. I saw the Prisoner bring him along by the Collar, and I saw Shotton strike him a Blow. He seem'd to be unwilling to go in to play, and said he would go in next.</p>
               <p>C. What had the Prisoner and Shotton to do in this?</p>
               <p>Smith. Nothing at all except they laid any Betts. The Deceased did go in and ran one Notch, and was out at the same End as I stood at. He said he was very ill, and wish'd he was at Home, but I did not hear him make any particular Complaint.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you hear any Thing but what was civil done or said by me?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, if there had I must have seen it, and I can't say that he used him ill any otherwise than bringing him along to play.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill, Surgeon. On the 18th of Nov. last I was sent for to view the Body of the Deceased on the Coroner's Inquest. I found an external Contusion on the Skin, about 8 Inches Diameter, which extended to the left Hypocondriack. Upon opening the Body I found the Cartilage of the eighth Rib on the left Side broken: in the left Cavity of the Thorax, I found between 15 or 20 Ounces of extravasated Blood, and the back part of the Lungs on that same Side were vastly inflam'd. Then I examin'd the right Cavity of the Thorax, and found 4 or 5 Ounces of Blood, and the Colon and the interior Parts of the Stomach were gangreen'd.</p>
               <p>Council. How do you apprehend that to be done?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill . By the Blows I should imagine, and certainly they were the Cause of his Death, for otherwise he was found.</p>
               <p>C. How long did you see him after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill. He died on the Wednesday, and I opened him on the Monday.</p>
               <p>C. Do you think that any Fever was the Occasion of this Disorder?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill . That has not yet come to my Knowledge: my Opinion is, that it proceeded from these Bruises and Blows.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Is it not common in a malignant Fever to have Part of the Stomach inflamed?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill. I have never seen it.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Might not that Rib be broke by a Fall?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill. Yes, to be sure it might.</p>
               <p>C. Was there any Appearance of Blackness upon the Place where the Rib was broke?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill. Yes, about eight Inches Diameter.</p>
               <p>Q. If any Person receives a Blow, will the Cartilage, or the Rib break first?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dudhill. The Cartilage would break sooner than the Rib.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>I think it was on the 23d of September, I heard there was to be a Cricket-Match between the Towns of Brentford , and Staines . I happened to have a Friend come in to dine with me, and therefore I thought we might after Dinner divert ourselves in seeing this Cricket-Match. They played very easy and quiet till the latter Part of the Game, when there were two Men to go in on the Brentford Side, and neither of those Men would go in; so a great Uproar began. The Deceased's Coat was unbutton'd, and I took hold of his Coat very inoffensively, as I thought, and desired him to go in. He d - 'd me, and asked me, what it was to me; upon which, I told him, if he did not play, it should be worse for him, for I would stand by the other Men, and see them righted, if it cost me 20 l. He lifted up his Hand, and I thought he had been going to strike me, and so I left him, and saw him no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person247">
                  Richard 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person247" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person247" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting on a Bench smoaking a Pipe just by the Prisoner, and saw him take hold of the Deceased. He told him, if he would not go in, he would Sue him if it cost him 20 l. I never saw the Prisoner attempt to strike him, neither did Shotton meddle with him while the Prisoner had hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q Did the Man play afterwards?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, very well. The Prisoner was in as good a Humour as could be, and talked to him as one Neighbour does to another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person248">
                  William 
                  Slaughter 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person248" type="surname" value="Slaughter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on Horseback on a pretty bighish Horse, and the Deceased was talk'd off to go in, but seemed unwilling. The Prisoner took hold of his Cloaths, and bid him go in and play a fair Game, or else he would</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040016"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>assist the Staines Men in getting the Money. At last he did go in, and play'd very well 'till he was bowl'd out. There was nothing done to hurt him that I saw, and the Prisoner's Hand was never higher than his Breast. He afterwards leap'd and skip'd about, and I don't know whether he was not the most active Man of the two and twenty. I have been acquainted with the Prisoner above 20 Years, and have played many a Game at Cricket with him, but I have done with it now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person249">
                  William 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person249" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person249" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the Gamesters, and stood just by. The Deceased was to have gone in the Time before he did, but another would go in before him, and when his Turn came, he refused, so the Prisoner took hold of him, and after he had loosed him, Shotton struck him and went out of the Ring.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person250">
                  Edward 
                  Haysler 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person250" type="surname" value="Haysler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person250" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , junior. I was one of the Gamesters, and was there all the Time. I saw the Prisoner take hold of the Deceased, and heard him say, if he did not go in, he should lose the Money if it cost him 20 l. The Deceased seemed to be uneasy, and shuffled from the Prisoner, and was going away; and then Kitt Shotton gave him a push and desired him to go in.</p>
               <p>Council. You call it a push, did not you see Shotton give him three or four Blows with his Fist?</p>
               <p>Haysler. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you think that Push could break his Ribs?</p>
               <p>Haysler No, nor hurt him neither .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person251">
                  Edward 
                  Haysler 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person251" type="surname" value="Haysler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person251" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , senior. I was in a one horse Chaise, and saw the Prisoner pull the Man along to make him go in. The Deceased got loose from him, and the Prisoner went back to his Seat, and Blows I saw none.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the Game plaid out?</p>
               <p>Haysler. There were about thirteen Minutes for them to play, and this Man went in and looked as sprightly as could be, and if there had been any Blows or Fighting, I must have seen it.</p>
               <p>Dr. Merrick. I attended the Deceased, and found him in very strong Symptoms of a malignant Fever, which is sufficient to kill any Man without Bruises. I viewed his Body in his Life-time, and saw no Blackness upon it. Mr. Dudhill apprehended there was some Mischief about his Ribs, upon which I looked at them, and observed one Cartilage to stand hither than the rest, but I did not venture to press hard enough upon it, to see whether it was broken or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any Complaints to you?</p>
               <p>Dr. Merrick. He was rather too low to make any ; what Questions I asked about his Disorder, were rather answered by the People about him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-28-person252">
                  James 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person252" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person252" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; 
               <persName id="t17411204-28-person253">
                  Robert 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17411204-28-person253" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person253" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and three other Persons, had known the Prisoner different Numbers of Years, and always thought him an honest, inoffensive Man. <rs id="t17411204-28-verdict125" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-28-verdict125" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
