<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-44">
               <interp inst="t17400903-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-44" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-44" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-44-off251-c249" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-defend322 t17400903-44-off251 t17400903-44-verdict254"></join>
         
               <p>413. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-44-defend322" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Hancock 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-44-defend322" type="surname" value="Hancock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-defend322" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-defend322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-44-defloc250">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-44-defloc250" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-44-defloc250" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-defend322 t17400903-44-defloc250"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-44-off251" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-off251" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-off251" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17400903-44-victim323" type="victimName">
                        Hannah 
                        Prince 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-victim323" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-44-victim323" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-44-victim323" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-off251 t17400903-44-victim323"></join>
                     </persName>
                    in a certain open Field near the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a linnen Shift, val. 12 d a linnen Apron, val. 12 d. 2 linnen Handkerchiefs, value 2 s. 2 Pieces of Linnen cut out for Sleeves, val.12 d. and a linnen Cap, val. 12 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400903-44-cd252" type="crimeDate">Aug. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-off251 t17400903-44-cd252"></join>.</p>
               <p>Hannah Prince. On the 23d of August, I was going from Limehouse to Bow, between 7 and 8 at Night, and not knowing the Way, I desired a Woman to direct me. The Prisoner, I believe, was somewhere behind, and heard me, for he came up and asked me if I was going to Bow. I said, Yes. He told me, he lived near that Place, and would put me in the Way. I returned him Thanks, and we went together through Poplar, and as he went along he spake to several Persons. At last he carried me a Back-way into a Field behind <placeName id="t17400903-44-crimeloc253">Poplar-Chapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-44-crimeloc253" type="placeName" value="Poplar-Chapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-44-crimeloc253" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-off251 t17400903-44-crimeloc253"></join>, and then told me he must give me a green Gown. I begg'd of him to desist, and desired him not to use me ill, but he slung me upon the Ground, and pinched me, and bit me, because I would not consent. But hearing some People coming along, I collar'd him, and held him as long as I could; then he got up, and as soon as I got up, he knocked me down. He gave me one Blow upon my Stomach, another upon my Arm, and one upon my Mouth, which cut my Lips against my Teeth; then he snatched the Bundle out of my Hands, which I was carrying to Bow, and tore the Handkerchief in which the Things were tyed up, before he could get it away from me. [The Witness gave an Account of the Things contained in the Bundle, as they are mentioned in the Indictment.] It was near 8, when he threw me down, but it was very Moon-light, and I believe I had walked a Mile from Limehouse, before he attacked me. When he had got my Bundle, he ran away, and I ran after him, and entreated him to give it me again; telling him, if he took my Things, I had no more to put on. But he got over a Stile, and ran off; and I, (not knowing where the Path led to,) was afraid to follow him any farther, so I stood at the Stile, and cryed, Stop Thief! Some People came up to me, and went after him, but not being able to take him, they return'd to me, and perswaded me to stay at Poplar that Night. I was very much surprised, and staid there till next Morning; then they carried me to see a Man at Blackwall , who they mistrusted was the Person, from the Description I had given them of the Prisoner. But he was not the Man; so I came back to Poplar, and saw the Prisoner pass by, near the White-horse: Upon which I jumped up, followed him, and collar'd him, and told the People he was the Man. Then I got one to hold him, while I went to see for an Officer, and when I came back; he confessed the Fact, and said he was sorry for it He own'd he beat me down, and took the Things from me, and he pull'd out one of the Handkerchiefs, (which had been in the Bundle,) and return'd it to me; his Mother being with him, he desired her to go home with me, and give me the rest of my Things. I went with her accordingly, and she returned<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030032"></xptr> me all but one Apron; so I returned with her to the Prisoner, and asked him where that Apron was? He was going to tell me , but his Mother stopp'd him, by saying it was lost out of the Hole I tore in the Handkerchief , in which the Things were tied up. In carrying him before a Magistrate, he said, if I would let him go, he would pay me for the Apron, and he did give me a Shilling. There was 2 Men to take care of him as he went along, but some Women rescu'd him , - I believe there were 40 of them about him. But the Gentlemen of the Town (Poplar) hearing the Prisoner was got away, were angry, and sent for the Officer the next Morning, and ordered him to see for him, and take him. He was afterwards re-taken, and carry'd before Mr Justice Jones, where he confessed it again. Upon my Oath the Prisoner is the Man: I walked far enough with him to know him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-44-person324">
                  Leonard 
                  Head 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person324" type="surname" value="Head"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person324" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner was taken on Sunday the 24th of August, by this Woman; and there being a great Noise, and a great many Women about him, he got away, Some Gentlemen hearing he was escaped, sent for me, (being an Officer) and ordered me to look after him. Accordingly I went after him all that Day to no Purpose, but on Monday Morning I apprehended him at Ratcliffe-Cross , as he was going to Work; and having got two Men to assist me, we carry'd him to Poplar Watch-house, till we gave the Prosecutrix Notice. As soon as she came to us, we carry'd him before the Justice, and he owned he knocked the Woman down, and took her Bundle from her. He said he was in Liquor when he did it, and was very sorry for it.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Prince. I am sure he walked very upright; and when he ran away from me, he ran a vast Pace. If he was in Liquor, it was not to be discerned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-44-person325">
                  John 
                  Ashton 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person325" type="surname" value="Ashton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person325" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw 
               <persName id="t17400903-44-person326">
                  Leonard 
                  Head 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person326" type="surname" value="Head"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person326" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that Monday Morning sauntering about at Ratcliffe-Cross ; I asked him the Reason of it? He told me, some Gentlemen at Poplar had threatened him, for not taking a Thief. I asked him if he knew the Man? He said, Yes; and told me who he was. So I carry'd him to an Alehouse, where a Parcel of Lumpers (i. e. Men employed in unloading Ships) were at Breakfast. He saw the Man among them , but I was afraid of their Knives, so we waited a while till he came out, and then we took him. He imme- diately owned he did the Thing, but he said he was in Liquor, and had given the Woman the Things again, and a Shilling. We went down to his Mother, and asked for the Apron which was wanting, and she said her Son had given the Woman a Shilling to satisfy her. Before the Justice he owned he robbed her, and knock'd her down, and said he was sorry for it, and it was the first Fact he ever had done in his Life. I made Answer , and said, - it was too soon now.</p>
               <p>Bomer Loveit . When we were going to Prison with him, I desired him to let the Woman have the Apron that was missing: He told me his Mother had pawn'd it. I went to the Mother about it, and she went with me to the Pawnbroker's; I redeemed it, and the Prosecutrix owned it.</p>
               <p>Prince. I described the Marks to them before they shew'd it me. I knew it by the broad Hem, a Darn, and a Hole burnt in it by a Spark which flew out of the Fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-44-person327">
                  Brian 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person327" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person327" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             likewise proved the Prisoner's Confession before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-44-person328">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person328" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person328" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400903-44-person329">
                  Mary 
                  Flemming 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person329" type="surname" value="Flemming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person329" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person329" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400903-44-person330">
                  Mary 
                  Blow 
               <interp inst="t17400903-44-person330" type="surname" value="Blow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person330" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-person330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That the Prisoner worked with their Master, (a Throwster) and had been entrusted very much in their Master's House; that he always behaved well, and they never heard any Harm of him before. <rs id="t17400903-44-verdict254" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-verdict254" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400903-44-punish255" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-44-punish255" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-44-defend322 t17400903-44-punish255"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
