<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440510-14">
               <interp inst="t17440510-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-14" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-14" type="date" value="17440510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440510-14-off76-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-defend215 t17440510-14-off76 t17440510-14-verdict80"></join>
         
               <p>262. + 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-defend215" type="defendantName">
                  Hugh 
                  Connor 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-defend215" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-defend215" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-defend215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17440510-14-defloc75">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-14-defloc75" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-14-defloc75" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-defend215 t17440510-14-defloc75"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440510-14-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440510-14-victim217" type="victimName">
                           Bridget 
                           Berridge 
                        <interp inst="t17440510-14-victim217" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-14-victim217" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-14-victim217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-off76 t17440510-14-victim217"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17440510-14-viclabel77" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-victim217 t17440510-14-viclabel77"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, and stealing a diamond buckle, value 15 l. three silver casters, value 5 l. a silver tankard, value 10 l. 10 s. two silver candlesticks with snuffers and stand, value 6 l. a silver sauce pan, value 2 l. 12 s. 6 d. a silver mug, value 1 l. 12 s. 6 d. eight silver spoons, value 7 l. 8 s. a silver spoon gilt, value 8 s. a knife and fork with a silver handle, value 10 s. a gold chain for a watch with three seals, value 3 l. a silver pepper box, value 11 s. 6 d. a silver soop dish, value 8 l. a silver salver, value 7 l. a silver waiter, value 1 l. a silver porringer, value 1 l. 15 s. a pair of silver monumental candlesticks, value 10 l. 10 s. a silver cup and cover, value 10 l. a snuff box with an Onyx stone, value 2 l. 2 s. and six diamonds, value 40 l.
            </rs> the goods and chattels of 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-person218">
                  Bridget 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person218" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person218" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17440510-14-cd78" type="crimeDate">April 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-off76 t17440510-14-cd78"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person219">
                  Bridget 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person219" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person219" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17440510-14-crimeloc79">Denmark Street St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-14-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Denmark Street St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-14-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-off76 t17440510-14-crimeloc79"></join>, my servant had been sick, and left my service, and upon that account I went out of town on the Wednesday, and staid till Monday, when the other servant was to come. I keep but one servant, a maid servant. I came to town on Monday the 23d of April between five and six in the evening, and when I came to my house there was a constable and a great croud about it, and the constable told me the house had been robbed, and set on fire - I left the house safely locked up when I went out of town.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find things when you went in?</p>
               <p>Berridge. They were all scattered about the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your house been broke at all?</p>
               <p>Berridge. I cannot tell that. The plate, &amp;c. were in a closet in my room, I used to keep them in a trunk in that closet.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of what things you lost?</p>
               <p>Berridge. I have lost a great many more things than are there. [A great part of the plate was produced, viz. the tankard, the salver, the monumental candlesticks, &amp;c. and Mrs. Berridge mentioned the particulars of most of the plate, as set forth in the indictment] I lost a great many other things that are not in the indictment, and I lost bank notes * and cash too.</p>
               <p>* It is computed the whole loss, bank notes, money, jewels, plate, linen, &amp;c. amounted to upwards of two thousand pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Berridge. I know nothing of him, I never saw him in my life before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever know me in your life time, Madam?</p>
               <p>Berridge. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing of her, I am sure.</p>
               <p>[Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-person220">
                  Thomas 
                  de Veil 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person220" type="surname" value="de Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person220" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced a box with six diamonds in it, which were the property of Mrs. Berridge.]</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-person221">
                  Thomas 
                  de Veil 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person221" type="surname" value="de Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These diamonds were delivered into my hands by the constable; they were never out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person222">
                  Samuel 
                  Urton 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person222" type="surname" value="Urton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person222" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of April about eight o'clock in the evening the Prisoner came to my shop in order to pledge this diamond buckle, he asked me 7 s. upon it, and I said I would lend him but 3 s. he stood very hard for 4 s. and I lent him 4 s. upon it, and I saw he was very full of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any thing of him before?</p>
               <p>Urton. Yes; the man does not live above thirty yards from my house, he came into the shop some days before, and was with my servant trying with a hammer whether some things were gold or not. I did not let him know that it was a diamond buckle, but he took it for a cypher buckle, an ordinary thing. I apprehended there was a robbery<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100017"></xptr> committed, and waited for a direction where to apply. (I did not stop him then, for I knew where to find the man at any time) - I live the corner of Crown Court, St. Ann's, Soho, I am a pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Berridge. This diamond buckle I left in my house when I went out of town.</p>
               <p>Urton. On the Wednesday morning I saw an advertisement in the papers, and went to Mrs. Berridge directly, and got two warrants from Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-person223">
                  Thomas 
                  de Veil 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person223" type="surname" value="de Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person223" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one to search his house, and the other to take his person.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Urton. He is a labourer to the paviours, he had lived in the neighbourhood a year or two. After I had got the warrants, I sent my boy to watch when he came. As soon as he came home, my boy came and told me, and then we went to his house, and took him and his wife together, but by some means or other the wife slipped away, and we thought she was gone for a set of Irish to make a rescue. We searched the house, and I believe there was as much linen as was worth a hundred and fifty or two hundred pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find this plate?</p>
               <p>Urton. It was found hid about the bed, and some under the bed. I would not search before Mrs. Berridge came, and she owned these things as soon as she saw them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has known me these three or four years, he never knew any harm of me.</p>
               <p>Urton. I have known him a good while, I never heard any such thing of him before; he used to come and borrow a shilling or six pence now and then upon some ordinary things of his own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person224">
                  George 
                  Appleton 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person224" type="surname" value="Appleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person224" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Urton brought a couple of warrants to me, we went to the Prisoner's house, and Mr. Urton said, Mr. Connor, I want to speak to you, then he told him his business. I searched him, and found in his hand a silver snuff box, and in his pocket the box with the diamonds, and the watch chain; there was another snuff box with three guineas in it, and I laid hold of a silver tankard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person225">
                  John 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person225" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be attending the parliament house at Westminster, Mr. Clarke came to me, and said, they were seeking after a man who had committed a very great robbery, and desired I would go with him; I said I had no warrant; Mr. Clarke said you may detain a thief without a warrant, and the other constable (Appleton) and I, and Mr. Urton, went and took the Prisoner. The other constable bid me search his pockets while he held him, I only searched to see whether he had any knife, pistol, or other weapon, and then the other constable pulled several things out of his pocket.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person226">
                  Jonathan 
                  Thistletion 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person226" type="surname" value="Thistletion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person226" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the tavern to take half a pint of wine, and my kinsmen came to me, and told me that Mrs. Berridge's house was on fire. (this was last Monday was fortnight, April 23.) I went to the house, there was a constable, and a very great croud; said I to the constable, what are you here for, break the door open? I went first into the kitchen, there was no fire there, I came into the dining room and I was forced to go back the smell of fire was so strong. I went into the closet, then the fire began to burn, and the trunk was on fire. I clapped my hand upon it, and beat the fire in. Close to the wainscot they had placed this stool, [the stool was produced, which had been stuffed, but the covering was burnt; a trunk was also produced with a hole burnt through the lid about six or seven inches square, which Mrs. Berridge said was the trunk which she kept the plate in,] close to the stool they had placed this trunk, and the waincoat began to slake; the stool I slung out of the window, and I thought if there had been any thing in the trunk when I beat the fire in to have thrown that out of the window, but it was quite empty. They had so contrived it to set fire to these in the closet (for the next house to it is a cabinet maker's, and a slight wooden building) that if it had been in the night we should have been all in flames.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person227">
                  John 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person227" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at searching the house, and saw the plate found in the house that belongs to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That house did not belong to me.</p>
               <p>Hunt. Some of the plate was found in drawers, others were hid in the bedclothes and under the bed. I was informed that the Prisoner had taken another house just by, so after we had secured the plate we went and searched the new house, and in that house I found these keys [there were some picklock keys produced] and in that house I found a receipt for a South Sea annuity, which was given in the name of Berridge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person228">
                  Mary 
                  Morson 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person228" type="surname" value="Morson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person228" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of April, it was on a Monday morning, I was going to market with my partner, I met Mr. Connor at the end of Maid's Court - it was between four and five in the morning, we bid good morrow to Mr. Connor, and he to us; when we came to Hog Lane I saw a sack lye upon the pavement, he ran to the sack, and took hold of it, and as he held hold of the sack he said this sack is very heavy, lend me a hand with it - he said you had better help me up with the bag, and he called out whether any body owned it, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100018"></xptr> no body did; he said, it is very hard I must take this as no body owns it. My partner took hold of the sack with one hand to help him up, and I took hold of it and helped him up with it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this, how long ago?</p>
               <p>Morson. I cannot tell how long, it was; April 23. St. George's Day.</p>
               <p>Q. What bulk was it?</p>
               <p>Morson. It was more than he could lift, or he would not have asked us to help him up with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it corn, or what was it?</p>
               <p>Morson. It felt like clothes - it felt hard and rattled, and he said afterwards, d - n it, there was nothing in but broken bottles and old rags.</p>
               <p>Q. How farris Maid's Court from Denmark Street?</p>
               <p>Morson. I do not know, it is by Peter's Street, near Soho Square, between Soho Square and St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>Q. What business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Morson. I belong to Billingsgate, I was going there for fish.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person229">
                  Mary 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person229" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person229" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 23d of April my partner and I were going along Maid's Court between four and five in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was light - as I was going along I met Mr. Connor - I have known him these five years - he lives in Berwick Street, he bid my partner good morrow, and she said the same; she asked him where he was going, and he said he was going to work; he went a little further, and he said here is a sack, I think it feels heavy, and he called to Mrs. Morson to help him up with it, and she helped him up with it upon his shoulder, and I laid one hand to it - I was going to Billingsgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Then he did not go any part of the way with you?</p>
               <p>Davis. Yes; he went a little way with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not he going up Tyburn Road?</p>
               <p>Davis. He came along with us through Maid's Court, and when we came into Hog Lane there the sack lay - Denmark Street comes into the middle of Hog Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to go with you any part of the way?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was all in our way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the court go towards Billinsgate and Tyburn Road too?</p>
               <p>Davis. We did not go to Tyburn Road.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you did not trouble yourself to know what it was?</p>
               <p>Davis. No; I did not - I did not hear any more of it till I was subpoena'd. I did not know of his being taken up only as my partner told me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person230">
                  Thomas 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person230" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person230" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about a year and a quarter, he worked for me some time as a paviour's labourer. I never heard any harm of him - He does not work for me now, he had been going away a week before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person231">
                  Richard 
                  Hatton 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person231" type="surname" value="Hatton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person231" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew any harm of him till now - he used to go to labouring work.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he an industrious sober man?</p>
               <p>Hatton. I cannot say any thing to that.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know any thing of him?</p>
               <p>Hatton. He has come to me and pledged some of his wearing apparel, and has paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person232">
                  Ann 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person232" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person232" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between two and three years, he has bought things of me, and paid me very honestly, that is all I can say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-14-person233">
                  Sarah 
                  Spratton 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person233" type="surname" value="Spratton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person233" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him a year and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Spratton. What he had of me he always paid me very honestly for.</p>
               <p>Q. to Urton. Do you think there were more of all the things than one person could carry?</p>
               <p>Urton. There was as much as two porters could carry at once, there were two very large bundles.</p>
               <p>- There was as much linen as I could well carry out of the coach into Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-14-person234">
                  Thomas 
                  de Veil 
               <interp inst="t17440510-14-person234" type="surname" value="de Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person234" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house. <rs id="t17440510-14-verdict80" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-verdict80" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-verdict80" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Acquitted of the burglary, guilty of the felony out of the dwelling-house to the value of 50 l.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17440510-14-punish81" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-punish81" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-14-punish81" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-14-defend215 t17440510-14-punish81"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
