<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470116-16">
               <interp inst="t17470116-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-16" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-16" type="date" value="17470116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-16-off70-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-16-defend198 t17470116-16-off70 t17470116-16-verdict73"></join>
         
               <p>89. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-16-defend198" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Lee 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-16-defend198" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-defend198" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-defend198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-16-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               feloniously assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470116-16-victim200" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Upton 
                        <interp inst="t17470116-16-victim200" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470116-16-victim200" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470116-16-victim200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-16-off70 t17470116-16-victim200"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, and robbing him of a Cambrick Stock, and one Half of a Silver Clasp
            </rs>. the <rs id="t17470116-16-cd71" type="crimeDate">16th of December</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-16-off70 t17470116-16-cd71"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-16-person201">
                  George 
                  Upton 
               <interp inst="t17470116-16-person201" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-person201" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was walking up Drury Lane, and the Prisoner forced her Discourse upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was it?</p>
               <p>Upton. On the 16th of December, between eight and nine o'Clock, she forced her Discourse to me, and called to another Woman, and I kept on, and turned into <placeName id="t17470116-16-crimeloc72">Angel-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470116-16-crimeloc72" type="placeName" value="Angel-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470116-16-crimeloc72" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-16-off70 t17470116-16-crimeloc72"></join>, and I had some Apprehensions they had a Design to rob me.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her Discourse to you?</p>
               <p>Upton. She intreated me to go in with her, which I denied; she called up another Woman to go with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Upton . I can't tell the Place's Name; I thought they had a Design to pick my Pocket, and I kept my Hand upon my Pocket, and the Prisoner took my Silver Clasp and Stock off my Neck.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was the Prisoner, when there were two Women there?</p>
               <p>Upton . This Prisoner, my Lord, took it, and the other Woman received it of her; upon which I laid hold of the other Woman; she said I wanted her to d - n the King; and, my Lord, upon which there came up a Man, and asked me what Business I had with those Women; I said they had robbed me; with that the Man made off: the Prisoner pulled out a Knife, and said, Here's a Knife , Here's a Knife; I called out for Assistance, two Men came by, and I begged their Assistance, accordingly they assisted me; I got her out of that Place into Drury Lane ; she said if I would let her go, she would get the other half of the Clasp, and give it me: she made a great many Disputes about it; I called for a Constable, and took her before the Justice, and he sent her to Prison .</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Will you ask the Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Sir, I am very innocent.</p>
               <p>Q. to Upton. Did she say any thing to you about delivering any thing? Was you under any Fear?</p>
               <p>Upton. I was afraid when they pulled out the Knife .</p>
               <p>Charles Church. Coming up Drury-lane, in order to go Home, I saw the Prisoner at the Bar and 
               <persName id="t17470116-16-person202">
                  George 
                  Upton 
               <interp inst="t17470116-16-person202" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-person202" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             together , and he said, Brother Soldier, assist me, for I have been robbed by two Women, and this is one; I said, what have you been robbed of; he said, I have been robbed of a Clasp and Stock, here's one Part, and this Woman has got the other Part ; there was another Woman came up and struck me, and wanted to rescue her from me; with that I spoke to her, I said, Do you know any thing of such a Thing? she said she had it not about her, but if I would let her go in, she would bring it out; I said if you know where it is, you may send for it; she struggled vastly to get away.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174701160013"></xptr>Court to the Prisoner. Will you ask the Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I kept Covent-Garden Market, it was a blustering Night, I was going Home: Just at the End of Russel-Street, the Gentleman took hold of me, and said, Betty, where are you going? I said you don't know me; yes he said he did, and kissed me, and put his Hands in my Bosom several Times, &amp;c. and I wanted to get away; when I would not let him do as he wanted , he said he had lost half a Clasp and Stock; he said if I would give him 3 s. he would let me go.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470116-16-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-16-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
