<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-2">
               <interp inst="t17470429-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-2" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-2" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-2-off5-c32" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-2-defend33 t17470429-2-off5 t17470429-2-verdict7"></join>
         
               <p>177. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-2-defend33" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Munson 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-2-defend33" type="surname" value="Munson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-defend33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-defend33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470429-2-off5" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-off5" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-off5" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking open the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470429-2-victim35" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Allen 
                        <interp inst="t17470429-2-victim35" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-2-victim35" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-2-victim35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-2-off5 t17470429-2-victim35"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and stealing from thence twenty five Pewter Plates, one Copper, four Dishes, a Pewter Hand bason , two Brass Candlesticks, and three Nails
            </rs>, <rs id="t17470429-2-cd6" type="crimeDate">March 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-2-off5 t17470429-2-cd6"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-2-person36">
                  Alexander 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17470429-2-person36" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person36" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was your House broke open at any Time?</p>
               <p>Allen. Yes, Sir, upon the 22d of March, in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your House?</p>
               <p>Allen. In the Parish of St George.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it broke open?</p>
               <p>Allen. The Window Shutter was cut and broke, then they took down the Casement, and broke the other Part of the Glass besides.</p>
               <p>Q. Would that make Room sufficient for a Person to get in?</p>
               <p>Allen. Yes , Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this?</p>
               <p>Allen. Between the Hours of twelve and one in the Night.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time did you find that it was broke?</p>
               <p>Allen. Between six and seven o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it done in the Day Time or Night?</p>
               <p>Allen. I can't tell whether it was in the Day or Night, but the Servant told me she found the Window broke open when she came down in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Allen. A Copper was taken out of the Wash-house.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was the Copper?</p>
               <p>Allen. It might weigh between thirty and forty Pounds ; and I lost out of the Kitchen , five and twenty Pewter Plates, and four Dishes , and a Pewter Hand-bason , and two Brass Candlesticks.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you get any of those things again?</p>
               <p>Allen. Here are some Chains we use in our Business of Rope making, these I can swear was taken away that Night.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by them again?</p>
               <p>Allen . A Gentleman here happened to be in a Shop the upper End of Rosemary-lane, when the Prisoner at the Bar came in to sell something , and the Man of the Shop asked the Prisoner what became of those Chains he showed him the other Day, he said he sold them to one Mrs Williams in Church-lane .</p>
               <p>Q. You did not hear this?</p>
               <p>Allen. No.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-2-person37">
                  George 
                  Adlington 
               <interp inst="t17470429-2-person37" type="surname" value="Adlington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person37" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . You hear what Mr Allen said he was informed of?</p>
               <p>Adlington. My Lord, on the 24th of March, I called at this Shop to buy a few Nails, where I saw the Prisoner at the Bar stand; my Curiosity led me to know what he, the Man of the Shop, would bid him for what he wanted to sell; I thought it would be little enough; and I heard the Master of the Shop say, George, what did you do with those things you brought to me; he told him he had sold them to one Mrs. Williams; says he, I would have you get them again, for I hear a House is broke open, and I believe they are stole; he said it was the House of one Mr Allen, a Rope-maker. I had not heard of the Advertisement till I came for these Nails ; I said, Mr. Sheppard, if you are an honest Man, you ought to stop this Fellow; he equivocated pretty much with me, and did not care to stop him; I said Mr Philips, I insist upon it you will stop this Man , that is the way to hear of the rest of the things; he would not do it; I turned about to the Prisoner at the Bar, and said, what is your Name? he said he would not tell me his Name: he said he was an honest Fellow , and he told me he would not tell me his Name . I said, then I assure you you shall tell me your Name before you and I part; accordingly there was a Man in the Shop, and I said Friend fetch me an Officer, when the Officer came , I carried the Prisoner into a Publick-house, within two or three Doors of this Iron-shop , I then wrote a Line to Mr. Allen, to let him know I had stopped a Person that I believe had robbed his Father's House, in the mean Time, this Person (the Prisoner) told me had the Chains, and had sold them to Mrs Williams for Three half-pence; I kept him in talk, having only myself and an Officer, till proper help came; when Mr. Allen came, I said we will go to the House where he says he has sold these things; when I came there, I told her I came for three Nails she had bought, I asked her if she knew one Munson , she said she did not, but she knew one 
               <persName id="t17470429-2-person38">
                  Jacob 
                  Moson 
               <interp inst="t17470429-2-person38" type="surname" value="Moson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person38" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Mr Allen , jun. was with me, and said, these are the things that were lost, I said you need not give any thing for them , but you may take them where you can find them : he, the Prisoner, was had before the Justice, where he swore he had sold them at that Place, at the Alehouse; I asked him how he came by them, and he said, he was grinding his Knife at Tower-hill, and he got them at the Bottom of the Trough, but they were as bright as they are now, he told me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290004"></xptr> that he had found them the Thursday Morning, in the Trough under a Grind stone at Tower-hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-2-person39">
                  Sarah 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17470429-2-person39" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person39" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-person39" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Nurse, and Mrs Williams was ill, and when the Prisoner brought these things, he said he went to grind his Knife, and found them under the Grind-stone, so I went to my Mistress for three half-pence for them.</p>
               <p>[It was asked what these things were worth, and Mr Allen said 3 s. a Pound, whereupon the Witness was severely reproved by the Court, for buying things in that Manner.]</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17470429-2-verdict7" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-verdict7" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty of the Felony and Burglary
            </rs>, but recommended him to Mercy.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-2-punish8" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-2-punish8" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-2-defend33 t17470429-2-punish8"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
