<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-18">
               <interp inst="t17470225-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-18" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-18" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-18-off76-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-defend241 t17470225-18-off76 t17470225-18-verdict80"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250022"></xptr>149. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-18-defend241" type="defendantName">
                     HenRY 
                     SIMMS 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-18-defend241" type="surname" value="SIMMS"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-defend241" type="given" value="HenRY"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-defend241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17470225-18-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               indicted for a Robbery on the King's Highway, upon the <rs id="t17470225-18-cd77" type="crimeDate">18th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-off76 t17470225-18-cd77"></join>, in Middlesex; and the Indictment sets forth, that the said 
                     <persName id="t17470225-18-person242">
                        Henry 
                        Simms 
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person242" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-18-person242" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-18-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did make an Assault upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470225-18-victim244" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Sleep 
                        <interp inst="t17470225-18-victim244" type="surname" value="Sleep"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-18-victim244" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-18-victim244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-off76 t17470225-18-victim244"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , putting him in bodily Fear, and by Violence taking from him one Silver Watch, value 3 l. and 6 s. in Money
            </rs>, the Property of Francis Sleep.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner when called to the Bar said, that he had but a very short Time to send Sixty-two Miles for his Witnesses; it was answered that he had Time enough to send for any Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-18-person245">
                  Francis 
                  Sleep 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person245" type="surname" value="Sleep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person245" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I set out from my House on Saturday Afternoon, about Five o'Clock, it might be a little more or less, it was about Dusk.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you set out from?</p>
               <p>Sleep. From Falconbridge court, in St. Ann's Parish, in the Liberty of Westminster; I was going to my own House at Whittlebourgh, in Watford Parish, where my Wife was gone for her Health; she was very sick, so was my Child; and between <placeName id="t17470225-18-crimeloc78">Hoasden green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-18-crimeloc78" type="placeName" value="Hoasden green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-18-crimeloc78" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-off76 t17470225-18-crimeloc78"></join> and <placeName id="t17470225-18-crimeloc79">Stone-bridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-18-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Stone-bridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-18-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-off76 t17470225-18-crimeloc79"></join> I met this young Man, the Prisoner, upon the Road; I had indeed overtaken a Carter that drove an Hay-Cart, which was upon a little Poney, like my own; and as the Carter and I were riding together, between Hodsden green and Stone-bridge, this young Man, the Prisoner, met me on the Road; he comes hollowing in a very bold refractory Manner, with something in his Hand; and when he came near, I saw it was a Pistol, I thought he had been a drunken Gentleman, he had the Appearance of a Gentleman; I thought he was drunk and wanted the Road; I crossed my Horse out of the Way, not designing to contend for the Road, I turned my Horse out of the Way, and he turned his Horse out of the Way to meet me, and swore in a blasphemous Manner, that he would shoot me dead if I did not stop; d - n your Blood, and a Number of Oaths, if I did not stop he would shoot me dead; so I stopped immediately, and he presented a Pistol at me, I judged it was rather longer than a common Pistol; he then demanded my Money, which I gave him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the Length of a Horse-pistol?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Not quite so long I believe. When he demanded my Money, I told him I had but little; I was going to see my Wife, and I had not Occasion for much Money, so I gave him my Money, which was 6 s. it happened to be in my Pocket alone, for I had changed a Guinea that Day, and paid 15 s. for the King's Tax; then he asked me for my Watch, and afterwards he demanded my Perriwig; it was a frosty Night, I desired him not to take my Wig, for I should catch cold; I told him it would do him very little Service, I did not wear costly Wigs, so for that Reason I obtained my Wig again; then he went to the other Person in Company, to whom he swore if he stirred a Foot further, he would strike him dead, still joining Oaths to his Words.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that Menace made to the Carter before he robbed you?</p>
               <p>Sleep. During the Time of his robbing me.</p>
               <p>Court. Then the Carter stood still during the Time he was robbing you?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, Sir, he went and demanded Money of him, but I don't remember that he had any of him. I forgot one thing, my Lord; before he left me, he insisted upon my swearing I would say nothing of what had past; I told him I was never used to swear since I was 18 Years of Age, and am now upwards of forty; I said I would lose my Life rather than I would swear an Oath; then he left me, and said two others would have robbed me if he had not; I said then what shall I say if any Body should attack me; he said, say Thomas, that was the Word, upon that he rode off; after he had given me that Instruction. I rode forwards towards Harrow; and in about a quarter of a Mile, I did meet two Persons, who rode swiftly past us, who said nothing to us, nor we to them; and I judged they were the Highwaymen, and had some Intelligence that they might know that he had robbed me, and so thought it in vain to stop us any more. So I said to the Man in Company, these were the two Men that he told us of, they had the Appearance of Highwaymen; for 'tis not usual for Persons passing in the Night, but they say good Night, or something to that Purpose; so I apprehended these were the Persons he mentioned; one was on a black and the other on a white Horse.</p>
               <p>Q. What Horse was the Prisoner mounted upon?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Upon a brown Horse, a very fine one. - I says to the Carter, I'll follow these two Men, I believe they belong to him, and by following them, perhaps we shall come to the Knowledge of this Person; so then without going to my House in the Country, I turned back towards London. As soon as I came over against the Place where I was robbed, I heard two Horses jump into the Field, and I could hear the Horses Hoofs trumpting at a great Rate between Edgware and Harrow Road; I rode on further to Hodsden-green, there I met several Persons that he had attacked, one Man had lost his Horse, and they rode towards London, so did I; they thought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250023"></xptr> they should overtake him; but it was all in vain, for he was better mounted than any of them. I rode as far as Paddington, and put up my Horse; I considered my Wife would be frightened if I did not come, so I went my intended Journey, and got there about Eleven o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Court. You say it was about the Hour of Five when you set out from Falconbridge-court, and you say you rode about five Miles from thence, between Stone-bridge and Hodsden-green, and the Prisoner came up to you; as it was dusk, how came you to know that the Prisoner at the Bar was the Person you met?</p>
               <p>Sleep. That Person at the Bar was so near me, and the Moon shone so bright, that I could see his Face as plain as I can now. I told the 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person246">
                  Carter 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person246" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person246" type="given" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had seen him before; I knew the Prisoner a Boy, I knew his Grand-mother, and I am now sure I am not deceived in his Face. I am certain he is the Man.</p>
               <p>Court. Now, Mr. Sleep, you say it was the 18th of October last; how long might you take in going from Falconbridge court to this Place where you met him?</p>
               <p>Sleep. I can't say, I did not ride fast; I apprehend I was about an Hour in riding of it, hardly so much.</p>
               <p>Court. You said you should know him again; and that upon Reflection his Grand-mother you knew, and you knew him a Boy?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him since the Time you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Sleep. My Lord, I knew him to be the Person, by recollecting his Face.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you your Watch?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, I have the Watch that was taken from him, and the Watch I could tell from a Thousand.</p>
               <p>[The Watch was produced in Court]</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by this Watch now?</p>
               <p>Sleep. It was advertised that this 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person247">
                  Henry 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person247" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person247" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken, after he robbed me, and he was committed to Bedford-Goal; there was another Circumstance occurred, that this Person, the very Saturday Night that he robbed me, he came to an Acquaintance of mine in Monmouth street; they told me that such a Person, 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person248">
                  Henry 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person248" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person248" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was advertised and taken up for the Highway, I said that is the Person that has robbed me; says they he was here that very Night he robbed you, and pulled out a Watch, such a Sort of a Watch as you described, and said, Was it not a Pity a Man should die for such a thing as this? he wanted a Pair of Boots in Monmouth-street, so then I said he was the Person that robbed me, and I had a Desire to go and see whether or no he had my Watch in Possession, but I let the thing lie a considerable Time, till I went into the Country to see my Mother; so I had the Curiosity to go from Luton to Justice Nodes at Bedford, and after I described my Watch to him, he brought it out.</p>
               <p>Q. And you swear that is the Watch the Prisoner took from you?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, please to ask him whether he knew me before the Time that the People told him I was there to buy a Pair of Boots.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Sleep. When did you know him?</p>
               <p>Sleep. I knew him when a Boy, by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person249">
                  Henry 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person249" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person249" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. You say these People in Monmouth street, they recollected and called him by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person250">
                  Henry 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person250" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person250" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Sleep. They knew him, my Lord, as well as I.</p>
               <p>Q. When he robbed you, did you recollect that he was the Person you knew when a Boy, by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person251">
                  Henry 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person251" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person251" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Sleep. No, I did not, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Court. Prisoner, have you any other Questions to be asked?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him what Time of the Night it was, whether there was any other Persons nigh at that Time; whether I hollowed cut or any Pistol fired, or any Person asked him for a Hat or Wig.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Sleep. Was there any Body near you?</p>
               <p>Sleep. There was no Body but the Carter.</p>
               <p>Court. You say you met several People, did you communicate the Robbery to the People you met ?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, I told them of the Robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. to Justice Nodes. Do you know any thing with Relation to the Prisoner's being brought before you, or conveyed to Bedford Goal, or any thing taken from him?</p>
               <p>Justice Nodes. On the 20th Day of October last, I was informed that the Warrington Coach was robbed, and they had taken an Highwayman; when the Prisoner was taken, there were three Watches taken from him, one was a gold one, and one of the silver ones this Witness came and owned; when under Examination, the Prisoner confessed that between Harrow on the Hill and London, he had robbed several People.</p>
               <p>Court. I ask whether the Watch delivered to 
               <persName id="t17470225-18-person252">
                  Francis 
                  Sleep 
               <interp inst="t17470225-18-person252" type="surname" value="Sleep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person252" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the Watch taken from the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Justice Nodes. I did deliver the Watch taken from the Prisoner, to Mr. Sleep; when under Examination he did own to me he had robbed several Persons between Harrow on the Hill and London, the 18th of October.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250024"></xptr>Q. Did he sign that?</p>
               <p>Justice Nodes. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am sure it was not a proper Officer that search'd me; I don't know what they might put into my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Sleep. Is that the Watch you was robbed of?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, my Lord, it is.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Would you ask any Questions to the Justice of Peace?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether he found that Watch upon me.</p>
               <p>Court. He does not say that he found it upon you; but you hear what Mr. Sleep and the Justice has sworn; Have you any Witnesses to call, or any thing to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As for bringing of People to my C haracter, 'tis only troubling the Court; but I apprehend the Law is so tenderly made in such Cases, that I don't think any Jury in the World will bring me in guilty upon this, to have a Bill found against me, when the Witness did not know that I was the Person, till I was at a House buying a Pair of Boots. I shall say no more, my Lord, at present.</p>
               <p>Court to Mr. Sleep. The People told you that he had produced the Watch?</p>
               <p>Sleep. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-18-verdict80" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-verdict80" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17470225-18-punish81" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-18-punish81" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-18-defend241 t17470225-18-punish81"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
