<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450424-6">
               <interp inst="t17450424-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-6" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450424-6" type="date" value="17450424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450424-6-off28-c55" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-defend64 t17450424-6-off28 t17450424-6-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>194. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-defend64" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Ryan 
                  <interp inst="t17450424-6-defend64" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-defend64" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-defend64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17450424-6-off28" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-off28" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-off28" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450424-6-victim66" type="victimName">
                           Dorothy 
                           Udall 
                        <interp inst="t17450424-6-victim66" type="surname" value="Udall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-6-victim66" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450424-6-victim66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-off28 t17450424-6-victim66"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in her dwelling * house
            </rs> , March 25.</p>
               <p>The * offence of 
               <persName id="t17450424-6-person67">
                  Peter 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person67" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person67" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in the preceding trial would have been capital, if the indictment had been laid for stealing in the dwelling house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person68">
                  Dorothy 
                  Udall 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person68" type="surname" value="Udall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person68" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17450424-6-viclabel29" type="occupation">keep a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-victim66 t17450424-6-viclabel29"></join> at the <placeName id="t17450424-6-crimeloc30">Crooked Billet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-6-crimeloc30" type="placeName" value="Crooked Billet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-6-crimeloc30" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-off28 t17450424-6-crimeloc30"></join> by the <placeName id="t17450424-6-crimeloc31">Hermitage-stairs</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="Hermitage-stairs"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450424-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-off28 t17450424-6-crimeloc31"></join>. This tankard was taken out of my house between eleven at night and one in the morning; - I know this only by information, for I am a lame woman, and am never out of bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person69">
                  Richard 
                  Udall 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person69" type="surname" value="Udall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person69" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Just after the brewers had done starting beer, about twelve o'clock at night, I brought two tankards of beer to them, and left two silver tankards with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner one of the brewers?</p>
               <p>Udall. No, he followed them under a pretence.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of the brewer's servants ?</p>
               <p>Udall. There were twelve of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person70">
                  Mary 
                  Catliff 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person70" type="surname" value="Catliff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person70" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Udall. On the 5th of March, after the brewers were gone, I went to the box where the prisoner sat, to take away one of the silver tankards, which were brought to the brewers. - The prisoner had one before him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner there at that time?</p>
               <p>Catliff . It was just such a ragged man, he would not let me see his face. I took the tankard that he had before him, to put upon the fire, to warm some beer for my mistress; and he said, that is my beer; I made answer, do you belong to the brewers, and he said yes: then I went away and left the tankard with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person71">
                  Joseph 
                  Wonnell 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person71" type="surname" value="Wonnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person71" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of March about 9 or 10 o'clock at night, the prisoner came into Mrs. Ashfield's, where he lodged, took a tankard from under his coat, and desired her to put it up, and said, I beg of you not to let any body see it; and he said, I desire you would not let Mr. Wonnell know any thing of it, but bury it under ground, and you shall have it for three or four pounds, and I will eat and drink it out.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wonnell. He is a <rs id="t17450424-6-deflabel32" type="occupation">lumper of ships</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-defend64 t17450424-6-deflabel32"></join>, - it is called so in a vulgar way, but it is unlivering of ships. I said the next morning to his landlady, it was wrong in you not to stop the tankard, and the prisoner. The prisoner was secured, he took up a fork, and attempted to push it at the Justice, and he would have murdered him, I believe, if he had not been prevented.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever see me deliver the tankard to Mrs. Ashfield ?</p>
               <p>Wonnell . I saw you deliver it to her, and I would not tell a lye.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person72">
                  Ann 
                  Ashfield 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person72" type="surname" value="Ashfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person72" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The prisoner delivered the tankard to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lodge at your house then?</p>
               <p>Ashfield. He did a little before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Ashfield . I have known him about a year off and on. When he came in, he said, I have got something for you (I thought he was going to pay me some money that he owned me) said I, this is place, Ned; and I said I would not meddle with it. He left it with me, I was afraid it was stolen; and sell a trembling and shaking. Said I to Mr. Wonnell, do you take it, for I know nothing of thieving, I never had any concern with stolen goods in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say when he brought it?</p>
               <p>Ashfield. I said I would have nothing to do with it. He put it into my hand, and said, I should have it for three pounds. I said again I would have nothing to do with it; but he left it with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing about your not shewing it to any body?</p>
               <p>Ashfield. Yes, he said I must not shew it to any body. I kept it in the room where I lay till morning, and then I asked him how he came by it; he told me he found it. I advised him to have it cried, but he did not do it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person73">
                  Alexander 
                  Farer 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person73" type="surname" value="Farer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person73" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a waterman.) I was at Mrs. Udall's about twelve o'clock that night, the prisoner was there, and lay with his head upon the table. The maid came and took hold of the tankard to put it upon the fire; he said, that is my beer ; the maid said, do you belong to the brewers; he said, yes, and I saw him lay his hand upon the tankard. Then I was called away to go with a fare, and saw no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person74">
                  John 
                  Udall 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person74" type="surname" value="Udall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Justice came to Mrs. Ashfield's house, and the prisoner struggled with me and collared me in the presence of the Justice, and I was almost strangled . He took hold of these tormenters. [A flesh fork, used in taking meat out of a pot, was produced] The prisoner jobbed this at the Justice's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174504240005"></xptr> throat, and if he had happened to have hit him with it, it would have killed him. Then we overpowered him, and he said if the Justice would let him sit down, he would not oppose him any more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was going down to the water side to work, and found this tankard by the side of some sugar hogsheads. I saw the handle of a tankard, so I took it and buried it in a dunghill; and the next day I went to my landlady Mrs. Ashfield , and told her I had found a silver tankard; said I, shall I cry it or keep it. She said, what occasion have you to cry it, as you found it, keep it . And then I went and fetched it out of the dunghill, gave it to my landlady, and she put it under her bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450424-6-person75">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17450424-6-person75" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-person75" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (To Ashfield ) Did you advise him to cry it, or did you advise him not to cry it?</p>
               <p>Ashfield. I advised him to cry it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have never a friend in the world but God and your honour: there is never an one in the court can give me an ill word.</p>
               <p>Ashfield. The Justice asked him where he found it, and the prisoner said he would not tell him. <rs id="t17450424-6-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17450424-6-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-defend64 t17450424-6-punish34"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17450424-6-punish35" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450424-6-punish35" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450424-6-defend64 t17450424-6-punish35"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
