<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-4">
               <interp inst="t17400416-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-4" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-4" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-4-off22-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-defend55 t17400416-4-off22 t17400416-4-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>194. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-4-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Wilcox 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-4-defend55" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-defend55" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-defend55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400416-4-defloc21">St. Butolph</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-4-defloc21" type="placeName" value="St. Butolph"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-4-defloc21" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-defend55 t17400416-4-defloc21"></join> , Aldgate, was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-4-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing 15 Yards of printed Cotton, value 30 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-4-victim57" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-4-victim57" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-4-victim57" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-4-victim57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-off22 t17400416-4-victim57"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in her Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-4-cd23" type="crimeDate">March 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-off22 t17400416-4-cd23"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Walker. On the 18th of March last, I was call'd down Stairs into my Shop, and found the Prisoner, and several Neighbours in the Shop: My Servant charged her with having taken 15 Yards of printed Cotton, which was mine, and she said she had nothing to say, for she had had the Cotton; those were the very Words; and she hoped I would not prosecute her. This is the Cotton, it lay upon the Counter when I came down Stairs; 'tis mine - I am a single Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-4-person58">
                  James 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17400416-4-person58" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-person58" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner came into the Shop, on <placeName id="t17400416-4-crimeloc24">Little Tower-Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-4-crimeloc24" type="placeName" value="Little Tower-Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-4-crimeloc24" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-off22 t17400416-4-crimeloc24"></join>, with another Woman, on Tuesday the 18th of March last, under pretence of buying something. It was in the Morning, but I can't tell the Hour. The Woman that was with her, bought enough to make a Child's Frock, and paid 3 s. for that, and a Bit of Cambrick. When they came in, they asked for printed Cottons, to make a Frock; and I shew'd them this very Piece, but they did not like it then; so I let it lie on the Counter, and shew'd them Purple and White, some of which they bought. When the Prisoner's Companion had paid me the 3 s. the Prisoner went out of the Shop, and her Companion stood at the Door talking with me: but suspecting I had lost something, I stepp'd out, and took the Prisoner 5 or 6 Doors beyond our Shop; and when I had got her back into the Shop, she took this Cotton from under her Apron, and gave it me into my Hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am innocent of taking the Linnen. The young Man ( Woodward ) took it up in the the Shop, but whether the other Woman left it there, or not, I can't tell. I did not give it him into his Hand; he took it off the Ground himself, and said, here's the Linnen.</p>
               <p>Woodward. She herself deliver'd it to me, from under her Apron, and her Companion desired me not to pull her about so. The other Woman I let go.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And she is run away.</p>
               <p>Woodward. I am sure the Prisoner is the Woman that deliver'd the Goods to me, when I had brought her back. They were above a quarter of an Hour looking on the Goods; and this Piece of Cotton lay under the other Goods I had shewn them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-4-person59">
                  Kezia 
                  Tingey 
               <interp inst="t17400416-4-person59" type="surname" value="Tingey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-person59" type="given" value="Kezia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-person59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner own'd her Crime, when she was brought back, and begg'd prodigiously that she might not be prosecuted: she owned she had stole the Cotton, and that she had been drawn into it, by bad Company. This was on the 18th of March last, in Mrs. Walker's Dining-Room.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known the Prisoner 19 Years: she has had 11 Children, and I nursed the youngest Child 3 Years. 'Her Father's Name is Mason, - a very honest Man; and she did keep a Publick-House, the Sign of the Swan , facing St Ann's Church, in St. Ann's Lane. She followed <rs id="t17400416-4-deflabel25" type="occupation">Needle-Work and Quilting</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-defend55 t17400416-4-deflabel25"></join>, and during the Time I have known her, I never missed her Conversation, till about half Year ago. Her Husband is Clerk to one Mr. Jordan, who fits Men out for the Sea: he is a very honest Man, and I never heard any harm of her. <rs id="t17400416-4-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-verdict26" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400416-4-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-4-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-4-defend55 t17400416-4-punish27"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
