<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-19">
               <interp inst="t17421208-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-19" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-19" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-19-off107-c137" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-19-defend173 t17421208-19-off107 t17421208-19-verdict109"></join>
         
               <p>19. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-19-defend173" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Creech 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-19-defend173" type="surname" value="Creech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-defend173" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-defend173" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17421208-19-defloc106">St Botolph Aldgate, London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-19-defloc106" type="placeName" value="St Botolph Aldgate, London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-19-defloc106" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-19-defend173 t17421208-19-defloc106"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17421208-19-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Watch with a Silver Case, Value 40 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-19-victim175" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Emmet 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-19-victim175" type="surname" value="Emmet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-19-victim175" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-19-victim175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-19-off107 t17421208-19-victim175"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in the Dwelling-house of the said Sarah
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17421208-19-cd108" type="crimeDate">Nov. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-19-off107 t17421208-19-cd108"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-19-person176">
                  James 
                  Emmet 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person176" type="surname" value="Emmet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person176" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of last Month, I was with this Person at the Bar, at the House of one Mrs Smallpiece. - The Prisoner lodges there. I went in with another young Woman, 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person177">
                  Sarah 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person177" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person177" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , between one and two o'Clock in the Afternoon, and sat down at the End of the Table with the Prisoner's Concern.</p>
               <p>Q. Concern! What is that?</p>
               <p>Emmet. She called her so: I do not know what she meant [Consort or Companion] which was 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person178">
                  Sarah 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person178" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person178" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person178" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person179">
                  Sarah 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person179" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person179" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I laid down upon the Bed together; I was not there above two Minutes, before the Prisoner came and laid down by my Side. I was no sooner laid down, but I was fast asleep: In a little Time I started up, and seeing the Prisoner was gone, Lord! says I to 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person180">
                  Sarah 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person180" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person180" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person180" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where is the other Person? She said she was gone. The Door was lock'd, and the Key put under it. I felt under the Bolster for my Watch, and it was gone. It was ten Days before I found this Woman, and it was said, that she went and was married with the Money she made of the Watch; but it has been prov'd since, that they were only married by jumping over a Mop-stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner gone when you fell asleep?</p>
               <p>Emmet. The Prisoner was not gone before I fell asleep, but she was gone before I was awake. - The Prisoner fell asleep, and I believe we all fell asleep. - I have had my Watch again: She confessed before the Alderman that she took it, and told that Gentleman (
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person181">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person181" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) where it was pawn'd, and that it was pawn'd for 22 s. 6 d. I heard her say, she took it from under the Bolster.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure she said so?</p>
               <p>Emmet. I verily think she said so, I will not swear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-19-person182">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person182" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person182" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . May it please you, my Lord, I will tell you the Story as well as I can. This young Man is my Kinsman: He said to me one Day, as I was going Home from the India House, that he had something to tell me. Says he, I have lost my Watch. I hope not, said I: Where did you lose it? Said he, I met a Woman in Bishopsgate-street, and went through Devonshire-Square, and went into a House with her, where there was another Woman; we all three lay down upon the Bed together, and I lay between the two Women when I was robb'd. We went into several Houses in order to find them, but could not: We happened to meet<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080012"></xptr> with the Husband that it was pretended she was married to with the Money she made of the Watch, and he went with us for the Sake of a Crown to betray her: We found her, and promis'd her, if she would tell us where the Watch was, we would show her Mercy, as far as it was in our Power.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that promis'd her Mercy?</p>
               <p>Jones. Both my Kinsman and I did: We went with her to the Three Kings in the Minories: She denied it for a long Time, but at last own'd that she took it from under the Bolster, and had sold or pawn'd it for 22 s. 6 d. I took two Men and a Constable, and went to the House where she said it was sold, and staid till ten o'Clock at Night, and could not find the People. We carried her before Alderman Bernard, and she confessed before him, that she sold it for 22 s. 6 d. and he committed her to Newgate. We went to a House where there sat an old Woman, which by the Description we had of her, was the Person she had sold it to. Do you sell a Dram? said I. She said, Yes. So we had a Quartern of Gin. Said I, I come to enquire after a Watch that is pawn'd here, and I am credibly informed, by one that is in Prison, that you have it; and if you do not return it, there is a Constable just by, and you shall go too. Said my Cousin, before I was aware, if you will let me have the Watch, I will give you the 22 s. 6 d. that you gave for it. Said she, I believe I can help you to it, but I have it not in the House. I went to an Alehouse at next Door, to enquire after this Woman's Character, and told the Woman the Story. Said she, if she promis'd to get it for you again, you will be sure of having it; and the Woman of the Alehouse lent me 22 s. 6 d. to pay for the Watch; there was a little Girl came to me, and gave me a Tap on the Back, and bid me come along with her. She led me into a narrow Passage in Rag-Fair, and bid me a good Night, and in that narrow Passage, I had the Watch put into my Hand; but who gave it me, I cannot tell, whether it was a Man or a Woman; the Person put a 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person183">
                  Brown 
                  Paper 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person183" type="surname" value="Paper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person183" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into my Hand, and in that Paper was the Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This 
               <persName id="t17421208-19-person184">
                  Sarah 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17421208-19-person184" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person184" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-person184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called me up Stairs, to bring a Quartern of Brandy; and I went down directly; she called me up Stairs again, and said, Take this and pawn it for me, and gave me Six-pence for my Trouble. The young Man was asleep then; I did not hear him speak: I was not within the Room; I was no farther than the Door. <rs id="t17421208-19-verdict109" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-verdict109" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-verdict109" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of the Felony: Acquitted of taking it out of a Dwelling-House
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17421208-19-punish110" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-19-punish110" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-19-defend173 t17421208-19-punish110"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
