<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490113-5">
               <interp inst="t17490113-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-5" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-5" type="date" value="17490113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490113-5-off24-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-5-defend53 t17490113-5-off24 t17490113-5-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>97. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-5-defend53" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Forster 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-5-defend53" type="surname" value="Forster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-defend53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-defend53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17490113-5-defloc23">St. John's, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-5-defloc23" type="placeName" value="St. John's, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-5-defloc23" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-5-defend53 t17490113-5-defloc23"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17490113-5-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver spoon, val. 10 s. one Portugal piece, ten guineas, ten pounds 18 s. in silver
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-5-victim55" type="victimName">
                     Lewis 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-5-victim55" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-victim55" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-5-off24 t17490113-5-victim55"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17490113-5-cd25" type="crimeDate">Jan. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-5-off24 t17490113-5-cd25"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-5-person56">
                  Lewis 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17490113-5-person56" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person56" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner had been at my house about 14 nights, and went away, Jan 7. I miss'd these things, I got a warrant and officer, and by directions found him in Hungerford-market, in One-tun court; he was in bed with a madam, and upon seeing me he stamp'd and said he had done for himself. We had him before the Justice, and on searching him found a purse, in which he told the Justice he believed there was about 10 l. but his worship found it to be 17 l. the prisoner said to me, it is your money, and I am sorry I should be guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-5-person57">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17490113-5-person57" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person57" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner asked me for a candle to go up stairs on Saturday night last: he went up stairs and came down again. My husband went up and found his money was gone; he returned and said we were robb'd: the young man who lodged in our house, said he heard Forster drop three or four pieces of money. The next morning my husband found the prisoner out, and carry'd him before a Justice, and from thence to a publick house, and there he confest the fact: likewise he confest it in Justice Manwaring's garden, saying he had used a friend very and was sorry for it. I saw this 3 l. 12 s. taken out of the purse before the Justice, and there I swore to it by a particular mark on the figure 9.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-5-person58">
                  Stephen 
                  Pett 
               <interp inst="t17490113-5-person58" type="surname" value="Pett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person58" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Beadle of the parish of St. John, Wapping; on Sunday-morning Mr. Jones call'd me out of bed, we took a person or two with us, and went to One-tun-court in Hungerford-market, and there we took the prisoner; he was in bed with a madam, and we brought him before Justice Manwaring, and found about 17 l. in a purse in his pocket. The Justice asked him how he came by that money, and he said he received it for wages and prize-money: being ask'd how much there was of it, he said he believed about 9 or 10 l. but, upon telling it over, there was 17 l. with the portugal piece, which Mrs. Jones swore to, which was produced in court: he said he was a sailor before the mast, the Justice told him by his appearance he should have taken him for a captain of a man of war, by his lac'd waistcoat, &amp;c. The Justice desired him to be ingennous, if he had any thing to say to Mr. Jones; so we went to an ale-house, and upon Mr. Jones's charging him with taking the money, he retun'd for answer, he was sorry for what he had done, adding, this money is all yours; and he own'd the same when we took him back again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I came to Mr. Jones's house on Saturday-night, I went to get a ring out of my chest but could not get my chest open; I went up again and I found my key and open'd my chest, and I could not find the ring; coming down I happen'd to make a sort of stumble on the stairs and I fell down; I had four guineas of my own in my pocket at that time, and I went to Covent-garden to my Lord's, and there I went to Hazard, and there I believe I won about 10 or 12 l. and the next morning Mr. Jones came to me at my lodgings with my wife, and took me to Justice Manwaring's and sent the girl to the Round-house. My captain and officers never could say but I was an honest fellow.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-5-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-5-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-5-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-5-defend53 t17490113-5-punish27"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
