<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440223-27">
               <interp inst="t17440223-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-27" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-27" type="date" value="17440223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-27-off153-c144" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend195 t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-verdict158"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-27-off153-c145" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend197 t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-verdict158"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-27-off153-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend199 t17440223-27-off153 "></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-27-off153-c148" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend201 t17440223-27-off153 "></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230016"></xptr>+ 167, 168, 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-defend195" type="defendantName">
                     Winifred 
                     Jackson 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend195" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend195" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , late of London, <rs id="t17440223-27-deflabel150" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend195 t17440223-27-deflabel150"></join>, 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     Judith 
                     Mayers 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend197" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend197" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17440223-27-deflabel151" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend197 t17440223-27-deflabel151"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person198">
                  Andrew 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person198" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person198" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late of London, jeweller, 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-defend199" type="defendantName">
                  Soloman 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend199" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend199" type="given" value="Soloman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late of the same place, <rs id="t17440223-27-deflabel152" type="occupation">jeweller</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-defend199 t17440223-27-deflabel152"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-defend201" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Mayers 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend201" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend201" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-defend201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , late of the same place, spinster, were indicted, for that <rs id="t17440223-27-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               they, upon the <rs id="t17440223-27-cd154" type="crimeDate">fourth day of March, in the 15th year of our Sovereign Lord George, the Second</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-cd154"></join>, &amp;c. at the parish of <placeName id="t17440223-27-crimeloc155">St. Christopher</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="St. Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-crimeloc155"></join>, in the ward of <placeName id="t17440223-27-crimeloc156">Bread Street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="Bread Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-crimeloc156"></join>, did unlawfully conspire, combine, and consult together, one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440223-27-victim203" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Sharp 
                        <interp inst="t17440223-27-victim203" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-27-victim203" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-27-victim203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-off153 t17440223-27-victim203"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , of London, <rs id="t17440223-27-viclabel157" type="occupation">laceman</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-27-victim203 t17440223-27-viclabel157"></join>, of a large sum of money, by unlawful and deceitful ways and means, to cheat and defraud
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The case, as laid in the indictment, was, that 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person204">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person204" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person204" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , having four East-India bonds in her custody, viz. N 11453, dated Sep. 30, 1708. which is set forth to be the property of the English Company, trading to the East-Indies. A. No 12179, dated June 22, 1711. A. No 15106, dated July 22, 1712. A. No 16388, dated Nov. 16, 1713. which are set forth to be the property of the united Company of Merchants of England trading to the East-Indies: And the East-India Company having given due and publick notice in the London Gazette, on the 21st of June, 1729. for the payment and discharge of the first of the said bonds, that bond ceased to carry any further interest from and after the 31st of December, then next ensuing; and the said Company having given the like notice on the 16th of May, 1730. for the payment and discharge of the other three bonds, those also ceased to carry any further interest from and after the 31st of December then next ensuing; and that on the 1st of Jan. 1730. and from thence continually to the 4th day of March aforesaid, there remained due and payable from the said Company, over and above the principal sums of 100 l. on each of the said bonds, no more than the sum of 96 l. for interest, on account of all the said four bonds; and they the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person205">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person205" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person205" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c. did falsely, freudulently, unlawfully, and deceitfully declare, affirm, and assert to the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person206">
                  Thomas 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person206" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person206" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that the Company, notwithstanding such publick notices, had, upon the petition of her the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person207">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person207" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person207" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at a General Court by them holden, ordered, that the said four bonds should carry interest to the said 4th day of March; and did likewise assert, that there was then due from the said Company, on account of the said four bonds, the full sum of 665 l. 2 s. and they did falsely and deceitfully entice the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person208">
                  Thomas 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person208" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person208" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to pay her, the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person209">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person209" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person209" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the said sum of 665 l. 2 s. which sum he, giving credit and belief to the aforesaid declarations, &amp;c. did then and there actually pay into the proper hands of the said Winifred, as so much money due from the said Company, on and for the purchase of the said bonds, by reason and means whereof the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person210">
                  Thomas 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person210" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person210" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did then and there pay to the said Winifred 169 l. 2 s. more than was really due; and thereby the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person211">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person211" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person211" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c. did unlawfully and fraudulently obtain from, cheat and defraud the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person212">
                  Thomas 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person212" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person212" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the sum of 169 l. 2 s. to the great deceit, fraud and demage of the said 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person213">
                  Thomas 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person213" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person213" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in contempt of our said Sovereign Lord the King, and his laws, to the evil example of all others, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecutor having opened the case, the bonds were produced, and Mr. Webb proved them to be the East-India Company's bonds.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person214">
                  Christopher 
                  Mould 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person214" type="surname" value="Mould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person214" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Secretary to the East-India Company, produced the minutes of the proceedings of the Company, and a minute made at a General Court holden the 22d of March 1736, was read, showing, that 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person215">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person215" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person215" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had petitioned, that her four bonds (of the numbers and dates set forth in the indictment) might be renewed, and the interest thereof to that time paid, notwithstanding the notices given by the Court of Directors in 1729 and 1730, that the said bonds should be paid off; and the Court's resolution thereupon, viz. ''Resolved, that the said bonds '' be paid off, with the interest thereupon, according '' to the notices given.''</p>
               <p>Q. Mr. Mould, Do you remember Mrs. Jackson's applying at that time upon this account?</p>
               <p>Mr. Mould. I remember the Lady's applying at that time; and it was taken notice of by every Director, she used to attend them and tease them so, from day to day, and time to time.</p>
               <p>Then the Council for the Prosecutor begged leave to call Mr. Sharp to prove what method this Lady (Mrs. Jackson) took to accomplish her ends in this case.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor's Council. Mr. Sharp, you are acquainted with Mrs. Jackson and Mrs. Mayers; pray give the court an account of this affair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. I never saw Mrs. Jackson or Mrs. Mayers, till I received a letter from Mrs. Mayers, which was wrote in this manner (I have not the letter here) ''I desire you will call upon '' me some afternoon, I have something to propose, '' which will be for your advantage. Your '' humble 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person216">
                  Servant, J.<interp inst="t17440223-27-person216" type="given" value="Servant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person216" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Mayers.'' Accordingly I went to Mrs. Mayers's, for as there was something to my advantage, I was glad to hear of it; when I went<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230017"></xptr> she said, I have something to propose very much to your advantage, but when I tell you, you would think I joke: She said, she knew a lady who had no relation in the world, who came to her house every night in the week, and if you will come here to morrow night you shall see her; she is worth forty thousand pound, and lives at one Mrs. Witham's in Chancery-Lane; she said she was a frugal lady, and would not spend it. I thought forty thousand pound was a great deal to lay hold of, and a good wife too, and I was to go the next night to meet her at Mrs. Mayers's - I had several letters, but not one of them has a date (I think this was in January or February 1741.) I went by appointment at five o'clock, she said she had been with Mrs. Jackson, that she was ill of a cold, and she was angry with herself she had spoke to me about it, for fear I should think she deceived me, and bid me not be uneasy, for she saw her every day, and would soon bring it to pass.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. Mr. Sharp, I understand there are some letters. Who wrote these letters?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. Mrs. Mayers said sometimes they were wrote by her son, and sometimes by her daughter: After these letters Mrs. Mayers would sometimes come and drink a pint of wine with me, says she, I will try, whether I cannot get her leave for you to go to her house; she has a great many East-India and South Sea bonds, and I will try whether I cannot get her to part with some of the bonds she had at her brother's death: She has petitioned the general court of the East-India Company, and they have ordered the interest to be paid to the year 1736, they have allowed her forty eight pound: Says she, you know those gentlemen, you trade with them, you must try to get this high interest for Mrs. Jackson, and she will reckon you 2 clever fellow, and then the match will be made at once; I said, I never bought or sold a bond in my life, and I did not care to meddle with them. Some time after she came and told me, that Mrs. Jackson said, if you will bring him, and he will talk of nothing but the bonds, he may come; so I met Mrs. Mayers at a tavern in Chancery-Lane (I believe this was in February) and there was Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person217">
                  Judith 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person217" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person217" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , her son and daughter; we went to Mrs. Jackson and Mrs. Mayers's son Solomon pulled out this petition (the petition to the East-India Company) he said he wrote it, that he was along with Mrs. Jackson, and delivered it, and that the Company had ordered that the bonds should be paid according to the information they had given me in a paper - They all said it, the mother, the son, and the daughter, and swore to it - The petition was produced by 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person218">
                  Solomon 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person218" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person218" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and so was the paper with the amount of the bonds drawn out, but not at the same time: I said these bonds have been out-standing a long time, I cannot see what interest is due upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. You say he told you the bonds were to be paid according to the writing he produced.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. When we were all together Mrs. Mayers appointed that Mr. Mayers should settle it with Mrs. Jackson before I was to give her the money for the bonds.</p>
               <p>Q. How could she deceive you in this when you had been apprized before of the order for paying the bonds off?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. I was not informed any otherwise than Mrs. Mayers informed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you come to any agreement that they came to any particular interest?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. When I desired the account in writing, he said the general court had ordered payment to be made upon the bonds according to what was in that paper - he told me they had petitioned the general court, and they all said the court had agreed that the interest should be settled to the time mentioned in that paper - they said there was forty eight pound due upon each bond down to the year 1736, as appears by the Company's books down to the year 1736, and that they had allowed all the interest to that time, and there the interest is cast up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they all agree that it should be put into writing?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. They all agreed to it, then Mrs. Jackson said, she would appoint a time for me to come and pay the money for them.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. Where did you go when you went from that house?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. We went back again to the tavern, Mrs. Mayers staid a little behind, and when she came she gave me a great deal of joy; she sat down by me, and gave me a prodigious slap upon the thigh, and said, God, you are a lucky devil, for she likes you prodigiously.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the next thing?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person219">
                  Judith 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person219" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person219" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next day brought this paper to my house, and said, my son has been with Mrs. Jackson all day settling the account, and this account he has brought you; says she, Mrs. Jackson will meet you on Thursday night at the Bank coffee-house, and then you are to buy these bonds; I said, buying of these bonds is no more than taking a bank note, for I can go to the India-house the next day and get the money again: I met her at the Bank coffee-house the 4th of March, 1741.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were there at that time?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. All the four persons I have indicted; I carried the paper with me - it was produced<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230018"></xptr> there, and Mrs. Mayers said this is the true interest due upon these bonds.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. Speak up boldly, Mr. Sharp, I cannot hear you.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. May be you do not desire to hear me. Mrs. Mayers said that was the right account: I said to Mrs. Jackson, Madam, I will give you the money for these bonds; but look here, Mrs. Mayers and Mr. Mayers, take notice of one thing; as for my part I cannot see how Mr. Mayers can cast up the interest; suppose the interest should happen to be more or less, if there is any mistake we must rectify it, and give or take the difference; and they all agreed to this.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. How is this a fraud then?</p>
               <p>Another Council. Out of your own mouth comes the truth.</p>
               <p>Sharp. I shall not deny this I say so still, and they all said, Aye, to be sure, the difference was to be settled: Mrs. Mayers came to my house, and said, Don't part with the bonds; I would have you keep them, for Mrs Jackson is as cunning a woman as any in the world; for she will come and look upon the bonds, to see if you can spare the money out of trade; and I believe I should not have gone about the money for the bonds, if Mrs. Mayers had not said that; I went on the Tuesday to Mr. Webb, at the India-House, and told him, I had got some East-India bonds; he looked at them, says he, Who had you these bonds of? Said I, What signifies who I had them of; he looked at them again, God bless me! says he, you had these bonds of Mrs. Jackson; I told him, I had, and shewed him the paper, with the account of the interest; he looked upon it, said he, Go back again to her, as fast as you can, for she has cheated you; I went several times, and could not see her; I went one day, and desired to see Mrs. Witham, and told her the affair, and she owned Mrs. Jackson had ordered herself to be denied; I brought an action and recovered the money; and what I do now is for the good of the publick; I have been 40 l. out of pocket already.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Webb. Suppose Mr. Sharp had come to you and told you of such a petition, could not you have informed him whether it had beenplied with?</p>
               <p>Mr. Webb. Yes, to be sure, if he had shewed me the bonds.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not you have told by the numbers?</p>
               <p>Mr. Webb. No. I could not, but if I had any acquaintance with the person, I would have endeavoured to have informed him, as well as I could.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council to Mr. Sharp. Had not yo the petition a month before you paid the money for the bonds?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. I had not the petition till I paid for the bonds; the petition was only read to me at Mrs. Jackson's, and it was only read to me when they brought the account of the interest.</p>
               <p>The petition to the honourable the Directors of the East-India Company was produced and read, and likewise the paper wherein they had cast up the principal and interest, with the particulars of the interest (said there to be as it stands on the Company's books) the total amounting to 665 l. 2 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-person220">
                  Emanuel 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person220" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person220" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe it was this February was two years, that Mr. Sharp was with Mrs. Jackson at our house, and Madam Jackson asked him, whether he had enquired about those bonds; he said, he had not enquired, for he had not proper instructions - He said, he would give her the money for the bonds, if she would give it him in writing, that if he could not get all the money of the Company, that she would return it; which she agreed to, and then she said, she would give him a copy of the petition to enquire by - They did not tell him whether the petition was presented, or no - My brother wrote out the petition, and I and my sister carried it about a month before March the 4th. My brother told him, Sir, if you think you can't get the money, don't take the bonds at all - I did not hear Mr. Sharp say any thing to it; and my brother wrote out the account; he took me with him to Mrs. Jackson's, and she told him how to write it, and my sister and I carried the account to Mr. Sharp, and said I had brought the account by Madam Jackson's order; and he said, tell Mrs. Jackson I will meet her at the Bank coffee-house, and I will pay her the money for the bonds; I know how to get the money of the Company, I know how to make the Company pay me - I heard him say these words; the money was paid the fourth of March.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. Do you remember at any time that he made any proposal of stifling the prosecution?</p>
               <p>Mayers. He desired my mother and sister would go out of town, and not appear at the trial, and he would pay the charges; and she said, she would not; he said, then it should be the worse for her.</p>
               <p>Council. This was when he sued Mrs. Jackson; but do you remember, that Mr. Sharp said at any time, he would have some money of Mrs. Jackson, or he would bring her to the bar?</p>
               <p>Mayers. Last December, or thereabouts, he said he was going to find a bill of indictment against Mrs. Jackson, and wanted my mother, brother, and sister, to go to the Old-Bailey, and he said, he would make them handsom presents, but they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230019"></xptr> would not; then he said, he would indict them all out of spite; he said, he would carry my brother off swearing, he would spoil all their swearing; my mother said, it was a vile thing to prefer an indictment, and so he went away in a passion.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. That boy never was at any of the meetings.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Witham. Mr. Sharp came to speak to Mrs. Jackson; I heard some high words, there was a mighty hurley burley, and Mr. Sharp said, I will send you all to Newgate. What, said I, I that know nothing at all of the matter? he said, Not you. I said, how came you to buy these bonds, when you bought them with your eyes open? he said, if it had been a thousand pound he would have done it for her - I believe all the county of Essex will give Mrs. Jackson a good character; her father was a man of good reputation, and so were all the family - I believe she is worth a good thousand a year, and a coach and four horses, near Brentwood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-person221">
                  Mary 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person221" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person221" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person221" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Mrs. Jackson was in custody of Mr. Carter the Tipstaff, Mr. Sharp was there, and he said to her, he would send Mrs. Mayers to keep her company; he said, he would have sent them, but they were worth nothing; but, Madam, you shall fine.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. I never said any such thing in my life.</p>
               <p>King. You did say so, and Mrs. Jackson made answer, and said, You would hang me if you could; and you said, Aye that I would, for I have already agreed with a surgeon for your body to be made a skeleton of; and when I have so done, you shall be put in a closet in my room, that when I have a mind to see Mrs. Jackson, I may go up and look at her.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person222">
                  William 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person222" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the tipstaff that took Mrs. Jackson up, and in conversation between Mr. Sharp and her, he was angry with her, and said, she had cheated him of a great deal of money, and he would send Mrs. Mayers to her. - He said, if he discharged her now, intimating. he had it in his power to discharge her or not, and that, if she would marry him, he would release her; those were not the very words, but to that purport.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Alcorn. I am a tenant to Mrs. Jackson, by the Exchange; I do not think she would defraud any person of a farthing.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person223">
                  Solomon 
                  Riatti 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person223" type="surname" value="Riatti"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person223" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have heard Mr. Sharp say, that Mrs. Jackson had made application to the East-India Company about her bonds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he at any time before he paid her the money for the bonds, tell you, the petition was rejected?</p>
               <p>Riatti. No, he never did.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sisson and Mr. Gibson have known Mrs. Jackson a great many years, and gave her the character of a very honest woman.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sandford was called by the Prosecutor, and being asked Mrs. Jackson's character, he said, he never heard any harm of her.</p>
               <p>It being proved, that, before the payment of the money for the bonds, there was an agreement made between the parties, that if it should happen, there was any mistake in the casting up of the interest, it was to be rectified; if it did not come to so much as the computation. Mrs. Jackson was to return the surplus; if it came to more, Mr. Sharp was to pay her. Whereupon, 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person224">
                  Winifred 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person224" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person224" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person225">
                  Judith 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person225" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person225" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were <rs id="t17440223-27-verdict158" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-verdict158" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-27-person226">
                  Solomon 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person226" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person226" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17440223-27-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Mayers 
               <interp inst="t17440223-27-person227" type="surname" value="Mayers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-27-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the two others in the indictment, did not surrender themselves.</p>
            </div1>
