<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480907-50">
               <interp inst="t17480907-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-50" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-50" type="date" value="17480907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480907-50-off254-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-defend385 t17480907-50-off254 t17480907-50-verdict258"></join>
         
               <p>440. + 
               <persName id="t17480907-50-defend385" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Garner 
               <interp inst="t17480907-50-defend385" type="surname" value="Garner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-defend385" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-defend385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of the Parish of <placeName id="t17480907-50-defloc253">St. Andrew Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-50-defloc253" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-50-defloc253" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-defend385 t17480907-50-defloc253"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17480907-50-off254" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-off254" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-off254" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               he, not having the fear of God before his eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17480907-50-cd255" type="crimeDate">6th day of July, in the 21st year of his Majesty's reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-off254 t17480907-50-cd255"></join>, in and upon 
                     <persName id="t17480907-50-victim386" type="victimName">
                        Hepzibah 
                        Dover 
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-victim386" type="surname" value="Dover"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-50-victim386" type="given" value="Hepzibah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-50-victim386" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-off254 t17480907-50-victim386"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , spinster, did make an assault, and her, the said Hepzibah, did feloniously ravish, and carnally know and abuse
            </rs>, against the form of the statute in that case made and provided.</p>
               <p>Hepzibah Dover sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What age are you?</p>
               <p>Hepzibah Dover . I am 12 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you 12 years of age?</p>
               <p>Dover. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-50-person387">
                  Esther 
                  Northam 
               <interp inst="t17480907-50-person387" type="surname" value="Northam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person387" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person387" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My daughter makes a mistake ; she was 13 years of age in June last.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dover . You are upon your oath, and the prisoner's life is at stake; you must speak nothing but the truth .</p>
               <p>Dover. I will not, my lord .</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Dover . I live with my mother in <placeName id="t17480907-50-crimeloc256">Eagle-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-50-crimeloc256" type="placeName" value="Eagle-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-50-crimeloc256" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-off254 t17480907-50-crimeloc256"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Does that man live with your father or mother ?</p>
               <p>Dover . No.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Dover. He is a <rs id="t17480907-50-deflabel257" type="occupation">carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-defend385 t17480907-50-deflabel257"></join>, and work'd just by.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your father?</p>
               <p>Dover. A clockmaker.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be with him?</p>
               <p>Dover. My mother sent me there for some chips and shavings, and he was in a two pair of stairs room; and he called me up where he was at work:</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he at work ?</p>
               <p>Dover. At the corner of our street .</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Dover. In July, I think.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of July?</p>
               <p>Dover . I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the beginning, middle, or latter end?</p>
               <p>Dover. It was, I believe, the beginning of July.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it?</p>
               <p>Dover. It was in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the house inhabited, or was it an empty house?</p>
               <p>Dover . It was an empty house.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any workmen there besides himself?</p>
               <p>Dover. There were none but him and me in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say to you?</p>

               <p>Dover . He asked me to come up to the two pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you go up stairs for?</p>
               <p>Dover . He said if I came up, he would give me some shavings ; and I went up to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the two pair of stairs room backwards, or forwards ?</p>
               <p>Dover. It was next Eagle-street.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came up there, did he give you any shavings ?</p>
               <p>Dover . The minute I came up, he threw me down, and stopped my mouth .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Dover. He threw me down, and stopped my mouth .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Dover . No.</p>
               <p>Q. When he threw you down, did you endeavour to cry out?</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes; but he stopped my mouth, and I could not cry out .</p>
               <p>Q. What did he stop your mouth with ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070023"></xptr>Dover . With his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a bed in the room, or did he throw you down upon the ground?</p>
               <p>Dover. He threw me down upon the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do then?</p>
               <p>Dover. He pulled up my petticoats .</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Dover. After he had pulled up my petticoats, he hurt me most sadly.</p>
               <p>Q. Were his breeches down, and unbuttoned?</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come and lie down by you, or upon you?</p>
               <p>Dover . He laid down upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do when he laid down upon you? Did he put his private parts into your body?</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he upon you?</p>
               <p>Dover. I believe about half an hour.</p>
               <p>[The girl expressed herself in such terms as fully proved the rape .]</p>
               <p>Q. What passed afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Dover . When I got up I told him I would tell my mother; and he said, if I did, he would murder me the first time he met me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry then?</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes, I cried when I was with him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you discover this to your mother ?</p>
               <p>Dover. About a week afterwards; I could not keep it any longer, for I was in such pain and misery , that I told my mother.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you did not tell your mother sooner ?</p>
               <p>Dover. Because I was afraid of my father-in-law .</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you could not keep it a secret any longer?</p>
               <p>Dover. By reason of the very great pain I was in; and then I told it to my mother, in the same manner I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the prisoner taken up?</p>
               <p>Dover. A week afterwards .</p>
               <p>Q. When you told your mother, was you carried to any body?</p>
               <p>Dover . Yes; I was carried to a great many.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her how long she knew me before .</p>
               <p>Dover. I knew him the summer before , and I believed him to be a very honest man , for he never offered any thing unhandsome to me before; and I had fetched shavings from him a great many times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her if ever she came after this .</p>
               <p>Dover. Yes, I did, and he said he would not give me any shavings.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did you go to him after this?</p>
               <p>Dover. But once, and that was 2 or 3 days afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing pass remarkable then ?</p>
               <p>Dover . He would have had me have gone up again, but I would not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any shavings then ?</p>
               <p>Dover . He would not give me any at first , but afterwards he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-50-person388">
                  Esther 
                  Northam 
               <interp inst="t17480907-50-person388" type="surname" value="Northam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person388" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person388" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the sixth of July last I sent my daughter to that man for some shavings.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to send her to him?</p>
               <p>Northam . Because he was at work in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Northam . About 4 o'clock in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was your daughter gone?</p>
               <p>Northam . She was gone better than half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she bring some shavings ?</p>
               <p>Northam . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing to you then?</p>
               <p>Northam . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she at any time make any complaint to you of being used ill by the prisoner?</p>

               <p>Northam . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that ?</p>
               <p>Northam . About a week afterwards I observed one night, when I was at supper, that she did not sit down. I did not say any thing to her that night .</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to you afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Northam . She said the next day, that her water scalded her so, that she was so hot, and so sore, that she could not fetch up a pail of water for the world. When she told me this , I told her, in 2 or 3 days she would be better, and she must not mind any such thing .</p>
               <p>Q. Was she better then ?</p>
               <p>Northam. She continued much the same .</p>
               <p>Q. Did she sit down the next day?</p>
               <p>Northam . No; she always hung on the backs of chairs, or leaned upon a table, till she had told what had been done to her.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this thing done to her?</p>
               <p>Northam . On the 6th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>Northam . On a Thursday ; and the Wednesday following I sent her for some more chips and shavings, and she said she could not go, for there was a hole before the door; and she cried, and desired I would not send her .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070024"></xptr>Q. Did she go then?</p>
               <p>Northam. No, she did not, and it went off; and the next day I said she should go, and drove her down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing in her gate?</p>
               <p>Northam. She walked very badly , but I did not think any thing of what was the matter with her. She brought me some shavings then; and she said, Mamma, don't be angry, for he was stronger than I; don't send me any more, for I never will go again; and she cried most bitterly.</p>
               <p>Q. I suppose this raised your curiosity . Give an account, as near as you can, in the words that she spoke.</p>
               <p>Northam . She fell down upon her knees , and said, I could not help it, indeed , for he was stronger than I; for when you sent me last Thursday , he bid me come up stairs, and he laid me down upon my back, and pulled up my petticoats , and put something into my body, &amp;c. and cried very much. Said I, why did not you cry out with all your might. She said, Oh mamma , I could not, for he stopped my mouth. I said, why did not you tell, me when you first came home . She said, because he threatened to murder me, if ever I told of it. I sent her to my midwife in Holbourn , who is now sick in bed of a fever, and to Mrs. Peters .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine her body ?</p>
               <p>Northam. Yes ; but she was so sore, that she could not bear me to touch her; and she appeared to be abused , and in a very vile condition . We have been forced to wash her three or four times a day, and tent her with fine line .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-50-person389">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17480907-50-person389" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person389" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-person389" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The child was brought to me, and looked like the picture of death .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the child ?</p>
               <p>Peters. Yes; and her linnen was in a most miserable condition?</p>
               <p>Q. How did she appear to have been used ?</p>
               <p>Peters. The inside of her body was sadly torn , and her private parts appeared to be scratched , and in a most miserable pickle , both before and behind.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Peters. About a fortnight, and they were healed then ; and her groin was black , and very much swelled.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by scratch'd? Were they lacerated, or torn ?</p>
               <p>Peters . The skin was almost torn off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she look as if she had been abused by a man?</p>
               <p>Peters. Yes; and I said it was my opinion that the child had the foul disease.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bavan (an Apothecary .) On the first of August I was desired to go to Mrs. Northam ; and the child and her mother gave the same account to me as they have delivered in court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the girl?</p>
               <p>Bavan . I examined her body, and found the parts almost healed, with respect to the laceration ; but she had a great running upon her, which appeared to be venereal.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was a venereal case?</p>
               <p>Bavan. I see a great many cases of this kind, and I am sure 'tis a venereal case .</p>
               <p>Prisoner . My lord, I never was concerned with her in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480907-50-verdict258" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-verdict258" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480907-50-punish259" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-50-punish259" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-50-defend385 t17480907-50-punish259"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
