<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430223-20">
               <interp inst="t17430223-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-20" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-20" type="date" value="17430223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430223-20-off102-c181" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-defend218 t17430223-20-off102 t17430223-20-verdict106"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430223-20-off102-c182" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-defend220 t17430223-20-off102 "></join>
         
               <p>155, 156. +
               <persName id="t17430223-20-defend218" type="defendantName">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend218" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend218" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              and 
               
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                      Peacock , otherwise <rs id="t17430223-20-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-defend220 t17430223-20-alias-3"></join>Bulley</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17430223-20-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-defend220 t17430223-20-alias-4"></join>Hubbard</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend220" type="surname" value="Peacock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend220" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-defend220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17430223-20-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430223-20-victim222" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Taylor 
                        <interp inst="t17430223-20-victim222" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-20-victim222" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-20-victim222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-off102 t17430223-20-victim222"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17430223-20-viclabel103" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-victim222 t17430223-20-viclabel103"></join>; in the <placeName id="t17430223-20-crimeloc104">Hospital of Bridewell</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-crimeloc104" type="placeName" value="Hospital of Bridewell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-crimeloc104" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-off102 t17430223-20-crimeloc104"></join>, about the Hour of three in the Night, and stealing one Silver Cup and Cover; 2 Silver Muggs; six Salvers; 3 dozen of Spoons; 2 dozen Silver handled Knives; 37 Forks; 1 Silver Sauce-pan; 3 Salts; 3 Salt-Spoons, &amp;c. Value 80 l. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17430223-20-person223">
                        Joseph 
                        Taylor 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person223" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-20-person223" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-20-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esq; in the said Dwelling-House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430223-20-cd105" type="crimeDate">February 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-off102 t17430223-20-cd105"></join>. -</p>
               <p>They were a second Time charged for stealing the said Goods in a Dwelling-House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person224">
                  Joseph 
                  Avery 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person224" type="surname" value="Avery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person224" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Butler to Mr Taylor, in Bridewell; I looked the Plate over on the 13th Day of this Month when my Master went out of Town; I left it locked up in the Back-Parlour, in the Beauset, and took the Key with me to Stanmore. On Thursday, when my Master came to Town, I found the Beauset was broke open, and the Plate gone, as mentioned in the Indictment; the biggest Part of the Plate was found; this is the Cup and Cover which I left in the Beauset, locked up when I went out of Town. (There was a Silver Sauce-pan and some other Pieces of Plate produced, which were prov'd to be Mr Taylor's.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person225">
                  Rachel 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person225" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person225" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I went to Bed, on Monday was seven-Night, the Door was locked; and in the Morning, I found the Beauset was broke open, and the Plate gone: There was a Boat and a Sauce-pan which stood upon the Dresser, they were both gone. - The Door was locked when I went to Bed, and I believe it was barred: - They came in at the Window, up one Pair of Stairs; the Sash was pushed up.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Sash was down, when you went to Bed?</p>
               <p>Walker. I am not positively sure, whether the Sash was up or down: There was a Blind before the Sash, when I went to Bed: That was in its Place then; the Blind goes with Pullies, and was out of its Place in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230014"></xptr>Job Steele. In the first Place, 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person226">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person226" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person226" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his Wife 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person227">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person227" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person227" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, were at the 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person228">
                  Ben 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person228" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person228" type="given" value="Ben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's-Head, in Shoe-lane. (I never was there three Times in my Life) The last Night I was there, I was with them; it was Monday was seven-Night; and we agreed to rob Esquire Taylor's House, in Bridewell, that Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever Servant to Mr Taylor?</p>
               <p>Steele. I never was his Servant. - And accordingly, departing from that House; we entered into Bridewell undiscovered, without any Suspicion; and went up a winding Fair of Stairs. - Yes, I do know, because there were four Stories; but I do not know how high we went: But we went into the House, about Three o'Clock in the Morning; all Three of us. I was the Person, that entered the House; and I will tell you, by what Method; I lay concealed upon the Stairs till Three o'Clock, and then I thought they were all asleep. - At three o'Clock I came into the inner, and then into the outer Court, and Bulley helped me up over the Pallisades; there was a Sash-Window, which I lifted up and entered in, as better knowing the House than he did (though he knew it pretty well). I went down, opened the Door, and let them in, and they struck a Light with their Tinder-box, which they had with them, and broke the Beauset up; they filled two Bags, which they carried away with them, and they left more Plate behind, than they took away: They might have taken Plates and Dishes along with them, which they said were Pewter, and they would not take them; but they were Plate; it was better than this Trumpery. [Meaning a Cloth Coat of Ralph Sleigh's, and a Staw Hat, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person229">
                  Richard 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person229" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person229" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which were laid in the Indictment.]</p>
               <p>Court. Was the Window close down when you came to it?</p>
               <p>Steele. No, it was not close down by near a Foot, but I could not get into it without pushing it up - They took away all, I had none of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you nothing at all for your Pains?</p>
               <p>Steele. No; I had nothing at all for my Pains.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they get in?</p>
               <p>Steele. I unbarred and unbolted the Door and let them in - at the outer Door of the House - they went directly into the Kitchen and struck a Light with their Tinder-Box, and lighted a Candle; I shewed them where the Beauset was; and with a Gimblet and a Knife they opened it, and took out what they pleased; they made themselves up 2 Packs, and then went into the Kitchen to see what was there, and they took that Sauce-pan; there was another which was a little blacker than that, which they would not take: I suppose they thought it was not Silver, but they took enough away, and too much too - I am sure the 2 Prisoners are the Persons who took the Plate away, Gentlemen: I have not known the Woman above three Months, but I have known him 20 Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know she is his Wife?</p>
               <p>Steele. I do not know whether she is or not, he has 2 or 3 Wives.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person230">
                  Richard 
                  Pice 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person230" type="surname" value="Pice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person230" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Night last, Mr Taylor sent for me, with a Message, that he desired to speak with me; he said, he believed he had got a Person who would give him Information of the People who had got the Plate: I went with the Person to a House in Horselydown, but I did not see them that Night; I went over again the next Morning with a Search-Warrant; there are two Doors to the House, 2 of us went in at the Fore Door, and I and another went in at the Back-Door; the first Person I saw was 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person231">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person231" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person231" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I believed, according to the Account that was given me, that he was the Man; I endeavoured then to know where they lodged, in order to find the Woman, but as I had a Search-Warrant to search the House, I did search Part of it, and they brought me Word the Woman was in the House; we went into the back Part of the House and found her there, and I found a Wooden-Chest, and in that Chest a Brass Pistol: I found this Plate in the House where the Man was: It is the Sign of the Boatswain and Call, in Horselydown, Fair-street; I think the Man's Name is Redrosse; I believe Bulley came in as a Guest, for they told me he did not lodge there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person232">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person232" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person232" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you find any Thing about me?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person233">
                  Richard 
                  Pice 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person233" type="surname" value="Pice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person233" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In the Room she was in, there was a small Silver Spoon found in the Ashes; I believe they had been burning a pretty many Papers: This little Silver Spoon she had in her Pocket. [The Spoons were proved to be Mr. Taylor's by 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person234">
                  John 
                  Avery 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person234" type="surname" value="Avery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person234" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; one of them was marked J. T. the other was marked 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person235">
                  M.
                   H. B. A. Ann Bulley
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person235" type="surname" value="H. B. A. Ann Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person235" type="given" value="M."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person235" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said that was her own Spoon; and Mr Taylor said, the M. was for Mustard, it was a Mustard Spoon, and that the Letters H. B. A. were fresh made] This Spoon was found in the Ashes.</p>
               <p>Council. We shall now prove how this Plate was carried about from one Place to another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person236">
                  John 
                  Gyles 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person236" type="surname" value="Gyles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (Coachman) My Stand is by White-Chapel Bars: Last Thursday was sen'night, between Twelve and One, the Prisoner at the Bar (the Man) came to me and asked for a Hackney-Coachman to go to Dulwich; I called a Hackney-man out of the House; I do not know whether he asked him 8<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230015"></xptr> or 10 Shillings; the Prisoner bid him six; I said, I could get him a Chaise and Pair for 7 Shillings, which I did, and took him up and carried him to Wentworth-street, Spital-fields, and took up a Portmantean-Trunk, and put it into the Hay-Bag, and a little square Box, with Nobs at the Bottom. - This is the Box; the Box was very heavy - the Box was put into the Chaise. - This is the Trunk; I was ordered to go to the Bell at Dulwich, and unluckily the Portmanteau burst open on the Road; I saw there was Plate in it, but I could not tell whether it was Pewter or Silver; and when I had sat him down I came away, and then I was to go and fetch that Woman which I did, and two Dogs. - I left this Box and Trunk with 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person237">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person237" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person237" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Bell at Dulwich. - He paid my Mistress before I went with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person238">
                  Charles 
                  Shooler 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person238" type="surname" value="Shooler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person238" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the two Prisoners up at the Flying-horse, in Lambeth-street, and carried them to the Fox under the Hill, at Camberwell; and then went to the Bell at Dulwich, and brought from thence, a four cornered Box: That is the Box, and a hairy Portmanteau Trunk; that I believe is the Trunk: And I carried them into Horselydown, Fair-street, to the Boatswain and Call, and set both the Man and the Woman down there: She took another four cornered Trunk out of that Trunk: - I left the Trunk and the Box there below Stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person239">
                  Richard 
                  Pice 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person239" type="surname" value="Pice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person239" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe, this is the Trunk; Mr Taylor's Plate was in, when I found it: - There is all the Reason in the World to believe so; I left it behind me: But there are the Marks of the Blows, which I made with the Hammer, when I broke it open. - I took the Plate out of a Bag, which was in that Trunk.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person240">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person240" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person240" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I desire that Box may be opened : (Which was done, and a Pistol taken out) Whose Pistol is that? It is his Pistol.</p>
               <p>Job Steele. I know the Pistol very well. - I own it to be my Pistol.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person241">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person241" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person241" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Whose Things are those? (A Pair of Pistols, and two dark Lanthorns were taken out of the Box. )</p>
               <p>Job Steele. What signifies my knowing of these Things. I know them very well: These Pistols are your's, I have seen you handle them many a Time: - These two Dark Lanthorns, I believe, are the Lanthorns we made Use of at Mr Taylor's House. - All the Things in the Box, were Bulley's, except one Pistol.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person242">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person242" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person242" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Man who is the Evidence is the Person who sent the Box with the Plate in it under our Care: He sent it by an unknown Hand, and I did not know how he came by it.</p>
               <p>- Elliot. I saw Job Steele come into Bridewell, with a Man and a Woman with him, on Monday was se'ennight, a small Matter before Eleven o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether the Prisoners were the Persons.</p>
               <p>- Elliot. By their Size they are the same; I did not see their Faces. - I am sure Job Steele was one, I have seen him more than an hundred Times, and know it was him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person243">
                  Andrew 
                  Culley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person243" type="surname" value="Culley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person243" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Shrove-Tuesday, about half an Hour after Five in the Morning, I met both the Prisoners coming out of Bridewell loaded, and I thought they were going a Country-Journey, because they went out Bag and Baggage at that Time in the Morning. I had no Suspicion of them, if I had I should have stopped them.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person244">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person244" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person244" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Are you married to 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person245">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person245" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person245" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person246">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person246" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person246" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot say I am not married to him?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person247">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person247" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person247" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She is my Wife.</p>

               <p>[Council for the Prosecutor offered to prove that he had another Wife; the Court would not enter into that, as they acknowledged they were married.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person248">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person248" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person248" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I desire to ask Steele some Questions. I desire the Box may be opened again, and the Brass Pistol taken out; Whose Pistol is that?</p>
               <p>Job Steele. I never saw the Box before in my Life; I know nothing of the Brass Pistol. These other two Pistols I have seen often enough; you had them when you lived at my House; that other Pistol is mine, I have owned it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person249">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person249" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person249" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Steele sent this Plate to me by an unknown Hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-20-person250">
                  Henry 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person250" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person250" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17430223-20-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430223-20-punish107" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-punish107" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-20-defend218 t17430223-20-punish107"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. 
               <persName id="t17430223-20-person251">
                  Ann 
                  Bulley 
               <interp inst="t17430223-20-person251" type="surname" value="Bulley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person251" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17430223-20-verdict108" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-20-verdict108" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, as being present with her Husband, and supposed to act under his Direction.</p>
            </div1>
