<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460226-36">
               <interp inst="t17460226-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-36" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-36" type="date" value="17460226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460226-36-off126-c385" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-36-defend450 t17460226-36-off126 t17460226-36-verdict128"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460226-36-off127-c385" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-36-defend450 t17460226-36-off127 t17460226-36-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>128. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-defend450" type="defendantName">
                     John Peter 
                     Mayaffree 
                  <interp inst="t17460226-36-defend450" type="surname" value="Mayaffree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-defend450" type="given" value="John Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-defend450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             stands indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17460226-36-cd125" type="crimeDate">20th Day of December</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-36-off126 t17460226-36-cd125"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-36-off127 t17460226-36-cd125"></join>, was <rs id="t17460226-36-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               possessed of a certain Lottery Ticket, that before that Time had been made in Vertue of several Acts of Parliament, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He stands indicted a second Time, for <rs id="t17460226-36-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               uttering and vending, with an Intent to defraud Persons unknown, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Gentlemen, The Prisoner at the Bar has pleaded that he is not Guilty: We , who are concern'd for his Majesty, shall call our Witnesses ; and if we prove to your Satisfaction , you'll please to find him Guilty.</p>
               <p>Another Council. I am Council of the same Side on the Behalf of the Crown, against the Prisoner . The Offence , you observe, he stands now indicted for, has been in some Measure open'd by the Gentleman before me.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, I believe it is pretty well known to you, that great Part of the Property of the Subjects of this Kingdom is in Government Paper-Securities. In order to secure that Property to the Subject, it is but necessary the severest Penalties should be inflicted upon those that should venture to alter those Securities . With Regard to this present Indictment it is laid different Ways . There are Charges upon the Prisoner at the Bar , that he in Fact did forge and alter this . It is likewise laid, that he did vend and sell the Ticket so alter'd and forg'd, as there are various Accounts in the Indictment. If we shall either shew to you that the Prisoner himself actually forg'd, or which is the same Thing, the same in its Consequences, he sold this Lottery Ticket knowing it to be counterfeit, the Offence will be the same . To prove that he actually forg'd this himself, it may be a difficult Matter, or to produce any Person that was present when he did. Gentlemen, you'll consider, that Forgeries are Works of a very dark Nature; but really the Evidence we shall lay before you, will amount , in my humble Apprehension, to a demonstrative Proof, that the Prisoner at the Bar was the Person who was actually guilty of altering this Ticket himself. Tho' supposing it does not come up to that, our Evidences will shew, that he did actually sell this Ticket so alter'd , knowing it to be so forg'd. Gentlemen , I think in order to find the Prisoner Guilty, there will be three Things to prove to you: First, That this was a forg'd, alter'd, counterfeit Ticket. This is the first Fact I shall lay before you. The next Thing , in order to bring it home to the Prisoner at the Bar, will be to shew you, that this Ticket so altered, counterfeited and forged , was sold by him to a Person at Hazard's Lottery-Office . The Third, that he knew it to be counterfeited and alter'd; or, which will amount to the same Thing, that he actually forg'd it himself. Gentlemen, I believe I shall be able to prove all these Things to you strictly and demonstratively. Gentlemen, the Method in which I propose to lay this Evidence before you, will be in the first Place to shew you, that the Ticket is in Fact an alter'd, counterfeit, not a true Ticket. In order to shew that, it may be necessary to observe to you the Manner of making out these Lottery Tickets. 'Tis directed, that there shall be a Book made, and that in that Book there shall be three Columns. I shall first mention to you the Columns, then the Reason. The Act of Parliament directs, that the Book shall be divided into three Columns, the middle Column is to be the Ticket, which is to be sold and dispos'd off to the Proprietor of the Lottery. The outside is to be given to the Adventurer. The Ticket next to that goes into the Wheel, but between them there are Flourishes, and those Flourishes must exactly agree. Further, at the End of the other Ticket there is another Flourish, which, when the Party comes to the Government to receive the Prize, supposing it to be a Prize, 'tis check'd with a Flourish remaining upon the Back; and if it does not agree with it, 'tis clear 'tis a Forgery. I don't think the Wisdom of Man could have invented a greater Method of certain Security, than having these particular Flourishes, so divided by a Pair of Scissars. Then, Gentlemen, let us consider , whether this Ticket deserves the Name of a true genuine Ticket; or, whether it deserves the Name of a counterfeit or forged Ticket. Upon the Face of the Ticket itself, we shall produce the Purport to be of Number 19165; that Purport is upon the Face of it. But Gentlemen, we shall shew to you these Tickets, as sign'd by Mr. Hans, who is the proper Officer for signing Tickets. We shall shew you this Number 105 is not the Ticket it was at the Time it was made out, but it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260032"></xptr> has been alter'd and counterfeited; and the Method is this; that it is not the Number 19105, but that it was a Ticket number'd 19165, so the Alteration that had been made in this Ticket, is by taking off the Top of the 6, the Bottom of the 6 remaining as a 0 , which will reduce the Number to 19105. To shew you this has been so, we have a Book from the Office here, and by comparing this Ticket with the Book of the Office, from which it was cut, do exactly tally ; the Flourish on this Ticket and the Flourish in the Lottery-Office Book do exactly tally with Number 19165. This proves that this Ticket must have borne Number 19165. To go further, that this could not be the original Ticket, the real Number of which was 19165; because comparing it with the Check of that Number, it entirely disagrees with it. This will plainly shew to you that this Ticket we now produce to you, is not the Ticket first deliver'd out. Gentlemen, there is likewise another Thing pretty plain here, that this could not be the original Ticket, because the Number 19105, it seems, the real Ticket, bearing Date 19105, has come to the Office to be claim'd, and that Ticket does exactly tally with its proper Number.</p>

               <p>The second Part will be more particular to your Consideration, which relates to the Prisoner at the Bar, that is, to bring home to him. The second Point will be to shew that the Prisoner at the Bar sold this very Ticket, now purporting to bear the Number 19, 105, and which will prove to you, that he sold the Ticket for 20 l. and it may not be improper to suggest to you the Reason the Person may have to alter the Number; 19, 165 was drawn a Blank, the Number 19, 105 was drawn a Prize, 20 l. If a Man by his Ingenuity, instead of being the Proprietor of a Blank, he was then entitled to a Prize of 20 l. We shall prove that the Prisoner brought this Ticket to Hazard's Lottery-Office as a Prize of 20 l. But, Gentlemen, there is a Step further we must go, and that is, to induce you to be of Opinion, that the Prisoner at the Bar, when he sold this Ticket, knew it not to be a real genuine Ticket; but that he either alter'd it himself with his own Hand, or he knew it to be alter'd by some other Person; and, Gentlemen, in Things of this Kind, as I mention'd before it, it is impossible to call any Person who was by at the Time of his forging of it. Would he call any Witness to see him perform it; nor after he had done it, would be in Prudence acquaint any Person that he had done it? Then how is it Persons are ever prov'd guilty of Facts of this Kind, but from Circumstances, if they are strong, clear and plain; such  will convince you that he did know? These are the Things that will be most proper for your Consideration; and, Gentlemen, we think we shall be able to do it.</p>
               <p>I would begin first with laying down one Fact. which shews , in my Opinion, the Wickedness of the Intention of the Prisoner at the Bar; that was this: This Ticket he bought at Wilson's Lottery-Office ; when he came there, he enquir'd for some Lottery Tickets to buy, and enquir'd for Numbers where there were either 6 or 9 in these Numbers: The People with regard to Chances might be superstitious; a plansible Reason he gives why he desir'd Numbers of 6 and 9, was that they were fortunate and lucky Numbers: Gentlemen, I am afraid it will be the Reverse to himself. Gentlemen, if you consider it, it is an easy Thing to take off 6 and make it an o. Thus the 6 and 9, by the Alteration of one of these Numbers, you have twenty-three Chances to one but it comes up a Prize; if you have the Number wherein there is a 6 and 9, keep it, see whether it comes up a Prize or not: If it comes up a Blank, if I will own this Number, in five Numbers suppose 6 and 9 to be among them, according to my Instruction you may have twenty-three Chances, in order to have a Chance of that's coming up a Prize; therefore he shews cum animo, that he applied at Wilson's Office to have a Ticket with a 6 and 9. As Matters of this Nature depend on Circumstances, we must lay all before you, and you must connect them all together. And after some Time that he had bought this Ticket , and it came up a Blank, he went and sold it for a Prize at Mr. Hazard's Lottery-Office. I believe it may be known to you to be pretty usual , when a Ticket is sold for a Prize, that the Owner of the Ticket, or the Person that sells the Ticket, is requir'd to indorse his Name on the Back of the Ticket; accordingly the Prisoner at the Bar was directed so to do when he sold this for a Prize of 20 l. Gentlemen, did he put his Name on the Back of it? No. What was the Name? 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person451">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person451" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person451" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun. How came he with his own Hand to write 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person452">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person452" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person452" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun. when his Name was 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person453">
                  Peter 
                  Mayaffree 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person453" type="surname" value="Mayaffree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person453" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not Wilson? Would a Man, who intended to act fairly, go not to put his true Name, 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person454">
                  Peter 
                  Mayaffree 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person454" type="surname" value="Mayaffree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person454" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and put one 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person455">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person455" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person455" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun.? That to me is an extreme strong Circumstance, that at that Time he was doing what he knew he ought not to do: He must know it was hazardous, dangerous to put his own Name: Had it been not a real good Ticket, he had been conscious to himself, he had been<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260033"></xptr> ashamed and afraid to put his own Name on the Back of it. The unhappy Person at the Bar did do so; instead of putting his own Name, he put 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person456">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person456" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person456" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun . If we make this to be Fact, with this Circumstance alone, which I did not think to do, there is another Circumstance, that at the Time he was charg'd with this Offence, that he himself own'd and acknowledged it. But, Gentlemen, you'll excuse me, however, from not relying singly on that Circumstance of his acknowledging alone ; though, to be sure, it is the strongest Evidence in the World; but to strengthen and corroborate that, we, on the Part of the Crown, think it our Duly to lay before you all the Circumstances. These are the Circumstances we must mention; we don't doubt , when we have laid these before you, but you will think this Ticket before you is forged and alter'd . Gentlemen, the bare selling a Ticket which has been alter'd, is of itself a pretty strong Suspicion upon the Party, at least it throws him upon this Proof. Any Man, indeed, may go into Change-Alley and buy a Ticket alter'd by another Person: But if one does do it, and goes to sell that again, it throws the Proof upon the Party to shew how he came by it. We can shew how this Gentleman came by this Ticket; that it was sold to him at Hazard's Lottery Office . That 19, 105 at Wilson's Lottery Office . As to 19, 105, that was never sold at that Office. So far the Council for the Crown.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner.] 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person457">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person457" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person457" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. Hand.) I think you are one of the Receivers, and appointed to sign the Lottery Tickets. Pray, Sir, look upon that Ticket; Did you sign that Ticket? Is that your Hand-writing ? Did you cut that Ticket out of the Book?</p>
               <p>Hand. No, I did not cut it, but I sign'd it.</p>
               <p>Council, to Mr. Hand. Where did you receive that Parchment?</p>
               <p>Hand. I receiv'd it from the Bank; this was sign'd by the Lords of the Treasury .</p>
               <p>Council, to Mr. Hand. When was it you wrote.</p>
               <p>Hand. The printed Part was all the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it separate, or in the Book?</p>
               <p>Hand. But five of them in a Leaf.</p>
               <p>Q. When you wrote it, it was then in a Book?</p>
               <p>Hand. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the Number, and write the Name so particularly ? Can you venture to swear that the Time you wrote your Name it bore the Number 19, 165 ?</p>
               <p>Hand. No, I do not particularly remember it.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, I suppose you wrote them cursorily as they fall?</p>
               <p>Hand. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is the Book deliver'd to, to sign?</p>
               <p>Hand. We take, perhaps, 10,000 at a Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not possible, in transcribing so many Numbers, that aMan may make aCypher, and forget to put a Top to it?</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Brother, I don't think that is a proper Question to be ask'd.</p>
               <p>Court. Mr. Hand has prov'd that this was an undrawn Ticket of the last Lottery deliver'd out.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Jones, Secretary to the Managers of the Lottery . Produce the Book out of which it was cut. Are you sworn? What is that you have in your Hand?</p>
               <p>Jones. The Book that contains 100 Tickets for the Lottery.</p>
               <p>Council. Be so good as to put this Number to 19, 105, and tell me how it tallies. Does it tally with the Check or not?</p>
               <p>Jones. It does not.</p>
               <p>Council. Now turn it to 19165, tell me how it tallies with that.</p>
               <p>Jones. It tallies with 19165.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you concern'd in the Lottery? I desire to know what is your Opinion, whence that Ticket was cut: Was it cut from 19165?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes. Because the Check agrees to it exactly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person458">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person458" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person458" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (by the Council) I think you told me the Ticket was cut off from 19165. It represents 19105 Do you think it has been alter'd?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes. In taking off the Top of the 6 and altering it to 0.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person459">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person459" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person459" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (by the Court) Are the Numbers printed or written?</p>
               <p>Jones. They are written.</p>
               <p>Council. I think we have sufficiently prov'd that this is a forg'd Ticket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person460">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person460" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person460" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person461">
                  John 
                  Disel 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person461" type="surname" value="Disel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person461" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Disel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy the Lottery Ticket of him?</p>
               <p>Disel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you the Servant of Mr. Hazard, are you not liable to make good any Deficiencies of Contract?</p>
               <p>Disel. No, Sir, I am not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you the Ticket in your Hand?</p>
               <p>Disel. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray did you buy the Ticket of the Prisoner at the Bar? Did you buy it in the Condition it is now? Pray what might you give for it?</p>
               <p>Disel. I gave 15 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he inform you that the Ticket was drawn a Prize? Did you buy it as such?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260034"></xptr>Disel. yes. It prov'd to be such by the Commissioners Prize-Papers.</p>
               <p>Q. And finding that Number to be drawn a Prize of 20 l. you gave him 15 l. for it.</p>
               <p>Disel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray Sir, did you require that he should endorse that Ticket?</p>
               <p>Disel. If they are Prizes, we always do it. If they are Blanks we don't insist upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. And the Prisoner at the Bar did endorse the Ticket. What Name is that endors'd by?</p>
               <p>Disel. 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person462">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person462" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person462" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Jun.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Are you sure it was he, look at him; did you ask him what his Name was ?</p>
               <p>Disel. No, not them, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. You only ask'd him to sign it. Did you ask where he liv'd?</p>
               <p>Disel, No Sir, I have since, but not before.</p>
               <p>Court. There is 20 l. wroce in the Front.</p>
               <p>Disel. That was wrote when I bought it.</p>
               <p>Q. You took it for a real, unalter'd Ticket.</p>
               <p>Disel. I paid 15 l. for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this young Man before?</p>
               <p>Disel. Sir, I have seen his Face before. He came to ask the Price of Blanks and Prizes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first Time you saw him after?</p>
               <p>Disel. I did not see him after, 'till I took him the 12th of January.</p>
               <p>Q. You took him, did you: What did you say to him?</p>
               <p>Disel. I took him skaiting on the Canal. Pull'd off my Hat to him, and said, I knew him; I ask'd him whether he did not remember selling a Ticket, a 20 l. Prize, I ask'd him his Name. He told me his Name was Wilson.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Did he tell you where he bought the Ticket?</p>
               <p>Disel. He said, at Wilson's Office.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any Thing to him at that Time about altering of it ?</p>
               <p>Disel. I did say to him, I believ'd it had been alter'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person463">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person463" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person463" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person464">
                  John 
                  Branch 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person464" type="surname" value="Branch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person464" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) You belong to Mr. Wilson?</p>
               <p>Branch. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of the Prisoner's coming to Mr. Wilson's to buy any Tickets?</p>
               <p>Branch. I can't be positive as to the Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come to purchase any Tickets before the Drawing? Did he, when he came to your House, purchase any Tickets?</p>
               <p>Branch. He purchas'd eight Tickets.</p>
               <p>Q. I desire to know of you, whether the Number 19,165 was the Number sold at your Office?</p>
               <p>Branch. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, Sir, when that Number 19,165 was sold at your Office, did it purport upon the Face of it to bear that Number? Was 19,105 ever sold at your Office? Are you sure that the Ticket 19,165 was sold at your Office? And the Time it was sold did it purport to bear that Number? Have you seen the Prisoner at the Bar any Time before now?</p>
               <p>Branch. I have seen him at our Office, I believe, twice, and never saw him after, 'till I saw him at the Constable's House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person465">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person465" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person465" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (for the Crown) You are positive that 19,165 was sold at your Office, and I think you are as positive that the Number 19,105 was not sold at your Office?</p>
               <p>Branch. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person466">
                  George 
                  Bret 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person466" type="surname" value="Bret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person466" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know this to be the Ticket I took out of the Office, which I suspected to be counterfeit, being cut away at the Top.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person467">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person467" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person467" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Bret) Look upon the Prisoner. Was you by the Prisoner at the Time he was apprehended? What Name did he answer to?</p>
               <p>Bret. I ask'd my Servant , whether that was the Gentleman of whom he bought the Ticket? And I ask'd the Prisoner, whether his Name was 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person468">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person468" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person468" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun. He said it was. After he came to our Office, I fetch'd the Ticket down Stairs to him, ask'd him, whether this was the Ticket he sold to my Servant? I ask'd him, whether it was his writing? He said it was his Hand-Writing and Name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person469">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person469" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person469" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person470">
                  Francis 
                  Jackman 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person470" type="surname" value="Jackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person470" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you live at Hazard's Lottery-Office?</p>
               <p>Jackman. I live at Charing-cross .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by at the Time the Prisoner was apprehended ?</p>
               <p>Jackman. Yes Sir; but was not near enough to see his Face.</p>
               <p>Q. Now, I desire to know what Name he would have gone by at that Time?</p>
               <p>Jackman. Mr. Bret fetch'd down the Ticket, and shew'd him the Writing, and he acknowledgld it was his own Hand-Writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person471">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person471" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person471" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person472">
                  John 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person472" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person472" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable) Was you by at the Time the Prisoner was apprehended?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I was charg'd by Mr. Bret.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, who belongs to that Office at Charing-cross ?</p>
               <p>Bret. Mr. Hazard and I, and one Mr. Baraway.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person473">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person473" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person473" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Constable) What was you charg'd with the Prisoner for?</p>
               <p>Constable. I was charg'd with him for counterfeiting a Lottery-Ticket. The Time he was in my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260035"></xptr> Custody, he own'd that that was his Hand-Writing. That was all that I heard him say.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner . If your Lordship will favour me upon this Act of Parliament in Point of Law - Now my Brother says that he has done - And if he has done, I apprehend clearly upon the Construction of this Act of Parliament, that your Lordship must direct the Prisoner to be immediately acquitted. This Indictment consists of eight several Accounts. Notwithstanding the fair Admonition they had to put it in a proper Way, if they could have done it, they have, with great Submission to the Court, in Point of Law, fail'd. My Lord, it is a new Prosecution, and founded upon a new Act of Parliament. Nor would I be understood by any Thing that may drop from me, in the least to encourage or cotennances the smallest Attempt to impose upon the Publick. My Brother will own, that I did desire last Sessions that this young Gentleman might be continued, on the Account of their failing in their Indictment then. I apprehend the same Objection still remains that was then debated, to be essentially necessary to the contributing to this Crime, which seems now to be defective, both upon the Face of the Indictment, and Appearance of the Evidence, that stands upon it. In the first Place, upon the Face of the Indictment, it was clearly determin'd by the Court, and upon the b est Reasons, that they fail'd for want of laying it in the Indictment. That this must be to defraud some Person or another; because any person living might take it and cut it to Pieces, and make what Alteration in it he pleased, provided he did it without an Intention to defraud any Person whatsoever; and this very Statute and very Clause, that authorises this Prosecution, seems to vindicate this Thing, and quote a proper Method for a Determination of it. First, whether this is a real or proper Ticket or not. I must confess that the Evidence that is given, never desires to carry it any further than the Law will bear. Here has been a Ticket that does not tally with these Books. My Brother talk'd of producing the real and true, that purports the Number, which this is alter'd to, which was actually, and bona side , entitled to this Prize. If it did come up a Prize. He says he had it; he should have produced it. Now if he had the Ticket, and do not produce it, tho' he suggests there is such a Ticket, as that, they are bound on their Oaths not to believe it; whatsoever Alteration there is in this Ticket produced in Point of Law, whether by Design or Accident must be reckon'd a real Ticket, unless they could have prov'd that any Person did actually alter it. And it seems to be calculated, upon reading this whole Clause, that the Legislature has determin'd, before there shall be a criminal Prosecution, that there shall be a thorough Examination into the Matter; therefore, your Lordship will please to observe, how the Statute has determin'd this Thing. Here is a Dispute between the Number of two Tickets. If this Ticket has been alter'd from 19165 to 19105, the Contest must arise, who is entitled to the Prize of the real Number, or the Owner and Proprietor of this alter'd Ticket, that imports at present to bear this Number; therefore, they should have gone to the Commissioners and Managers to adjust this, before the Prosecution could have been set on Foot [some Clanses in the Act of Parliament were read]. Next Place it says, if any Dispute should arise - Here is a Contention and a Dispute; the Contention is, whether this Number now importing 19105, which they say is alter'd; or whether the Ticket 19165 is the real Benefit Ticket. This must invariably be, I apprehend in Point of Reason and Point of Law, between the Proprietor of the real Ticket and the Owner of this Ticket.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Veaw. What do you know of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Veaw. He was in our Compting-House ever since he was eight Years old. He behav'd honourably and well.</p>
               <p>Q. Who has he liv'd with here in England?</p>
               <p>Veaw. A Jeweller in Tavistock-Street. I never heard but he behav'd in every thing well: That is the Character he has had all along; and he was entrusted with Jewels?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of your own Knowledge that he has been entrusted with Jewels?</p>
               <p>Veaw. He has been at my Compting-House, sent by his Uncle; and I know he has always done well.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, Sir, how old may he be?</p>
               <p>Veaw. About seventeen Years.</p>
               <p>Q. When in Holland he was put into the Compting-House , at eight or nine Years of Age? When he came into England he was about eleven Years of Age? You remember him in the Compting-House in Holland?</p>
               <p>Veaw. Yes, in my own Compting-House.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he in your Compting-House?</p>
               <p>Veaw. He was there above half a Year .</p>
               <p>Q. Now give me Leave to ask you , how you came over to England?</p>
               <p>Veaw. I have liv'd in England almost nine Years, backwards and Forwards .</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before you came over the first Time, or afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Veaw. Afterwards, when I went over again.</p>
               <p>Q. You say in your Compting-House : Was he there entrusted with large Sums of Money? Do<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260036"></xptr> you commonly trust Boys with large Sums of Money?</p>

               <p>Veaw. What large Sums they can pay in Silver.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person474">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person474" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person474" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mayaffree) How long has this young Man liv'd with you?</p>
               <p>Mayaffree. Six Years.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Manner has he behav'd?</p>
               <p>Mayaffree. Very well. I have entrusted him several Times with 2 or 3000 l. value.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he had the Command of Money, upon your Oath, has he not defrauded or cheated you?</p>
               <p>Mayaffree. Not of one Farthing. A very honest sober Person, every Body lov'd him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person475">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person475" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person475" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-36-person476">
                  William 
                  Joslin 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person476" type="surname" value="Joslin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person476" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Joslin . Three or four Years. He always had a good Character, Sometimes he has brought Jewels to our House from his Uncle, of a considerable Value. I have always heard a fair Character of him. I was never more surpris'd than to hear of of this Indictment laid against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-36-person477">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-36-person477" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-36-person477" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Parquot) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Parquot. I have known him a great While. I know him to be an honest, sober Lad.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that he is a Man that would be guilty of such a Crime as this?</p>
               <p>Parquot. I was astonish'd when I heard such a Thing of him.</p>
               <p>Several other reputable Persons appear'd in Behalf of the Prisoner, and gave him a good Character.</p>
               <rs id="t17460226-36-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                  <interp inst="t17460226-36-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460226-36-verdict128" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
            
                  <p>Guilty <rs id="t17460226-36-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17460226-36-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-36-defend450 t17460226-36-punish129"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>.</p>
                  <p>His Lordship in the Conclusion of his Charge, to the Jury, desir'd them to take into some Consideration , the Character, which gives some Weight in Cases of a doubtful Nature.</p>
                  <p>The Jury on Account of his excellent Character and tender Years, recommended him to his Majesty's Mercy.</p>
            
               </rs>
            </div1>
