<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-16">
               <interp inst="t17400903-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-16" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-16" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-16-off101-c119" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-defend139 t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>380. + 
               <persName id="t17400903-16-defend139" type="defendantName">
                  George 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17400903-16-defend139" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-defend139" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-defend139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-16-defloc100">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-defloc100" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-defloc100" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-defend139 t17400903-16-defloc100"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-16-off101" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-off101" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-off101" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17400903-16-victim140" type="victimName">
                        William 
                        Martin 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-victim140" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-16-victim140" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-16-victim140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-victim140"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him 2 s. and 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400903-16-cd102" type="crimeDate">July 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-cd102"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. On Thursday the 10th of July, between the Hours of 2 and 3 in the Afternoon, in going from Bonner's-Hall to Old-Ford, I was attacked in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400903-16-crimeloc103">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc103" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc103" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-crimeloc103"></join> , by the Prisoner at the Bar. I was in my Chaise, by myself, in the Highway, - the Road that leads from <placeName id="t17400903-16-crimeloc104">Bethnal-Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc104" type="placeName" value="Bethnal-Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc104" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-crimeloc104"></join> to <placeName id="t17400903-16-crimeloc105">Old Ford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc105" type="placeName" value="Old Ford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-16-crimeloc105" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-off101 t17400903-16-crimeloc105"></join>. I am sure the Prisoner is the Man: He was on Foot, and crossing the Way suddenly, he catch'd hold of the Horse's Reins, and presenting a Pistol, he demanded my Money. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030015"></xptr> drove the Horse myself, and being alone, I was somewhat startled at such an unexpected Visit, at that Time of the Day; and I had some Things of Value about me, which I forgot in a Hurry of Business to leave behind me. However, observing some People at a Distance, at Work in a Pea-field, and imagining he had not seen them, (for I believe they were about 40 or 50 Yards off,) I thought proper to acquaint him with it, in Hopes of deterring him from prosecuting his Design, or else that I might watch an Opportunity to jump out of the Chaise, and defend myself. So I stood up in the Chaise, and asked him how he could be so impudent as to rob me, in sight of so many People? And I held out my Hand at the same Time, hoping they would come to my Assistance; but being disappointed of that, as he kept his Pistol at my Head, and as my Life was at his Mercy, I thought the safest Way was to sit down, and in some Measure to comply with his Demand. Therefore putting my Hand into my Pocket, I pull'd out some Money and gave him, which I afterwards found, a Halfcrown and a Halfpenny: for my Glove being on, I could not get my Hand to the Bottom of my Pocket, and I did not care to pull it off, lest I should discover a Mourning-Ring of more Value. But instead of asking me for more Money, he immediately demanded my Watch, which I had been so careful of concealing, that I imagined he had not seen it; for I had tuck'd the Chain into my Pocket, and endeavoured to hide it: therefore, not imagining he had seen it, I deny'd that I had one. He still insisted upon it that I had one, and upon my finding that I could not escape without being plundered, I resolved to attempt jumping out of the Chaise; but before I could compleat my Design, he left the Horse's Head where he stood, and crouching under the Horse's Head, he advanced nearer to me, and altered the Position of his Hand as he advanced: and at last (with the utmost Cruelty) he snapp'd his Pistol at me. It happened, that it only flashed in the Pan; and when I saw that, I jump'd out of the Chaise immediately, on the same Side the Prisoner stood. He ran away; I ran after him with my Whip in my Hand; and when I had pursued him about 30 Yards, he turned and presented his Pistol at me, with the same Menaces as before. I was not certain what Number of Pistols he might have about him, so seeing a Brickbat, I stooped down and catched it up to defend myself; and as he stood, I flung it at him, and very narrowly missed him. Upon this, he immediately turned Tail again, and I made after him. Now I was satisfy'd he had no more Pistols about him; so I kept shouting out, - Now I have you! - You have no more Pistols! He, upon this, made up to a Field, and I briskly made up to him, and finding he began to give out, I struck him with the But-end of my Whip, on the hind-part of his Head, and repeated my Blows, which made him turn about again upon me. But some how or other I lam'd his Right-hand with a Blow; and then I flew at him, and wrenched the Pistol out of his Hand, upon which he immediately cried out - he would surrender. This is the Pistol I took from him; the Bullet is in it, - but the Flint is taken out, and the Touch-hole is plugg'd up. By this Time a Person on Horseback, who was in the Field where I saw other Men at Work, came up to me, and he went with me to Bethnal-Green ; but being informed the Gentlemen in the Commission were gone to Hackney, we carry'd the Prisoner before Mr Justice Selman, at Old-Ford, who was so kind as to take his Examination and Confession, which is now in Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-16-person141">
                  Samuel 
                  Sadler 
               <interp inst="t17400903-16-person141" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-person141" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to Mr Selman ; but I was not present at the Time he took this Examination. Mr Martin will prove the Prisoner's signing it, and I will prove Mr Selman's Hand.</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. I heard it read over to him, and saw him sign it. I think, - and to the best of my Remembrance, - I saw Mr Selman sign it, but I cannot positively charge my Memory with that.</p>
               <p>Mr Sadler proved Mr Justice Selman's Hand. The Prisoner's Examination was read; which was to the following Purport.</p>
               <p>'' The Examination of George White, taken this '' 10th Day of July 1740.</p>
               <p>'' Who being charged by William Martin, of '' Shadwell , <rs id="t17400903-16-viclabel106" type="occupation">Surgeon</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-victim140 t17400903-16-viclabel106"></join>, with stopping him on 
the '' Road, leading from Bethnal Green to Old-Ford, '' and taking from him two Shillings and Six-pence '' Halfpenny; confesseth, that he stopped him, '' and took the above-mentioned Sum from him, '' and that he voluntarily subscribeth this Confession.''</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I resign myself up to your Lordship's Honour and Pleasure; and as it was through Poverty I did it, I hope for Transportation.</p>


               <p>Mr Martin. There was a Gentleman so unfortunate, as to be shot into the Face, with 2 Sluggs, but a few Days before, by this very Man. <rs id="t17400903-16-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400903-16-punish108" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-16-punish108" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-16-defend139 t17400903-16-punish108"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
