<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410828-18">
               <interp inst="t17410828-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-18" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410828"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-18" type="date" value="17410828"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410828-18-off97-c95" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-defend133 t17410828-18-off97 t17410828-18-verdict103"></join>
         
               <p>21. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410828-18-defend133" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Moulds 
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-defend133" type="surname" value="Moulds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-defend133" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-defend133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17410828-18-defloc95">St. Mary Rotherhith</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-defloc95" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Rotherhith"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-defloc95" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-defend133 t17410828-18-defloc95"></join>, <rs id="t17410828-18-deflabel96" type="occupation">mariner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-defend133 t17410828-18-deflabel96"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17410828-18-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he not having the fear of God before his eyes, &amp;c. and contriving and intending one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410828-18-victim135" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Stone 
                        <interp inst="t17410828-18-victim135" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410828-18-victim135" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410828-18-victim135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-off97 t17410828-18-victim135"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   to kill and murder, on the <rs id="t17410828-18-cd98" type="crimeDate">3d of July in the 10th year of his majesty's reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-off97 t17410828-18-cd98"></join>, a great quantity of liquid laudanum, being deadly poison, into a certain liquor called flip, did put and mix, he well knowing the same to be poison, and afterwards that he the said Moulds the poison aforesaid, so mixed, &amp;c. to him the said Stone did give and cause to be given, to drink and swallow down: And afterwards he the said Stone the said poison by the procurement of him the said Moulds did drink and swallow down, whereupon he the said Stone by the poison aforesaid, so as aforesaid taken was render'd sick and distemper'd, of which sickness, &amp;c. from the said 3d to the 5th of July he languish'd and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The counsel for the king having opened the indictment, and the nature of the evidence, the witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-18-person136">
                  Robert 
                  Stimpson 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person136" type="surname" value="Stimpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person136" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was boatswain of the <placeName id="t17410828-18-crimeloc99">ship Samuel and Rebecca</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="ship Samuel and Rebecca"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-off97 t17410828-18-crimeloc99"></join>, and the Prisoner was <rs id="t17410828-18-deflabel100" type="occupation">chief mate</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-defend133 t17410828-18-deflabel100"></join>.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. I had known him about a year and half before this happen'd; I was on board with him, and the ship was just come from Norway to this port of London, laden with deals.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Do you remember 
               <persName id="t17410828-18-person137">
                  Edward 
                  Stone 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person137" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person137" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. Yes, he was a <rs id="t17410828-18-viclabel101" type="occupation">custom-house officer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-victim135 t17410828-18-viclabel101"></join>, and was put on board us at Gravesend, and came up with the ship to <placeName id="t17410828-18-crimeloc102">Hanover Hole</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-crimeloc102" type="placeName" value="Hanover Hole"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-18-crimeloc102" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-18-off97 t17410828-18-crimeloc102"></join>, where we cast anchor.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How long had the ship been here before he went on shore?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. It might be about 5 or 6 days, and I heard that he was very sick with drinking some flip when he went on shore.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Do you know any thing of the making this slip?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. Yes, Sir, I made it my self by the Prisoner's directions.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Can you remember what you put into it?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. There was beer, sugar, and brandy, and he told me what I must put into it was the same as limons.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Why did you put any thing else into it?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. Yes, Sir, the prisoner gave me a phial of stuff to put into it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How much might there be in the phial?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. To the best of my remembrance there was about a small dram-glass full.</p>
               <p>Counsel. What colour was it?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. It was of a reddish colour, and the Prisoner told me it was of the same nature as limons, but I did not taste it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you taste the flip?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. Yes, I drank twice, and it made me vomit very much; and I think it had a sort of bitter taste. - It did not taste sour at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did you drink of it?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. I might drink better than a gill, but I don't think I drank half a pint of it. We had about 3 pints in the whole.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Who drank of it besides you?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. There was one Davy, another officer, and 2 or 3 more belonging to the ship drank of it; and I afterwards saw Davy vomiting in the hold.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174108280008"></xptr>Q. Were any of the persons that you saw drink of it quite well afterwards?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. There was the maid on board the ship ask'd me to let her drink of it, and I never heard her complain.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the liquor in the phial been put into it when she drank?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. About a minute or two, and I had not stirr'd it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How came you to know that the stuff in this phial was laudanum?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. I never heard that it was; but to be sure it was something of detriment. I told the Prisoner when I was in Yarmouth goal, that it was something more than ordinary; and he said that Alexander, one of the foremast men, went on shore for it and gave it him, and he told me I need not give my information so strong. He said it was a sleeping dose, since I have been in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Do you think if this flip had been made in the usual manner it would have had this effect?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How came you to get to Yarmouth immediately after the death of Stone?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. Mr. Foster the surveyor came on board and examined me in the cabbin about this; and when I came out of the cabbin, the Prisoner bid me go on shore, or else I should come into trouble; and when I came on shore I saw Stone on the half deck by the main shrouds vomiting, but I can't tell whether he drank of the flip or not.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How long after the people had been drinking this liquor, did you see Stone?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. About 3 hours and a quarter: He was then awake, and was walking sore and ast on the deck.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Had you any discourse with the Prisoner after Stone died?</p>
               <p>Stimpson. He told me an officer was dead, and that it was reported that capt. Cox's people had been the occasion of his death; and so by his persuasion I went down to Yarmouth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-18-person138">
                  Thomas 
                  Davy 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person138" type="surname" value="Davy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person138" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and the deceased were officers of the customs on board this ship. On saturday between 3 and 4 o'clock in the afternoon, Banks alias Vanderbank, a one-eyed man, brought the cann of flip down and recommended it to 
               <persName id="t17410828-18-person139">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person139" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person139" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one of the King's watermen, and he drank of it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Did Banks drink of it himself?</p>
               <p>Davy. I saw him put the cann to his mouth, and he said, Mr. Ross my service to you; but he did not seem to have his lips wet.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was there any complaint of an ill taste that it had?</p>
               <p>Davy. Yes, it had an ill taste and an ill smell too.</p>
               <p>Counsel. What sort of a taste had it?</p>
               <p>Davy. A sort of a spicey taste. I drank about a coffee cup full, and it work'd upon me as if my dinner did not fit well, and I call'd for some small beer; that made me vomit, and I continued drinking and vomiting 'till 10 o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>Counsel. If this liquor had been honestly made do you think it would have troubled you?</p>
               <p>Davy. No, if it had not been intoxicated with any thing.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How long did you st ay on board?</p>
               <p>Davy. '
               <persName id="t17410828-18-person140">
                  Till 
                  Mr 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person140" type="surname" value="Mr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person140" type="given" value="Till"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Foster came, and then we found the brandy which was conceal'd in half anchors.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say that Stone drank any?</p>
               <p>Davy. No; but after the people in the hold had drank of it, it was sent up to him on deck.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-18-person141">
                  Martha 
                  Chandler 
               <interp inst="t17410828-18-person141" type="surname" value="Chandler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person141" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drank of this flip before the brandy was put in, and it did me no hurt at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this Stone?</p>
               <p>Chandler. Yes, very well, and I saw him drink of it, but I can't tell what quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought it to him?</p>
               <p>Chandler. I can't tell. The officers and all the ships crew were together in the hold.</p>
               <p>Q. Who drank besides Stone?</p>
               <p>Chandler. Stimpson and Banks. One Gardiner who was cook of the ship told me he drank a pint and half of it, and he was very sick after it, for (he said) he drank the bottom of it, and stirr'd it up with his knife.</p>
               <p>No other evidence being offer'd to support the charge, the Prisoner was <rs id="t17410828-18-verdict103" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-18-verdict103" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
