<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-10">
               <interp inst="t17471014-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-10" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-10" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-10-off45-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-10-defend164 t17471014-10-off45 t17471014-10-verdict47"></join>
         
               <p>387. 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-defend164" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Butcher 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-10-defend164" type="surname" value="Butcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-defend164" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-defend164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17471014-10-off45" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-off45" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-off45" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing, on the <rs id="t17471014-10-cd46" type="crimeDate">24th of Sept</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-10-off45 t17471014-10-cd46"></join>. eleven Yards of Long Lawn value 15 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-victim166" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Hainsworth 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim166" type="surname" value="Hainsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim166" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-victim168" type="victimName">
                     Obadiah 
                     Kemp 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim168" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim168" type="given" value="Obadiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-victim168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>Kemp. I live at Tower-hill; I lost a Remnant of Long Lawn the 24th of Sept. last.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the Day did you lost it?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I can't say directly the time, but I believe it was about two o'Clock; there were two People came into my Shop; I have seen the Prisoner several times, and the Person that was with her, as far as I know, upon the same Errand; while I was stepp'd aside, to change some Money for a Neighbour, in the interim, I apprehend, this Person conveyed this Remnant of Lawn under her Cloke; when I came back from the Cash, she was not gone; I received from her, and her Companion, two or three Shillings for Goods that they bought; my young Man was on the Stairs looking over them; he goes to the Desk and writes me a Line, that the young Woman, the Prisoner, had taken something from the Counter, or out of the Window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where she put it?</p>
               <p>Kemp. He said it was in her Pocket, or under her Cloke; when they paid me, I let them go out of the Shop, and I said, are you sure they have stole any thing? He said, I am positive they have; upon that I called her, and she came back.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search her?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I got her into the Shop, and she dropp'd the Lawn at the Door; I did not see her drop it myself; I charged her with taking of it; she seemed at first to deny it, but afterwards confess'd it, and hop'd I would forgive her; she acknowledged she did take it, before several People, and this 
               <persName id="t17471014-10-person169">
                  Lawn 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17471014-10-person169" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person169" type="given" value="Lawn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person169" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             know to be my Property, but I can't swear I saw her take it; or see her drop it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Gentlemen says it was Noon, when it was Evening.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-person170">
                  John 
                  Lassen 
               <interp inst="t17471014-10-person170" type="surname" value="Lassen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person170" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr Kemp; I stood upon the Stairs and watched her, and saw her take it and put it under her Clothes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her go out of the Shop?</p>
               <p>Lassen. Yes, my Lord, and I ran after her and call'd her back. She seem'd to feel in her Pocket, as she came along, as if she had a Mind to drop it, but I did not see her. She at first deny'd it, but she afterwards seem'd to own it, but said, if he would forgive her would never play such Tricks afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-person171">
                  Hannah 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17471014-10-person171" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person171" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not see the Prisoner take any Thing, but I saw her drop something; I thought it was an Handkerchief; I am sensible it was her that dropp'd it. I took it up and gave it to Mr Kemp. She dropp'd it upon the Step going in at the Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I came back I said, you may search me, if you please. He said, if I would pay him for the Long Lawn he would discharge me,</p>
               <p>Kemp. I said, if you would give me an Account of the Long Lawn that was stole by your Partner, that cost me 4 l I would discharge you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-10-person172">
                  William 
                  Gould 
               <interp inst="t17471014-10-person172" type="surname" value="Gould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person172" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have known the Prisoner fourteen or fifteen Years; she always liv'd with her Father, who is a Waterman, and she has always had an honest Character. She has been at my House divers of Times, and a Month at a Time, and I never miss'd any Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Gould. I am a Goldsmith in Foster-lane.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-10-verdict47" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-verdict47" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-verdict47" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty to the Value of 10 d
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-10-punish48" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-punish48" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-10-punish48" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-10-defend164 t17471014-10-punish48"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
