<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410514-3">
               <interp inst="t17410514-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-3" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-3" type="date" value="17410514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410514-3-off12-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-3-defend44 t17410514-3-off12 t17410514-3-verdict15"></join>
         
               <p>3. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-defend44" type="defendantName">
                     Josiah 
                     Dard 
                  <interp inst="t17410514-3-defend44" type="surname" value="Dard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-defend44" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-defend44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17410514-3-defloc11">St. Dunstan in the West</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-3-defloc11" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan in the West"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-3-defloc11" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-3-defend44 t17410514-3-defloc11"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410514-3-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17410514-3-victim45" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Wall 
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-victim45" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-3-victim45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-3-victim45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-3-off12 t17410514-3-victim45"></join>
                     </persName>
                    with a certain Stick, in a certain Yard, or open Place called <placeName id="t17410514-3-crimeloc13">Bell-Yard</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-crimeloc13" type="placeName" value="Bell-Yard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-crimeloc13" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-3-off12 t17410514-3-crimeloc13"></join>, being the King's High-way; putting him in Fear &amp;c. and in a forcible and violent Manner demanding his Money, with Intent the same to steal &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17410514-3-cd14" type="crimeDate">April 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-3-off12 t17410514-3-cd14"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Wall. On Saturday the 11th of April, I had Business which called me out into the City to several Places, where I staid 'till between one and two o'Clock in the Morning, and as I was going past the end of Salisbury-Court in Fleet-street , in my way<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174105140003"></xptr> Home, I met 3 Persons who seemed to stand in a Conference together: I passed them, and when I came to Fetter-Lane, I found myself by them again, and presently the Prisoner was even with me. I turn'd up Bell-Yard as my nearest way Home; the Prisoner followed me, and we went together 'till we came very near the Top of the Yard; then he catched hold of my Coat with one Hand, and with the other he pulled a short Stick out of his Bosom, and with Imprecations demanded my Money. Immediately he fell on me with his Stick and repeated his Blows so fast on me, that if he had not held me up by my Coat, I must have fallen to the Ground. Upon this I cryed out Watch! but none being near , I seized him myself and then he cried out a Sodomite, but some People coming to my Assistance, we were both secured and sent to Prison together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person46">
                  John 
                  Tenant 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person46" type="surname" value="Tenant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Watchman in St. Clement's Parish, and hearing Watch called several Times, I turned out of great Sheer Lane to see what was the the Matter , and then I saw much such a Man as the Prisoner lying over the Prosecutor with a short Stick: I asked him why he did so, and the Man said the Prosecutor was a Sodomite, and still kept beating him with his Stick, and in a few Minutes the Stick was found on the Ground. Upon this I laid hold of the Man, and when he found that I was going to take him away, he charged me with the Prosecutor, and I delivered them both to a Watch-man belonging to the Roll's Liberty and went back to my Stand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Did the Prosecutor at that Time say that I attempted to rob him ?</p>
               <p>Tenant. No, he desired the Prisoner might be stopped, but I heard nothing of a Robbery.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE .</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I had been drinking in the Stand, and turned up Bell Yard in order to go Home: this Man met me, and we jostled together ; upon which he pulled out a Stick and knocked me down several Times, and the Constable coming up, asked me what I had lost ? I told him my Wig, and insisted on Satisfaction for it, but he would not give me any, and so we were both committed to Prison together. He knocked me down several Times, and I am sure he is put upon this Prosecution for the Sake of the Reward*.</p>
               <p>* There is no Reward at all in Cases of this Nature.</p>
               <p>Tenant . The Prisoner did not say that the Prosecutor had struck him, neither did he charge him with his Wig.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person47">
                  Mary 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person47" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person47" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner several Years, and never heard any Thing unhandsom of him in my Life. His Father is a Picture Frame maker, and he has follow'd that Business 'till this Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person48">
                  William 
                  Drawwater 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person48" type="surname" value="Drawwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him a great many Years, and never heard an ill Character of him in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person49">
                  Hugh 
                  Latham 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person49" type="surname" value="Latham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person49" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him several Years, and never heard any Ill of him in my Life.</p>
               <p>Will. Rogers. I live within 3 or 4 Doors of him, and never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person50">
                  Thomas 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person50" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person50" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been in Company with him and his Father, and never heard any Thing amiss of him .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person51">
                  Thomas 
                  Arrowsmith 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person51" type="surname" value="Arrowsmith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him from a Child , and never heard but that he behaved himself with a great deal of Honesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-3-person52">
                  Robert 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17410514-3-person52" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person52" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his Father, and have intrusted him to deal for me, and he has always brought me my Money honestly. <rs id="t17410514-3-verdict15" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-3-verdict15" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
