<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490405-22">
               <interp inst="t17490405-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-22" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-22" type="date" value="17490405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490405-22-off108-c121" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-defend161 t17490405-22-off108 t17490405-22-verdict112"></join>
         
               <p>264. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490405-22-defend161" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Maclocklin 
                  <interp inst="t17490405-22-defend161" type="surname" value="Maclocklin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-defend161" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-defend161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17490405-22-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490405-22-victim163" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Tribe 
                        <interp inst="t17490405-22-victim163" type="surname" value="Tribe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-22-victim163" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-22-victim163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-off108 t17490405-22-victim163"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's high-way, of one silver watch, val. 10 s. one pair of silver shoebuckles , val. 5 s. one guinea in gold, and 16 s. in silver
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490405-22-cd109" type="crimeDate">Mar. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-off108 t17490405-22-cd109"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-22-person164">
                  Benj 
                  Tribe 
               <interp inst="t17490405-22-person164" type="surname" value="Tribe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person164" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep the three Tuns at Bow, I had been at London about my wine licence, going home I took 
               <persName id="t17490405-22-person165">
                  Archibald 
                  Forister 
               <interp inst="t17490405-22-person165" type="surname" value="Forister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person165" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the watchman at <placeName id="t17490405-22-crimeloc110">Mile end</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-22-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="Mile end"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-22-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-off108 t17490405-22-crimeloc110"></join> to light me home; the prisoner at the Bar met us about eleven o'clock at night, he had two more with him; they first came up and ask'd the watchman the way to White-chappel, the two came and look'd full in my face, and ask'd the same; we were both turned with our<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050010"></xptr> faces towards London, directing them, the third person came up behind me and gave me a blow on my shoulder, and a little trip on my heel, so that I fell against the bank; he put his left arm upon my throat to keep me from making a noise; I said, What is the matter? What do you want, friend? says he, your money you dog! he began to grabble in my right-hand pocket; but my right-hand being a little lame, I put my money on my left side: in this time the watchman was knock'd down and his light put out, he was crying out for mercy, there were two upon him: he knowing the prisoner at the Bar, inadvertently said, Macklocklin , I did not use you so when I had you two days and a night in custody for knocking a man down, and when I lent you my hat to go before the Justice; he speaking that word, they made him cry out more and more, O Lord! O Lord! have mercy on me: Said I, pray gentlemen don't commit murder; I have money, take it, it is in my left pocket; so the man that knock'd me down, put his hand in my pocket and pull'd out my money ; by my intreaties they seemed a little softned , the other two left the watchman and came to me, so they all had a hand in robbing of me, they took my watch: said I, take it and welcome; the prisoner came to my buckles , he began with my left foot, and the other two took out my right shoebuckle .</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Tribe. One guinea in gold, and 16 s. in silver; the man that knock'd me down took that, they got off me and left me lying against the bank; they had haul'd the watchman at a distance from me, and pull'd him by the legs into a ditch: said I, you have been so good as not to hurt me, pray be so good to help me up; one of them gave me his hand and helped me up: I was no sooner on my legs but one of them (I suppose the prisoner) took me a violent blow on my head and said, Deliver! and took off my hat and wig: I said, gentlemen, I thought I had delivered: said he, Deliver your all you dog? said I, I have a disorder in my head , and I am fearful of catching cold in my head ; I am afraid of an ague, &amp;c. Said I, please to give me my hat or wig, I should be oblig'd to you: one of them held his hand in my wig towards me, and said, D - n you: said I, will you please to give it me? he said nothing: said I, shall I be so bold to take it? so I took my wig and put it on my head; then I asked him for my hat also: one of them said, D - n you, you will ask for all again presently? No, said I, gentlemen , I will not; please to give it me, and I shall be obliged to you. With that they made a grumbling and went off towards White-chapel.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you light enough to discern the prisoner's face?</p>
               <p>Tribe. I could see them coming to me by the light of the lanthorn; but when the light was out I could not. I can swear to the prisoner's face, and by his short hair, and that remarkable lock behind.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-22-person166">
                  Archibald 
                  Forister 
               <interp inst="t17490405-22-person166" type="surname" value="Forister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person166" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was going to light Mr. Tribe home the 29th of March, about eleven o'clock from Mile-end to Bow, we went 'till we pass'd the Plough, it was half way between Mile-end and Bow, there came one man up. I got near the ditch to let him pass me; when4 he came just to me he ask'd if that was the way to White-chappel; I said, It is as straight as you can walk: I turned my head about , and the prisoner at the bar gave me a blow on the side of my head with something he had in his hand; I took it to be a hanger; I knew him before, as having him in my custody, as mentioned before; it was about six weeks before this: after I was down the other man took me by the legs and dragg'd me into the ditch , and the prisoner jump'd on my breast: I said, Why do you use me so barbarously; I did not use you so Maclocklin when I had you in my custody two days and a night? &amp;c. Said I, You cannot expect a great deal from a poor watchman: they took one shilling and fourpence from me; it was the other man that took it; they searched my pockets and took an old knife; the other spoke I believe in Irish ; they took my hat and wig, and left my hat with another man that was lying bound in the field that same night: When they left us, we went on; I got my lanthorn done up and I went back again, going along I found Mr. Tribe's hat in the field ; they had left it there.</p>
               <p>John Hill. I am a constable; I was going round the parish to collect my money, I went into the house call'd the Three Mackerels , there was the prisoner, I took him there: Said the prisoner, The watchman was very much abus'd, and I did it; this was the 31st of March: I say, said he, I am the man that did it; I went and call'd the watchman that was abus'd and secur'd the prisoner: the watchman said, That is the man that abus'd me and stamp'd on my breast .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence . Last Friday when I came in to the place where the gentleman was, I said to the landlord, Let us have a pot of beer: I had not been at Mile-end for five weeks before that :<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050011"></xptr> said the landlord to me, Here is a thing lodg'd against you, and I am very sorry to hear it; said he, There has been a man robb'd and a watchman beat, and it is laid on you: Upon me, said I, How can that be? I have been out of Mile end these five weeks? With that Mr. Hill came and looked at me very earnestly, and ask'd my name; I told him, he goes and brings a watchman and another gentleman, and I had a house full of them about me, and they took me up; I have witness to prove I was in my lodging that night by seven o'clock, and in bed before nine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-22-person167">
                  Ann 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17490405-22-person167" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person167" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live in East Smithfield; the prisoner lodg'd at my house, he has lodg'd with me about six weeks; he is a <rs id="t17490405-22-deflabel111" type="occupation">labouring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-defend161 t17490405-22-deflabel111"></join> , he always keeps good hours; he us'd to be always in by seven or eight o'clock : he never exceeded ten. I always see my lodgers in before I go to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How many lodgers have you?</p>
               <p>More. I have six .</p>
               <p>Q. What do they give a night?</p>
               <p>More. Two-pence; but I do not turn away three halfpence ; there was a man in bed with him that night, and two women lay in the same room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that man; that is the man we want to see?</p>
               <p>More. I have not seen him since?</p>
               <p>John Hill. The woman's account and the prisoner's do not agree; for he swore before the Justice he had not been come from Plymouth above a fortnight.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490405-22-verdict112" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-verdict112" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490405-22-punish113" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-22-punish113" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-22-defend161 t17490405-22-punish113"></join>
               Death
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
