<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-20">
               <interp inst="t17401015-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-20" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-20" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-20-off101-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-20-defend138 t17401015-20-off101 t17401015-20-verdict103"></join>
         
               <p>453. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-20-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     May 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-20-defend138" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-defend138" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-defend138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             * was indicted for <rs id="t17401015-20-off101" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-off101" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-off101" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 4 Moidores, 5 Thirty-six Shilling pieces, 20 Guineas, and 44 s. and 6 d. in Money, the Money of 
                     <persName id="t17401015-20-victim139" type="victimName">
                        William 
                        Silver 
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-victim139" type="surname" value="Silver"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-20-victim139" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-20-victim139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-20-off101 t17401015-20-victim139"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17401015-20-person140">
                        Nathanael 
                        Bishop 
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-person140" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-20-person140" type="given" value="Nathanael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-20-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17401015-20-cd102" type="crimeDate">Nov. 3. 1736</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-20-off101 t17401015-20-cd102"></join>.</p>
               <p>* See Last January Sessions-Book, No. 125.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150009"></xptr>The Counsel for the Prosecution set forth, that the Prisoner was a Member of that Set of Men, who go under the Denomination of Gamblers; the most dangerous Community to the Publick; that in the Schemes they lay to trap their Neighbours, Providence takes care they shall be ensnar'd themselves, and fall into that Pit which they dig for others; and that the Prisoner had now brought himself into the Commission of a Felony, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>William Silver was called and sworn.</p>
               <p>Couns. Go to the Bar, and see if you know that Man.</p>
               <p>Silver. That is the Man: He met me by Milford-Lane, and gave me a Bobb on the Shoulder; I turn'd to see who it was, O, says he, I beg your Pardon. I thought it had been somebody else; but I can hardly believe my Eyes: Pray, What Countryman are you? I told him I was Berkshire; Why, says he, I came from High-Wicomb myself: Pray, Who do you know there? Said I, I know Mr. 
               <persName id="t17401015-20-person141">
                  Bracken, O<interp inst="t17401015-20-person141" type="given" value="Bracken"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-person141" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said he, I know him very well, he was the last Person I drank with, may , the last Person I spoke to: What Part of Berkshire? I came (said I) from Walgrove ; Did you, said he? I want to send a Letter to a Person in your Parish, who had a Debt owing him from one in Town who paid him but 2 s. and 6 d. in the Pound, and is now in such Circumstances, that I believe I can get him the remainder; and if you will carry it, I will give you half a Pint of Wine; so we went into the Feathers-Tavern, he asked me if I would not smoak half a Pipe with him, I said, I did not care if I did; and as we were lighting our Pipes, he stooped down, and took up a Paper; he then said somebody had had very bad Luck, and wished the Owner had it; Don't carry it away, said I, but leave it at the Bar; then, said he, I'll pawn it for a Pint of Wine. In a little Time another Man came, and peeped in at the Door: the Prisoner asked him what he meant by coming into a private Room; I ask Pardon, said he, but I had the Misfortune to drop a Paper here just now; What is it, says the Prisoner? It is a Receipt for 200 l. Why, says the Prisoner, I was just going to mortgage it at the Bar for a Pint of Wine; the other Man immediately threw down a Shilling for it, and was going away, but the Prisoner stopped him, and said, he should take Part of the Wine; on his Persuasion he sat down. He said he had been at a Cock Match, that the Landlord of the House told him one particular Cock was better than such a one, and persuaded him to lay a Wager on it's Head, which he did, and lost; but the Landlord was his Friend, and laid down the Money for him. Before we had drank the Wine out, the Stranger turned himself about, and took a pack of Cards out of the Window, and he and the Prisoner sell to shewing Tricks with them; the other Man pulled a Card out of the middle, and said, Now I will tell you what that Card is before I see it, and I'll lay you a 100 l. that I tell any Card in the Pack; the Prisoner thereupon fetched 20 l. and told it down on the Table, and called me out, and desired me to lend him some Money to make his up; There will be no Damage, (said he) only tender it down, and keep it in your own Hand; for I may as well win the Fool's Money as another. I told him I had not above a Shilling in my Pocket; he asked me if I could not borrow some to lend him, I told him, No; but he over-persuaded me, and I went to one Davis's, where I got 25 l. 12 s. and 6 d. and to Mr Ford's, and had 30 l. Coming back he desired me to go in at Bishop's, at the Fleece below St Paul's, that we might tell the Money, and see how much was wanting to make it up 80 l. There were 10 l. wanting, which he said he could borrow of a Friend just by; he put his Money into my Bag with that which I had borrowed, and I put it on the Table by me. I happened to turn my Head, and in that Time he changed my Bag for another like it, and left me under pretence of going to get the Remainder of the Money. I waited some Time, and he not returning, I examined the Bag, and found in it only Half-a-crown's-worth of Halfpence, and some pieces of Lead.</p>
               <p>Couns. Who was to have the Bag, before the Wager was laid?</p>
               <p>Silver. I was to keep the Money, and had it in my possession till it was taken away. When he had put his Money into my Bag, I put it on the Table before me, and I am sure there was nobody else in the Room, but the Maid, who brought in a Pint of Beer.</p>
               <p>Couns. What became of the Stranger?</p>
               <p>Silver. We left him at the Feathers, while we went for the Money. I never saw him afterwards.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was you to have any Part of this Wager?</p>
               <p>Silver. No: The Wager was between the Prisoner and the Stranger, I had nothing at all to do with it.</p>
               <p>Couns. On your Oath, Was your Money ever in the Prisoner's Custody?</p>
               <p>Silver. Not, till it was taken away by him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. How came you to borrow Money for a Person you knew nothing of? Suppose the Stranger had won, Who was to have had the Money?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150010"></xptr>Silver . The Prisoner said it was impossible he should; but if it had happened otherwise, he ought to have made it good.</p>
               <p>Couns. What was the Prisoner's Money, Gold or Silver?</p>
               <p>Silver. There was some Gold, and some Silver, but I can't say what Pieces they were. His Money and mine were mixed, and told together.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prisoner, here made an Objection in Point of Law. That as the Money was borrowed to serve the Prisoner, and as the Prosecutor depended upon him for the Re-payment of it, this Fact could not be deem'd Felony.</p>
               <p>In Answer to which it was urged, by the Counsel for the Prosecution; That this was one of the worst Sort of Felonies, and a Case in which the Publick are greatly concern'd: That this Money never having been lent to the Prisoner, nor was to have been entrusted in his custody, it must be deem'd a felonious taking. That a Person having taken a Ring off his Finger, at the Request of another, for him to see it, his going off with it had been adjudged Felony.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17401015-20-verdict103" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-verdict103" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-20-verdict103" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               The Court were of Opinion this Indictment was not well laid; but the Prisoner was ordered to remain in custody, unless he could find sufficient Sureties to appear, to take his Trial for the Fraud. Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
