<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17481012-6">
               <interp inst="t17481012-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-6" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17481012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-6" type="date" value="17481012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481012-6-off31-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-defend68 t17481012-6-off31 t17481012-6-verdict33"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481012-6-off35-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-defend68 t17481012-6-off35 t17481012-6-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>+ 484. 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-defend68" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Emerson 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-6-defend68" type="surname" value="Emerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-defend68" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-defend68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             *, of <placeName id="t17481012-6-defloc30">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-6-defloc30" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-6-defloc30" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-defend68 t17481012-6-defloc30"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17481012-6-off31" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-off31" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-off31" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               violently and feloniously assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17481012-6-victim70" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Swaine 
                        <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim70" type="surname" value="Swaine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim70" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off31 t17481012-6-victim70"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off35 t17481012-6-victim70"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling house, putting him in fear and danger of his life, and taking from him 3 s. in money
            </rs>, the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17481012-6-person71">
                  John 
                  Swaine 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person71" type="surname" value="Swaine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person71" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in his dwelling house, <rs id="t17481012-6-cd32" type="crimeDate">Sept. 30th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off31 t17481012-6-cd32"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off35 t17481012-6-cd32"></join>.</p>
               <p>* This Indictment was founded on the statute of the 3d and 4th of William and Mary, which makes this offence felony without benefit of clergy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person72">
                  John 
                  Swaine 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person72" type="surname" value="Swaine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday the 30th of Sept. between ten and eleven at night, or before the watch went eleven, the prisoner came into my shop, and asked for a penny dram of cinnamon water, (I believe the door was a little upon the jar) and he asked me to drink a dram, and I drank one with him , and he threw down six-pence; and while I was giving him change, he pushed the door too, and I went from behind the compter in order to let him out, and then he pretended he had left some company at the tavern, and wanted to borrow some money to discharge his reckoning (this was at first) and then he insisted upon what I had in my pocket, and said he must have money, and would have money, and then he took 3 s. from me; after he had got the 3 s. the prisoner took me by the collar, and said, if I made any resistance he would destroy me; then he unbottoned my coat, waistcoat, and breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say then?</p>
               <p>Swaine. While he had me by the collar, he demanded the key of the till, I said I had nothing there that was my own; he held me fast, and took me with him to the till, and there was a tobacco box in the till, in which was 18 s. 6 d. and he took that out of the tobacco box, and went away with the money; there was a bag of half pence in the till, he took that up, and asked what they were, I said they were to pay the small beer brewer, and he said he would not take them: then he set a candle down upon the floor, and asked me to let him out at the back door, and after he was out at the door, he said, if ever I saw him again, and ever took any notice of him, he threatened my life. I do not remember the words he said</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner the same clothes on then as he has now?</p>
               <p>Swaine. Yes; but not the same hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before?</p>
               <p>Swaine. No never.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in any house with him before?</p>
               <p>Swaine. No. The next day I went to the chandler's shop over against me, and told them of it, and about ten o'clock on the Monday night, the woman of the house came, and bid me look into the back room, and see if I knew any body there; I went into the room, and saw the prisoner sitting there, and they brought him some meat, and he asked for pepper and salt; I then said to him, sir, have you no knowledge of my face? he said, no; and I said, by G - d you are the man that robbed me, and then he owned it directly.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Have you any lodgers in your house?</p>
               <p>Swaine . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not call out to these lodgers?</p>
               <p>Swaine. Because I did not know whether they were in bed or up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not this cook's shop open then?</p>
               <p>Swaine. No; there was never a shop open in the place.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know who shut your shop door?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120008"></xptr>Swaine . Because there was no body in the shop but him and I.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know but the door might shut of itself?</p>
               <p>Swaine . I am very sensible to the contrary; for I saw him do it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not your's a glass door?</p>
               <p>Swaine . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. So any body going by might look in?</p>
               <p>Swaine. It slides up.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you cry out, stop thief? do not you think if you had cried out aloud the watchman would have heard you?</p>
               <p>Swaine. I did not care to run the risque of it, for I did not know who was near him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you a great mastiff dog there?</p>
               <p>Swaine. Yes; but he was chained.</p>
               <p>Mr. Keyan . About ten o'clock one Monday night, I think it was the third of October, I was charged with the prisoner by the prosecutor; I took him down to Justice Fraser's, and he was in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner confess any thing that night?</p>
               <p>Keyan . No; it was the next night.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say? what were his words?</p>
               <p>Keyan . He said he had borrowed some money of the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any sum?</p>
               <p>Keyan. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person73">
                  John 
                  Dunham 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person73" type="surname" value="Dunham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person73" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep the cook's shop. The prisoner at the bar came to my shop between nine and ten on the Monday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him then?</p>
               <p>Dunham . I knew him by being a customer, and he asked for a groat's worth of beef (which I served him with) and he went into the back room; and I said to Mr. Swaine, I believed there was some body there that he knew; he looked in, and said, he did not see any body; for the prisoner sat so that the prosecutor could not well see him; and Mr. Swaine went into the room, and said to the prisoner, young man don't you know me, and the prisoner said he did not; and Mr. Swaine said to the prisoner that he had robbed him; he owned he had borrowed some money of him, and said if he did not make it up, it would be the worse for him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person74">
                  Margaret 
                  Bertie 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person74" type="surname" value="Bertie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person74" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Richmond .</p>
               <p>Q. What business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Bertie. None at all; I live with my father.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your father?</p>
               <p>Bertie. A gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bertie. Yes; I have known him since Christmas last.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Bertie. He is a sea surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Bertie. He lives in Kew Lane at Richmond, and his lady lives there; the prisoner has a sober, honest character. His father is very old, and could not come.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him have any business as a surgeon?</p>
               <p>Bertie. Yes. Here is a gentleman here that knows him to be a surgeon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person75">
                  Edward 
                  Monk 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person75" type="surname" value="Monk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person75" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a waterman, and live at Richmond.</p>
               <p>Q. What character does he bear?</p>
               <p>Monk. He bears a very good character. I have walk with him with 100 l. in my pocket, and never mistrusted him. I know his lady very well, and she kept the best of quality company.</p>
               <p>- Johnson . I am a Smith, and live in Marlborough street; I have known the prisoner six or seven months, and he always bore a very good character, and always acted as such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person76">
                  Mary 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person76" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person76" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am servant to Mr. Emerson, and have lived with him since the sixth of March.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been married?</p>
               <p>Trueman. About six or seven years. I knew my mistress before he was married to her.</p>
               <p>Q. What character has Mr. Emerson?</p>
               <p>Trueman. A very good one. as far as I can see.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person77">
                  Thomas 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person77" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person77" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a chairman, and ply in Covent Garden; I have known him 20 years, and he had the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person78">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person78" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person78" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I knew him at Bristol, where he was in the sea service, and all the officers respected him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person79">
                  John 
                  Kilpin 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person79" type="surname" value="Kilpin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person79" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house; the prisoner came sometimes to my house, and had opportunities of taking away things, but he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-person80">
                  Thomas 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person80" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person80" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Bell and Castle at Windsor.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Stevens. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe him to be an honest man, or not?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, I do not. I have very great reason to say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever make any inquiry after him in Kew Lane .</p>
               <p>Stevens. The Duke of St. Alban's park-keeper made a strickt inquiry after him in Kew Lane ,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120009"></xptr> and he said, if there was such a person there, he lived in a garret .</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17481012-6-person81">
                  Sarah 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17481012-6-person81" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person81" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you live with the prisoner in Kew Lane ?</p>
               <p>Trueman. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he keep a house, or was he a lodger?</p>
               <p>Trueman. He kept a house there all the time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481012-6-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17481012-6-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-defend68 t17481012-6-punish34"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was also indicted for <rs id="t17481012-6-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing, 18 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-6-victim83" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Swaine 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim83" type="surname" value="Swaine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim83" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-6-victim83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off31 t17481012-6-victim83"></join>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off35 t17481012-6-victim83"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17481012-6-cd36" type="crimeDate">Sep. 30th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off31 t17481012-6-cd36"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-6-off35 t17481012-6-cd36"></join>, but not tried.</p>
            </div1>
