<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440912-51">
               <interp inst="t17440912-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-51" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-51" type="date" value="17440912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440912-51-off288-c397" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend499 t17440912-51-off288 t17440912-51-verdict291"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440912-51-off288-c398" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend501 t17440912-51-off288 t17440912-51-verdict291"></join>
         
               <p>407, 408.  
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-51-defend499" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Peirson 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend499" type="surname" value="Peirson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend499" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend499" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-51-defend501" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Fitzwalter 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend501" type="surname" value="Fitzwalter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend501" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-defend501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17440912-51-defloc287">St. Sepulchres</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-defloc287" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchres"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-defloc287" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend499 t17440912-51-defloc287"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend501 t17440912-51-defloc287"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17440912-51-off288" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-off288" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-off288" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440912-51-victim503" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Jones 
                        <interp inst="t17440912-51-victim503" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-51-victim503" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-51-victim503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-off288 t17440912-51-victim503"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting him in fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a hat, value 5 s. a perriwig, value 5 s. and 5 s. 6 d. in money
            </rs>, the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17440912-51-person504">
                  Henry 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17440912-51-person504" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person504" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17440912-51-cd289" type="crimeDate">September 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-off288 t17440912-51-cd289"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-51-person505">
                  Henry 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17440912-51-person505" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person505" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had business to do last Sunday in Whitechappel, and returning home in the evening with 
               <persName id="t17440912-51-person506">
                  William 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17440912-51-person506" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person506" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             over Moorfields, it rained, and we went in and drank a pot of beer; going down Long-Lane between 9 and 10 o'clock, Berry stopped to do his occasions and I went on a little before. As soon as I came to the cross way to go into <placeName id="t17440912-51-crimeloc290">Hosier-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-crimeloc290" type="placeName" value="Hosier-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-51-crimeloc290" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-off288 t17440912-51-crimeloc290"></join>, I was stopped on the highway by three fellows; the Prisoners are two of them, and the other was a lusty fellow; he laid hold of my breast, and I said, what do you want? Another came up to me and said, he wanted my money - That genleman there in the blue, Peirson; and he bid Fitzwalter put his hand in my pocket, and see what money I had got, and said if I said any thing he would rip me open.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a knife in his hand?</p>
               <p>Jones. I believe he had a knife in his hand: Berry was then coming along, and I cried, hollo, Mr. Berry! and then the lusty fellow jumped over the rails with my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of the Prisoners put his hand in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, Fitzwalter did, and took out 5 s. 6 d. then Mr. Berry came up; I laid hold of Fitzwalter, and Berry laid hold of Peirson; we endeavoured<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174409120030"></xptr> to get them to a publick house to secure them, and up came four or five lusty fellows and said, D - n your eyes let them go, or we will cut you as small as sausages - They had something in their hands, but I can't tell whether they were knives or swords, and we were obliged to let them go to preserve our lives, but they were taken again on Tuesday night.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know them again as it was so late in the night?</p>
               <p>Jones. The lamps were very light - I am sure the Prisoners are the persons; I took particular notice of them and of their cloaths.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-51-person507">
                  William 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17440912-51-person507" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person507" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Jones and I went out together last Sunday, and returning home going down Long-Lane, I had occasion to ease myself and he kept on. In about two or three minutes I came up with him, and he was by the rounds near Hosier-Lane, I said, Hollo, Mr. Jones! said he, I am robbed. I took hold of this boy in the blue coat [Peirson] and Jones took hold of him in the green [ Fitzwalter ] one had an apron on hanging down, and the other had something about him tucked up. I saw Jones without his hat and wig; then four or five fellows came up to us and said, What are you going to do with those boys? One of them had a stick and jobbed it in my face, and they said they would cut us as small as sausages if we did not let them go, and indeed I was glad to let them go. - I saw something glisten, but whether it was a sword or a hanger I cannot tell - I know these are the persons, because we had them a minute or two under a lamp in Smithfield. The Tuesday following I saw the Prisoners in the fair in Southwark, and I said to one that was there, these chaps robbed a friend of mine last Sunday. I dogged them out of the fair to St. Margaret's-Hill, and then took them; and Peirson said in the coach as we were coming along, that we could not hurt them, for they did nothing but pick pockets of handkerchiefs - They said they lived in Black Boy-Alley.</p>
               <p>Peirson. We have no witnesses, we have none but our own dear selves. Both <rs id="t17440912-51-verdict291" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-verdict291" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17440912-51-punish292" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-51-punish292" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend499 t17440912-51-punish292"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-51-defend501 t17440912-51-punish292"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Peirson. I am between fourteen and fifteen years old.</p>
               <p>Fitzwalter . I was thirteen years old last July.</p>
               <p>The Jury on account of their youth, recommended them to the Court as objects of his Majesty's mercy.</p>
            </div1>
