<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-24">
               <interp inst="t17441205-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-24" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-24" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-24-off153-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-defend253 t17441205-24-off153 t17441205-24-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>35. + 
               <persName id="t17441205-24-defend253" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17441205-24-defend253" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-defend253" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-defend253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17441205-24-defloc152">St. Botolph, Bishopsgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-24-defloc152" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph, Bishopsgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-24-defloc152" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-defend253 t17441205-24-defloc152"></join>, was indicted (together with three other persons unknown) for <rs id="t17441205-24-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441205-24-victim255" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Welldy 
                        <interp inst="t17441205-24-victim255" type="surname" value="Welldy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-24-victim255" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-24-victim255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-off153 t17441205-24-victim255"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting him in fear, &amp;c. and taking from him 4 s. 3 d. in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-24-cd154" type="crimeDate">Nov. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-off153 t17441205-24-cd154"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-24-person256">
                  Thomas 
                  Welldy 
               <interp inst="t17441205-24-person256" type="surname" value="Welldy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-person256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 9th of November, between 9 and 10 o'clock, or about 15 minutes after 9, I saw the Prisoner, and some others with him, they passed me in Old Bethlehem; there was the prisoner, another man, a woman, and a little boy: as I came by the posts in <placeName id="t17441205-24-crimeloc155">Moorfields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-24-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Moorfields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-24-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-off153 t17441205-24-crimeloc155"></join>, the little boy and the woman came close up to me; said I, You little dog, do you want to pick my pocket? and the prisoner said, D - n your eyes, what do you want? the little boy drew a knife at me, and said he would immediately let my puddings out, if I did not let him have what I had; the woman had a knife, and she threatened to rip me up; I had just 4 s. 3 d. which they took from me; there was another fellow along with the prisoner, and he gave me a great blow, and said, D - n your eyes, take that, all the black-boy-alley boys are not taken yet.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know the Prisoner was one of them?</p>
               <p>Welldy. I took particular notice of his feet, for he is lame; I know he is the person, for he held me by the collar, the moon shone, and the lamps were lighted, - it was by the lamps facing Bethlehem-gate, close to the rails; when he was taken the other day, I was sent for by the constable, and I said I had been abused and robbed, but I did not mind the money so much as being abused.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know he is the very man?</p>
               <p>Welldy. He had a long reddish beard on then, he is the man that held me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire that Mr. Lloyd, the man that took me last Sunday, may not be present while the other witnesses are examining. [Mr. Lloyd was ordered to withdraw.]</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Why did not you discover that you had been robbed, directly?</p>
               <p>Welldy. I told it to my family, and to a great many people that night, and to an hundred, I am sure, since.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever tell Mr. Lloyd of it before the Prisoner was taken up?</p>
               <p>Welldy. I never saw Lloyd till I was sent for; I have said many a time, that it was a lame-footed man that took hold of me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-24-person257">
                  Thomas 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17441205-24-person257" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-person257" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner to be a common pick-pocket, and has been so for a matter of 14 years. Mr. Welldy was in company with two or three more, and owned that he had been robbed in Moorfields; there were two men who knew the Prisoner very well, came to me, and said they believed they knew where he was to be found; that he used to be about St. Paul's Church-yard, and under Newgate, and last Sunday night I took him under Newgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Lloyd took me up about a month ago, but he could not make any thing out against me, so I was discharged; and he said, though he could not keep me then, he would have me again. <rs id="t17441205-24-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-24-punish157" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-24-punish157" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-24-defend253 t17441205-24-punish157"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
