<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-21">
               <interp inst="t17470909-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-21" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-21" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-21-off90-c145" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-21-defend177 t17470909-21-off90 t17470909-21-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>336. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-defend177" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-21-defend177" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-defend177" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-defend177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted <rs id="t17470909-21-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyTreason"></interp>
               for Petty-Treason and Murder; and the Indictment sets forth, That she, upon the <rs id="t17470909-21-cd91" type="crimeDate">21st Day of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-21-off90 t17470909-21-cd91"></join>, not having the Fear of God, and being mov'd by the Instigation of the Devil, being then the <rs id="t17470909-21-deflabel92" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-21-defend177 t17470909-21-deflabel92"></join> of one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470909-21-victim179" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Williams 
                        <interp inst="t17470909-21-victim179" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-21-victim179" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-21-victim179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-21-off90 t17470909-21-victim179"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously, traiterously, with Malice aforethought, did make an Assault, with a Knife in her Right-Hand, in and upon the left Side did feloniously strike or stab, giving the said 
                     <persName id="t17470909-21-person180">
                        Thomas 
                        Williams 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person180" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-21-person180" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-21-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   upon the said left Side one mortal Wound, the Breadth of one Inch, and the Depth of six Inches, of which Wound he instantly died
            </rs>. She was likewise charg'd with the same Murder by the Coroner's Inquest.</p>
               <p>Susannah Hill. I live in Field-lane; our House faces the Court where the Prisoner lived. I live over against the Blackmore's Head.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Hill. I can't say the Day of the Month, but it was between three and four o'Clock in the Afternoon. I think it was about six Weeks ago I heard Murder cry'd out several Times. I ran into the Court where she liv'd, and I saw Mrs Powel, and she cry'd out Murder. She had a Shoemaker's Knife in her Hand all over bloody. I ask'd her what was the Matter ? She said, Mrs Williams had killed her Husband. I went up Stairs into Mrs Williams's Room. I went into one Room and then into the Bed-Room.</p>
               <p>Q Had they a House, or only Lodgings?</p>
               <p>Hill. I can't say. When I went in there I saw the Deceased lie on the Ground. I think he was not dead. I think I saw his Eyes move. I think he was not quite dead, but he did not speak. When I went in Mrs Williams was towards the Head of him, Mrs Williams, so call'd; she had one Hand towards his Nose, and the other Hand closing his Eyes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Blood about him? Was his Clothes off or on?</p>
               <p>Hill. His Clothes were on. And I said, Mrs Williams, you have kill'd your Husband. She said, she had not, for he fell upon the Knife, and did it himself. When he was turn'd up, to the best of my Knowledge, the Wound was under his Blade Bone.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Wound, in the fore part or back-part?</p>
               <p>Hill. In the Back part.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his Clothes pull'd off?</p>
               <p>Hill. They turn'd him upon his Face and his Clothes were turn'd up; the Blood was in a Clodder about the Bigness of a Halfpenny Saucer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it on the right Side or the left?</p>
               <p>Hill. I think on the right, but I can't say, I was in such a Fright. I said, Oh! Mrs Williams, do you think this Wound can be given him by a Fall upon the Knife. Then she put her Hands together, and said several Times, I did it, I did it, I did it, a great many Times over.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person181">
                  Anne 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person181" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person181" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live the very next Door to the Prisoner. When I came home, between three and four o'Clock in the Afternoon, it was on a Tuesday, but the Day of the Month I can't tell, and the Nurse that nurss'd her Child, that suck'd at her Breast, she call'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090013"></xptr> me up. Powel, says she, come up, there is Murder done. Upon that I went up directly, and in the first Room I saw nothing at all; in the next Room I saw him lie with his Head toward the back Window, upon his Back.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he alive then?</p>
               <p>Powel. He was neither alive nor dead; his Eyes twirl'd; he could scarcely draw Breath. I saw him lying on his Back, with his Head to the Window, and his Knees laid up a little crooked.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner in the Room?</p>
               <p>Powel. I saw her upon her bended Knees, stroking his Mouth up, and his Eyes up so, and said my Tommy is dead, my Tommy is murder'd</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say who murder'd him?</p>
               <p>Powel. No, Sir. I went to stretch his Legs out, and there was as much Blood as would fill an Half-penny Saucer, all in a Clodder; then coming down Stairs I saw the Knife in the Fore-Room, where he used to work.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Knife bloody?</p>
               <p>Powel. It was bloody up to the Handle, and I took the Knife and brought it down in the Yard. When I came down there was an Oration quickly made, and the Neighbours came in. There was one Mr. Taylor came in, and saw the same Action, of closing his Eyes and Mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Wound?</p>
               <p>Powel. I did not see the Wound.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Pray ask her, whether it was not off the Box that she took the Knife?</p>
               <p>Powel. It was off the Box that he sat on; he had no Seat; I found the Knife where all his Tools laid.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Blood in the Fore-Room?</p>
               <p>Powel. Not a Bit of Blood in the Fore-Room; his Head was down upon the Ground, and she was closing his Eyes, and said, My Tommy is dead, My Tommy is kill'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person182">
                  Edmund 
                  Brewer 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person182" type="surname" value="Brewer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person182" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live right over against where the Murder was committed. I was standing at my Kitchen-Window, and the Prisoner came out, and cry'd, Murder, Murder. I did not go over, but she came a second Time; and cry'd, Murder, Murder, I have killed my poor Tom.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not go upon the Cry of Murder ?</p>
               <p>Brewer. Because it was a common Thing, she often cry'd out Murder; but I can't say that I ever heard him cry Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person183">
                  John 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person183" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person183" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was at Work backwards, and hearing a Tumult that Mrs Williams had kill'd her Husband, upon that I went up Stairs, and saw the Man lie upon the Ground, and she upon her Knees, with one Hand to his Mouth, and her other Hand closing his Eyes; and I said, Mrs Williams, how is this, you have done some Mischief, the Man is dead ? And I perceived some Blood. I laid over the Bed, to feel where the Wound was. I says, you have killed your Husband; how could you do so? With that, says she, I have not kill'd him. I said, You are a vile Jade, you have kill'd him. Then she clapp'd her Hands together, and said, if I have, I am here ready to suffer for it. I said, here's Blood, the Wound is in his Back.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you turn him up?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. The Women said I did, but I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body turn him up?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. Not while I was there, my Lord, I put my Hand under and put my Finger in the Wound, and as near as I can guess it was under his Shoulder; but I can't say which Shoulder.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there Blood in the Room?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. The Blood lay under his Loins.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you said, here is the Wound; you Jade, you have certainly kill'd him.</p>
               <p>Carpenter. Yes, Well, says she, I have, my Tommy is kill'd, is dead, and I am here to suffer for it.</p>
               <p>Court. Are you sure of these Expressions ?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. I am sure she said, my Tommy is dead; if I have killed him I am ready to suffer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body else in the Room ?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. There were several Women in the Room, but I did not know them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person184">
                  James 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person184" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person184" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was sent for to examine the Wound, and I found it an Inch long under the Shoulder; and upon examining with my Probe I found it enter'd the Cavity of the Thorax, and it was about six Inches deep.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that, in your Opinion, the Occasion of his Death?</p>
               <p>Hicks. Undoubtedly it was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you form any Judgment what Instrument it was done with?</p>
               <p>Hicks. With a Knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Knife to try whether it tally'd with the Wound?</p>
               <p>Hicks. I had not.</p>
               <p>(The Knife produc'd in Court.)</p>
               <p>Court. Let Mr Hicks see that Knife.</p>
               <p>Hicks. It seems to tally with the Wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it could be done by his falling upon that Knife ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090014"></xptr>Hicks. Not without the Knife was to stand upright. I think the Man would not take that Pains to do it himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person185">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person185" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person185" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I don't know any thing of the Fact; but one told me there was a Murder committed, and desired me to take the Person into Custody. Accordingly when I came, I took her to my Lord Mayor; there appeared two or three Witnesses against her; one produc'd a Knife, and said that they found it all bloody, and this Apron was taken from her Side at my Lord Mayor's; he desired that I would take this, and the Knife, into my Possession; it was in this Manner stained with Blood.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Prisoner say any thing ?</p>
               <p>Davis. The Prisoner did say, that they had had Words, and she push'd him, and he fell against the Knife, that is what she told me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Mr Williams that I lived with. I never was married to him; I have had four Children by him - I was just come from Market; I sell Fruit and Things - When I came Home he begins his Airs as usual in striking and beating me; he struck me across my Eyes and Nose; I says, What is that for? D - n you, you must go out. I says, Do you design to sit down to your Work to day? D - n you you Bitch, says he, and bit my Finger very much, and with struggling together close by the Box, we fell upon it; I got up first, and I said, Tom, Tom; he ran directly, and cry'd Lord, Lord, and run into the back Room, and fell over the Bed: When I saw him sit at the Foot of the Bed, and not stir, I said Tom, Tom, and he made me no Answer: I then said, For God's Sake, for Christ's Sake, come up somebody, I believe my Husband is dead. 
               <persName id="t17470909-21-person186">
                  Sarah 
                  Mascall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person186" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person186" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             she came from my Child's Nurse's, and said, don't frighten your Wife.</p>

               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-21-person187">
                  Sarah 
                  Mascall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person187" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person187" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person187" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you any thing to say?</p>
               <p>Mascall. I have nothing further, than her Husband and she seem'd to have some Words; I had a Child at Nurse in the same House - I am a Servant. When I went to see the Child, she cry'd out for somebody to come to her Assistance; I said to Nurse, I would not have you go down, there is nothing to be said between a Man and his Wife.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>Mascall. Somebody came to assist me; when I went down, the Man lay a-cross the Washing-tub and Floor; I said, Mr Williams don't frighten your Wife? I helpt her, and I said I believe he is dead: I said, is he in a Fit, or what is the matter ? She said, she did not know. I said, I believed he was dead. When she let his Head go, it went down again as one dead, and I heard her say that her Finger was very much bit; she said when he bit her Finger, that he fell down upon the Knife; certainly he might fall down - I imagined he did so; I can't tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-21-person188">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17470909-21-person188" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person188" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Fruiterer in the Fleet-market. I know nothing of the Fact, but the Woman always seemed an honest industrious Person. I seldom saw her in the Market scarce a Month together, but I saw her with black Eyes, and her Face bruised some way or another. I know nothing of the Fact, only the Woman used to take Care to get an honest Livelihood. I believe she was very badly used.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470909-21-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-verdict93" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470909-21-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-21-punish94" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-21-defend177 t17470909-21-punish94"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
