<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450530-23">
               <interp inst="t17450530-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-23" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-23" type="date" value="17450530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450530-23-off144-c255" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-defend307 t17450530-23-off144 t17450530-23-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>287. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450530-23-defend307" type="defendantName">
                     Jeremiah 
                     Burton 
                  <interp inst="t17450530-23-defend307" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-defend307" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-defend307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17450530-23-defloc143">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-23-defloc143" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-23-defloc143" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-defend307 t17450530-23-defloc143"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450530-23-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch with a steel seal, value 50 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450530-23-victim309" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17450530-23-victim309" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-23-victim309" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-23-victim309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-off144 t17450530-23-victim309"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450530-23-cd145" type="crimeDate">May 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-off144 t17450530-23-cd145"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-23-person310">
                  Richard 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person310" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person310" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17450530-23-viclabel146" type="occupation">Valet de Chambre to my Lord Essingham Howard</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-victim309 t17450530-23-viclabel146"></join>. On the second of this month when his Majesty went to the house of Lords, I went with my master's robes, and as I was coming from the house with his Lordship's robes under my arm (there being a great croud) the Prisoner at the Bar pushed very hard upon me, and I found my watch was drawing away, and immediately it was gone: the Prisoner looked me full in the face, and being close to me, I suspected him: I laid hold of him, and said, I take you on suspicion of stealing my watch. I saw one Mr. North a Marshal's man, and charged him with the Prisoner. I went to carry my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174505300026"></xptr> Lord's robes home, and came back again, got a coach, and Mr. North and another person assisted me to carry him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17450530-23-person311">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person311" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person311" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but before we carried him there I took him to an alehouse, the 
               <persName id="t17450530-23-person312">
                  Robin 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person312" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person312" type="given" value="Robin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Little John, and the people told him he had better confess the fact, return the watch, and go about his business; he said he knew nothing of it, but he said there was a man in a blue grey coat that was near me, who was suspected of doing these things. I said, if he would get me my watch again, I should be glad, for I wanted to go about my business; and I proposed his depositing five guineas as a security for the watch; and the people advised him to send for a friend to bring some money: the Prisoner sent a man with a note to the Goat at Charing Cross for the man to come to him, and sent another to carry a note to a friend of his in Paul's Alley Aldersgate Street, for five guineas as a security for the watch, and it was to be deposited in Mr. North's hand, for I only wanted a security for my watch to be lodged in his hand: when we went from the alehouse he was carried to Mr. North's house, and about nine or ten o'clock a porter came to ask for Mr. North, and said he had a parcel for him: Mr. North said to me, I'll lay you 20 l. there's your watch again: the porter was admitted into the room, and I had my watch again: this is the watch I lost that day.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get the watch again?</p>
               <p>Brown. It was brought me in a little bit of rag by the porter to Mr. North's house.</p>
               <p>Q. You charge the Prisoner with taking your watch from you, how do you know he took it?</p>
               <p>Brown. I don't know that he took the watch from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let the Prisoner go?</p>
               <p>Brown. Not till I had my watch again; when I had my watch again, Mr. North said, you must go before a Magistrate before the Prisoner can be discharged. We went before Justice Fraser, and we were to tell him we had some words and a quarrel in the Park, and I came to have him discharged: (not knowing so well as a great many people do,) and the Justice said it was a felony, and he could not discharge him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said if I would give him five guineas he would make it up with me.</p>
               <p>Brown. I did not want any thing more than my watch again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You can't say I took the watch from you?</p>
               <p>Brown. I can't swear that you took the watch from me, but I verily believe if I had not secured you, I should never have had my watch again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not take it, I know nothing at all of the taking it from you.</p>
               <p>Jury. Why did not you search him?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They did search me.</p>
               <p>Brown. They always have their accomplices ready to take any thing from them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-23-person313">
                  Charles 
                  Cleave 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person313" type="surname" value="Cleave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person313" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Plumb Tree Court by the New Market. I have known the Prisoner about five years, he is a poulterer by trade, and married a cap maker: I have bought several caps of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his settlement?</p>
               <p>Cleave. It was in Aldersgate Street at one 
               <persName id="t17450530-23-person314">
                  Philip 
                  Emms 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person314" type="surname" value="Emms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person314" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. - I believe he lodged there about two months ago - he lived about four years ago in Three Tun Court in Redcross Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character as to his honesty?</p>
               <p>Cleave. I think he had a good character, I never knew that he was ever charged with any such thing before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-23-person315">
                  Matthew 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person315" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person315" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner ten years, he was a poulterer, he kept a house in Three Tun Court, and followed cap making.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you saw him?</p>
               <p>Cleave. I have not seen him for about three months.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Cleave. I keep the White Bear Inn in Old Street. He used to come often to my house, and frequently brought parcels of caps to sell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-23-person316">
                  William 
                  Tinling 
               <interp inst="t17450530-23-person316" type="surname" value="Tinling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person316" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about seven years, and never knew any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his business?</p>
               <p>Tinling. He used to go about with rabbets and fowls, but he has left that off about a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business are you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174505300027"></xptr>Tinling. I belong to the Crown Office. I have bought fowls and rabbets of him, and I believe him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Another witness said she had bought black velvet caps of him for hostlers for about four years, and believed him to be a very honest man. <rs id="t17450530-23-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450530-23-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-23-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-23-defend307 t17450530-23-punish148"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
