<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410514-15">
               <interp inst="t17410514-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-15" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-15" type="date" value="17410514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410514-15-off76-c113" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-defend142 t17410514-15-off76 t17410514-15-verdict79"></join>
         
               <p>15. 
               <persName id="t17410514-15-defend142" type="defendantName">
                  Timothy 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17410514-15-defend142" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-defend142" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-defend142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17410514-15-deflabel74" type="occupation">the younger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-defend142 t17410514-15-deflabel74"></join>, of <placeName id="t17410514-15-defloc75">Twickenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-15-defloc75" type="placeName" value="Twickenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-15-defloc75" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-defend142 t17410514-15-defloc75"></join>, was indicted (with Timothy Hall, the elder, not taken) for <rs id="t17410514-15-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17410514-15-victim143" type="victimName">
                        James 
                        Hedger 
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-victim143" type="surname" value="Hedger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-15-victim143" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-15-victim143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-off76 t17410514-15-victim143"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Watch, with the outside and inside Cales made of Silver, value 5 l. and a Watch Chain made of base Metal, value 6 d
            </rs> . the Goods of the said Hedger , <rs id="t17410514-15-cd77" type="crimeDate">April 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-off76 t17410514-15-cd77"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-15-person144">
                  James 
                  Hedger 
               <interp inst="t17410514-15-person144" type="surname" value="Hedger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person144" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at a Sale where the next Witness had bought some Goods for me, and came part of the way home with me. When he left me, the Prisoner and his Father overtook me, and one took hold of one Arm, and the other of another; they asked me, if I had any Money, and I said, I had not, for I had laid it all out at the Sale . Upon that, the Prisoner said, D - n him, he has a good Watch, and pulled it out of my pocket. There was a Man to whom I owed some Money followed me from the Sale, and the Prisoner and the other Man, seeing him, they both ran away. This was on the 26th of April, between 5 and 6 in the Evening, and in about half an Hour afterwards they were taken.</p>
               <p>C. Did you ever find your Watch again?</p>
               <p>Hedger. I am a <rs id="t17410514-15-viclabel78" type="occupation">Gardner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-15-victim143 t17410514-15-viclabel78"></join>, and was planting some Lettices, and the Doors of my House next the Street were open; and when I came out of the Garden, I found my Watch on a little Table under the Window, but how it came there, I can't tell.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether, when he came home, his Daughter did not ask him where his Watch was, and whether he did not say, he had left it at the Red Lion?</p>
               <p>Hedger. No, I did not. I am sure the Prisoner at the Bar is one of the persons who stopped me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I take him from the Red-Lion , and carry him to his own House?</p>
               <p>Hedger. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-15-person145">
                  Solomon 
                  Wiseman 
               <interp inst="t17410514-15-person145" type="surname" value="Wiseman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person145" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep the Sign of the Hitt or Miss on Twickenham Common , and went with the Prosecutor to the Sale, and bought some things for him; I went part of the Way home with him; but he being in Liquor, I took him back again to the Red Lion, and about 2 or 3 Hours afterwards I heard that he had lost his Watch, and the Prisoner and the other Man were delivered into my Custody.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever hear any thing to my Dishonesty?</p>
               <p>Wiseman . No, not that I know of.</p>
               <p>Jury . Were the Prisoners search'd for the Watch when they were taken?</p>
               <p>Wiseman. No, they were not.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did you see any Sign of the Prosecutor's having a Watch about him when you parted with him?</p>
               <p>Wiseman. Yes, I saw it in his pocket, and bid the Man of the House take care of it. The other Man, who was taken with the Prisoner, was carried before the Justice, but Hedger said, the Prisoner was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174105140009"></xptr> the Man who took his Watch out of his pocket, and he had nothing to do with the other Man; upon which he was discharged.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desired the Prosecutor to leave his Watch with the Man at the Red-Lion, for he was very much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Hedger. I was not so much in Liquor, but I paid Money and took a Receipt for it. As to the Prisoner, I never saw him before that Time in my Life.</p>
               <p>Wiseman. He was so drunk, that I carried him back to the Red-Lion, and how long he staid there after I left him, I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not one 
               <persName id="t17410514-15-person146">
                  Ned 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17410514-15-person146" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person146" type="given" value="Ned"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             go for the Watch to the Red-Lion?</p>
               <p>Hedger. Yes, he told me he did, but it was not at my Desire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-15-person147">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stent 
               <interp inst="t17410514-15-person147" type="surname" value="Stent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person147" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner these 9 or 10 years, and never heard that he was in any Misdemeanour in my Life.</p>
               <p>Mary Hall. I can swear for his Honesty, as far as this, that he never was in any Trouble before. <rs id="t17410514-15-verdict79" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-15-verdict79" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
