<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17461015-20">
               <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17461015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="date" value="17461015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17461015-20-off79-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend304 t17461015-20-off79 t17461015-20-verdict82"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17461015-20-off79-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-off79 t17461015-20-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>353, 354. 
               
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-defend304" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Taylor 
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend304" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend304" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-defend305" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Robinson 
                  , <rs id="t17461015-20-deflabel78" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-deflabel78"></join>, <rs id="t17461015-20-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-alias-1"></join>otherwise the Wife of the said 
                        <persName id="t17461015-20-person307">
                           George 
                           Taylor 
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person307" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17461015-20-person307" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17461015-20-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend305" type="surname" value="Robinson Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend305" type="given" value="Mary George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-defend305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17461015-20-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               conspiring together, that the said 
                     <persName id="t17461015-20-person308">
                        George 
                        Taylor 
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person308" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person308" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   should personate Mr. 
                     <persName id="t17461015-20-person309">
                        Richard 
                        Holland 
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person309" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person309" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in order to her being married to the said 
                     
                        <persName id="t17461015-20-victim311" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Holland 
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-victim311" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-victim311" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-victim311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-off79 t17461015-20-victim311"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , that she might entitle herself to his Estate, &amp;c. and accordingly they were married the <rs id="t17461015-20-cd80" type="crimeDate">18th of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-off79 t17461015-20-cd80"></join>
               
                  </rs>, at <placeName id="t17461015-20-crimeloc81">the Parish Church of St. Andrew, Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20-crimeloc81" type="placeName" value="the Parish Church of St. Andrew, Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20-crimeloc81" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-off79 t17461015-20-crimeloc81"></join>.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prosecution. This Indictment further sets forth, that 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person312">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person312" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person312" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon the 18th Day of July, at the Parish of St. Andrew, Holbourn , did unlawfully contract Marriage with the the said 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person313">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person313" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person313" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in the Name of the said 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person314">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person314" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person314" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Council. I am likewise Council in this Cause for the Prosecution; though this Indictment is laid several Ways, as is usual in such Cases, in order to prevent notorious Offenders escaping Justice, yet the Sum of the Indictment is only the fraudulent and wicked Contrivance of a Marriage between the two Defendants, in which the Defendant Taylor, was to personate, and did personate, Mr. 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person315">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person315" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person315" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is laid to be with a Design to distress and injure Mr. Holland, to entitle 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person316">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person316" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person316" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , after his Death, to his Estate and Effects, as supposing this had been a real and true Marriage between Mr. Holland and her; but in this Case the Intent of the Person can be made no otherwise than by the Nature and Circumstances of the Fact; therefore, Gentlemen, I would beg Leave to state the Nature of the Thing; this Person, 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person317">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person317" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person317" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , liv'd with Mr. Holland. The first Step we could trace out , was the Meeting of the two Defendants at the Sun-Tavern in St. Paul's Church-Yard in July last.</p>
               <p>You can't expect we should call Witnesses to this Meeting, the Nature of the Thing will not admit of it; the Intent of that Meeting will appear best by those Actions that follow it; therefore, Gentlemen, I shall go to the next Step, taken the 18th of July: As this Defendant, 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person318">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person318" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person318" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was to personate Mr. Holland, who is a Gentleman of Fortune, it was necessary he should be provided with proper and decent Cloaths to personate a Gentleman ; for that Reason the Defendant, Mrs. Robinson, on the 17th of July, sent a Box from her Master's House at Hornsey , in which there were a Coat of Mr. Holland's, a ruffled Shirt, Neckcloth and Wig, these were directed to be left at Mr. Casker's, who keeps an Inn in Little Britain, the 18th of July. The Defendant came to Town from Hornsey herself, goes to Mrs. Casker, finding it there she gave Directions<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150019"></xptr> to deliver this Box to the Person she should send for it ; when she had done this , she went directly to Mr. Holland's House in Newgate-Street, there she pull'd off a sort of Riding Habit , and dress'd herself in white Sattin , which is in general looked upon to be the proper Habit for a Bride . As soon as she was dress'd, she went to the Sun Tavern in St. Paul's Church Yard, where they had their former Meeting; it was now about Eight o'Clock in the Morning . There she dispatched another Messenger for 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person319">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person319" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person319" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the East-India House, where he was sure to be in the Way: He came directly to Mrs. Robinson, at the Sun Tavern in St. Paul's Church Yard. As soon as he came, she sent him to Doctors-Commons to procure a Licence for Marriage, in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person320">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person320" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person320" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Hornsey, Batchelor , and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person321">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person321" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person321" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person321" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the same Place, Widow. The Defendant, Taylor, goes to Doctors-Commons, and enquires for Mr. Rushworth, Proctor; this Mr. Rushworth ask'd him whether he was the Person to be marry'd ; he answer'd he was not: Perhaps you will wonder, he that was to personate Mr. Holland, should say he was not Mr. Holland; the Reason of that was, that he had not as yet got on the Cloaths of Mr. Holland that were design'd for him. Upon this Mr. Rushworth told him that he must have one of the Parties themselves come to him, and that Party must enter into a Bond, or make an Affidavit , or he could not grant a Licence. He returned to the Sun Tavern, where the Defendant Robinson was waiting for him, and told her what Mr. Rushworth said; she goes immediately to Mr. Rushworth , and enters into Bond according to the Practice of that Court and Place, and the Place that was fix'd upon for this Marriage , was at St. Andrew's Holbourn; it was not at the Fleet, or any such scandalous Place, therefore the Place fix'd upon was St. Andrew's . When Matters were so far prepar'd, the next Step was, she dress'd up the Defendant , Taylor, in order to personate Mr. Holland; therefore , Gentlemen, he is sent to Mr. Casker for this Box; the Box is delivered to him according to the Direction of the Defendant Robinson; he carries it to Mr. Stangate's in Holbourn, opens the Box, takes out the Coat, Neckloth , and Wig, and puts his own Cloaths in the Box: He then goes immediately to the King's Head Tavern, Holbourn, where the Defendant, Robinson, was waiting for him, to go to be married. When he came there, it was necessary the Wig should be comb'd out; the Wig was comb'd out ; from thence they went immediately to the Church, where the Defendant, Taylor, answer'd to the Name of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person322">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person322" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person322" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and was married in that Name: So they return'd to the King's Head Tavern to take a short Dinner. It was then thought the Business was done. They had then done with the Cloaths of Mr. Holland, therefore the next Thing was to send them out of the Way; so the Defendant, Taylor, goes back to Mr. Stangate's , changes his Cloaths, puts Mr. Holland's Cloaths into the Box, and takes a Person to carry the Box to Mr. Caskers. About an Hour after, the Defendant, Robinson, goes to enquire after this Box; she gets somebody to carry it to Mr. Holland's, and at Mr. Holland's there was a Key of the Box left with the Defendant, Taylor , but it happen'd that the Wig in this Box was missing, and it happen'd likewise there were some Papers in the Coat Pocket, which he put up in a particular Manner, which when he came to see again, he found they were put out of Order: These two Things together, with something Mr. Holland was told, gave him some Suspicion, that he set about searching into this Affair; upon that he took up both the Defendants, and carried them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person323">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person323" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person323" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Defendant, Taylor, made a Confession; we have Evidence of both their Confessions, but we believe we shall hardly have Occasion to make Use of either of them, but there is one Circumstance that may be mentioned, which happen'd upon this Information. The Defendant, Taylor, was ask'd, whether the Marriage was consummated ; upon that the Defendant , Robinson, said, you don't understand the Meaning of that Word; upon that he spoke plainly, that he had not lain with her. I mention this to shew that there was no real Marriage intended by these two Persons, but a fraudulent Marriage to another Person. 'Tis not to be suppos'd , that Persons that had so much Art and Wickedness to conduct a Scheme of this Kind, should have so much Honesty to declare their wicked Intentions, therefore the Fact must be gather'd from Circumstances. Let us consider what would be the natural Consequence of this Marriage, suppose it could have been brought to take Effect, between Mr. Holland, and the Defendant, Robinson; if it took Effect in his Life-time, it would have been the greatest Injury imaginable, not only in Point of Fortune , in marrying 2 Gentleman of Fortune to a Servant, a Person worth nothing , and probably less than nothing, and binding him to a Woman; whereas the very Manner of his being bound to her, he must derest and abhor. If it was to take an Effect after his Death, then it would be a great Loss to the Heirs of Mr. Holland, who would lose so much of their own just Rights . 'Tis not only a Misdemeanour, but of such a heinous Nature ,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150020"></xptr> that there is no Punishment that the Law can inflict for a Misdemeanour , is severe enough.</p>
               <p>Please your Lordship, I am likewise Council for the Prosecution. - Gentlemen, this is an Offence of the most uncommon Kind, as well as of a most wicked and dangerous Tendency. 'Tis a Robbery not only against a single Person, but his Heirs and Executors ; it would leave an Imputation of Charge upon him after his Death: All this was to be effected after his Death, the Consequence of this would have been, to set up Claims for the Distribution of his Estate against his Heirs and nearest of Kin : Nay, it might have been attended with another Consequence ; he might have married a Lady , and have had Children, that this fictitious Marriage might have been set up against his real one, and might prove his lawful Children to be illegitimate, and his Estate go amongst Counterfeits and Impostors.</p>
               <p>The Common Law of England, as 'tis a Law of Mercy, anticipates the Devices of wicked People; therefore, Gentlemen, if we prove this Fact of Confederacy , if that Man did personate Mr. Holland in that Marriage, you will inflict such a Punishment as the Crime deserves, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Court. I am not for going a round-about Way when a shorter is sufficient; you might go through all the other Evidence for the Entertainment of the Audience, but if you prove the Fact 'tis sufficient.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person324">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person324" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person324" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . By Vertue of a Licence from the Commons, the 18th of July, immediately after Morning Prayers, I married a Couple by the Names of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person325">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person325" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person325" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the Parish of Hornsey , Widow, and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person326">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person326" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person326" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Batchelor, of the same Place.</p>
               <p>[The Licence produced in Court.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person327">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person327" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person327" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (By the Council for the Defendants) By what Names did they go?</p>
               <p>Wright. By the Names of Robinson, Widow , and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person328">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person328" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person328" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Batchelor, as mention'd in the Licence.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he (Taylor) was one of them?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it Registered?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, Sir: As to the Woman I can't pretend to say; she had a large Bonnet covered all over her Eyes.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendants. Mr. Wright, since you speak to the Identity of the Man, do you know that you ever saw him before? I suppose you marry a great many Persons. Don't you remember how you came to be so particular as to take upon you to say that these are the Cloaths that the Man wore at that Time?</p>
               <p>Wright. The Man was in so great Confusion that the Sweat run down his Face. He seem'd in the greatest Agony and Confusion whatever.</p>
               <p>Q. Sir, had you a Suspicion that the Man was doing any Thing wrong?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, Sir; but I saw the Man in such a Confusion, that I took particular Notice of him. The Man had a whitish Coat, and the Wig as Mr. Holland has now.</p>
               <p>Council. So the only Reason you judge them to be the same Cloaths, is because he had a white Coat and Wig?</p>
               <p>Wright. I saw them upon Mr. Holland's Back four or five Days after. Mr. Holland call'd to ask me if I could take it upon me to say that he was the Man that I married?</p>
               <p>Council. Sir, was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person329">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person329" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person329" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ? Did you not declare before the Justice that you did not remember the Man nor Woman? Did you at that Time say that you knew the Man at all?</p>
               <p>Wright. I gave a Description of the Man as well as I could?</p>
               <p>Stephen Hall. I am Deputy Clerk of St. Andrew's Holbourn. The Man is the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Woman the same?</p>
               <p>Hall. I can't positively swear to her; I verily believe it to be the Woman, but she had a large Bonnet on; I think that is the Woman that I gave away the 15th of July; but I have brought the Register-Book.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Thing of a Licence produced?</p>
               <p>Hall. The Man brought a Licence, the Minister has it, which is now in Court.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present all the Time of the Ceremony? Were they actually married together, those two Persons?</p>
               <p>Hall. That Man (Taylor) was, and I verily believe it to be the Woman. They were married by the Names of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person330">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person330" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person330" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person331">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person331" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person331" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which I thought something odd, the Woman's Name to be before the Man: The Entry is, July 18, 1746. 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person332">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person332" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person332" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Widow, and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person333">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person333" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person333" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Batchelor, of Hornsey .</p>
               <p>Q. Who made that Entry?</p>
               <p>Hall. Sir, I make these Entries myself.</p>
         
               <p>The Remainder of this Trial, with several other remarkeble ones, will be published in our next .</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17461015-20">
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17461015"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20" type="date" value="17461015"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the COUNTY of MIDDLESEX,</p>
                  <p>Held at Justice-Hall in the Old Baily, On WEDNESDAY the 15th, THURSDAY the 16th, and FRIDAY the 17th of October,</p>
                  <p>In the 20th Year of his MAJESTY'S Reign.</p>
                  <p>BEING THE Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY OF THE</p>
                  <p>Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person334">
                     Richard 
                     Hoare 
                  <interp inst="t17461015-20-person334" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person334" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-20-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VIII. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Sold by C. NUTT, at the Royal-Exchange, and at all the Pamphlet-Shops of London and Westminster. 1746.</p>
                  <p>(Price Six-Pence)</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. As to this Woman at the Bar, did you not say something more positive of her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person335">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person335" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person335" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Hall. No, I said I believ'd her verily to be the Person.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she dress'd?</p>
               <p>Hall. In a white Sattin Gown, with a large Bonnet over her Face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person336">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person336" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person336" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person337">
                  John 
                  Lamb 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person337" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person337" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Lamb. On the 18th of July, between the Hours of Eleven and Twelve, I went into the Church, and went down just as they were going to the Altar ; and I staid all the Time there while they were married. And as to the Prisoner at the Bar, I can safely take an Affidavit to the Man; as to the Woman, I belive her to be the Woman; but she had an extraordinary large black Bonnet on, that I could not see Part of her Face: As to the Man, he had such a large white Coat, that you might almost put a little Boy in it ; you might button it Half a Yard over.</p>
               <p>Q. By what Name did he go?</p>
               <p>Hall. He went then by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person338">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person338" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person338" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of Hornsey .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say, at the Performance of the Ceremony, I 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person339">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person339" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person339" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Hall. Sir, I can't say I was so near as to hear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person340">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person340" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person340" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person341">
                  Mary 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person341" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person341" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you belong to St. Andrew's Church in Holbourn ?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the Church upon the 18th of July, when there was a Marriage there?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at the two People at the Bar, and tell us whether those two were the People that were married.</p>
               <p>Price. Mr. Taylor was the Man, and I believe Mrs. Robinson was the Woman: The Woman was dress'd in a white Sattin Gown, and she had a black Bonnet over her Face.</p>
               <p>Q. What Name was he married by?</p>
               <p>Price. He was married by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person342">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person342" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person342" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person343">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person343" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person343" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person344">
                  Philip 
                  Moor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person344" type="surname" value="Moor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person344" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you?</p>
               <p>Moor. I am Clerk to Mr. Rushworth, of Doctors-Commons. On the 18th of July, between the Hours of Nine and Twelve; 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person345">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person345" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person345" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner at the Bar, came to Mr. Rushworth's Office, and ask'd if he might have a Licence there; I ask'd him if it was for himself; he said, No; I said , One of the Parties must come; upon that he return'd . Accordingly Mrs. Robinson came; she was shewn into the Office, and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person346">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person346" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person346" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went away , and left her there. Mr. Rushworth came down Stairs, and took her up into his Office.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you see this Woman do?</p>
               <p>Moor. Sir, I saw her do no particular Act, but only came for a Licence.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>Moor. I did not hear her say any thing particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe that to be the Licence?</p>
               <p>Moor. I believe so; but I did not see the Inside of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she subscribe an Affidavit?</p>
               <p>Moor. Not in my Presence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150023"></xptr>Council. How came you to be so positive to this Gentlewoman ; did you ever see her before?</p>
               <p>Moor. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. I suppose you don't remember all the Persons that come to your House for Licences. If her Face was cover'd with this Bonnet, my Lad, how came you to be so particular as to her Face.</p>
               <p>Moor. It's a Thing that seldom happens , for a Woman to a apply for a Licence .</p>
               <p>Council. So then, when a Woman applies for a Licence, you more particularly remark her. Had you met this Woman afterwards in the Street, should you have known her?</p>
               <p>Moor. Yes; because, I believe I have seen her before, considerable Time before she liv'd in that Neighbourhood .</p>
               <p>Council. Just now, if I understood you, you said you had not seen her before: If you had been accidentally in her Company, should you have remark'd that she was the same Woman, if you had had no particular Cause to have taken Notice of her?</p>
               <p>Moor . I don't know whether I should or no.</p>
               <p>Council. My Lad, I would ask you, How long was it before any body came to ask you any thing with relation to that Woman ?</p>
               <p>Moor. About nine or ten Days.</p>
               <p>Council. Who was the Person that apply'd to you ?</p>
               <p>Moor. One Mr. Gosling, a Proctor in the Commons.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you then presently recollect the Circumstances of that Woman.</p>
               <p>Moor. When they told me of the Licence , I recollected then.</p>
               <p>Council. When you was first apply'd to, did you, or did you not recollect the Person of the Woman?</p>
               <p>Moor. The Question that was put to me was, Whether I did not remember there was such a Licence? but I could not, at that Instant , recollect that she was the Woman , 'till they told me Circumstances more particular .</p>
               <p>Q. Now, before you recollected that she was the Person of the Woman, did any body remind you of any particular Circumstance to put it into your Memory? The first Time you saw her, did you recollect her?</p>
               <p>Moor. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council . This Mrs. Robinson is a pretty tall Woman; therefore, though she had a Bonnet upon her Head, you might see her Face much easier than another Person, as you are such a short Man .</p>
               <p>Moor . Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Then you were very curious , my Lad , and peep'd very earnestly at it; then it pleas'd you very much.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person347">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person347" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person347" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person348">
                  Henry 
                  Simons 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person348" type="surname" value="Simons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person348" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you? Simons. A Porter; I ply at the Sun Tavern in St. Paul's Church-Yard .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember this Woman, Mrs. Robinson, being at the Sun Tavern the 18th of July?</p>
               <p>Simons. I have no Knowledge of the Woman at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body send you to fetch Mr. Taylor?</p>
               <p>Simons. There was a Woman sent me for the Man that is at the Bar , to the East-India Warehouse in Fenchurch-Street; it was in July, but what Day of the Month I can't tell .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bring that Man ?</p>
               <p>Simon. He did not come with me, but he came about a Quarter of an Hour afterwards, and ask'd me where the Woman was . He was in a darkcolour'd Coat .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person349">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person349" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person349" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person350">
                  John 
                  Loe 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person350" type="surname" value="Loe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you?</p>
               <p>Loe. I am a Drawer .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Robinson, the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Loe . Yes, Sir, she liv'd in the Neighbourhood before ; I don't know any thing but of her sending the Porter for 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person351">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person351" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person351" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the Woman before ?</p>
               <p>Loe . Yes, Sir; I knew Mrs. Robinson a long Time before she liv'd in the Neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. When Taylor came, do you remember Mrs. Robinson's and his going out together ?</p>
               <p>Loe . No, Sir, I don't remember that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person352">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person352" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person352" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person353">
                  Thomas 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person353" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person353" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Did any body , upon the 17th of July, order you to carry a Box from Mr. Holland's House in Hornsey, to Town ?</p>
               <p>Howard. Yes, Sir; Mrs. Robinson, at the Bar, she order'd me to bring the Box to Town, and to leave it at the Stable where her Master puts up his Horses.</p>
               <p>Q. What's the Name of the People?</p>
               <p>Howard. Casker .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person354">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person354" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person354" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Casker) Do you remember a Box brought to your Inn the 18th of July last? Do you know 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person355">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person355" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person355" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Casker . That Man , the Prisoner, came for the Box : Mrs. Robinson came early in the Morning and told me the Man would call for it; the Prisoner came in the Morning to take it away; and in the Afternoon he brought it again. Mrs. Robinson came in the Afternoon to know if the Box was brought ; I said, Yes; then she said, Send it to Mr. Holland's in Newgate-Street .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150024"></xptr>Q. Do you know what was in the Box?</p>
               <p>Casker . No, Sir , I cannot tell .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person356">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person356" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person356" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person357">
                  Robert 
                  Montgomery 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person357" type="surname" value="Montgomery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person357" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner? Have you seen her write ?</p>
               <p>Montgomery . Yes, my Lord, several Times .</p>
               <p>Q. Is that her Writing ?</p>
               <p>Montgomery . Yes, my Lord, I believe it is her Writing .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person358">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person358" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person358" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person359">
                  Miles 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person359" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person359" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know these two Persons at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Parker. I know the Gentlewoman, not by Name, but by Sight, for many Years ago .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember her being at the King's-Head Tavern the 18th of July?</p>
               <p>Parker. I remember she was there, (but I can't remember the Time) and I think that Man, the Prisoner, was with her about Ten o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they dress'd ?</p>
               <p>Parker. She was dress'd in white Sattin and a Bonnet ; she staid there and drink'd a Pint of Wine herself, before that Gentleman came. He went out, and came in again; when he came in again he came in a light-colour'd Coat and a light Wig, and he wanted the Wig comb'd; he said, You need not carry it to the Barber's; Can't you comb it yourself; so I comb'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they do there ?</p>
               <p>Parker . They din'd there .</p>
               <p>Q. What had they for Dinner ?</p>
               <p>Parker. To the best of my Remembrance, they had an Artichoke and a cold Lobster.</p>
               <p>Council. Please your Lordship, and Gentleman of the Jury , I am Council in this Cause , for Mrs. Robinson; against whom there is an Indictment for Conspiracy, &amp;c . And the Gentlemen are extremely sensible , I find, on the other Side , if they had laid this Fact without coupling it with a Conspiracy, that it would not have been at all criminal. Our Common Law don't hinder any People from marrying together by any Name they please; therefore, this Conspiracy only must appear to you to be some Injury to some Person or another, and particularly this Gentleman, who says he is so injur'd . I shall heartily agree with the Doctrine that has been advanced by the Gentlemen on the other Side, with regard to this Conspiracy; but that Intent ought to be made plain ; which must naturally arise from the Fact itself, and not by way of Supposition; for 'tis Conspiracy only, as I apprehend, will make it criminal. I should be sorry to advance Doctrines not establish'd by the Law Common, or by Statutes. I never heard , that particular Persons may not marry by whatsoever Name they please. Supposing People were got in Debt, and it was improper to go by their own Names, and they thought proper to marry by a fictitious Name, and this Name happens to with the Name of some Man or Woman; they may imagine they are injur'd: By what Law is any Man injur'd by it? If they could make out that there has been a Combination on purpose to affect the Estate of a third Person, or on purpose to claim that Estate in their Lifetime; then it would have amounted to a Combination together; it would have amounted to a Conspiracy, to injure a third Person: But, is there any thing like it? Was there any Discourse upon it? What they might have in their Heads, God knows! I never knew any human Judicature could reach the Thoughts or Intentions, 'till Facts were made plain and clear .</p>
               <p>As in the Case of the Lottery Ticket, that was argued in this Place some time ago: Any Person living might take it and cut it to Pieces, and make what Alterations he pleas'd, provided he did it without any Intention to defraud any Person .</p>
               <p>My Lord, this is a Precedent of the most dangerous Consequence; and 'tis stretching the Law upon the suppos'd Fancy of an Indictment-Drawer, beyond whatever was known: If this was to prevail , I could mention an hundred Illconveniencies Persons might be brought into .</p>
               <p>Suppose a Person comes into a Room, and there should happen to be a Parcel of Ladies, and he blows out the Candle; Oh! this is a Rogue, and he intends some Attack upon their Virtue : If a covetous Man; Oh, this is a Rogue; he could blow the Candle out with no other Intention but to pick these Ladies Pockets; and all upon a Supposition; whether the Man ever touch'd one of the Women, or ever attempted to pick a Pocket. So the Drawer of the Indictment is to fancy that this is a criminal Thing, tho' no Fact was ever done. I should agree with you, if she had come and said she was actually married, and had declared her Intention , or had she claim'd any Benefit; but to say , 'till that is done, what I had in my Head, you must take upon yourself that Judgment which the Almighty only can , who knows Thoughts; though this might be a Frolick better let alone: But should not a Woman get her a Husband if she can, and the Man get him a Wife; Marriage is honourable in all; and I could wish People would marry one with another and live such Lives as they should do; the contrary is Batchelor's Doctrine. I never heard Marriage should be call'd Conspiracy, because I have a Mind to marry a Woman by a Name not her own; perhaps it might<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150025"></xptr> be some private End of their own, which the World might not know; perhaps there was an Estate depending upon it . I'll imagine there was as well as they: Suppose she should have married a Person by another Name ; it might be because she would not be despised by her Relations, or in Order to pass well in the World. We are bound never to believe Iniquity unless it appears.</p>
               <p>My Lord there is a great Stress laid upon this Habit, this Dress of the Lady's; she was dressed in Sattin, says the Gentleman, a pure white innocent Sattin; a very proper Dress for a Bride. He would conclude from thence, that she was the Person actually married at this Time: There is no positive Evidence she was married, 'tis only grounded on Supposition. She was dressed in a black Bonnet. That is not conclusive Evidence; a Hundred Ladies may wear white Sattin and have black Bonnets, and the same Day one of these Ladies might be married; and yet a young Gentleman, says he, looked at her very narrowly and could see her Face. It was a wonderful Thing; I think it a great Difficulty to distinguish one Woman from another when muffled up; therefore it was no Wonder if this young Spark might be deceiv'd, as his Curiosity was only led by the Size of this Bonnet. Why, Gentlemen, is so great a Stress to be laid on this Habit because it was white Sattin? That might be emblematical of Innocence; there is something of a particular Softness in the Colour, more agreeable to the Touch than rougher wrought Silk, therefore very proper for a Bride; and I believe 'tis their common Dress: Therefore because it was white Sattin, and a Woman had it on, they conclude this must be the Woman .</p>
               <p>My Lord they have gone through a Train of Evidences; but let us see whether this will amount to Evidence. They give you a Narrative of their meeting at the Stable, there was a Box brought, &amp;c. Here's a Gentleman that fills up Mr. Holland's Coat compleatly, but this Man could not fill it up; which Way was that personating him ? for my Part, I am at a Loss to know ; I should rather think that their Intention was entirely otherwise; or he would have had a Coat that should have fitted him better. What say they then, that there came a Box to Casker's, and then sent to Mr. Holland's: Gentlemen, how can you tell but these Clothes might be lent to the Gentlewoman to get her a Husband. I am told she was not actually a Servant, but came there with the Esteem and Approbation of Miss Andrews, she having had the Tuition of her. If Mr. Holland had a Mind for a Person that was agreeable to him, the Clothes might be taken by his Approbation; I have known frequent Instances of Clothes being given, and sometimes lent by Masters. Why therefore this such a mighty Matter, that a Suit of Clothes should go out of the House? How does this manifest an Intention to do him any Wrong? If I have another Man's Suit of Clothes and am married in them, must it be inferr'd from thence that I intended to get his Estate? They might also have said I intended to rob him, or cut his Throat. I cannot, my Lord, for my Heart, conceive why this Person is to claim this Gentleman in his Life-time; it could not be prov'd, she never did it, or said she was the Wife of Mr. Holland; and why should they say it was to affect him after his Death? This is saying a Thing that I might never have had in my Head; this Intention ought to have been manifested by some overt open Acts done; as if a Man shoots off a Gun into a Place where there are an hundred People walking; there he is doing an unlawful Thing, where the People are in the utmost Danger; but is marrying in itself, by another Name, an unlawful Thing ? Is marrying in another Man's Clothes unlawful; I never heard of it; nor I hope there never will be any such Law. I shall say but one Word more in Favour of my Client, which I hope will be sufficient to conclude this Matter: Supposing , for Instance, that she had private Reasons of her own for obtaining a Husband in some Shape or another. I will suppose now, if we are to go upon Suppositions, that she had done something or another that was improper, that she wanted a Husband, and she had a Mind to conceal his Name; suppose she had a Husband to screen her from Debt, and so married him by another Name; every Creditor of her's might say, that she conspired to marry that Man in order to cheat them of their Debts .</p>
               <p>Council. I am Council of the same Side, Please your Lordship, and you Gentlemen of the Jury, to favour me with a few Words: I beg Leave humbly, in the first Place, to say, if they were married, as the other Side insist upon, then an Indictment for Conspiracy must lie against Husband and Wife; in the next Place I shall shew, that there is no sufficient Proof of the Fact: Then again I would observe, that an Indictment for Conspiracy against Husband and Wife cannot stand; and if your Lordship should be of Opinion with that Part of the Indictment; yet, as 'tis laid, I apprehend the Gentlemen have fail'd in Point of Proof; they have proved no Conspiracy at all; as to injuring the Person of Mr. Holland, I apprehend nothing of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150026"></xptr> that Kind has been proved ; and as to an Injury of his Estate, Goods or Chattels, I apprehend nothing has been prov'd, nor against himself, his Administrators , Heirs, Executors, &amp;c. A Conspiracy, in its Nature, must be to do an Injury to a Third, in regard to his Person or Estate. Gentlemen, as to the Fact, where a Person is to be convicted as a Criminal; where a Person is subjected to a Fine or Imprisonment, there ought to be the clearest Proof in the World. As to the Marriage, I don't apprehend any one Person has been capable to prove the Fact, as to the Identity of the Woman; that is the Fact that you are to try: If there is no Evidence of it, in all Cases of criminal Prosecutions, we are to incline to the favourable Side , which is Mercy. As there has been no Injury done to the Person of Mr. Holland, so I apprehend any two Persons may marry, in any Name whatever, without a Crime; or, if it is a Crime, not punishable by an Indictment. If there had been any Claims on Mr. Holland's Goods or Effects, that might have been Evidence of Intention and Conspiracy; but as nothing of that has been prov'd, so it can't be proved any Injury to him: Persons may have particular Ends to themselves in marrying in what Name they think fit; 'tis not that which constitutes the Offence; but it must be done with a Design to prejudice Mr. Holland; and as he has shew'd nothing of that Sort, no Injury can be done to him or his Successors; therefore they have fail'd in this Point.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-20-person360">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person360" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person360" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I humbly beg this Favour, though they prove my Dress, that you would ask Mr. Holland whether it was not my every Day's Dress; and I don't know , at this Time, whether I had it on or not : Mr. Holland invited me as a Companion to himself; and I have it under his Hand that I was not his Servant. 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person361">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person361" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person361" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person361" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person362">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person362" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person362" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17461015-20-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of Conspiracy.</p>
               <p>[Mr. Holland recommended Taylor to the Favour of the Court, as believing him to be drawn in by the Woman .]</p>
               <p>The Judgment of the Court upon 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person363">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person363" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person363" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was as follows, That you be <rs id="t17461015-20-punish83" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish83" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish83" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-punish83"></join>
               imprison'd for the Space of two Years in the Gaol of Newgate
            </rs>; and after the Expiration of that Time to <rs id="t17461015-20-punish84" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish84" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish84" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-punish84"></join>
               give Security of 500 l.
            </rs> and pay a <rs id="t17461015-20-punish85" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish85" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish85" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend305 t17461015-20-punish85"></join>
               Fine of five Marks
            </rs> .</p>
               <p>As to you, 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person364">
                  George 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person364" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person364" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Sentence that the Court thinks proper to pronounce upon you is, that you be <rs id="t17461015-20-punish86" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish86" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish86" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="otherInstitution"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend304 t17461015-20-punish86"></join>
               imprison'd for six Months in the Poultry-Compter
            </rs>; that <rs id="t17461015-20-punish87" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish87" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish87" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend304 t17461015-20-punish87"></join>
               you give Security yourself in the Sum of 40 l. and two Securities in 40 l. each
            </rs>, and pay a <rs id="t17461015-20-punish88" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish88" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-punish88" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-20-defend304 t17461015-20-punish88"></join>
               Fine of five Marks
            </rs> .</p>
               <p>After Judgment was passed 
               <persName id="t17461015-20-person365">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-20-person365" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-20-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced a Paper to prove that she was not with Mr. Holland as a Servant; but it was not read; she also petition'd the Court for Leave to be remov'd from Newgate, either to the Poultry-Compter or the Fleet-Prison, alledging , that she had been ill, and Newgate was too close for her; but it was denied .</p>
            </div1>
