<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470604-19">
               <interp inst="t17470604-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-19" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470604"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-19" type="date" value="17470604"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-19-off72-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-defend240 t17470604-19-off72 t17470604-19-verdict76"></join>
         
               <p>252. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-19-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Hurlock 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-19-defend240" type="surname" value="Hurlock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-defend240" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17470604-19-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               indicted for Willful Murder, and the Indictment sets forth, That he, not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, and being moved by the Instigation of the Devil, on the <rs id="t17470604-19-cd73" type="crimeDate">11th Day of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-off72 t17470604-19-cd73"></join>, in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470604-19-victim242" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Pitts 
                        <interp inst="t17470604-19-victim242" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-19-victim242" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-19-victim242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-off72 t17470604-19-victim242"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did feloniously make an Assault, and he said 
                     <persName id="t17470604-19-person243">
                        Samuel 
                        Hurlock 
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person243" type="surname" value="Hurlock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-19-person243" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-19-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , with a certain Instrument, called a Bayonet, in the Left Breast, between the 2d and 3d Ribs, did give one mortal Wound, the Breadth of one Inch, and the Depth of four Inches
            </rs>. He stands likewise indicted for the same Murder by the Coroner's Inquest.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person244">
                  William 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person244" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person244" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person245">
                  Samuel 
                  Hurlock 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person245" type="surname" value="Hurlock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person245" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. Will you give an Account to the Jury how 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person246">
                  John 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person246" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came by his End, did you know 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person247">
                  John 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person247" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an Account of what you know how he came by his Death.</p>
               <p>Johnson. In the first Place I heard 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person248">
                  John 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person248" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person248" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             cry out Murder.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Johnson. In Bed, at my Master's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your Master live?</p>
               <p>Johnson. In <placeName id="t17470604-19-crimeloc74">Sugar Loaf Court in Goodman's Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470604-19-crimeloc74" type="placeName" value="Sugar Loaf Court in Goodman's Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470604-19-crimeloc74" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-off72 t17470604-19-crimeloc74"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Master's Name?</p>
               <p>Johnson. My Master's Name is Jones. I am an Apprentice to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner at the Bar lodge there?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner at the Bar <rs id="t17470604-19-deflabel75" type="occupation">Journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-defend240 t17470604-19-deflabel75"></join> to your Master?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lodge in the same Room with Pitts the Deceased, and the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I lay in the same Room, but at the Stair's-head, it was near to them.</p>
               <p>Court. Now give an Account of what you know concerning the Death of this Pitts?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I heard Pitts cry out.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Between Two and Three o'Clock on Monday Morning the 11th of May.</p>
               <p>Court. After Pitts cry'd out Murder what then?</p>
               <p>Johnson. After the Deceased cry'd out Murder, I said what is the Matter; then the Prisoner came to me, but he did not speak a Word, but stabb'd me in the Head with a Dutch Bayonet several times; then he went back again to the old Man, and I went down to my Master.</p>
               <p>Court. And what then?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Then my Master came up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner do any thing to the Deceased?</p>

               <p>Johnson. As I came along the Room I saw the old Man, the Deceased, lay upon the Ground, without a Shirt or Stocking on, and I saw the Prisoner at the Bar stabbing of him, but I could not see what it was with.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Deceased cry out?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, he cry'd out Murder.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040028"></xptr>Q. Did the Deceased say any thing when you cross'd the room?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He said, dear Sam. What are you doing of? Then I went down for my Master, and he came up.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Would you ask this Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you hear me let him in?</p>
               <p>Johnson. That I can't tell , for I was asleep.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see me stabbing him?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes, I did, with one Leg out of the Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person249">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person249" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Give an Account of what you know of this Matter.</p>
               <p>Jones. I heard a Noise in the House, and in a short time after the Boy came down Stairs and cry'd Murder; and said, Master, I am murdered. My Wife let him in; and when he came into the Room his Face look'd as if it had been in a Blood Tub. I did not much mind it when he knock'd at the Door; I thought he had been saucy and they had given him a knock. My Wife says to me, Why don't you get up, Sam. is murdering the old Man? So I went up Stairs; as soon as I got in at the Door, (he stood with this thing in his Hand) I said, 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person250">
                  Sam 
                  What 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person250" type="surname" value="What"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person250" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do you mean by it? I had no sooner said the Word, but he stabb'd me directly.</p>
               <p>(The Witness show'd the Wound to the Court, and produc'd the Instrument with which the Murder was committed.)</p>
               <p>When he stabb'd me in the Belly then I went to seize him, to see what he had got. I thought I had receiv'd a knock. I did not think of a Stab at first: Then I clos'd with him. I saw that he overpower'd me, and I call'd to my Wife and Daughter; and the Girl brought a Candle in her Hand, and the Prisoner attempted to blow the Candle out; and the other lay upon the Floor all the time kill'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Deceas'd say any thing?</p>
               <p>Jones. He said, he will murder you, as he has done me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this that you went up?</p>
               <p>Jones . I can't say directly the time, it might be about two o'Clock. I went up without a Candle , but the Girl brought up a Candle.</p>
               <p>Court. You say you observ'd him standing.</p>
               <p>Jones. I saw him standing, and I thought to struggle with him, but when I went to struggle with him he cut my two Fingers, but I did not part from him till I got this Thing from him. When we had got the Mastery of him, then the Boy went down Stairs, and let the Neighbours in; then he dress'd himself; we were all naked, he , my Wife, and I and the Boy, we had nothing on but our Shirts. The old Man that is dead had never a Shirt on.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing farther?</p>
               <p>Jones. We took the Prisoner up; he was carried to the Cage, from the Cage to the Justice's. I believe what we have said here was said before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Court. You did not examine the Deceased ?</p>
               <p>Jones. I went to the Infirmary after he was there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live after this?</p>
               <p>Jones. It might be two or three Hours; I can't say, it might be more or less.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any Wounds upon him?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, Sir, I saw something stick out of his Belly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Blood?</p>
               <p>Jones. I saw a great deal of Blood upon the Floor; I'll engage a Quart or two; at least there was that, for it soak'd quite through the Cieling. I saw a great many Wounds on a great many Parts of his Body.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Would you ask this Witness any Questions.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You did not see him?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not see you do any thing to him at all; but I felt you hit me; did you not hit me?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person251">
                  Joseph 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person251" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person251" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Richardson. About ten or eleven o'Clock, as I lie next to Hurlock's Room, in another House, I heard a Noise.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a Noise?</p>
               <p>Richardson. I heard a Groaning, then I heard Pitts, the Deceased, cry out Murder. Then said he, Sam. has knock'd me down again. Sam. said he, What have I done to you, that you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040029"></xptr> use me so? A little while after I hears Mr Jones up in the Shop, I heard him say, he has got a Sword or Dagger in his Hand; he cry'd out Murder, to the best of my Knowledge. I went down Stairs and knock'd at the Door, and Johnson the Apprentice came to the Door all bloody. I took the Candle and went up Stairs. I saw the Deceased lie in the Middle of the Room, naked, all bloody, and great Quantities of Blood. The Prisoner never spoke; but the first Word I said, See what you have done? You have killed the Man, his Guts come out - He lay on the Floor all over bloody; he had no other Colour , - the Prisoner had nothing on but his Shirt and Cap.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-19-person252">
                  Thomas 
                  Sheilds 
               <interp inst="t17470604-19-person252" type="surname" value="Sheilds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person252" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What Business are you? Sheilds . An Apothecary .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Deceased ? Give an Account what you observed that might be the Occasion of his Death?</p>
               <p>Sheilds. Between three and four o'Clock on Monday Morning, the 11th of May, the Deceased was brought to the London Infirmary . I found the Deceased in the Agonies of Death . I examin'd several Wounds he had about him; some in his Breast ; some in his Belly; to the Number of thirteen . He had bled a great Quantity of Blood, as I was informed.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of Wounds were they?</p>
               <p>Sheilds . I have seen the Bayonet , and I am ready to think they were made with that . I ordered him to-bed , and a Servant to attend him; and order'd them to give an Attention, if they could hear if he should speak, but he could not speak.</p>
               <p>Court. Will you tell us, whether any of those Wounds were of such a Nature, that you think might be the Cause of his Death?</p>
               <p>Sheilds . I examin'd the Body, and found four Wounds in the Breast, one of which had enter'd the Heart, another the left Lobe of the Lungs, another had entered the Liver an Inch and a half, another Wound had enter'd the Liver four Inches deep; each of which Wounds would have been mortal, and I apprehend, they were the immediate Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner . Will you ask this Witness any Question ? What have you to say for yourself? What Defence do you make ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I let the Deceased in about twelve o'Clock on Sunday Night; after letting him in I went to bed again and he too, and I went to sleep, and some how or other he got himself atop of me about two o'Clock. I awak'd in a Surprize, and I said, Mr Pitts, What are you about to do? Says he, you d - d Dog, I'll murder you. Will you, says I; He gets out of the Bed, and I got out of the Bed, and took that Bayonet, and stood in my own Defence.</p>
               <p>Q. And pray, what had the Deaceased in his Hand ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know of any thing he had , I did not see any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any thing farther to say in your Defence? Or have you any Witnesses to call ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, my Lord, there can be no Witnesses, because there was no body with us.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470604-19-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17470604-19-punish77" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-19-punish77" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-19-defend240 t17470604-19-punish77"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
