<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-34">
               <interp inst="t17400116-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-34" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-34" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-34-off161-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-34-defend245 t17400116-34-off161 t17400116-34-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>118. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-34-defend245" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Nicholls 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-34-defend245" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-defend245" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-defend245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of St. Catherine Cree-Church was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-34-off161" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-off161" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-off161" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Mustard-Caster, Value 50 s.
            </rs> the Goods of the 
               <persName id="t17400116-34-victim246" type="victimName">
                  Provost
                   and Fellows of Oriel College, in Oxford<interp inst="t17400116-34-victim246" type="surname" value="and Fellows of Oriel College"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-victim246" type="given" value="Provost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-victim246" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-34-off161 t17400116-34-victim246"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17400116-34-cd162" type="crimeDate">December 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-34-off161 t17400116-34-cd162"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-34-person247">
                  John 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17400116-34-person247" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 20th of November last, two Silver Casters were lost out of <placeName id="t17400116-34-crimeloc163">Oriel College Hall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-34-crimeloc163" type="placeName" value="Oriel College Hall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-34-crimeloc163" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-34-off161 t17400116-34-crimeloc163"></join>. One was a Pepper-Caster, and the other a Mustard-Caster, with a Mustard-Spoon in it. I missed them when I came to lay the Cloth for Supper, and enquired if they had not been taken to some of the Gentlemens Chambers, but could not get any Intelligence of them. This Caster I brought up from College with me, to compare with what we had lost. I know it belonged to the College. Dr. Hodges is Provost. The Proprietors are called by the Names of the Provost and Fellows of Oriel College in Oxford.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know I stole them? Or can you say you saw me in the College.</p>

               <p>Peters. I know he belongs to Oxford: He work'd at a Cutler's Shop, by the King's-Head-Tavern, and after that he <rs id="t17400116-34-deflabel164" type="occupation">kept a little Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-34-defend245 t17400116-34-deflabel164"></join> of his own, in the Butcher-Row, I can't remember that I have seen him about the College.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-34-person248">
                  Samuel 
                  Nicholls 
               <interp inst="t17400116-34-person248" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person248" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of December, about 11 at Noon, the Prisoner came to my Shop, in the Parish of Cree-Church, and offered this Caster to Sale; 'tis filed both above and below the Swage. I asked him how he came by it? He said he dealt about the Countries, in Silver and Hard-ware, and that he bought it in Oxfordshire, about 50 Miles off, - at a little Town in Banbury Parish. I asked him who he knew there? But when he found I knew the Country, he would say no more, only that he gave 40 s. for it, and paid a Crown an Ounce. I looked upon the Bottom, and saw the Weight engraved on it, 9 Oz. 3 qrs. Upon this I had him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17400116-34-person249">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17400116-34-person249" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who committed him, and bound me to prosecute. I intended to have advertised it, but the next Morning I put it in the Fire to try an Experiment, by which we often find out the Marks which have been filed out. When it was red hot, the Place where the Arms of the College had been, was as black as my Hat, and I could plainly perceive, 3 Lyons passant, and Orie-Col. I informed Mr. Robinson of this, and he advised me to write to Sir John<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160017"></xptr> Boyce of Oxon; which I did, and described the Caster. On Saturday following, I received a Letter from Mr. Bentham of Oriel-College, and he wrote me Word, that the College and the World were obliged to me for my Information; that they had lost such a Thing, and that he had wrote to Mr. Noel, of St. Katherine Cree-Church, to wait on me, and take proper Measures for bringing the Criminal to Justice. This Caster which has been sent up, was made at the same Time with the other, and has the same Marks upon it. On my Oath, I believe the Marks, which have been taken out of this Caster, were the same which are upon this, which is produced from the College. The Piercing is the same, and the Date of the Year likewise. After the Prisoner was committed, Mr. Noel and I went to him in Prison, but he would give no Account how he came by it. He told us, he knew well enough what to say when he came on his Trial.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I go about the Countries, and sell Silver Buttons and Hard-ware with a Licence: I bought this Thing of a Man, who seeing I had Silver-Buttons and Tea-Spoons in my Box, he offered me this Caster, and I bought it of him for 50 Shillings.</p>
               <p>Peters. I know nothing of the Prisoner's Character myself; but before I came up, the Provost and Fellows ordered me, before I came up to London, to enquire into his Character of those who knew him; but I could not find any one who would give him a good one. He had left his Shop, and the Town, when I went to enquire after him. <rs id="t17400116-34-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-34-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
