<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490222-21">
               <interp inst="t17490222-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-21" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-21" type="date" value="17490222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-21-off89-c104" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-defend140 t17490222-21-off89 t17490222-21-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>180. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-defend140" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Burk 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-21-defend140" type="surname" value="Burk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-defend140" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-defend140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , late of <placeName id="t17490222-21-defloc88">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-21-defloc88" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-21-defloc88" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-defend140 t17490222-21-defloc88"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17490222-21-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490222-21-victim142" type="victimName">
                           Terence 
                           Walden 
                        <interp inst="t17490222-21-victim142" type="surname" value="Walden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-21-victim142" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-21-victim142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-off89 t17490222-21-victim142"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   of one waistcoat, value 2 s. and a linnen handkerchief , value 6 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490222-21-cd90" type="crimeDate">February 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-off89 t17490222-21-cd90"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person143">
                  Terence 
                  Walden 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person143" type="surname" value="Walden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person143" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He came to me in <placeName id="t17490222-21-crimeloc91">Lincoln's-Inn fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-21-crimeloc91" type="placeName" value="Lincoln's-Inn fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-21-crimeloc91" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-off89 t17490222-21-crimeloc91"></join> , near Justice Dennison's house, about half an hour after nine o'clock, took hold of my breast and knocked me down, and asked me to deliver my money; I got up again; says I, I have no money, with that he took my waistcoat and handkerchief; he stepped two or three paces back, and held a knife in one hand and a stick in the other; he held the stick over my head, and said damn you, if you do not deliver your money I will rip you open; I cried out and ran, then he ran; so I pursued him down Duke street; he came back again up the other side the square; there squire Oshurae's man met and laid hold of him till I came up; the prisoner said it was not him that robbed me, it was another; there was a watchman and Judge Dennison's man came to my assistance.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220007"></xptr>Q. Are you sure the prisoner at the bar is the person that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Walden. He was never out of my sight , but as he passed the arch he ran through.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to run away?</p>
               <p>Walden. My crying out was the cause of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person144">
                  John 
                  Potts 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person144" type="surname" value="Potts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person144" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am squire Osburne's servant; I was coming up Lincoln's Inn Fields, and believe I was within 20 yards, when I heard the cry, murder! seven or eight times, I pursued and heard somebody run and cry, Stop thief! then I stood still , thinking I could be of no service; presently I saw the prisoner come through the middle arch way; I ran to him and took hold of his collar, but I had strained my leg and could not hold him; but somebody came to my assistance before I had quite dismist him; then I was obliged to go home, and I never saw him since till now.</p>
               <p>Peirce Frances. On February the 3d I was sitting in the kitchen that was backwards, I heard a great cry of murder! stop thief! &amp;c. I listened and lost the found, then I heard it come back again; now thinks I, I shall be time enough; I took a pistol from off the shelf and ran out; as I came into the street, the last witness was carried home lame, and, I believe, I was the next person that laid hold of the prisoner; I told him I would blow his brains out if he stirred. 
               <persName id="t17490222-21-person145">
                  Terence 
                  Walden 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person145" type="surname" value="Walden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person145" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was in the front of him, upbraiding him with what he had done; I think there was another person came much at the time I did; we took him to the Justice's house in the Fields; he was not at home; then we thought proper to search him; in his right hand pocket we found a clasp knife open, then we sent for a constable: the prosecutor had the bundle in his hand, saying to the prisoner, you villain! this is what you took from me; in doubling the prisoner had thrown away the stick and the parcel.</p>
               <p>Q. What said the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Frances. He put up his hand and said, I have had a blow; pretending he had been abused; but I saw no appearance of any blow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person146">
                  Richard 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person146" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person146" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman in Lincoln's-Inn Fields; the third of this month I heard murder cried; I ran directly out of my box towards the cry, as I turned the corner to go to Duke street, I clapped my hand upon the prisoner; the first person I saw was Judge Dennison's servant with a pistol in his hand, saying, if he stirred he would blow his brains out; there was the prosecutor, who said this is the man. We guarded him to Justice White's, about four doors below; he was not at home; then we searched him; there was a clasp knife open took out of his pocket</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person147">
                  John 
                  Lacey 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person147" type="surname" value="Lacey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person147" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a chairman; the prisoner is the person we took; I attended him to prison, and saw the knife took out of his pocket; he was in the possession of three or four men before I came up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person148">
                  John 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person148" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person148" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable; this is the stick Mr. Walden said the prisoner knocked him down with; here is the handkerchief and waistcoat; and this is the knife; it was open thus. [They were shewn in court.]</p>
               <p>Q. to Walden. Is this the stick the prisoner knocked you down with?</p>
               <p>Walden. It is the very stick; he held it over me long enough to give me an opportunity to see it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-21-person149">
                  William 
                  Renolds 
               <interp inst="t17490222-21-person149" type="surname" value="Renolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person149" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the prison; the prisoner is the person delivered to us by the witnesses .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I am a <rs id="t17490222-21-deflabel92" type="occupation">sea-faring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-defend140 t17490222-21-deflabel92"></join>: I had been at Wapping; betwixt nine and ten coming home by Lincoln's-Inn Fields, by the New market, I was knock'd down, my hat took off of my head and six pence took out of my pocket; the thief said, you dog, if you don't run, I will cut you down with my hanger; while I was running these people met and stopped me, and asked me if I was the man that had robbed the prosecutor; I said I had been abused and robbed myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490222-21-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490222-21-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-21-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-21-defend140 t17490222-21-punish94"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
