<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-53">
               <interp inst="t17421208-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-53" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-53" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-53-off266-c438" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-53-defend540 t17421208-53-off266 t17421208-53-verdict268"></join>
         
               <p>60. 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-defend540" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Sharp , otherwise <rs id="t17421208-53-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-53-defend540 t17421208-53-alias-1"></join>Sparkes</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-defend540" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-defend540" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-defend540" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17421208-53-off266" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-off266" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-off266" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing one Pair of Stays, a Holland Apron, a black Silk Hood, a Child's Dimity Coat, and other Things
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-victim542" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Leake 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-53-victim542" type="surname" value="Leake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-victim542" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-victim542" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-53-off266 t17421208-53-victim542"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             , <rs id="t17421208-53-cd267" type="crimeDate">Oct. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-53-off266 t17421208-53-cd267"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs Leake . My Child had the Small-Pox, and the Apothecary told me it was a bad Sort, and if I nurs'd it, I should be in Danger of my Life; so I got this Woman to look after it, and left her in Charge. I missed several Things: Said I, they cannot go out of the Drawers without being took. I missed likewise a Silver Spoon out of the Beauset. I charged her with them, and she stood very stiff in it that she had them not. I took up my Maid, 
               <persName id="t17421208-53-person543">
                  Ann 
                  Fell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person543" type="surname" value="Fell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person543" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person543" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; said she, I do not think but what Betty (that is the Prisoner, for so she is called in the Market) ought to be taken up as well as I, for I saw her take a white Frock out of the Drawer. About a Month afterwards I had a Search-Warrant from Justice Poulson , and I found the Things at Mrs Motte's, at Islington.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person544">
                  Sarah 
                  Motte 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person544" type="surname" value="Motte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person544" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person544" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep a Chandler's-Shop at Islington , and sell Meat. The Prisoner came late one Night to Islington, and left this little Bundle along with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lend any Money upon them, or let her have any Geneva ?</p>
               <p>Motte . I do not sell any. I opened the Bundle while she was there, to see what was in it. Mr Leake came and took them with a Search-War rant: It was about six Weeks ago, which was the next Day after she left them. Her Husband is gone as a Marine: he is a small Relation of my Husband's. - She had a very good Character before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person545">
                  Robert 
                  Leake 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person545" type="surname" value="Leake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person545" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Beginning of July, 
               <persName id="t17421208-53-person546">
                  Ann 
                  Fell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person546" type="surname" value="Fell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person546" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person546" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was hired as a Servant to me: The Child being ill of the Small-Pox, and my Wife not having had them, we trusted her with the House. I missed a Silver Spoon, and several Things: I charged her with them, and she threatned to sue me for Scandal: We let it lie dormant to the Middle of September, and missed other Things afterwards. 
               <persName id="t17421208-53-person547">
                  Sarah 
                  Sparkes 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person547" type="surname" value="Sparkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person547" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person547" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             kept out of the Way, and I was informed there was a Bundle left at Mrs Motte's at Islington; I got a Search-Warrant, and at Mrs Motte's, and another House, found the Things mentioned in the Indictment, and then took up the Prisoner. The Prisoner said she bought the Apron of 
               <persName id="t17421208-53-person548">
                  Ann 
                  Fell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person548" type="surname" value="Fell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person548" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person548" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , our Servant, for 2 s. and that 
               <persName id="t17421208-53-person549">
                  Ann 
                  Fell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person549" type="surname" value="Fell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person549" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person549" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave her the Stays which were taken off her Back at Justice Poulson's. When I took hold of her, she put two Half Guineas into my Hand, and said, there is the full Value of the Things that I had: I said, as she had been concerned with Thieves, you must take your Fate with the rest. I have not found the twentieth Part of the Things I lost.</p>
               <p>Wm Peck . I had a Search-Warrant brought me to search the House of one Morgan, and found but a Trifle there; when I served the Body Warrant on her, she slipped two Half-Guineas into my Hand, and begged I would let her go; I believe she put them into my Hand above twenty Times; I told her, if she would give me as many Guineas as there were Days in the Year, I would not take it. I carried her to one Sprag's , there she put the Money into my Hand again several Times, and finding I would not take it, she would fain have got off, and have left the Child she had in her Arms.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at Mr Leake's House when the Child had the Small-Pox; she had given the Maid these Things, and the Maid said, if I would come an Hour or two sooner, of an Evening, she would give me something to make me amends.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person550">
                  Mary 
                  Pritchet 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person550" type="surname" value="Pritchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person550" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person550" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About six Months ago, Mrs Leake came to my House, and said she would swear a Robbery against this Woman and transport her; says this poor Woman, pray, Madam, do not expose me, your Maid gave them to me. Says she, you are a lying Bitch - She said she would either hang her or transport her. - I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080040"></xptr> trusted her in the Market, and never lost the Value of a Penny by her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person551">
                  Sarah 
                  Sallery 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person551" type="surname" value="Sallery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person551" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person551" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . This Woman has been a Chair-woman a great many Times; I have trusted her with Linnen, Brass and Pewter, and other Things, which she might have stole; and I never lost any Thing, and I believe what she is charged with, is owing to their Maid; I believe her to be as honest a Creature as ever came into a House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person552">
                  John 
                  Miltax 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person552" type="surname" value="Miltax"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person552" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known this Woman these two Years; I have trusted her with Linnen and other Things, and never lost any Thing in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person553">
                  Ann 
                  Crook 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person553" type="surname" value="Crook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person553" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person553" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . She has worked at our Shop this Year and half; I have trusted her with Things and never missed any, and believe her to be a very honest Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-53-person554">
                  Joseph 
                  Calloway 
               <interp inst="t17421208-53-person554" type="surname" value="Calloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person554" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-person554" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her these two Years; she has carried Meat for me, and received the Money for it, and brought it me; I never found she wronged me, and believe her to be a very honest Woman.</p>
               <p>Leake. Mrs Pritchet and I have been at Law together, and she does it out of Spight.</p>
               <p>Pritchet. Yes, my Lord, we have been at Law together, and I believe the Prisoner at the Bar has a better Character than the Prosecutrix. <rs id="t17421208-53-verdict268" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-53-verdict268" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
