<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470604-28">
               <interp inst="t17470604-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-28" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470604"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-28" type="date" value="17470604"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-28-off110-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-28-defend318 t17470604-28-off110 t17470604-28-verdict113"></join>
         
               <p>261. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-28-defend318" type="defendantName">
                     Martha 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-28-defend318" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-defend318" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-defend318" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17470604-28-off110" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-off110" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-off110" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               she not having the Fear of God, but being moved by the Instigation of the Devil , by striking, or pushing down to the Ground, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470604-28-victim320" type="victimName">
                           Henrietta 
                           Swetman 
                        <interp inst="t17470604-28-victim320" type="surname" value="Swetman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-28-victim320" type="given" value="Henrietta"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-28-victim320" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-28-off110 t17470604-28-victim320"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , did give one mortal Wound on the back-part of her Head, of which mortal Wound Henrietta , the <rs id="t17470604-28-viclabel111" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-28-victim320 t17470604-28-viclabel111"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17470604-28-person321">
                        James 
                        Swetman 
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person321" type="surname" value="Swetman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-28-person321" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-28-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , instantly dy'd
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17470604-28-cd112" type="crimeDate">May the 27th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-28-off110 t17470604-28-cd112"></join> .</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-28-person322">
                  James 
                  Swetman 
               <interp inst="t17470604-28-person322" type="surname" value="Swetman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person322" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know 
               <persName id="t17470604-28-person323">
                  Martha 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17470604-28-person323" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person323" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person323" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Sweetman . She liv'd upon the same Floor, at one Mr May's, a Potter's Shop; between ten and eleven o'Clock at Night, 
               <persName id="t17470604-28-person324">
                  Martha 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17470604-28-person324" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person324" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-person324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and knock'd at the Door of our Room, and said, She would break the Door open. With that my Wife bid this Boy by me open the Door. I was in Bed when she came into the Room, She demanded the Bolster , and Words arose . My Wife said, she should not have the Bolster till we had the things she had of ours. I bid her to depart the Room, but she did not think proper to do it. She said she would not go till she had her Bolster. So my Wife was going across the Room she either struck my Wife, or push'd her, I can't say which . My Wife fell; I seeing my Wife falling, I jump'd out of Bed. I saw her Hand go; whether it was pushing or striking I can't say; and my Wife never spoke afterwards .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go and look upon your Wife?</p>
               <p>Swetman . I went to my Wife to give her some Water, but there was no Passage. Mrs May, the Woman of the House, came to the Door. I said I was busy with my Wife, I could not open it. With that she said, she would break it open. I went and open 'd the Door, and she came or look 'd into the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did your Wife lay from the Door?</p>
               <p>Seaman. But a little Way.</p>
               <p>Q. How came Mrs May to know it?</p>
               <p>Seaman. When I got out of Bed, after the Prisoner had flung my Wife down, this Woman, the Prisoner , cried out Murder; and this Mrs May came in, or look'd in, and said, Lord have Mercy upon me, she is dead. I went to lift her up on the Bed, and her Head fell every Way , and never stirr'd more. Immediately after that the Constable and Watchmen came, and she, the Prisoner, was committed, and I also, till the Coroner had sat upon her; and it was the Opinion of them, I heard, that the Fall was the Cause of her Death. When I charg'd the Prisoner she charg'd me, and I was put into Consinement .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040037"></xptr>Q. Did you examine your Wife what was the Matter with her; whether there was any Bruise upon her?</p>

               <p>Swetman. Before two o'Clock I was in the Watch-house .</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body examine her ?</p>
               <p>Swetman. I heard there was a Fracture in her Head , which they thought was the Occasion of her Death.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Wife well before this happen'd?</p>
               <p>Swetman . Yes, she was about to eat her Supper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did no body examine your Wife, to see what was the Matter with her?</p>
               <p>Swetman . None, to my Knowledge, it was not in my Power to send any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is the other Witness?</p>
               <p>Swetman. My Son, this Child; none but he was by.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is that Boy?</p>
               <p>Sweetman . If he lives till next October he will be ten Years old.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. What have you to say to this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I went into the Room for a Bolster I had lent them two Months before. I wanted it for a Person that came to lie with me. They insisted upon it, that I should not have it. He got out of Bed and struck me, and throw'd me down. In the mean time his Wife fell down. I disputed with him, and not with her; the Woman never touch'd me, nor I her.</p>
               <p>- May. I was at Supper, and about eleven o'Clock the Prisoner at the Bar went from me. This House joins to the House that I live in. As I was at Supper, I could hardly have thought she was got up Stairs, one Upton told me there was a Cry of Murder in the House. I turned into the Shop, and said, What Confusion is this, to have Murder cry'd? When I came in I met the Prisoner at the Bar. I said, Where is Murder cry'd? And they said, it was in Swetman's Room. The Deceased fell so near the Door that I could not push forwards. I look'd in, and said, Oh dear! What is done? I look'd in, and there was the Husband and Son. I knock'd at the Door, and he did not open it for some time; and I said, if he did not open it I would break it open by Violence; and when I insisted upon the Door being open'd, he said, I will let you in presently, and he opened the Door; and he said, I was giving my Wife some Water. I look'd, but there was none . He was first charg'd. The Prisoner was without side of the Room when she cry'd Murder.</p>
               <p>- Upton. I was in my own Apartment. I lodge in the same House. I heard Murder cry'd. Mrs Williams cry'd Murder. I ask'd Mr May, as he was Landlord of the House, to go up with me. I said, for God's sake, don't let there be Murder cry'd in the House and no body go up. I went up, and I saw the Deceased, some Part of her was upon the Bed, and some Part on the Ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Wound upon the Woman that was dead?</p>
               <p>Upton . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look for any?</p>
               <p>Upton. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470604-28-verdict113" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-28-verdict113" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
