<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410514-24">
               <interp inst="t17410514-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-24" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410514-24" type="date" value="17410514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410514-24-off114-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-defend219 t17410514-24-off114 t17410514-24-verdict118"></join>
         
               <p>26. 
               <persName id="t17410514-24-defend219" type="defendantName">
                  Gerrard 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-defend219" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-defend219" type="given" value="Gerrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-defend219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17410514-24-defloc113">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-24-defloc113" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-24-defloc113" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-defend219 t17410514-24-defloc113"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410514-24-off114" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-off114" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-off114" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17410514-24-victim220" type="victimName">
                        Elizabeth, the <rs id="t17410514-24-viclabel115" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-victim220 t17410514-24-viclabel115"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-person221 t17410514-24-viclabel115"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17410514-24-person221" type="victimName">
                              Roger 
                              Connor 
                           <interp inst="t17410514-24-person221" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17410514-24-person221" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17410514-24-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim220" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim220" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her, a Cloth-pocket, value 1 d. one Guinea, and 3 s. 1 d. in Money
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of the said 
               
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-victim223" type="victimName">
                     Roger 
                     Connor 
                  <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim223" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim223" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-victim223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            ; <rs id="t17410514-24-cd116" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-off114 t17410514-24-cd116"></join>.</p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's Desire, the Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person224">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Connor 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person224" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person224" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 8th of April, between 10 and 11 at Night, I was going to the Corner of Plumbtree-Street , for some Butter and Sugar, and as I was coming home to <placeName id="t17410514-24-crimeloc117">Denmark-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-24-crimeloc117" type="placeName" value="Denmark-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410514-24-crimeloc117" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410514-24-off114 t17410514-24-crimeloc117"></join>, the Prisoner met me, and knocked me down. I cried out, and turned about, to look in his Face, and saw two Men at a Distance, standing still. I saw the Prisoner's Face perfectly, by the Light of the Lamps. He had a Knife in his Hand, with which, as soon as he had knocked me down, he cut off my pocket. I attempted to cry out again, but he told me, if I spoke a Word, he would certainly cut my Throat. I had in my pocket, a Guinea, and 3 s. and 1 d. or 3 Halfpence; and as soon as he had taken it away, he went up to the two Men, and I strove to creep home as well as I could. The next Morning this piece of my pocket was found by a Milkman, in the place where I was robbed; and it agrees exactly with that piece which was left behind.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How came she to know me that Night?</p>
               <p>Connor . I was acquainted with him before; he came into my House, the Day before this, and burst into the back Room, and asked if it was to be lett; so that I took particular Notice of him.</p>
               <p>Jury. What Distance were the two Men from you?</p>
               <p>Connor . About 20 or 30 Yards.</p>
               <p>Jury. By what Light could you distinguish them?</p>
               <p>Connor. By the Light of a Lamp, about 5 or 6 Yards off.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her how far she was from a House when she was knocked down?</p>
               <p>Connor . It was in the Street, and there are Houses on each side of the way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Time of Night did she leave the Shop where she went to buy the Sugar?</p>
               <p>Connor . Between 10 and 11 o'Clock, and presently afterwards the Prisoner met me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If her pocket was cut off, why did not she take the Watchman from his Stand, and follow me?</p>
               <p>Connor . I saw no Watchman, nor no body; for the place was quite clear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person225">
                  Henry 
                  Atterbury 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person225" type="surname" value="Atterbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person225" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I took the Prisoner on Thursday in last Sessions, in a Cobler's Shop. When I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174105140014"></xptr> laid hold of him, the Cobler swore he would stab me; and the Prisoner got from me, and ran up Stairs, but at last we took him; and after we had handcuffed him, we brought him to an Alehouse , where he told me. that 2 other Men were concerned with him in the Robbery. This was at Humphries's , the Constable's House, and we were by ourselves. While we were together, a Woman came to him , and put some Money into his pocket, and bid him puff no body.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he ever see me before that Day?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. No, I never did, to my Knowledge .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was he entrusted with me any part of the Day?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. Yes, they all went out of the Room, and left us together; and he told me every particular Word.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How came he to light on me?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. I was coming from Kensington Gravel-pits , to meet Mr. Jenkinson, an Attorney, and there happening to be a Mob, I went to see what it was, and was charged to assist the Constable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was he at Work that Week?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. I am a House-carpenter, and work at it sometimes, in doing Jobbs for one and another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person226">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person226" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Milkman, and as I was going about my Business, picked up this piece of the Woman's pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Time in the Morning did he find it?</p>
               <p>Wright. I believe it was about half a quarter of an Hour past Seven.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person227">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person227" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person227" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came from Bristol about 2 Months ago, and wanting private Lodgings, I took a Room in Cornor's House. One Night, about 9 or 10 o'Clock - I can't tell what sort of Time it was, but I believe it was about 6 Weeks ago, I saw Mrs. Connor's Husband give her a Guinea and some Silver, and she went out. She returned as dirty as if she had been rolled in the Kennel, and said, she had been robb'd; that three Men were concerned, and that she knew the person who knocked her down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What did you say to Mrs. Connor when she went out?</p>
               <p>Porter. Her Husband asked her, why she had not got Butter and Sugar; and then she fetch'd him some white , and some brown Sugar; I believe there were about 3 pounds and an half of each .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see any Gold in Mrs. Connor's Hand, when she went out ?</p>
               <p>Porter. Yes, her Husband handed the Guinea over the Counter to me, and I gave it to her.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Woman's Husband is a Smugler . On the 7th of April, I took up one Kennedy, a Smugler , who lodges in their House, for calling me Informer, because I had made a Discovery of a great deal of Tea, and they were lying in wait to shoot me; and because I made this Discovery, they have sworn fastly against me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person228">
                  Patrick 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person228" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person228" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the Prisoner in the Street , and he asked me, if I knew one Kennedy , a Smugler , and desired me to go to Connor's, to ask him to bail him: accordingly I told Connor the Story; but he would not bail Kennedy.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not Connor threaten what he would do to me, if I informed against any of his Lodgers?</p>
               <p>Kelly. I know nothing at all of that. I remember nothing else said by Connor in relation to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Katharine Kelly. I am Wife to the last Witness, and what I have to say, I will say very true. I came to the Prisoner's House, the Night before he was taken, between 7 and 8 o'Clock, which was the very Night that Connor says she was robbed: The Prisoner was sitting by the Fire, with some Oatmeal to make a little Broth for himself and his Wife. I was for going Home, but he desired me to get his Supper ready; so I staid 'till near one o'Clock in the Morning; and I declare on my Oath, he never left the House, from the Time that I went in, to the Time of my coming away. His Wife is my Sister, and she and her Children were lying on the Bed at the same Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person229">
                  John 
                  Longhton 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person229" type="surname" value="Longhton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Prisoner; I never saw him before to-day in my Life. As to Atterbury , he is a very extravagant Fellow, and has spent a great deal of Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would perjure himself?</p>
               <p>Loughton. I can't charge him with that - I can't judge of people's Consciences. - I did say, that if he had a great deal of Money, he would be very troublesome.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Atterbury said at the Gate to Day, that if he should hang me, he should have a great deal of Money, and would drive all Kensington Gravel-pits before him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person230">
                  Sarah 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person230" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person230" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Wednesday was 5 Weeks I was at the Prisoner's House; his Wife was sick a Bed, and 2 Children along with her. The Prisoner was sitting by the Fire-side, and there was a pot boiling on the Fire, with a Breast of Mutton in it. I went there just as St. Giles's Bell rung Nine, and as I came out of the House, the Watchman went Eleven; and the Prisoner was not out of the House all the Time. Mrs. Kelly was there, and I left her and another Woman, whose Name is Gough , behind me when I went away.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to recollect the Time?</p>
               <p>Graham. I lodged in his House 3 Quarters of a Year; I left it on the Saturday , and went to fetch some Things away from thence .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person231">
                  Jane 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person231" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person231" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Wednesday Night I went to see the Prisoner's Wife and Children, and he lay on the Foot of the Bed; to the best of my Knowledge, it was in April. I went there about 10 o'Clock,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174105140015"></xptr> and found his Wife and 3 Children sick ; and his Brother and Sister were there at the same Time. I staid with them the best part of an Hour; and the Prisoner had a Breast of Mutton boiling on the Fire; and he never stirr'd out of the House while I was there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person232">
                  Richard 
                  Humphries 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person232" type="surname" value="Humphries"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person232" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was Constable, and apprehended the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not desire me to make myself an Evidence?</p>
               <p>Humphries. I told him t hen was his Time to save himself, and he said he knew nothing at all of the Matter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he trust me in the Care of Atterbury alone that Day?</p>
               <p>Humphries. I had him to my own House; and it was in the Fore-room, and we were in and out all Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Atterbury there?</p>
               <p>Humphries . Yes, he was there all Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge Atterbury to assist you?</p>
               <p>Humphries. No, I did not, the Man that I charged to assist me is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the Prisoner and Atterbury together alone any part of the Day?</p>
               <p>Humphries. They might be alone for some small Space of Time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he hear me say to Atterbury, there were 2 Men concerned with me?</p>
               <p>Humphries. No I did not, nor any Thing like it.</p>
               <p>Q. During the Time that the Prisoner was in your Custody, what did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Humphries . He always insisted that he knew nothing of what he was charged with.</p>
               <p>Jury. Who was the 1st Man that laid hold of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Humphries. It was one Horsenail, a Plumber in Cow Lane .</p>
               <p>Q. to Atterbury. How came you to go to this Constable's House with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. Humphries shew'd me the Warrant at the Cobler's Door , so I and another Man catched hold of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Where did I tell him that 2 Men were concerned with me?</p>
               <p>Atterbury. It was in the Fore Box, and he would have told me every Thing had not the Woman come in, and given him Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person233">
                  James 
                  Ingram 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person233" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person233" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have seen the Prisoner at an Alehouse which I used, and never knew any Harm of him. I was present when Mrs. Connor brought the Warrant to the Constable's House, and then we went to the Cobler's, were the Prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire this Witness may be asked, how long he sat with me at Humphries's House, and whether I was not asked divers Times to make myself an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Ingram. There were 2 or 3 People that asked him to be an Evidence, and he said, would you have me be an Evidence of what I know nothing at all of? I was in the House with him from the Time he was taken, to the Time that he went before Mr. De Veil, and he always continued in the same Story, and never made any Confession at all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he hear me own that there were two other Persons concerned with me in this Robbery?</p>
               <p>Ingram. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person234">
                  Joshua 
                  Bewley 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person234" type="surname" value="Bewley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person234" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Officer of the Excise. Connor is a Smugler, and the Prisoner has been very serviceable to the Revenue. I have seized Tea my self several Times on his Information.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person235">
                  Thomas 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person235" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person235" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Officer of the Excise. I have made several Seizures on the Prisoner's Informations, and in particular, the last Time I was out with him, the Prosecutrix and some others threatned him, and said they would serve him such a Trick as should make him smart before it was long, for at that Time he had given me an Information against these People.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person236">
                  Martin 
                  Colton 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person236" type="surname" value="Colton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person236" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I likewise am an Officer of the Excise, and have had several Informations from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person237">
                  Francis 
                  Waker 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person237" type="surname" value="Waker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person237" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Stove Grate Maker, and the Prisoner has been a Servant to me off and on for 8 or 9 Years, and always behaved well. As to his general Character, I never heard that he was a Thief in my Life, and as to the House which Connor keeps, I have been there myself, and have been informed that they are all a Parcel of Smuglers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person238">
                  Henry 
                  Downes 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person238" type="surname" value="Downes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person238" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner these 5 or 6 Years: I always took him to be a hard working Man, and never heard him charged with Theft.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person239">
                  Lewis 
                  Sellier 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person239" type="surname" value="Sellier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person239" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He worked for me last Winter, and I always took him to be an honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person240">
                  Patrick 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person240" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person240" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner worked on the same Floor with me, and always labour'd very hard.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person241">
                  Mary 
                  Melon 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person241" type="surname" value="Melon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person241" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three Years: he lived next Door to me, and I never heard any ill Thing of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410514-24-person242">
                  Ann 
                  Kalendar 
               <interp inst="t17410514-24-person242" type="surname" value="Kalendar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person242" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him three Years. On the 7th of April, I was going by Connor's House and saw the Prisoner in the Shop, and he desired me to drink with him, but I saw such a Heap of Folks there, that I did not chuse to go in. <rs id="t17410514-24-verdict118" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410514-24-verdict118" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
