<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-70">
               <interp inst="t17431207-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-70" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-70" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-70-off361-c476" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend617 t17431207-70-off361 t17431207-70-verdict364"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-70-off361-c477" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend620 t17431207-70-off361 t17431207-70-verdict364"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-70-off361-c478" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend622 t17431207-70-off361 t17431207-70-verdict364"></join>
         
               <p>+ 
               <persName id="t17431207-70-defend617" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Clifford 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17431207-70-alias-12" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend617 t17431207-70-alias-12"></join>Boston</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend617" type="surname" value="Clifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend617" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend617" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-defend620" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Ettington 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend620" type="surname" value="Ettington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend620" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend620" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-defend622" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Kaines 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend622" type="surname" value="Kaines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend622" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-defend622" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of <placeName id="t17431207-70-defloc360">St. Buttolph Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-defloc360" type="placeName" value="St. Buttolph Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-defloc360" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend617 t17431207-70-defloc360"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend620 t17431207-70-defloc360"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-defend622 t17431207-70-defloc360"></join> , were indicted for <rs id="t17431207-70-off361" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-off361" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-off361" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431207-70-victim624" type="victimName">
                           Margaret 
                           Gyles 
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim624" type="surname" value="Gyles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim624" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim624" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her three Ells of Holland, value 10 s. one Yard of Cambrick, value 4 s. 6 d. and a Silk Handkerchief, value 4 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431207-70-victim626" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Gyles 
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim626" type="surname" value="Gyles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim626" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and a Cloth Cloak, value 10 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-victim628" type="victimName">
                     Susanna 
                     Frenson 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim628" type="surname" value="Frenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim628" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-victim628" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17431207-70-cd362" type="crimeDate">Nov. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-off361 t17431207-70-cd362"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-person629">
                  William 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17431207-70-person629" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person629" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person629" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Beadle and Constable of Portsoken Ward. The 21st of Nov. at Night I was sent for to Mrs. Dudley's at the Queen's Head in <placeName id="t17431207-70-crimeloc363">Harrow Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-crimeloc363" type="placeName" value="Harrow Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-70-crimeloc363" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-70-off361 t17431207-70-crimeloc363"></join>, upon Account of two Women being robbed; Mrs. Gyles and Mrs. Frenson were there; one of them was just come out of a Fit and very dirty; they said, they had been robbed by a Woman and five Boys; Ettington was there, and said that I knew the Persons who had committed the Robbery; I think he said it was Green-Gown Mary (that is the Prisoner) with two Carmen. I took 
               <persName id="t17431207-70-person630">
                  Mary 
                  Clifford 
               <interp inst="t17431207-70-person630" type="surname" value="Clifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person630" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person630" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that Night, out of Bed at Mrs. Sturgis's in Gravel-Lane; and she was next Day committed to the Poultry Compter. The Friday following Mrs. Gyles and Ettington came to me about finding these Carmen that committed the Robbery; there were some Thieftakers employed, and they brought Pugg to me, that is, this Ettington. Said I, this Person I can take at any time, and I don't think him guilty; they said, stay a little while, and we will bring you another; then they brought Kaines, and Kaines said, he had his Hand under Gyles's Coats while Clifford committed the Robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-person631">
                  Margaret 
                  Gyles 
               <interp inst="t17431207-70-person631" type="surname" value="Gyles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person631" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person631" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of November, coming along Somerset Street, between six and seven in the Evening, Mrs. Frenson, seeing some Bottles and Glasses in a Window, said she was a little sick, and we went in; in comes this 
               <persName id="t17431207-70-person632">
                  Mary 
                  Clifford 
               <interp inst="t17431207-70-person632" type="surname" value="Clifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person632" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person632" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and five Fellows; said Mrs. Frenson, that is the Woman that knocked me down. Said I, you may be mistaken; you can't swear to People's Faces; I spoke to the Prisoner, and asked her to go aside [to a private Place] - I asked her, because I thought she was not the Person Mrs. Frenson took her to be. I went out, and she with me; and when we came to the Corner of Somerset Street, coming from Harrow Alley by the vacant Place - about four or five Doors from the Place where we were drinking, she whistled and said, Now you B - h I will have my Revenge on you; I will cut your Throat from Ear to Ear; she said she would have my Heart's Blood, she would present the Blood Bowl to me; upon her whistling, the two Prisoners and three more Fellows came and surrounded me, and Clifford took Frenson's Cloak off my Back, and my Bundle from me; and then they all ran away in a Body together - I am sure that those two Youths are part of the Gang - The five Men rifled my Coats - Both the Prisoners had one Hand, if not both under my Petticoats - They did nothing else, they did not take any thing from me - I never saw the Woman before - I did cry out, but I could not cry out at the first Threatning, because they muffled my Head - One of the Boys went to kiss me with one Hand round my Neck, and the other under my Clothes - It was while they were kissing me, she took the Things - After I cried out Stop Thief three times; Clifford came back again with the Cloak over her Arm and the Bundle in her Hand. and knocked me down in the Mud, and said, take that in the room of the Blood Bowl.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frenson confirmed Mrs. Gyles's Evidence; that when Mrs. Gyles asked to go aside, Clifford took her into the vacant Place by Harrow Alley, and whistling, five Fellows came round her, some like Carmen, and some like Butchers, but could not swear to either Ettington or Kaines, any farther than seeing them in the Shop - that one of the five Men put his Hand under Gyles's Clothes, and another kissed her, while Clifford took away the Bundle, and then ran all away together; that upon crying out, Stop Thief! Clifford came back again, and pushed them both in the Mud, and stamped upon the Small of Mrs. Gyles's Back, and said, you B - h, take that instead of the Blood Bowl.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Lamp?</p>
               <p>Frenson. There was a Lamp or two at a Distance, but I could not well distinguish the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gyles . Did not you see these two Boys that Night at the Queen's Head in Harrow Alley?</p>
               <p>Gyles. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to charge them then?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070038"></xptr>Gyles . Because I had no Assistance.</p>
               <p>Q. You had the Constable along with you, and might have had what Assistance you pleased.</p>
               <p>Gyles. There was not Assistance enough to carry them to Goal; I said that Night that Ettington was one of the Fellows - I did not know Kaines so well as the other, that was the Reason I did not accuse him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see these two Boys at the Queen's Head that Night?</p>
               <p>Frenson. Yes -</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not Mrs. Gyles charge them then?</p>
               <p>Frenson. Because she was in a Fit - Ettington said to me, if you will come to morrow at eleven o'Clock, you shall have your Things produced .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-70-person633">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17431207-70-person633" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person633" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Ettington told me there had been a Robbery committed upon two Women; I went with him to the Watch-house, and fetched Mr. Day the Constable; Ettington went with me into the Queen's Head, and the Women were there, and they did not offer to charge him - I am sure the Women were in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Day. Mrs. Gyles was just come out of a Fit, I did not perceive them to be in Liquor. All <rs id="t17431207-70-verdict364" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-70-verdict364" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
