<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470604-25">
               <interp inst="t17470604-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-25" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470604"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-25" type="date" value="17470604"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-25-off97-c237" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-25-defend284 t17470604-25-off97 t17470604-25-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>258. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-25-defend284" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Stabock 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-25-defend284" type="surname" value="Stabock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-defend284" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-defend284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470604-25-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three Guineas and ten Shillings in Money, and eight Pounds weight of Pickle Pork
            </rs> , the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-25-victim286" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Alcock 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-25-victim286" type="surname" value="Alcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-victim286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-victim286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-25-off97 t17470604-25-victim286"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470604-25-cd98" type="crimeDate">August the 29th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-25-off97 t17470604-25-cd98"></join>.</p>
               <p>Council. I am of Council for the Prosecution, and the Indictment charges her with stealing th ree Guineas, and ten Shillings in Money, and eight Pounds weight of Pork. Gentlemen, The Cafe I have to lay before you is as wicked a one as ever appeared. It is not only a Crime Committed by herself , but 'tis seducing a Youth of about thirteen Years of Age to be a confederate with her in robbing of her Master. The Case as I am instructed is this; She was hired to live with the Prosecutor Mr Alcock; she continued there but a little white; and there was a Boy, one 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person287">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person287" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person287" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , about thirteen Years of Age, employed by Mr Alcock to look after his Shop; this Maid inveigles this Boy by a Way, which I rather chose should come out by the Witnesses; she decoys him, and robs him first of his Innocence, then led him on from one Crime to another. She prevails with the Boy to take out Money out of his Master's Till at several Times. The Boy was at last detected. And then comes still a greater Crime, she desir'd the Boy to suppress the Truth, and to charge his own Sister of that Crime she was not only guilty, but guilty of inducing him to commit it. We shall likewise prove his desiring to charge his own Sister with the Crime.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-25-person288">
                  John 
                  Alcock 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person288" type="surname" value="Alcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner lived with me a Year and an half; she was discharged my Service the 31st Day of August last.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Business?</p>
               <p>Alcock. I am a <rs id="t17470604-25-viclabel99" type="occupation">Silversmith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-25-victim286 t17470604-25-viclabel99"></join> at Cripplegate, and have lived there nine and twenty Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a Servant named 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person289">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person289" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person289" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Alcock. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of the Prisoner at the Bar taking any thing of your's, and what?</p>
               <p>Alcock. I have lost Money several Times; sometimes a Guinea, and sometimes half a Guinea, and other Pieces of Money. I examin'd how this could Possibly be. I never thought or the Boy not the Maid.</p>
               <p>Q. Whom did you examine first.</p>
               <p>Alcock. There was a Gentleman in the Neighbourhood came to me, and says, Who does this Boy belong to? He lays out a great debt of Money<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040032"></xptr> in the Neighbourhood; what do give him a Week? I says, the common Custom is Half-a-Crown a Week; immediately upon this I examined him, and upon searching of him, I found in a Button-hole of his Waistcoat this 18 s. Piece, I have in my Hand; upon that he confess'd the whole Affair; he confess'd he had from Time to Time taken a Guinea out of my Till, &amp;c. Sir, says he, I'll tell you the whole Affair, she broke the Lock before my Face, and there happen'd to be no Money, says she this won't do at this Time. So they go a second time, and he breaks open the Lock, after he had been tutor'd so to do; when she came to him this second Time, Now says she, Dick, try what you can do; the Boy tries, and he opens it , and there happen'd to be Money; Now , says she, take it out and give it me, which he did, and had done it sundry Times; she sometimes gave him 3 or 4 s. out if it, and bid him be a good Boy.</p>
               <p>Court. Then all you know of your own Knowledge is, that you lost Money at several Times out of your Till; do you know any Things of your own Knowledge against the Prisoner at the Bar, touching particular Pieces of Pork?</p>
               <p>Alcock. She took some Pieces of Pork, and carried them to one Mrs Thomson, by Battle-Bridge, the other side of the Water; I heard her acknowledge it before a Person that shall inform the Court of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Prisoner at the Bar own she had took this Pork, or the Boy?</p>
               <p>Alcock . When I went to her, Oh, says she, if I had not acknowledge the Pork, as for the Money you could have done nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person290">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person290" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person290" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How old are you?</p>
               <p>Wood. I shall be 13 next July.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know what it is to taken an Oath, what is the Punishment in case you forswear yourself ?</p>
               <p>Wood . If I take a false Oath I shall spoil the Character of another, and go to Hell myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you live with Mr Alcock ?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, Sir, almost two Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person291">
                  Jane 
                  Stabock 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person291" type="surname" value="Stabock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person291" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she Servant at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lie a-Nights?</p>
               <p>Wood. In the Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever come down to you?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, she used to come down to me, and buss me, and play with me, and shew me how to open the Till.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Thing in her Hand at that Time to open it?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, Sir, a Piece of Steel, and she open'd it before my Eyes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Day of the Month?</p>
               <p>Wood. It was about a Month before she went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Money at that Time?</p>
               <p>Wood. There was no Money at that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come down at another Time?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, in the Morning betimes.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to you?</p>
               <p>Wood. She bid me try what I could do, to open the Till.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get up?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, Sir, and I opened the Till with a bit of Steel, that was in a Drawer in the Shop, and took a Guinea in Gold, and some Silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with that Money?</p>
               <p>Wood. I gave it into her Hands, and she gave me about a couple of Shillings; and she gave me my Victuals that Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come down at any other Time?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attempt to open the Till at any other Time?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, Sir, not when she was with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the Piece of Gold?</p>
               <p>Wood. My Master found it about me, in my Cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to have an 18 s. Piece?</p>
               <p>Wood. It was out of the 36 s. Piece that was changed, which I took out of the Till.</p>
               <p>Council. The first Time you say there was nothing found in the Till?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. The next Time you open'd the Till?</p>
               <p>Wood. The next Time I open'd the Till, and I found Silver and Gold, there was an 18 s. Piece, or a Guinea.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040033"></xptr>Q. Did you or she open the Till at any other Time?</p>
               <p>Wood . Not she and I together, but I have open'd it by myself, and have carried it to her, and she has given me something out of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Wood. I used to carry it to her after she had lived at another Place; I used to carry it to her, and she used to give me 3 or 4 s. and my Victuals in the Park.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Times may you have carried Money to her in this Manner?</p>
               <p>Wood. Several Times.</p>
               <p>Q. How much Money may you have carried to her in the whole?</p>
               <p>Wood. About 15 l.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you was charged with doing those Crimes?</p>
               <p>Wood . When I took the 36 s. Piece, then I changed it, and gave her 10 s.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the Remainder of the Money ?</p>
               <p>Wood. I had that about me in my Waistcoat , my Master had that, and 10 s. I gave her, and the rest I spent . It was Master's little Girl that found the 18 s. Piece upon me; she saw a little of it stick out of the Button-hole of my Waistcoat .</p>
               <p>Q. Had your Master examined you before?</p>
               <p>Wood . Yes, but he found but four Pence halfpenny about me; he did not think of any thing being in the Button-hole of my Waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Court. Upon it's being found upon you, what did you say?</p>
               <p>Wood. I gave it to my Master. I was just about being sent out of an Errand, when I returned I told them all; I told them how it was my Sister that persuaded me; the Maid told me whenever I was catch'd, I should say it was my Sister , and never say it was her, and I did say so .</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Sister ever concern'd in this Affair?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does this Sister live?</p>
               <p>Wood. She lives in Ratcliff-Highway .</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Sister ever at your Master's House ?</p>
               <p>Wood . Never.</p>
               <p>Q. And what was done to your Sister ?</p>
               <p>Wood. My Master put her into the Poultrey-Compter ; then I told it was this Maid.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after did you tell it was the Maid?</p>
               <p>Wood. About two Days afterward .</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant to the Witness Wood , I think the first Time the Maid open'd the Till, there was nothing; the second Time that you open'd it, there was something?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes, the first Time she was present with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she ever present when you open'd the Till afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Wood. No.</p>
               <p>Council. What sort of Coin did you find at several Times afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Wood. Sometimes a Guinea, and sometimes Shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the 18 s. you first found in the Till?</p>
               <p>Wood. She was along with me, and I delivered it into her Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the several Coins at other Times that you took?</p>
               <p>Wood. Sometimes a Guinea, and sometimes Shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find 18 s. afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Wood. I found 36 s. the last Day, and that I chang'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you change it?</p>
               <p>Wood. I chang'd it into Silver, and there was an 18 s. Piece in that, and that 18 s. Piece was found upon me.</p>
               <p>Council. Pray how long had the Maid been gone from the Place before you made this Discovery ?</p>
               <p>Wood. She had been gone 10 Months, or three Quarters of a Year .</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she in the House with you?</p>
               <p>Wood . A good while, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. There was no Money in the Till at the Time that she open'd it?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the Maid live in the House with you?</p>
               <p>Wood. Half a Year, I believe .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040034"></xptr>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person292">
                  John 
                  Chute 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person292" type="surname" value="Chute"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person292" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Chute . Sir, I have seen her very often at Mr Alcock's, when a Servant there, and have seen her since, I saw her the 26th of May last.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Chute. That was in York-Buildings, I think it was at the Sign of the Griffin .</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any Declaration then?</p>
               <p>Chute. Mr Alcock was present, and Mrs Lincey , a Relation of the Boy's. Mr Alcock said to her, I am afraid you have had some Hand in this, my Information is such by the Boy ; she deny'd she advis'd the Boy, but she acknowledg'd she had taken two Pieces of pickled Pork.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you hear her own she had taken away two Pieces of pickled Pork?</p>
               <p>Chute. I did, and she sent them away to one Mrs Thomson's. Mr Alcock got her to this Publick House , because he would not go to her Place to expose her; she wanted then a little private Discourse to make up the Affair, than to come to before a publick Court.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to you?</p>
               <p>Chute. Says she, this may be made up in a private Manner by some Gentlemen, than before a publick Court; at this Time there was a Person came and call'd her out, and said something to her; then she came in again, and said she was sorry she had confess'd any thing about the Pork, but for the Money they could not hurt her.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person293">
                  Ann 
                  Lincey 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person293" type="surname" value="Lincey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person293" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Lincey . I have seen her, but never till last Tuesday was 7-Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see her?</p>
               <p>Lincey. I saw her in York-Buildings.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when she was examin'd, what did she say?</p>
               <p>Lincey. I heard her say she had taken two Pieces of Pork from her Master, and sent them away by the Boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say any other Thing?</p>
               <p>Lincey. I heard her say, that the Money she did not value ?</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. You hear what this Boy has sworn against you. What have you to say against this Charge?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing of what is spoken of .</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-25-person294">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person294" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person294" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person294" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Fox. She was my <rs id="t17470604-25-deflabel100" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-25-defend284 t17470604-25-deflabel100"></join>, she has liv'd with me two Months and two Days, she was taken from my House, her Master came on Tuesday was 7-Night, and her ask'd for Jenney, and Jenney was called out of the Kitchen, and he said how do you do Jenney ; so she came to me in the back Parlour . Says she to me, please to give me leave to go out and speak to my Master . I desired her not to stay, I was very angry that she was gone so long.</p>
               <p>Council. I ask you how she behaved?</p>
               <p>Fox. She behaved very well. I am sure she might have robb'd me of 200 l. and run away. She was with me till she was taken up. She was not taken up till the Thursday following that her Master was with her on Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you observe many Persons coming to her while she lived with you?</p>
               <p>Fox. I never saw any body come to her, but a Woman over the Water.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that Boy come to her?</p>
               <p>Fox. I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-25-person295">
                  Andrew 
                  Mayfrew 
               <interp inst="t17470604-25-person295" type="surname" value="Mayfrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person295" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner was a Servant of mine for five Months. I was then in Lodgings at Mr Jones's in Beaufort Buildings . She came to me in the latter End of August , and went away the latter End of January .</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Opportunity of defrauding you?</p>
               <p>Mayfrew . She had Plate and Linen, and other Things under her Care.</p>
               <p>Council. Did she behave in an honest Manner, had you any reason to suspect her?</p>
               <p>Mayfrew . No.</p>
               <p>Q. If you wanted a Servant now, would you take her into your service?</p>
               <p>Mayfrew . Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. I'll ask you this single Question, Did you ever see the Boy there?</p>
               <p>Mayfrew. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner had others to appear to her Character, but they were not examin'd. Her Mistress appeared to be a very sober, creditable Person, and also her Master that she had lived<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040035"></xptr> with before; and both spoke well of her .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470604-25-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-25-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
