<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440223-3">
               <interp inst="t17440223-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-3" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-3" type="date" value="17440223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-3-off14-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-3-defend41 t17440223-3-off14 t17440223-3-verdict17"></join>
         
               <p>142. 
               <persName id="t17440223-3-defend41" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17440223-3-defend41" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-defend41" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-defend41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17440223-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a pair of leather breeches, value 5 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440223-3-victim43" type="victimName">
                           Joshua 
                           Malcher 
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim43" type="surname" value="Malcher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim43" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and a coat and waistcoat, value 20 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440223-3-victim45" type="victimName">
                           Slade 
                           Bowler 
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim45" type="surname" value="Bowler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim45" type="given" value="Slade"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-3-victim45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17440223-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">Jan. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-3-off14 t17440223-3-cd15"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Goodman. I perceived the stairs to be dirty with somebody's feet, and traced the steps up three pair of stairs, and found, by the marks of the feet, that somebody was gone into one of the rooms; I went in, but did not see any body. I opened a closet door, and there I found the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see any thing in my custody?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Goodman. I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-3-person46">
                  Joshua 
                  Malcher 
               <interp inst="t17440223-3-person46" type="surname" value="Malcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-person46" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Hearing somebody was in the house, I went up stairs into the room, and missed a pair of leather breeches, which hung by the side of the bed; I went into the closet, where the Prisoner was concealed, and found a coat and waistcoat lying partly upon a box and partly upon the floor, and my breeches under them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-3-person47">
                  Slade 
                  Bowler 
               <interp inst="t17440223-3-person47" type="surname" value="Bowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-person47" type="given" value="Slade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up stairs, to see if any thing was lost, and I found my coat and waistcoat upon a box, which I had left hanging upon a peg in the closet.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not they fall down upon the Box?</p>
               <p>Bowler. Not very well - They might fall upon the box.</p>
               <p>Mrs. - The box stood so far from the peg, that I think it impossible they could fall upon it. [The gentlewoman described it to be about two yards from the peg.]</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am an <rs id="t17440223-3-deflabel16" type="occupation">apprentice to the sea</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-3-defend41 t17440223-3-deflabel16"></join>; I have served three years honestly, and have got four to serve; I ran into the house to escape a press-gang, for, being in a sailor's habit, I was afraid of being pressed.</p>
               <p>Bowler. He was not in a sailor's dress, he was in a livery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask the Prosecutors whether there were not two or three sailors waiting to press me?</p>
               <p>This was denied by the Prosecutors, who said they were at work in the yard, and if there had been any, they should have seen them.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner said, Mr. Dalby, an Apothecary on Ludgate-hill, would give him a good character. Mr. Dalby was sent for, but could not come. A gentleman who lives there was sent for, who came and acquainted the Court, that he had known the Prisoner about three months, that he came over in the Hope; but could not say much to his character. The prisoner said, he knew that he had been entrusted with plate and things of value; but the gentleman said, he did not know any thing of it. <rs id="t17440223-3-verdict17" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-3-verdict17" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
