<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-7">
               <interp inst="t17471014-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-7" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-7" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-7-off32-c136" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-7-defend145 t17471014-7-off32 t17471014-7-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>384. 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-7-defend145" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Martin 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-7-defend145" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-defend145" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-defend145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, and the Indictment sets forth, That he together with one John Brown not yet taken, on the <rs id="t17471014-7-cd31" type="crimeDate">24th of September</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-7-off32 t17471014-7-cd31"></join>, <rs id="t17471014-7-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               did steal half a Pound of Tea, value 5 s. the Goods of the Company of Merchants trading to the East Indies. Likewise indicted for stealing half a Pound of Tea
            </rs>, the Goods and Chattels of persons unknown, <rs id="t17471014-7-cd33" type="crimeDate">September 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-7-off32 t17471014-7-cd33"></join>.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. I am Council in this Prosecution, which you observe is carried on by the 
               <persName id="t17471014-7-victim146" type="victimName">
                  East-India
                   Company
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-victim146" type="surname" value="Company"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-victim146" type="given" value="East-India"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-victim146" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-7-off32 t17471014-7-victim146"></join>
                  </persName>
            , who in their publick, as well as private Capacity, are certainly the greatest Traders in Europe. You will find in the Progress of this Trial the Necessity the Company is under, in putting a Stop to the Progress of these Practices. Generally speaking, this Tea, when it comes to be landed, is put on Botolph Wharf; and 'tis necessary to put their Tea into Carts, to be carried to the Company's Warehouses; and 'tis necessary to employ Porters and Carmen. And I think, Gentlemen, on the 14th of September there was a Discovery made of a great Fraud upon the Company; the Fraud was this, the Carmen, when they took the Tea in order to carry it to the Warehouses, they considered how much Money it produc'd, they bored Holes in the Chests; one saw another do it; at last it became universal. The Prisoner, he is an Apprentice to one 
               <persName id="t17471014-7-person147">
                  William 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person147" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person147" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Master Carman, he had seen the Carmen playing their Tricks, and he bored a Hole and shook out about half a Pound of Tea. This will be prov'd to you by one of the Accomplices. As soon as he had got this Tea he carried it to a Person that he thought it would be very welcome to. The Indictment is against this particular Person. We will call our Witnesses, and prove the Fact, and you will see it necessary, in order to preserve the Property of the fair Trader, and to do Justice to the Company, you will find no difficulty to prove the Prisoner guilty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-7-person148">
                  Robert 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person148" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person148" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Husband to the United East-India Company, my Business is to unload the Ship, and likewise to make out the Accounts for the Customs.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. You are their Officer?</p>
               <p>Day. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. I think there was an universal Complaint, that the Company was defra uded?</p>
               <p>Day. I was in Company with the Constable when he brought the Prisoner at the Bar, as one that was concerned in defrauding the Company.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he mention in particular that gave him the Information?</p>
               <p>Day. 
               <persName id="t17471014-7-person149">
                  Richard 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person149" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person149" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the first Person that the Constable mentioned; he said, that Roberts confess'd that he had been concern'd with others in those Practices.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-7-person150">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Maschall 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person150" type="surname" value="Maschall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person150" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the Constable that belong to the Custom house; I saw nothing of the Thing done, but what was took out of the Chest in the Cart; but Roberts voluntarily did confess, that there was a Hole in the Corner of the Chest; they made it large enough to put their Hands in.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there not other People absconded?</p>
               <p>Maschall. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this a general Practice?</p>
               <p>Maschall. This is a Practice done of late, but I never knew it before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-7-person151">
                  Richard 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person151" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person151" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Carman; this 
               <persName id="t17471014-7-person152">
                  William 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17471014-7-person152" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person152" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I was in the Cart together, and we got, I believe, the Value of half a Pound of Tea of the East-India Company; where the Hole was not big enough, we made it bigger, we did not care which so one made it, and we were to share this Tea together, and we sold it an Alehouse for Half a Crown.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that Martin assisted?</p>
               <p>Roberts. Some run out, and some we pull'd out.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the Money?</p>
               <p>Roberts. He had Half, and I had Half.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. Was this an Invention of your own, or was it from seeing other People do it?</p>
               <p>Roberts. Seeing how several other Carmen did it, we did it; it was a general Practice for the value of two or three Days, or a Week, it might be; and we thought we might as well do it as others.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you break the Hole on purpose to get the Tea out.</p>
               <p>Roberts. We had broke it on Purpose to get the Tea out.</p>
               <p>Court. As I understand, there was some little Holes in the Chest that some Tea did drop out, did this Half-Pound come out with a Hole made, or did it drop out before?</p>
               <p>Roberts. Some might drop before, and more afterwards.</p>
               <p>Court. Do you expect any Reward for this Evidence?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, Sir; I came as an Evidence of my own accord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-7-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>As the principal Witness against the Prisoner was the Accomplice, and hoping it was the first Fact, he was only <rs id="t17471014-7-punish35" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-punish35" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-7-punish35" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-7-defend145 t17471014-7-punish35"></join>
               ordered to be whipp'd
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
