<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-28">
               <interp inst="t17430114-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-28" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-28" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-28-off143-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-28-defend351 t17430114-28-off143 t17430114-28-verdict146"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140022"></xptr>99 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-defend351" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Burnet 
                  <interp inst="t17430114-28-defend351" type="surname" value="Burnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-defend351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-defend351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-28-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting Elizabeth , the Wife of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430114-28-victim353" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Bailey 
                        <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim353" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim353" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , on the Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a short Cloak , Val. 6 s.
            </rs> the Property of Francis Bailey <rs id="t17430114-28-cd144" type="crimeDate">Dec. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-28-off143 t17430114-28-cd144"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-victim355" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Bailey 
                  <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim355" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim355" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-victim355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . On the 18th of December, as I was going home, in company with Mrs Jackson, at half an Hour after 11 at Night, two Men came out of an Ale-house in the Strand, near Southampton-street , the Prisoner came to the left Side of me, untied my Cloak, took it off my Shoulder, and run away with it. - I saw him do it; he looked me in the Face all the time, but I had not Power to cry out, or make any Resistance, I was so frightened. I am sure the Prisoner is the Person, because there was a Light at the Door, and another in the Entry. The other Man ran away. The Prisoner owned the Robbery the next Morning before the Justice.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Would you have sworn against me, if you had not carried me back to the Ale-house? -</p>

               <p>Bailey. Yes, I would: I said you was the Man as soon as the Watchman brought you up to me.</p>

               <p>Winisred Jackson. The Prisoner came behind Mrs Bailey: I saw him at her Shoulder, and he pulled her Cloak off in a Minute. I cannot say whether he untied it, but he gave it a Tug, and it was gone: He run away with it. I cried out, Stop Thief; and he was taken. - When he was brought up to her, she said, That is the Man.</p>

               <p>Court. Did not you, or she, doubt of his being the Person, 'till you went to the Ale-house and satisfied yourselves?</p>

               <p>Jackson. I knew him from the very first. I said, as soon as he was brought up, he was the Person; we went into the Plume of-Feathers Ale-house , because he said he had not been there; and the Mistress of the House, the Drawer, and two or three more Persons , said, he had been there, and had been gone out of the House but a few Minutes.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-person356">
                  Thomas 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17430114-28-person356" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person356" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 18th of December I was in the Strand, and saw the Prisoner running along with a Scarlet-Cloak in his Hand; he turned into Southampton-street : I made a Blow at him with my Stick, but missed him: I run after him and cried out, Stop Thief ; and a Watchman asked , Where is he? And I said, On the Bedford Head-Side. A Chairman had stopped him before the Watchman took him: He had no Cloak upon him when he was taken, so he must certainly have dropped it; he never was out of my Sight till he was taken. The Watchman said, he was a Thief; and the Prisoner told him, he would learn him to take his Character away. Says I to the Watchman, Hold him; I will see whether his Character is good or no. When he was carried to Mrs Bailey , she said she saw him come out of the Alehouse ; and he said, You lye, you Bitch, I have not been in the House To night.</p>

               <p>[His having been in the Ale-house just before was confirmed by the other Witnesses.]</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-person357">
                  Joseph 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-28-person357" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person357" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Chairman. I stopped him, and the Watchman came over, and said he was a Thief , so I delivered him up to the Watchman.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Was I walking or running; or had I any thing about me?</p>

               <p>Smith. He was walking with his Hands before him , he had nothing about him then.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-person358">
                  John 
                  Gager 
               <interp inst="t17430114-28-person358" type="surname" value="Gager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person358" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman at the Corner of Southampton-Street . The Chairman delivered him to us, I went into the Strand to find the Gentleman, who cried out stop Thief, and the two Gentlewomen challenged the Prisoner directly, and said he was the Thief; he abused them very much for pretending to take away his Character, and would have charged the Constable with them, for he said he was going about his Master's Business.</p>



               <p>T. Manning. I am a Watchman, and stand next Door to the Bedford-Head ; hearing a Cry of Stop Thief, I took to the middle of the Way, and dogged the Prisoner; I found him two Doors from my Stand, walking, and he was fumbling about his Pocket, and I thought I saw him fumble something out of it, and I believe it was the Cloak, and that he dropped it down one of the Areas.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-person359">
                  Mary 
                  Sheffield 
               <interp inst="t17430114-28-person359" type="surname" value="Sheffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person359" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At 8 o'Clock on Sabbath-Day Morning; a Chairman knocked at our Door, and said, Neighbour here is a Cloak in your Area: that is the Cloak I found in our Area, two Doors from the Bedford-Head , in Southampton-Street ,</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-28-person360">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17430114-28-person360" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person360" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That is my Cloak.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say, but that I get my Bread honestly by riding <rs id="t17430114-28-deflabel145" type="occupation">Postilion</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-28-defend351 t17430114-28-deflabel145"></join>; I rode Postilion to my Lord Fairfax, I went to see my Sister the Saturday before I was taken, and she kept me all Night. I was to have gone with a set of Horses to the Bath, but staying too long, the Horses went away without me. My Lord Cardigan would give me a Character for my H, if I was going into any Place. <rs id="t17430114-28-verdict146" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-verdict146" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-28-punish147" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-28-punish147" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-28-defend351 t17430114-28-punish147"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
