<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-6">
               <interp inst="t17420428-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-6" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-6" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-6-off41-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-defend104 t17420428-6-off41 t17420428-6-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>8. 
               <persName id="t17420428-6-defend104" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-defend104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17420428-6-defloc40">St. Martin in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-6-defloc40" type="placeName" value="St. Martin in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-6-defloc40" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-defend104 t17420428-6-defloc40"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17420428-6-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17420428-6-cd42" type="crimeDate">15th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-off41 t17420428-6-cd42"></join>, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-6-victim106" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Gilchrist 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-6-victim106" type="surname" value="Gilchrist"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-6-victim106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-6-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-off41 t17420428-6-victim106"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling House of 
                     <persName id="t17420428-6-person107">
                        John 
                        Naydon 
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person107" type="surname" value="Naydon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-6-person107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-6-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did make an Assault, and with both his Hands, to and against a certain Chair and a boarded Floor, the said Gilchrist did throw, and with both his Hands, divers Times on the Belly of the said Gilchrist did strike, giving him several mortal Bruises, of which he languish'd to the 16th of the same Month, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time charg'd by Vertue of the Coroner's Inquest for Manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person108">
                  Hugh 
                  Heap 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person108" type="surname" value="Heap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person108" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was in the Room when the Thing happen'd; it was on the 15th of April, the Deceased came into the Room where the Prisoner was drinking, with a Pretence for some Salt, and he accordingly went to the Salt Box to take some out, which I believe was with a full Intention to quarrel with the Prisoner. There were some Words between them, and the Prisoner got up and gave Gilchrist a Push towards the Door, and bid him get out of his Company. Gilchrist then came back again, and the Prisoner a second Time desired him to quit his Company; upon that, Gilchrist hit the Prisoner a slap on the Face; they immediately clos'd, and fell on the Floor together. They had three Falls in the whole, one of them was over a Chair, and in the last Fall, some how or other, Gilchrist got the Prisoner's Finger in his Mouth, and bit it, and the Prisoner endeavouring to disengage his Finger, had his Thumb bit too. After this, they both got up; the Prisoner went home with his Mother, and the Deceased sat down in a Chair in the same Room 'till he return'd. The Prisoner (when he came back) offer'd to call for a Tankard of Beer to drink Friends with Gilchrist, but they did not drink together that I saw. Mr. Gilchrist about 9 or 10. Minutes afterwards, complain'd that he was sick, and went home with a Neighbour.</p>
               <p>C. How long did he live after this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280008"></xptr>Heap. As I was inform'd, about five and twenty Hours: I never saw him afterwards.</p>
               <p>C. Did you see any Bruise upon him?</p>
               <p>Heap. I did not see any thing that could hurt either of them.</p>
               <p>C. You say when Gilchrist came into the Room for Salt, the Prisoner gave him a Push ?</p>
               <p>Heap. I believe he came with a full Design to quarrel, for by enquiring afterwards, I found he had nothing to eat with his Salt; besides they had Words before, and the Prisoner had left his Company the same Day. Neither of the Pushes could hurt him, and he was not hurt by him to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was there not a Sash Door going into the Kitchen, through which Gilchrist could see whether I was there or not?</p>
               <p>Heap. Yes.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did I desire him to go out of the Room.</p>
               <p>Heap. Yes; he gave him those Pushes, and desired him to walk out of the Room, for he did not care to keep him Company. I heard the Prisoner declare (the Day before this happen'd) to Gilchrist himself, that he never would come into his Company again if he could help it. I have known the Prisoner some Years, and never knew him quarrel with any Body before. As to Gilchrist, here are People that knew him better than I. I never saw him but 3 or 4 Times in my Life, and never drank with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person109">
                  Thomas 
                  Hayes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person109" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person109" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It happened on the 15th of April last, I went to this <placeName id="t17420428-6-crimeloc43">Heathcock Alehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-6-crimeloc43" type="placeName" value="Heathcock Alehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-6-crimeloc43" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-off41 t17420428-6-crimeloc43"></join> in the Evening as I usually do, and in the Kitchen there are few but Neighbours come in. There is a Sash-Door which parts it from the public Room. When I had been there about a Quarter of an Hour, the Deceased opened the Door, and came in: he push'd between the Company, and went directly to the Salt Box. As he was going back again, the Prisoner told him he was a Scoundrel, and gave him a Push on the Elbow, such as would not knock down a Child of a Year and half old if it could stand: he bid him get out of hit Company, and repeated his Push, and presently after that, they said Gilchrist struck the Prisoner, but I being behind, did not see the Blow; however, they presently clos'd, and threw me, Chair and all down to the Ground. They got up again, and the Deceas'd fell against the Table, and from thence a-cross a Chair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner do any Thing to him when he was down?</p>
               <p>Hayes. No, the Prisoner bid him get up, and said he scorn'd to take any Advantage of him; accordingly the Deceased did get up, and they clos'd and fell a second Time upon the Floor, the Prisoner uppermost: there were no Blows that I perceiv'd, and I was as near as any body could be. They were not down a quarter of a Minute, but they got up and clos'd again, and fell a third Time, the Prisoner uppermost again. Then Gilchrist got the Prisoner by the Finger, and in loosing that, he bit his Thumb, and then they both got up again.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you not see any violent fighting and Blows ?</p>
               <p>Hayes. No, only hugging one another and falling.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not the Deceased come with Violence against the Table?</p>
               <p>Hayes. Yes; they both came against the Table.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. Had the Deceas'd any Occasion to come into that Room at all?</p>
               <p>Hayes. No; for I ask'd all the People of the House whether he had any Thing to eat, and he had not. I can't say what his Pretence was for coming in, but I really believe it was to quarrel, because he peep'd over the Curtain to see if the Prisoner was there. I have known the Prisoner from his Cradle, living in the same Neighbourhood: I never saw him quarrel in my Life, but he behav'd always civilly. As to Gilchrist, when he was in Liquor, there was not an iller Temper living, and they tell me, he had not been sober 2 or 3 Days, and he seem'd to me to be a little in Liquor then.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Do you apprehend any Hurt could proceed from those Falls?</p>
               <p>Hayes. No, I don't apprehend there was the least Damage in the World.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person110">
                  Isaac 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person110" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person110" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe Mr. Gilchrist was the first Occasion of this Quarrel, because he open'd the Door, and came into the Kitchen. He went directly to the Salt Box, took some Salt, and in his Return back, stood facing me and 2 or 3 more who sat on the same Bench. The Prisoner said, get out of my Company, what do you follow me for? you Scoundrel ! He was then sitting on his Seat, and told Gilchrist if he would not go out, he would shove him out, and he then gave the Deceased a Push and he fell into a Chair. The Prisoner again bid him go out; he said he would not, upon which he gave him another Push, and he fell down again. The Deceased<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280009"></xptr> got up, and gave the Prisoner a slap on the Face, upon which they immediately clos'd, and some how or other the Deceased was shov'd into a Chair. The Prisoner said, get up you Scoundrel, for I will not take any Advantage of you; he then got up, and they both clos'd and fell more.</p>
               <p>again, and I parted them, after which I saw no</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Prisoner seem to have any Prejudice against the Deceas'd?</p>
               <p>Smith. None at all, but the Prisoner, as I was told, absconded his Company that Day in the other Part of the House, and went into the Kitchen to shun him. I saw no more than one Blow, because I had hold of the Prisoner's Mother, and I did hear one or two more, but I did not see them.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you hear the Deceased make any Complaint ?</p>
               <p>Smith. He made no Complaint at the House, only cryed out, he has hurt me. I went home with him, and carried him up Stairs, and sat him in a Chair by the Bedside. He told me his Belly was hurt, and he liv'd after this between 25 and 26 Hours.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q What do you apprehend he went to get Suit for ?</p>
               <p>Smith. I don't apprehend he had any Occasion for it, but that he came in on purpose to quarrel. I have known the Prisoner about a dozen Years, he always behav'd well, but he was not sober at this Time. As to Gilchrist, he was when sober, a peaceable, good-natur'd Man, but when he was fuddled, as bad as bad could be, and he was then very drunk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person111">
                  Wm 
                  Bridges 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person111" type="surname" value="Bridges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person111" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the Company, and was drinking in the Room when the Deceased opened the Door and came in. He went directly to the Salt-Box, and turn'd back and look'd at us all; upon which the Prisoner said, get out, you know I will not be in your Company, and gave him a slight shove, and push'd him against the Door. - not in such a Manner as to hurt him Gilchrist ask'd him, what he meant? and then the Prisoner gave him another shove; with that, Gilchrist struck him in the Face, and they clos'd together, and fell against the Table, the Table, they fell a-cross a Chair. prisoner bid him get up. for he would take age of him. Gilchrist accordingly got they had another Tustle, and fell on together: they got up again, and and I was not apprehensive that would ensue. They fell a third Time, and then the Deceased got the Prisoner's Finger in his Mouth, and made him cry out, and in endeavouring to disengage it, the Deceased bit his Thumb.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was there no Violence us'd?</p>
               <p>Bridges. No more than is generally us'd in fighting.</p>
               <p>Counc. When the Deceas'd was down, did not the Prisoner knee him or beat him?</p>
               <p>Bridges No, after it was over, he sat in a Chair, and hung down his Head; and then went to a Bench, and lay all along and groan'd. Several People there desir'd him to go Home, and at last Mr. Smith, and one of the Drawers carried him home.</p>
               <p>Counc. Before he was carried home, did he not complain of having receiv'd hurt?</p>
               <p>Bridges. He complain'd that he was not well, - to the nearest of my Thought. I can't say how long he liv'd after this, but I heard next Night that he was dead.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Do you think the Deceased's real Design was to get some Salt?</p>
               <p>Bridges. I believe it was to quarrel, for we enquir'd whether he had any Thing to eat with that Salt, and we found he had not. I heard that there had been Words between them, and that the Prisoner would not be in his Company if he could help it.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Could Mr. Gilchrist see over the Sash-Door whether I was in the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Bridges. Yes, he was tall enough. The Prisoner bears a very good Character, and is a peaceable, inoftensive Man: As to the other, I apprehended he was in Liquor at that Time.</p>
               <p>- Jones. I was Journeyman to the Deceased, and was at Home when he was brought in. He was set down in a Chair in the Shop, and he said, he had received his Death that Night, and cry'd out that he was murder'd, but did not say by whom. He seem'd very much disguis'd in Liquor when he was brought in.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was he not sober before he died?</p>
               <p>Jones. I can't tell that. He was brought in about a quarter past ten at Night, and died about twenty-four Hours afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person112">
                  Mary 
                  Bineham 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person112" type="surname" value="Bineham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person112" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was a Lodger in the Deceased's House, and saw him when he was brought home The first Word he said when he came in was, that he had got his Death's Wound. He was very much in Liquor, and said sometime afterwards, that he receiv'd it from the Prisoner. I was frequently with him 'till he died, and he said it was a sad Thing for a Man to be murder'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280010"></xptr> so. He died within four and twenty Hours afterwards.</p>
               <p>C. Was he sober when he died?</p>
               <p>Bineham I really can't say whether he was sober or not, for he never had any Rest from the Time that he came into the House.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Character had the Deceas'd? was he very Quarrellonic ?</p>
               <p>Bineham. Not that I know of; - he was a good-natur'd, honest Man.</p>
               <p>- Allen. I was not in the Deceased's House when he came Home, but I saw him after the Quarrel. He sent for me 3 times before I went to him, but at last I did go to him; it was then a little after 11 o'Clock, and he was in his Bed. I found him very ill, crying out, my Belly! my Belly! I ask'd him what was the Matter, and he said he was kill'd by H - J - I ask'd him how it happen'd? he told me, ''He went in to '' fetch some Salt for 
               <persName id="t17420428-6-person113">
                  Billy 
                  Nind 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person113" type="surname" value="Nind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person113" type="given" value="Billy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and as he came '' back, the Prisoner got up, call'd him Scoundrel, '' and ask'd him what Business he had '' there, and gave him a Shove''. He said, '' They went to fighting, and when he fell '' down, the Prisoner knee'd him.'' I staid there 'till the Surgeon came, and saw him let Blood, and was with him most part of the next Day.</p>
               <p>C. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Allen. He was in Liquor when I first saw him, but was very sober the following Day: He gave me this Account at Night, and repeated it again to me the next Day when he was sober.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was Mrs. Bineham there at the same Time with you?</p>
               <p>Allen. I can't say; she was there several Times afterwards.</p>
               <p>Pris Q Will you take upon you to say that at eight, the Morning the Man was sober?</p>
               <p>Allen. Yes, I dare say he was.</p>
               <p>Mr. Small. Surgeon. I was call'd to attend the Deceased the 15th of February. He complained of extreme Pain in his Bowels, and seem'd then to be pretty much in Liquor. I did not know the Man, so that I could not be a Judge whether it was the Liquor, or the Agony of the Pain; for the Agony was so great, that when I went to open a Vein in his Arm, he could not bear to be stirr'd without complaining.</p>
               <p>I visited him next Morning, and he then appear'd to be in a dangerous Way. I informed another Surgeon of my Name, of the Condition I found him in: and desired him to go and see him; he accordingly did, and we declared him to be in imminent Danger. I saw him again in the Evening, after which I saw him no more 'till he was dead.</p>
               <p>C Was he sober when you saw him the next Day?</p>
               <p>Mr. Small. He gave distinct Answers both Morning and Evening to what Questions I put to him, and such as I think a sober Man would give; but I did not ask much about the Thing of him, because the By-standers are much sitter Persons to tell that.</p>
               <p>C. Did he give you no Account?</p>
               <p>Mr. Small. Yes, he said a Man with his Knee (I think he express'd it) stamp'd upon his Belly. I open'd his Body in the Presence of two or three Surgeons We found no external Bruises, but the Guts were broke in two different Places, which I apprehend proceeded from a violent Cause, either from a strong Pressure on his Belly, or a violent Blow. As the Man had been drinking, as I heard, for some Days before, the Gut might have been pretty much distended with Liquor, and any Thing of a Pressure or violent Push, might so far drive that Liquor from one Side to another, that where any Hindrance happened it might break the Guts through.</p>
               <p>C. Is it a usual Thing when the Intestines are not diseas'd, that they should burst without leaving an outward Mark ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Small. It is a very unusual Thing, and the Surgeons that were present, were of Opinion that such a Thing might not happen again in an Age There was no Sign of an Inflamation where they were broke, much less or Mortification, for they seem'd to be as good Order there, as in any other Part.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person114">
                  John 
                  Maynard 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person114" type="surname" value="Maynard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Heath Cock. On the 15th of April, the Prisoner and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17420428-6-person115">
                  William 
                  Nind 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person115" type="surname" value="Nind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person115" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in and sat down in one of the bo; this was between 3 and 4 o'Clock, and Mr. Gilchrist was then in the Kitchen. He went but in a short Time with Mr. Smith, and sat in the same Box where the Prisoner and Nind were drinking. They call'd for a Tankard of Beer, and I drew it; Smith paid for it, and went away; then Gilchrist began to quarrel with the Prisoner, and said, D - n you, you Dog, I will fight you now, or at any time; I will kill you. The Prisoner told him he would not have any Thing to say to him, and would not keep him Company. Gilchrist then took the Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280011"></xptr> by the Nose, and struck him in the Face, and Nind standing up, Gilchrist struck him two Smacks in the Face. The Prisoner then paid his Reckoning, and went away to Mr. Smith's, and about 6 o'Clock came in again, and sat down in the Kitchen. The Deceased was then asleep in a Box in the other Room, and was very much in Liquor. I did not see him go into the Kitchen, neither did I see any thing of the Quarrel, but I am certain he had no Occasion for Salt, for no Body in that Room had any thing to eat with it. As to Gilchrist's Character, he was when sober, very good-natur'd, but when he was in Liquor he would make a great Disturbance in the House.</p>
               <p>John Lambert I draw Beer at the Heath-cock, and remember the Afternoon that the Quarrel happen'd. The Prisoner and Mr. Nind were at out House together between 3 and 4 in the Afternoon. The Prisoner made an Officer to go into the Kitchen, but seeing the Deceased there, he drew back, and said, Gentlemen, I beg Pardon. They then went into the other Room, and call'd for Beer and Tobacco. When they had been there about half an Hour, the Deceased went out, but soon return'd with Mr. Smith; and went into the Box where the Prisoner and Nind were drinking. Smith said the Reckoning and went away, leaving Gilchrist behind. Then the Deceased began to quarrel, and call'd the Prisoner Scoundrel and Villain. The Prisoner desired him to be quiet, and got up to go on, upon which Nind desired, him to stay, and then the Deceased took him by the Nose, and gave him a slap in the Face. The Prisoner never offer'd to strike him or lift up his Hand; but immediately paid his Reckoning and went out.</p>
               <p>C. Before the Prisoner went away, did the Deceas'd use any particular Expressions?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Yes, he said he would fight him, the Prisoner in a merry way reply'd, What will you fight meant ? Why D - you ( said the Deceased ) at Sword and Pistol, and I will not leave you alive. Gilchrist was very drunk at that Time. Between 6 and 7 in the Evening, the Prisoner and Smith came in again together, and sat in the Kitchen. The Deceased was then asleep in one of the Boxes, and did not wake 'till between 9 and 10. Then he got up and rubb'd his Eyes, and look'd over the Sash-door of the Kitchen. Observing the Prisoner there, he went in towards the Chimney for some Salt, - Mr. Nind, nor any of the Company had nothing in the World to eat. I then went down for Beer, and when I came up again, I heard a rumbling and Noise in the Kitchen. I open'd the Door and saw the Deceased strike the Prisoner in the Face. Then they collar'd each other, and fell a-cross the Back of a Chair. The Prisoner got up, and told the Deceased he would not use him ill, and I believe no Hurt could happen, for the Prisoner got up that Minute from him.</p>
               <p>C. Did Mr. Gilchrist seem to be sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person116">
                  Lambert 
                  He 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person116" type="surname" value="He"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person116" type="given" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was pretty much fuddled, but had recover'd something: - I had known him half a Year and never saw him right sober in my Life.</p>
               <p>C. Was he apt to be quarrelsome in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Lambert. He would curse and swear and quarrel with any Body that spoke to him. The Prisoner always behav'd well, and I never saw him quarrel.</p>
               <p>C. How many Falls did you see between them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-6-person117">
                  Lambert 
                  Two 
               <interp inst="t17420428-6-person117" type="surname" value="Two"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person117" type="given" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in all; the first was a-cross a Chair, and the Gilchrist made up to the Prisoner again, but missing his Blow, run his Head against the Chimney-piece. Then they tumbled against the Side of a Table bound round with Iron. I did not see the Prisoner strike him or knee him, for as soon as they were down, one or two of the Company took them up directly.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-6-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-verdict44" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-6-punish45" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-punish45" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-6-punish45" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-6-defend104 t17420428-6-punish45"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
