<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-51">
               <interp inst="t17400116-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-51" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-51" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-51-off244-c329" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-51-defend446 t17400116-51-off244 t17400116-51-verdict247"></join>
         
               <p>140. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-51-defend446" type="defendantName">
                     Alice 
                     Cook  alias <rs id="t17400116-51-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-51-defend446 t17400116-51-alias-6"></join>Taper</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-defend446" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-defend446" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-defend446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-51-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Guinea, and 2 s. and a Farthing from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-51-victim448" type="victimName">
                           Christopher 
                           Blinkhorn 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-51-victim448" type="surname" value="Blinkhorn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-51-victim448" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-51-victim448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-51-off244 t17400116-51-victim448"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-51-cd245" type="crimeDate">January 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-51-off244 t17400116-51-cd245"></join>.</p>
               <p>Blinkhorn. On Sunday Night last, about half an Hour after 10, I was coming along <placeName id="t17400116-51-crimeloc246">Knaves-Acre</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-51-crimeloc246" type="placeName" value="Knaves-Acre"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-51-crimeloc246" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-51-off244 t17400116-51-crimeloc246"></join>, and met the Prisoner. Where are you going (says she) so much in a Hurry? Home, says I, and what have you to say to that? Will you give me any Thing, quoth she? I have but a few Halfpence, said I, and I asked her a very impudent Question, that I believe I did; and told her I had got Two-pence, but she must be quick, for I was in a Hurry, and had not much Occasion for her Company neither. So I gave her the Two-pence, and then she pretended that Two-pence was too little. Well, says I, I'll see if I have any more Farthings, and so I gave her 2 Halfpence more. But while I was talking to her, she got her Hand into my Pocket, and took out a Guinea, 2 Shillings and a Farthing. After this, I told her directly she had picked my Pocket; she denyed it, but I took her to the next Alehouse, and called a Watchman. When the Watchman came, I told her she had picked my Pocket of a Guinea, 2 Shillings and a Farthing, and if she would give me the Money again, I would release her; if not, I would send for the Constable. Nay, I told her, if she would return me the Guinea, she should have the overplus for her self, but she would not own it; so the Constable was sent for, and I delivered her up to him. He carry'd her to the Watch-house, and there she was searched, but no Money was to be found. At last says the Beadle, these Creatures very often hide Things in their Stockings, and upon searching the Stocking on her right Leg, out came the Guinea, 2 Shillings and a Farthing, to be sure. Next Morning we had her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17400116-51-person449">
                  Edward 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17400116-51-person449" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-person449" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and there she own'd the Money to be mine, and that she had robbed me of it, and begged my Pardon.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Man has offered me Money a great many Times, I serve the House in Grosvenor Square, where he lives, with Fish and Oysters.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-51-person450">
                  John 
                  Yarmouth 
               <interp inst="t17400116-51-person450" type="surname" value="Yarmouth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-person450" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday Night about a quarter before 11, a Watchman came to the Watch-house to fetch the Constable to the Barley-mow, in Knaves-Acre. I went with him, and there sat Blinkhorn and the Prisoner, and 2 other Men by them: And without Doors there was a couple of their Fosticates intending to get in, but we shut the Door against them. They told us they belonged to this very self same Creature at the Bar, and the Constable ordered me to disperse them, and I did so. Then Blinkhorn told the Creature, if she would give him the Guinea, she should have the 2 Shillings<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160040"></xptr> and the Farthing for her self; but it signified nothing, - she was cafe-hardened. So Mr Constable and I were both of one Opinion, and that was, that she should be taken proper care of. Accordingly I took hold of one of her Hands, and another Brother Watchman took hold of the other Hand, to guard her down to the Watch-house. But we had not gone far, before these 2 Fosticates came swearing upon us again: However we got the creature to the Watch-house, where we desired her to give the Man his Money: She said she had it not, so we examined her, and searched her modestly, but found no Money. Upon that says I, here's a proper Place to search, meaning her Shoes and Stockings. So with all the Pleasure in the World, Madam pulled off her 2 Shoes; and one Stocking as quick as her Shoes, and that was quick enough; and by the same Token she had large Buckles in them. But when she came to untye her Right Garter, or a Peice of White Tape, she was not so quick. I would not be obstinate, but said, Madam, if you please I'll help you; and so I turned down her Stocking, and out dropped a Guinea, 2 Shillings and a Farthing. The next Morning she was carried before his Worship, and there she begged the Coachman's Pardon, and said, she would never do so no more. <rs id="t17400116-51-verdict247" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-51-verdict247" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
