<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490705-57">
               <interp inst="t17490705-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-57" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490705"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-57" type="date" value="17490705"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-57-off281-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-57-defend365 t17490705-57-off281 t17490705-57-verdict283"></join>
         
               <p>435. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-defend365" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Kelley , alias <rs id="t17490705-57-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-57-defend365 t17490705-57-alias-5"></join>Mason</rs>, alias <rs id="t17490705-57-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-57-defend365 t17490705-57-alias-6"></join>Smith</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-defend365" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-defend365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-defend365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17490705-57-off281" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-off281" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-off281" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a stove-grate with an iron back, four harrateen curtains, a warming pan, a copper sauce-pan, and other things, all laid above the value of 40 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490705-57-victim367" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Kelley 
                        <interp inst="t17490705-57-victim367" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-57-victim367" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-57-victim367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-57-off281 t17490705-57-victim367"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17490705-57-person368">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Furnese 
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person368" type="surname" value="Furnese"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-57-person368" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-57-person368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-57-cd282" type="crimeDate">March 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-57-off281 t17490705-57-cd282"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person369">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person369" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person369" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 20th of September the prisoner came down to Portsmouth, and came on board the Nottingham, she enquired if any there belonged to Dublin, I gave her some gin slip, she pleaded poverty, saying, she had no money to pay for her lodging, I gave her a shilling, and sent her on shore. We agreed to live together. I took lodgings the latter end of October; I gave her money to purchase goods for me; the first thing bought was a bed cost 50 s. an iron grate, 28 s. 6 d. fire-tongs, poker, tea-kettle, warming-pan and stewpan, 12 plates, 4 pewter-dishes, 7 chairs, a table, a large looking-glass, 4 harrateen curtains and 2 blankets.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to lose these things?</p>
               <p>Kelley. On the 20th of March she desired me to go to Deptford to fetch a pig, and we were to get some peas and make it fat; and while I was gone, she got assistance, and carried away all my goods.</p>
               <p>Q. What name did this woman come to you by?</p>
               <p>Kelley. She said her name was Kelley, and she was glad to meet with any of the name out of the country.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050018"></xptr>Q. Did you give her liberty to pawn any of these things?</p>
               <p>Kelley. No, I never did. I have found some of the goods again in the man's possession she cohabited with last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I took the room, and paid quarterly for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it with your desire the prisoner should take the room?</p>
               <p>Kelley. It was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We went for man and wife, and lived together as such.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not, tell your aunt you were married?</p>
               <p>Kelley. She passed for my wife; but I never owned her as such.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you contented she should pass for your wife?</p>
               <p>Kelley. I cannot deny that; but I never was married to her.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Furness. 
               <persName id="t17490705-57-person370">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person370" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person370" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took a lodging of me, and brought many goods; and they were taken away by the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they taken away by his consent?</p>
               <p>Furness. I believe they were not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time were they taken away?</p>
               <p>Furness. I do not know the time exactly, it was a little before quarter-day; the prisoner then told me, he was gone to Deptford, or Greenwich, I know not which, and she was going to set up a shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person371">
                  Mary 
                  Macway 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person371" type="surname" value="Macway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person371" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17490705-57-person372">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person372" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person372" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I was with him at the buying his goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid for those goods?</p>
               <p>Macway. 
               <persName id="t17490705-57-person373">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person373" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person373" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did they not go for man and wife then?</p>
               <p>Macway. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person374">
                  Peter 
                  Penney 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person374" type="surname" value="Penney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person374" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mrs. Furness. I saw the prisoner and two men moving the goods from my mistress's house; they carried them all away, I know not whereto.</p>
               <p>Q. Did 
               <persName id="t17490705-57-person375">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person375" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner then pass for man and wife?</p>
               <p>Penney. They did not, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Jos. Richman. The prisoner has been at my house several times after the man was robb'd. He had a warrant from Justice Broadhead to search for the goods. He had her taken up, had her before the Justice, and she was to have been committed; she got bail, ran away from her bail, and was taken again at Portsmouth, and brought to town, and lodged in the Round-house. She was taken out from thence to swear a robbery against the prosecutor: which she did; then he was committed. I once heard the prisoner say, she would swear her soul to the Devil but she would be revenged on him.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person376">
                  Mary 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person376" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person376" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged with the prisoner and Mr. Kelley. They lived as man and wife together; and I know he has used her very ill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person377">
                  Mary 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person377" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person377" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person377" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner to be a hard-working woman, and I have known the prosecutor about eight months; he always acknowledged her as his wife.</p>
               <p>Cross examined,</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner when she kept company with one Smith?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. Yes I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of her carrying any goods away?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person378">
                  Ann 
                  Bucanan 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person378" type="surname" value="Bucanan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person378" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person378" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has used my house about eight months; and so has he: they always went for man and wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person379">
                  Paul 
                  Bucanan 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person379" type="surname" value="Bucanan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person379" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first time I saw the prisoner and prosecutor was in Christmas holy-days; they that time seem'd to take a liking to me and my wife; they have din'd together divers times in my house, and seem'd to be agreeable one with another, but I did not know where they lived; they sold fish, and were pretty customers as they pass'd and repass'd: I do not know whether they are man and wife. One night in particular I heard him say, my dear, go home and make the bed, and I'll not be long before I am with you: after bail was given in the woman was released, and Mr. Kelley and she have come to my house three or four times and have eat and drank together. I took upon me once to talk to Mr. Kelley, for charging the prisoner with a robbery and now to be so free with her; speaking broken Irish, h e said he had no intention to prosecute, or any thing of that nature.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-57-person380">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17490705-57-person380" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person380" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-person380" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Kelley came to me the beginning of last October to invite me to his wedding dinner, to a house the corner of Prince's-street. I went in the evening, and there was a very great supper.</p>
               <p>Cross examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any entertainment?</p>
               <p>Stiles. Yes, and dancing too.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon them to be man and wife then?</p>
               <p>Stiles. They appeared so to me.</p>
               <p>A witness. Mrs. Kelley came to bring me a gown to make, and told me it was to be her wedding-gown,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050019"></xptr> and both he and she ask'd me to cometo their house on such a day, saying they should be married that day: I went, there was much victuals, and we were very merry and dancing. One morning after this he came to our house, I ask'd how she did; he seem'd much disturb'd, and desir'd me to go and see her, which I did, and found her with black eyes: she told me he gave them to her; they had fish for dinner; he fed her as she lay in the bed, and said he was sorry for what he had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they no words about Smith then?</p>
               <p>Witness. There was something said about him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-57-verdict283" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-57-verdict283" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
