<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411014-14">
               <interp inst="t17411014-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-14" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-14" type="date" value="17411014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411014-14-off79-c102" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-defend134 t17411014-14-off79 t17411014-14-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>18. 
               
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-defend134" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Quaite 
                  <interp inst="t17411014-14-defend134" type="surname" value="Quaite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-defend134" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-defend134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17411014-14-defloc78">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-14-defloc78" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-14-defloc78" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-defend134 t17411014-14-defloc78"></join> was indicted for <rs id="t17411014-14-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411014-14-victim136" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Dance 
                        <interp inst="t17411014-14-victim136" type="surname" value="Dance"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-14-victim136" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-14-victim136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-off79 t17411014-14-victim136"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain open place, called <placeName id="t17411014-14-crimeloc80">St. James's Park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-off79 t17411014-14-crimeloc80"></join>, putting him in fear, and taking from him a silver watch, value 40 s. a shagreen case with instruments, value 5 s. and 1 s. 10 d. in money
            </rs>; <rs id="t17411014-14-cd81" type="crimeDate">Sept. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-off79 t17411014-14-cd81"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person137">
                  Richard 
                  Dance 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person137" type="surname" value="Dance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person137" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 6th of September I had been at Battersea , and returning late at night through St. James's Park, I heard the drum beat at the Tilt-yard . I then thought it my nearest way to get upon the Parade, in order to go out. I had not got above 30 yards upon the green park, but the prisoner came up to me and knocked me down. As soon as he came up to me he pulled out a knife, and made an attempt upon me, at the same time telling me, if I made any noise or resistance, he would murder me. I desired him to spare my life, upon which he held the knife in order to murder me, and I holding up my hand in my defence, he cut my fingers in this manner. He then took from me my watch, a case of instruments, 1 s. 6 d in silver, and 4 d. in copper. I was very much bruised, beat and cut, and when he had robbed me, he ran away, but being encouraged by people coming by, I pursued him. He still continued his course, and in the pursuit he slipped off his coat and Waistcoat, and this centry laid hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know it was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dance. It was a moon-light night, but a little cloudy. I am very positive to him, for he never was out of my sight till he was detected by this witness.</p>
               <p>Q. How far had he gone before he was taken?</p>
               <p>Dance. About two or three yards, according as the people ran: he might be sometimes nearer, and sometimes farther.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him where we met together ?</p>
               <p>Dance . No where but where I tell you; on the grass part of the park that leads from the Mall to the Parade.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person138">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person138" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was centry on St. James's Park; and about half an hour past ten at night, I heard a gentleman call out Murder! I went over to the middle of the Mall and heard Murder cried again. I called out, Where are you? the same cry was repeated two or three times, and then I saw the prisoner running away with his coat and waistcoat on his arm. This gentleman ( Dance ) was running after him, and I likewise went up with a design to take hold of him. He ran as far as the first centry that belongs to the Tilt-yard , and then he turned towards Buckingam House . I took him by the rail, coming off the grass, and got hold of the collar of his shirt, but that giving way, I delivered him to the care of some soldiers, and they let him escape. He then went to his house, and after having put on his regimental clothes he came to the Tilt yard and was retaken.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the prisoner's other clothes?</p>
               <p>Smith . He dropp'd them, and the prosecutor pick'd them up and gave them to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What light had you to see the prisoner's face ?</p>

               <p>Smith . It was a moonlight night but a little cloudy. After the prisoner had escaped from the soldiers, 2 corporals came to me and desired me to let the drummer (the Prisoner) have his clothes, but I refused, for I had laid them up in security in order to give them to the pay-serjeant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner own those clothes?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, he own'd them before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dance . I pick'd up the clothes myself and gave them to this soldier. I saw the prisoner drop them, and I saw them afterwards at a public house .</p>
               <p>Smith. The prisoner was carried before justice Manley , where the prosecutor swore to him, and when he found he was going to be committed to the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140009"></xptr> Gate House, he owned the clothes and desired to have them again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person139">
                  William 
                  Pierce 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person139" type="surname" value="Pierce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person139" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on the Tilt-yard guard as a corporal when the prosecutor came up, and my captain ordered me to go with him to find the prisoner. He (the prosecutor) was all over bloody, and one of his fore fingers was cut very deep. Captain 
               <persName id="t17411014-14-person140">
                  Lowry
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person140" type="given" value="Lowry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ordered me to go to St. James's with him, and in going along I went to Smith and asked him if he could tell me who was concern'd in it: he told me Tom . Sheerer could, and at last I was informed that 
               <persName id="t17411014-14-person141">
                  Jack 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person141" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person141" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             himself had got the prisoner's clothes: upon which we came down with another soldier towards St. James's House, and saw Smith coming out with the clothes, and so we went with them to the Goat ale-house in the Pav'd alley, where we searched the pockets, and found in them a leather sort of a round thing with a hole in it, a purse with 2 s. in it, and a piece of stuff that belongs to the brace of a drum, which made me think they belonged to a drummer. I desired the gentleman to go home that night, and promised him to find the man if I could. Accordingly after I had made all the enquiry I could, about 3 quarters of an hour after 11 at night I went towards Whitehall, and the prisoner came by in company with Scholes and Holbrook. I ask'd them what the prisoner's name was? they told me Quaites ; so I call'd him and took hold of him by the collar and told him he was my prisoner. He desired me to let him go and see for his clothes, but I carried him to the guard-room and charged him with the two serjeants of the guard: he was detained all night, and the next day carried before justice Manley .</p>
               <p>Q. What clothes had the prisoner on when you took him?</p>
               <p>Pierce. He had his regimental drum clothes on.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I desire to go and see the prosecutor upon St. James's guard ?</p>
               <p>Pierce. No, only to see his clothes, and I told him I had got them in custody, and I would take care of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person142">
                  William 
                  Cowton 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person142" type="surname" value="Cowton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person142" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Serjeant. This corporal (Pierce) brought the prisoner to me, upon which I confined him directly. I got a drum cord and tied his 2 legs and arms together, and set a centry over him with a drawn sword 'till morning. I saw the prosecutor that night; he was very bloody and came to make his complaint to captain Lowry, and I told him I would use my endeavours to find the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person143">
                  Rowland 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person143" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person143" type="given" value="Rowland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am the constable that had the warrant against the prisoner. He denied the fact before the justice, but own'd that he was in the scuffle ; and that he saw some money in the prosecutor's hand, and that it dropp'd in the grass.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing said about the clothes?</p>
               <p>Davis. They were saying that he was in his shirt, and he owned that he was in a scuffle and lost his clothes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person144">
                  John 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person144" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person144" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , serjeant, confirmed the deposition of 
               <persName id="t17411014-14-person145">
                  William 
                  Cowton 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person145" type="surname" value="Cowton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person145" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , with this addition, that the prisoner owned he had lost his clothes, that he had the prosecutor's money, and that he had given it him to conduct him through the park: that he (this witness) went next morning with the prisoner, at his desire, to look in the grass for the watch, but that it was not found.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>I had been to see a comrade to Hammersmith, and being in liquor, and coming through the Park in my way home I sat down, and fell asleep. While I was asleep, this gentleman came up, and tapp'd me on the thigh, and asked me if I was asleep? I said yes: what is that to you? he ask'd me if my breeches were cloth or leather: I ask'd if he had not his feeling. After this he offered some indecencies to me, and I told him he should go with me to the centry: he desired me not to expose him, and pull'd out some money which he threw on the grass, and then fell to beating me. He then cried out murder! I am robb'd of my watch! and a chairman and a woman came to my assistance. My coat was pretty wide, and my waistcoat had no sleeves, and they slipp'd off in the scuffle. I told the chairman how it was between us, and so he gave me my clothes. I had got them on my arm, and this centry came up and took the clothes from me, and I went off. About an hour and half afterwards, hearing that such a thing was alledged against me, I surrender'd myself to these two men, and was with them when Smith seized me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person146">
                  John 
                  Walkinshaw 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person146" type="surname" value="Walkinshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person146" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was centry in St. James's Park at nine o'clock at night, the next post to Spring Garden Gate , and the horse parrole came past me. I heard a sort of a murmuring which I thought was in the wilderness: - There was no moonlight nor any such thing, but it was a very dark night . For about 2 minute and an half all was quiet and still, and then I heard a cry of thieves! I am robb'd! I was a little surprised and kept still on the watch, and as I listen'd the voice came nearer to me. I thought I heard a patting on the grass , so I went to the rails , and peep'd between the sky in this manner, and I saw something moving. Presently I could hear stop thief! I am robb'd! and afterwards the prisoner and this gentleman came up. They were 3 yards asunder , and the prosecutor had neither his hat nor wig on. The gentleman said he was robb'd, and the prisoner said, he had offered something vile to him. I damn'd them both, and ask'd them how they came there? The gentleman said he came in at Buckingham gate , and that the prisoner pretended to shew him the nearest way to the Tilt-yard guard. I detain'd the prosecutor and took him into my centry box; and then he complaining that his head was very cold for want of his hat and wig .<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140010"></xptr> I went with him to look in the grass for them. He found them both, and then I was for taking him back again , but he desired me not to be in a hurry, for he believed he should find his watch: G - D - you, says I, (I ask pardon for swearing, for I did say so) did you not tell me the man had got your watch? He grovel'd in the grass 20 or 30 times for the space of a minute and half and could not find it. I then gave the prosecutor over to a man nearer the Tilt-yard guard, and as we were carrying him along he fell to eating apples out of his pocket, and if I would be so good as to take his waistcoat, he said he would come in the morning, and he desired me not to expose him, for he did not know whether the fellow had his watch or no. I told him if he would not give me 20 guineas and his waistcoat I would not let him go, and so I delivered him up to the other centry.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prosecutor appear to be bloody at that time?</p>
               <p>Walkinshaw . I can't tell. I had him by the arm, and told him if he offered to stir a foot, I was loaded and would shoot him. After I had delivered the prosecutor to the centry, I ask'd Smith where the fellow was that ran away, and he said he had got his clothes. Smith took hold of the prisoner, and I seiz'd the gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person147">
                  John 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person147" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person147" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , deposed to the same effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person148">
                  John 
                  Scholes 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person148" type="surname" value="Scholes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person148" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was at the suttling house with my comrade, and hearing a noise in the Park, I ran and met the prisoner in the gravel walk between the Mall and the chairs which are put for people to sit in. He is a drummer, and I was very much surpriz'd to hear him charged with such a thing, and I bid the centry take care of him; but while I was turning myself round, he rushed out of the centry's hand. Immediately I turn'd to the prosecutor, and seeing him bare headed, I asked him where his hat and wig were? He said the rogue had robb'd him of them, and the centry that had hold of him said he should go before the officer of the guard. He had not gone above ten or twelve steps before he desired to look for his hat and wig, and he went into a lonesom place by the side of the canal, call'd the Princess's walk: a place not sit for them to be in, for every centry has orders to keep people out of it even in the day time. He grovel'd about some time, and sound his hat and wig, and after that being pretty much 'frighted, he desired the centry to stay a little and let him look for his watch. The centry would not stay, but took him along, and he offered to give any satisfaction in the world not to be exposed. After this, hearing that Smith had got the prisoner's clothes, I desired him to let me have them, but he refused. I and my comrade then went to our quarters at the Horse Granadier Drum in King Street, and while we were eating some pork, the prisoner came in and surrender'd himself to us, and we were carrying him to the guard when Smith met us and took him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person149">
                  John 
                  Holbrook 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person149" type="surname" value="Holbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the person to whom the prisoner was delivered by Smith. He deposed, that the prisoner rushed from him, without his clothes. The other part of his evidence was of the same tenor as that given by Scholes .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person150">
                  John 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person150" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person150" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on White-ball guard , and went to the Horse and Drum, to drink a pint of beer, and the prisoner coming in, the corporals accused him of robbing the gentleman in the park. He denied it, and surrender'd himself up into their custody.</p>
               <p>- Terry . I keep the Horse Granadier Drum in King-street, and Holbrook and Scholes are quarter'd at my house. They came in by themselves about half an hour after 10 at night and sat down. I asked them to eat some pork, and they told me there had been a great stir in the park, and that a drummer had robbed a man. They had not drank a pot of beer before the prisoner came in. They charged him with it, and he surrender'd directly.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. A man came to me last Sunday, and asked me if any body was concerned with me, and if I did not impeach them, he said, the prosecutor would bring a man that should hang me right or wrong. This is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person151">
                  Samuel 
                  Stone 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person151" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person151" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The prosecutor told me he had been robbed, and I went to Newgate with another person to see one Downes, who is a debtor there. The prisoner was then sitting in an adjacent box, and I told him, if any body was concerned with him, I would have him make himself an evidence, and he said, he could not do it now. The prosecutor bears the character of an honest worthy man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-14-person152">
                  Thomas 
                  Bamford 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person152" type="surname" value="Bamford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person152" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17411014-14-person153">
                  John 
                  Marshal 
               <interp inst="t17411014-14-person153" type="surname" value="Marshal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and J - R - had known the prosecutor different numbers of years, and always took him to be a very sober honest man. <rs id="t17411014-14-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17411014-14-punish83" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-14-punish83" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-14-defend134 t17411014-14-punish83"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
