<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440728-28">
               <interp inst="t17440728-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-28" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-28" type="date" value="17440728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440728-28-off163-c315" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-28-defend384 t17440728-28-off163 t17440728-28-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>332. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-defend384" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Turner 
                  <interp inst="t17440728-28-defend384" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-defend384" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-defend384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17440728-28-defloc162">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-28-defloc162" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-28-defloc162" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-28-defend384 t17440728-28-defloc162"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440728-28-off163" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-off163" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-off163" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 3 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440728-28-victim386" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Tuck 
                        <interp inst="t17440728-28-victim386" type="surname" value="Tuck"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440728-28-victim386" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440728-28-victim386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-28-off163 t17440728-28-victim386"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440728-28-cd164" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-28-off163 t17440728-28-cd164"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person387">
                  Samuel 
                  Tuck 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person387" type="surname" value="Tuck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person387" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 15th of May I was walking in Covent Garden 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person388">
                  Piazzas
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person388" type="given" value="Piazzas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person388" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and was enticed by a couple of young women to go to a house in <placeName id="t17440728-28-crimeloc165">St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-28-crimeloc165" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-28-crimeloc165" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-28-off163 t17440728-28-crimeloc165"></join> about ten o'clock at night. As soon as I got into the room the two women and I had a glass of gin ; when we had drank that the two women fell upon me, and took my silver buckles out of my shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner one of the two women?</p>
               <p>Tuck . I saw her in the house, but she was not one of the two women. When they had taken my buckles they left me in the room by myself, then I went out of the house with a design to go home about my business; as soon as I came out the Prisoner at the bar followed me, came unawares behind me, and tore my watch out by main force through the waistband of my breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you prevent her doing it?</p>
               <p>Tuck . Because I was by myself, and she came unawares upon me. I turned round, and saw the watch in her hand, and she went into the house she came out of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel the watch taken out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Tuck. I felt the watch going. I turned round and saw it in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. So you did not secure her?</p>
               <p>Tuck. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at that time perfectly sober?</p>
               <p>Tuck . I was sober when I came into their company, I had been drinking a dram or two with them - I was not so much out of my senses, but I could remember very well what I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink any thing before you went there?</p>
               <p>Tuck. I drank one dram before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He had a warrant against the other two women.</p>
               <p>Tuck . I had a warrant to take the two women; I at first learned the name of one of them, but the name of the other I could not learn.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge the other women with?<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280026"></xptr> Did you charge them with taking your watch as well as your buckles?</p>
               <p>Tuck . No; only with taking the buckles; the Prisoner's name was in the warrant, but it was only for taking the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you secure the Prisoner then?</p>
               <p>Tuck . I secured her the next day.</p>
               <p>Jury. Why did not you secure her then, you might have run after her and taken her?</p>
               <p>Tuck . I was afraid of having my brains knocked out.</p>
               <p>Jury. You don't say there were any men in the house; did you see any men there?</p>
               <p>Tuck . No; I did not see any.</p>
               <p>Jury. It is not probable that these people should take his buckles out of his shoes, and leave a watch in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Prosecutor came th e next day to search for a watch; I stood with my back to the window, he said he saw nobody that he knew; the Constable asked him whether he could swear to any body, at last he laid his hand upon my shoulder, and said, you are the woman that robbed me of my watch; and Mr. Waters made answer, and said, I must take charge of you, and I went down to the watch-house with them. I never set eyes on him before, and I did not know him again when I saw him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person389">
                  Mary 
                  Durham 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person389" type="surname" value="Durham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person389" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person389" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner five or six years, and know her to be a hard working person. I live in the same house where she did, the Prisoner was fast asleep by the fire side when the Prosecutor came in with the two women. I heard him cry he was robbed, and I saw one of those creatures run through the coach yard about eight or nine doors lower, one ran after her, and cried, 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person390">
                  Bess 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person390" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person390" type="given" value="Bess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , why don't you come back, (they are both of them by New-Goal now.) I will take my oath to both of them by their faces, and to one of them by her shape, she is crooked.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you were in the house after these women run out; did you continue in the house yourself?</p>
               <p>Durham . No; I went out and sat upon the steps.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner go out?</p>
               <p>Durham. No; she was sitting by the fire side.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have seen her go out, if she had gone out?</p>
               <p>Durham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>Durham. I went up to bed three or four minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. If you went up to bed so soon, how do you know she did not go out?</p>
               <p>Durham. I did not hear her stir afterwards, if she did go out it was unknown to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person391">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person391" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person391" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mrs. Bradley in St. Giles's in the Fields. I saw two creatures with the Prosecutor, one of them held him fast against a wall, and 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person392">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person392" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person392" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person392" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             run away with his watch - 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person393">
                  Mary 
                  Mascall 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person393" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person393" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person393" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person394">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person394" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person394" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person394" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were the two persons; 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person395">
                  Mary 
                  Mascall 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person395" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person395" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person395" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, by G - d I have got his buckles, and the other is run away with his watch; Smith took the watch, I saw the chain of it in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a silver or a gold watch?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person396">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person396" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person396" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was a silver watch, a middle sized watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person397">
                  Ann 
                  Spratt 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person397" type="surname" value="Spratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person397" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person397" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep a publick house in Church Lane, I sat up that night for a man and his wife who lodged in my house: I heard some tongues talking, and went to the door, and there was one 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person398">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person398" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person398" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the left hand of this young man [the Prosecutor.]</p>
               <p>Q. Can you remember him?</p>
               <p>Spratt. Yes; I can - he stood with his back to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What discourse was there?</p>
               <p>Spratt. The discourse was this; he said let me feel; says 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person399">
                  Betty 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person399" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person399" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person399" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I thought you would lie here all night, and Smith said let me feel; she spoke in a vulgar way, and she said he should feel. He unbuttoned his breeches, and she took hold of his fob, and gave something a twitch, and whipped it away, but I cannot tell what it was. Mascall came in again, the watchman then went past eleven, and the Prosecutor said, are you the watchman? and he said, yes. Says he, I am robbed, and he mentioned a watch for one thing, and either buttons or buckles, I cannot tell which ; and I heard no more of it till Wednesday morning when the house was searched.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person400">
                  Hannah 
                  Battle 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person400" type="surname" value="Battle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person400" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person400" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be standing at the door, and the last witness said that a young man and one of the women were gone up stairs; when the Constable came next day, he said to the Prosecutor, do you know any thing of that young woman [the Prisoner?] and he said, no. Said one of the gentlemen, you ought to be well horsewhipped. There are two women in the New Goal who he swore took his watch.</p>
               <p>Tuck. I swore to the other two women who are in custody for taking my buckles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person401">
                  Henry 
                  Townley 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person401" type="surname" value="Townley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person401" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I had no warrant to take the Prisoner, I had a warrant to take two other women.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person402">
                  Samuel 
                  Tuck 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person402" type="surname" value="Tuck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person402" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with you?</p>
               <p>Townley . Yes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280027"></xptr>Q. Do you remember what Tuck said? Did he charge you with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Townley. When he first saw her, he said she was not the woman - I am upon my oath, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you afterwards present when he said she was the woman?</p>
               <p>Townley. Yes - I was in the watch-house, the Prosecutor came in about one o'clock in the morning in liquor, and said he had been robbed. Mr. Waters was the constable of the night, and I am his headborough; three or four of us went that night into that street, and he did not know which was the house. He came at three or four o'clock that afternoon, and brought this warrant, and swore to three persons robbing him of his watch and buckles. I went to search for these women, (they lodged there then) and there was the Prisoner and three more women in the house; when I came into the ground room, I said to the Prosecutor, is ever an one of these women one of the persons that robbed you? Look and take notice of them; and he said never an one of those women robbed him. The Prisoner showed us into every room of the house, and when the Prosecutor was coming out of the house, he turned about, and said, this is the woman, and I will swear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-28-person403">
                  John 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person403" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person403" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The night after Mr. Townley had the warrant, was my watch night; I saw Mr. Townley in the afternoon, says he, it is your watch night, there is a young fellow has lost his watch, and I cannot find the people; said he, will you take the warrant from me, and I said I would; but the young man came to the watch house and I gave Mr. Townley the warrant again, but he desired me to take a walk with him there; when I came there I saw the Prisoner, I had known her six or seven years; said I, 
               <persName id="t17440728-28-person404">
                  Betty 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17440728-28-person404" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person404" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-person404" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have a suspicion of two people in your house having committed a robbery, and I am come to search (there were some other women there) the Prisoner took a candle and lighted us, and the Prosecutor said none of those persons were the women that robbed him; and as he was coming out of the house, he turned back again, and said, that is the woman, and I will swear to her. <rs id="t17440728-28-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-28-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
