<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410405-53">
               <interp inst="t17410405-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-53" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-53" type="date" value="17410405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410405-53-off218-c271" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-53-defend386 t17410405-53-off218 t17410405-53-verdict221"></join>
         
               <p>58. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-defend386" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Theobalds 
                  <interp inst="t17410405-53-defend386" type="surname" value="Theobalds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-defend386" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-defend386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             the younger was indicted for <rs id="t17410405-53-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="barratry"></interp>
               Barretry
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prosecution set forth, that the Prisoner stood charged with Barretry, and that it was Matter of Concern to see a Man who had been brought up in an honourable prosession , so far demean himself, as to stir up Suits among his Majesty's Subjects, to get Money to himself and distress his Fellow Creatures. That the Prisoner was charged with 15 separate Articles of Barretry, and if there should be proof of three only, that would be sufficient to convict him of this Offence, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The 4th Article against the Prisoner was read, the Substance of which was, That he the said Theobalds , on or about the <rs id="t17410405-53-cd219" type="crimeDate">13th Day of July 1739</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-53-off218 t17410405-53-cd219"></join>, at the House of 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person387">
                  William 
                  Castledine 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person387" type="surname" value="Castledine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person387" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , did incite and persuade him the said Castledine, to join with him in a Bill of Indictment against 
               
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-victim389" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Drinkwater 
                  <interp inst="t17410405-53-victim389" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-victim389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-victim389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-53-off218 t17410405-53-victim389"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             for Barretry; which Bill of Indictment by the procurement of the said Theobald, was preferred to the Grand Jury of Middlesex, and by them found a true Bill. And on or about the 18th of July, by Vertue of the Lord Chief Justice Lee's Warrant, he the said Drinkwater was carried to Woodstreet Compter, and there detained till he gave Bail; and afterwards on the 3d of December he the said Drinkwater was tried for the same Offence and acquitted.</p>
               <p>[Here the Record of the Drinkwater's Acquittal was read.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person390">
                  Joseph 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person390" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person390" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner, Castledine, I and some more, had a Meeting together at the Salutation-Tavern in Holbourn, and there it was agreed between them, that an Indictment should be preferred against Drinkwater for Barretry: Theobalds said it would be a Means to bring him to Terms. In a little Time afterwards the Bill was preferred to the Grand Jury, and the Prisoner himself told me it was found a true Bill.</p>
               <p>Council. Was there any Mention made of an Act of Barretry that Drinkwater had done?</p>
               <p>Williams. No, there were some Indictments between Drinkwater and Castledine, and the Prisoner said that would bring Drinkwater to Terms.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person391">
                  Lydia 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person391" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person391" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Theobalds say, if Drinkwater was cast for Barretry, it was a very hard Thing, for it was what few people understood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person392">
                  Hannah 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person392" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person392" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person392" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first Time that I heard any Thing of this Affair, Theobalds came in, and said he had found out a new Way to punish Drinkwater : Then Griffits, Castledine, the Prisoner and another went into the parlour to consult together, and soon afterwards the Bill was found.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Where was all this Discourse?</p>
               <p>Thomas. At Castledine's House in Johnson's-Court, Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person393">
                  Jonathan 
                  Bellamy 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person393" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person393" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Constable of St. Bride's, and had a Warrant against Drinkwater given me by Castledine. I apprehended him, and Theobalds gave me a Guinea for my Trouble.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person394">
                  Robert 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person394" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person394" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Hick's-Hall, and saw Mr. Theobalds , Griffits, and one 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person395">
                  James 
                  Maul 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person395" type="surname" value="Maul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person395" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             go in, they returned presently and said the Bill was found.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person396">
                  William 
                  Griffits 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person396" type="surname" value="Griffits"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person396" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was concerned in this Bill against Drinkwater, and my Name was on the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174104050015"></xptr> Back of the Bill, but I can't tell who were concerned in framing it. I did design to prosecute Drinkwater, because he had done me an Injury.</p>
               <p>Council. Was not this Thing set on Foot without your Knowledge?</p>
               <p>Griffits . No, I heard that such a Thing was intended, and I joined in it.</p>
               <p>Council. Was there not a Cause depending at that Time against Castledine, for keeping a Bawdy-House?</p>
               <p>Griffits . I am not positive of that. The Reason why I designed to prosecute Drinkwater was this: He met me and abused me very much, and in about 3 Quarters of an Hour, he served me with the Copy of a Writ. This was in Easter Term, so Castledine employed a Man to take it in Hand, and they got Judgment against me by Default. As soon as this was done, he countermanded Trial, and when I brought it on before the Lord Chief Justice Willes I nonsuited him, and the next Term at Guild-Hall he swore he had no Notice of Trial; when that very Morning he delivered a Brief into his Council's Hand. As to Drinkwater's general Character, he always was looked upon to be a very litigious Man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cummins . About 2 Years and half ago, I was Tipstaff of the Court of King's-Bench, and having a Warrant against Drinkwater, I carried him to my own House, and he behaved himself there in such a Manner, as frighted my Wife very much - I don't think there is such another litigious Fellow in London .</p>
               <p>Here the 5th Article against the Prisoner was read, the Substance of which was, that he the said Theobalds on or about the 13th of July 1739, did persuade 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person397">
                  William 
                  Castledine 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person397" type="surname" value="Castledine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person397" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to join with him in a Bill of Indictment against 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person398">
                  John 
                  Drinkwater 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person398" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person398" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; which Bill was preferred to the Grand Jury, and found a true Bill; on which such proceedings were had, that afterwards at the Sessions of the Peace, he the said Drinkwater was tried and acquitted.</p>
               <p>[The Indictment against Drinkwater was read.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person399">
                  Joseph 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person399" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person399" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Theobalds told me there was a Bill found against Drinkwater in London, and that he was on the Back of it as a Witness against him. There was a Bill then depending against Castledine for keeping a Bawdy-House, and Theobalds said, the Way to perplex Drinkwater and bring him to Terms, was to indict him for Barretry.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. At Hicks's-Hall they got off by an Artifice, and we were informed that an Indictment for this Offence need not be local, and therefore brought this in London.</p>
               <p>The purport of the 8th Article was, That he the said Theobalds contriving to vex 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person400">
                  John 
                  Drinkwater 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person400" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person400" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did apply to 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person401">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Delander 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person401" type="surname" value="Delander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person401" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person402">
                  William 
                  Lowton 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person402" type="surname" value="Lowton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person402" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to prosecute the said Drinkwater for a Felony, in receiving 8 l. 8 s. of the said Delander for a Watch, and not discovering the Felon who stole the same: That a Bill was exhibited to the Grand Inquest and found a true Bill, on which Indictment such proceedings were had, that he the said Drinkwater was acquitted.</p>
               <p>* [The Indictment against 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person403">
                  John 
                  Drinkwater 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person403" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person403" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was read.]</p>
               <p>* See Session's-Book 1739, No. 8. Pag. 164.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person404">
                  William 
                  Lawton 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person404" type="surname" value="Lawton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person404" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was summoned before Mr. De Veil, and when I came there I saw Mr. Theobalds , and he would have persuaded the Colonel to give me my Oath, how I lost the Watch; I thought it very hard that I should be called on to tell a long Story, and therefore refused to give any Account; however I received a Subpoena to appear before the Grand Jury, but I was not called, and after that, Theobalds told me the Bill was found, and he had done without me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you never swear that this Watch was stolen from you?</p>
               <p>Lawton. No, I never did, nor can't.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You say you can't tell how you lost this Watch. He was in a Bawdy-House, and this Watch was taken, and all the Inside of it was taken, and the Shagreen Case found in his Fob: - Every Subject has a Right to prosecute by 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person405">
                  Jonathan 
                  Wild 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person405" type="surname" value="Wild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person405" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Act. Did I not appear as an <rs id="t17410405-53-deflabel220" type="occupation">Attorney</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-53-defend386 t17410405-53-deflabel220"></join> in that Cause?</p>
               <p>Lowton. I believe he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person406">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Rayner 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person406" type="surname" value="Rayner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person406" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person406" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Servant to Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17410405-53-person407">
                  Deborah 
                  Pope 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person407" type="surname" value="Pope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person407" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person407" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , when she was in Trouble about this Watch; and Mr. Theobalds would have given me 5 Guineas to swear against Drinkwater whom I never saw. I was to swear that I saw Drinkwater give Mrs. Pope 4 Guineas on Account of the Watch, that it might be paid back!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person408">
                  Lydia 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person408" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person408" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person408" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know any Thing of Theobalds being concerned in the prosecution of Drinkwater about the Watch, for I believe Castledine carried it on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person409">
                  Hannah 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person409" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person409" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person409" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I used to be always at Castledine's House, and I think I heard Theobald say in the parlour, that he promoted this prosecution against Drinkwater, and it was to transport him on some Act, but I can't tell what.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-53-person410">
                  Joseph 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17410405-53-person410" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person410" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Theobalds was concerned in the prosecution of Drinkwater, but I believe he was employed as an Attorney by Castledine.</p>
               <p>There were divers other Articles exhibited against the Prisoner, but there not being sufficient Evidence he was <rs id="t17410405-53-verdict221" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-53-verdict221" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
