<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-11">
               <interp inst="t17470909-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-11" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-11" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-11-off47-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-11-defend97 t17470909-11-off47 t17470909-11-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>323. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-11-defend97" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Fletcher 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-11-defend97" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-defend97" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-defend97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted by the Coroner's Inquest, for <rs id="t17470909-11-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               the Murder of her bastard Child, by throwing it in a certain House of Office
            </rs>, <rs id="t17470909-11-cd48" type="crimeDate">August the 30th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-11-off47 t17470909-11-cd48"></join>.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Thompson. I live in <placeName id="t17470909-11-crimeloc49">Chambers-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-11-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="Chambers-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-11-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-11-off47 t17470909-11-crimeloc49"></join>; the House is let out into Tenements. Last Sunday was a Fortnight, two Women came and asked to go into the Yard to the Privy, and after they had been there about two Minutes, they said they wanted to speak to one of us; when I came into the Yard, they said there was a Child in the Vault; I said it must be a dead Dog; they said it was not, it was a Child; and when I went I could not raise it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know who put it there?</p>
               <p>Thompson. No, Sir, nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you swear nothing more than this before the Coroner?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I saw the Prisoner about three Weeks before, and she had a big Belly; she came in on Sunday, and ask'd to go backward: I said she was welcome, but there were two Women there.</p>
               <p>Court. This was last Sunday was Se'nnight: Had she been in your Privy before?</p>
               <p>Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When she came in, did she come along with the two Women?</p>
               <p>Thompson. No, she came after them.</p>
               <p>Court. But the Child was found before?</p>
               <p>Thompson. Yes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090007"></xptr>Court. But what was that to this Woman the Prisoner? Why did not you secure those two Women?</p>
               <p>Thompson. They were at Hickes's Hall ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-11-person98">
                  Sarah 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17470909-11-person98" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person98" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in a lower Room of the House, and as I was going out on an Errand for my Mistress, there was News that there was a Child found in 
               <persName id="t17470909-11-person99">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17470909-11-person99" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person99" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Vault. I went upon this News, and found there was a Child, and a fine Babe.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know, whether the Prisoner went into that Vault?</p>
               <p>Martin. I can't tell, but they examin'd her Breast, and found Milk, and she was charg'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know she ever was in that Vault? Is it a common Privy, or does it belong to Mrs Wood?</p>
               <p>Martin. To Mrs Wood.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner absolutely deny'd her being in that Vault.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-11-person100">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17470909-11-person100" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person100" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were two Women came in last Sunday was sev'nnight, and ask'd to go up in the Yard. That young Woman and I live together, and this Privy belongs to our Tenement, and nobody else have a Right to come there.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wood. Nothing, but only that the Neighbours had a Suspicion that it was her Child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she use to go into the Privy?</p>
               <p>Wood. I don't know what she might do before we came; for we came there but the Night before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive that she was with Child?</p>
               <p>Wood. I never took so much Notice of her, but what the Neighbourhood said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-11-person101">
                  Mary 
                  Bowler 
               <interp inst="t17470909-11-person101" type="surname" value="Bowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person101" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was brought to me on a Sabbath-Day, I believe it was the 30th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. For what Purpose was she brought to you?</p>
               <p>Bowler. Those that brought her said, That she seem'd to be in Labour the Thursday before. Upon that I examined the Woman, and I insisted it was entirely false, it could not be her Child of so late a Date.</p>
               <p>Court. You examined her. Did she appear to be delivered of a Child?</p>
               <p>Bowler. She has had a Child, but I don't apprehend at that Time. There were several that pulled her about, and frighten'd her; and it was a particular Time, and that might give a Suspicion it was her Child.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lodged in this House for five Weeks, but never was in this Vault during the Time, till I ask'd that Gentlewoman's Leave on Sunday after the Child was found; and on this Thursday that was mentioned I was working for one Charmichael, picking of Hair, from nine o'Clock in the Morning till six at Night.</p>
               <p>When this Bill was presented to the Grand Jury, who, upon hearing the Affair, return'd it Ignoramus. And upon Examination of the Affair by judicious Persons in the Neighbourhood, the Charge upon the Prisoner appeared entirely without a Foundation, and arose from some poor, ignorant, and rash People, by whose Means this poor Creature was like to fall a Sacrifice to the Mob. It seems she has a Child now in the Workhouse, whom she suckled for two Years, and has given another Child suck since, which was the Occassion of her having Milk in her Breasts.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470909-11-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-11-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
