<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-36">
               <interp inst="t17400116-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-36" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-36" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-36-off171-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-defend255 t17400116-36-off171 t17400116-36-verdict174"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-36-off171-c179" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-defend257 t17400116-36-off171 t17400116-36-verdict174"></join>
         
               <p>120, 121. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-36-defend255" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Taverner , alias <rs id="t17400116-36-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-defend255 t17400116-36-alias-2"></join>Howard</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend255" type="surname" value="Taverner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend255" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-36-defend257" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Sargeway , alias <rs id="t17400116-36-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-defend257 t17400116-36-alias-3"></join>French Hannah</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend257" type="surname" value="Sargeway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend257" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-defend257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17400116-36-off171" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-off171" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-off171" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-36-victim259" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Bockcomb 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-36-victim259" type="surname" value="Bockcomb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-36-victim259" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-36-victim259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-off171 t17400116-36-victim259"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , between 2 and 3 in the Night, and stealing a Silver Watch, val. 30 s. a Velvet Hood, val. 2 s. 6 d. 3 Linnen Shirts, value 18 s. a Cambrick Apron, val. 5 s. a Holland Apron, val. 2 s. 6 d. a Pair of Stockings, val. 2 s. and a Piece of Pork, val. 6 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400116-36-cd172" type="crimeDate">Dec. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-off171 t17400116-36-cd172"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-36-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Bockcomb 
               <interp inst="t17400116-36-person260" type="surname" value="Bockcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday, December 2, about 11 o'Clock at Night, I went to Bed, and left my House safe: when I came down Stairs on Monday Morning about 8, I found the Sash up; the Window-Shutters open about a Nail of a Yard, and a Silver Watch, a Velvet Hood, 3 Shirts, a Cambrick Apron, and a Piece of Pork were gone. I am positive the Sash was down, and the Shutters were close when I went to Bed, but by Accident, the Pin was not put in the Shutters. When I went to Bed, I took the Piece of Pork out of the Cupboard, and put it upon a Corner Table, by Way of Security against the Mice; and the Pork was taken away, but a Silver Spoon, which was in the Dish with the Pork, was left. This made some of my Neighbours suspect the Lad, (the next Witness) because he is near-fighted, and they imagined he either did not see the Spoon, or that it was Silver. When the Boy was taken, he confess'd the Fact, and among the Things taken, he mentioned a Pair of Stockings, which I did not miss, till he told me of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-36-person261">
                  Henry 
                  Bentley 
               <interp inst="t17400116-36-person261" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person261" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two Prisoners went with me to this Woman's House in <placeName id="t17400116-36-crimeloc173">Newtoner's Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-36-crimeloc173" type="placeName" value="Newtoner's Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-36-crimeloc173" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-36-off171 t17400116-36-crimeloc173"></join>, and the Window-Shutters towards the Street, being neither pinn'd nor key'd, I took a Shutter down; then I lifted up the Sash and went in, between three and four in the Morning. They both stood close to the Window to take the Goods in their Aprons. - I have been in Trouble five Weeks about this Affair. - After I was first taken, I made my Escape, and was concealed under the Prisoners Bed for several Days, and then I was retaken. - The Watch (which I took out of a Drawer) and three Shirts I gave Sargeway through the Window, into her Apron. Taverner took the Velvet Hood, and Stockings, and the Piece of Pork, into her Apron. Then I got out through the Window, and went Home with them, and we all went to Bed together, and eat the Pork in Bed, without any Bread. In the Morning Taverner was called up, by one Kelley, to go to BillingsGate, and when she came back, Sargeway tied up three Shirts, two Aprons, the black Velvet Hood, and the Pair of Stockings, in a Handkerchief, and carried them out. When she returned, she said she had pawned them for 6 s. and 6 d. but she would not tell me where she had pledged them. I was left a-Bed, while they went out to pawn these Things, and they gave me 3 s. out of the 6 s. and 6 d. As to the Watch, I told the Prisoners I believed I could sell it; and I carried it to one 
               <persName id="t17400116-36-person262">
                  John 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17400116-36-person262" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Painter, in Church-Lane, and left it with him to sell for me; but the Day following he told me, he believ'd it was stole, and he said he would give it the Headborough, that it might be advertised; but he never did, for as soon as I was found out, and and taken up, he went off the Ground with it.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Can you say we went with you to Mrs Backcomb's House?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160018"></xptr>Bentley. I had knowledge of the House, and that the Shutters were not pinned. I told them of it, and the 2 Prisoners and I made an Agreement to go thither, at a House which we frequented in the Coal-Yard.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. How came we to give you 3 s. when you say we had but 6 s. 6 d. among us all?</p>
               <p>Bentley. They told me they could get but 6 s. 6 d. upon the Things, but I believe they got more; for Taverner, when she carry'd them out, had an old dirty blue Cloak on, and in about 2 Hours after she had pawn'd them, she had got a good whitish Cloak, and new Stockings on.</p>
               <p>Taverner. I know nothing of the Robbery. I went to Bed that Night about 9 o'Clock, and got up about 5 in the Morning, to go to Billingsgate for Fish, as I used to do. When I came Home again, there was a Hubbub, about the Boy (Bentley's) being found in the Room. We had no Lock to our Door, and any Body might get into the Room.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bockcomb. She says there was no Lock to the Prisoner's Room: When I went thither, I desired the Prisoners to let me go in, and search the Room. Taverner gave me 2 Keys, but neither of them would open the Door, upon which, my Servant got a Story-Ladder, and went in at the Window; then he opened the Door, but they found nothing, except the Pork-bones, which I believe were mine, - they were like mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Was you in the Room yourself?</p>
               <p>Backcomb. No.</p>
               <p>Sargeway. Before we should have taken the 3 Shirts to have pawned, surely we should have pawned the Watch; - He is a Boy that has robb'd all the Neighbourhood. They gave him a little Victuals out of Charity, at Mr. Russel's where I wash, and he said there, he would hang his Father and Mother, before he would be hanged himself. He's a vile, cruel Creature.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-36-person263">
                  Thomas 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17400116-36-person263" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person263" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the Evidence on Suspicion of robbing me, and delivered him to the Prosecutrix; He has a bad Character, all over the Neighbourhood. When I took him, I asked him what he had done with Mrs. Bockcomb's Things? He told me he knew nothing at all of the Robbery. I have known Sargeway about 2 Years, and my Wife has entrusted her to wash Linnen; I don't know she ever wrong'd me of a Farthing. As to Taverner, she lives in the Neighbourhood, and goes to Billingsgate for Fish, I know no Harm of her. While I was searching for the Boy, they never offered to go out of the Way.</p>
               <p>Bentley. I know this Man, to be as vile a Fellow as ever came before your Lordship. Both <rs id="t17400116-36-verdict174" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-36-verdict174" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
