<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460226-27">
               <interp inst="t17460226-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-27" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460226-27" type="date" value="17460226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460226-27-off93-c254" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-27-defend299 t17460226-27-off93 t17460226-27-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>115. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-defend299" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Hooker 
                  <interp inst="t17460226-27-defend299" type="surname" value="Hooker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-defend299" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-defend299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460226-27-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing from 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460226-27-victim301" type="victimName">
                           Rachel 
                           North 
                        <interp inst="t17460226-27-victim301" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460226-27-victim301" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460226-27-victim301" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-27-off93 t17460226-27-victim301"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 5 s. 6 d. 1/2, two Half Crowns and 6 d. 1/2
            </rs> .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person302">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person302" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person302" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to North) Give an Account of what you know of the Prisoner at the Bar. She is charg'd with picking your Pocket.</p>
               <p>North. Gentlemen, my proper Witness is not here, I have sent , I expect him to be here every Moment .</p>
               <p>Q. Give an Account of what you know of this Matter .</p>
               <p>North . I had been at an Acquaintance's House of mine , the other End of the Town. Coming home I was very late, between Eleven and Twelve o'Clock.</p>

               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>North. To the best of my Knowledge, Sunday Night last was three Weeks; this happen'd in <placeName id="t17460226-27-crimeloc94">Cheapside , near Bow Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460226-27-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="Cheapside , near Bow Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460226-27-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460226-27-off93 t17460226-27-crimeloc94"></join>: There were two Creatures came up to me and said, How do you do, good Woman? She (the Prisoner) got up close by me, whereas my Pocket hung as it does now: Says I, good Woman, I don't know you. There were two Creatures together. She put her Hand into my Pocket and took out two Half Crowns, a new Six-pence and some Farthings, to the best of my Knowledge three Half-pence. When she took it out I felt her Hand in my Pocket, but I did not seize her immediately, because I could not see the Watchmen about. Thinks I, when I see a proper Watchman I'll charge you with it. There were three of the Creatures. When they came down Foster-Lane, says she (the Prisoner) I'll go Home this Way; says I, I can go Home this Way too. When I saw the Watchman upon the Stand I took immediately hold of her Arm; I said, you have robb'd me of such and such Money. When we came to the Watchman, as she is a common Creature that every one knows, I said, you robb'd me; she express'd herself in a Way I cannot express. I have a Husband, and I have got a Child almost nine Years old; I told her, I did not know what she meant by it; I don't desire, I said, any further Law; but I would have my own. Says the Constable, give<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260018"></xptr> this poor Woman her Money, if you have robb'd her; and if you insist upon it, good Woman, she must go to the Compter. Says I, she has robb'd me. When she came to the Compter Gate, oh! says she, I'll give twenty Half-Crowns, I'll give you your Money again to let me free. Please you , my Lord, we went to the Compter; when we went before the Alderman, oh, says he, 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person303">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hooker 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person303" type="surname" value="Hooker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person303" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person303" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I know you to belong to a Gang of Thieves in Cheek-Lane , you come often upon such Affairs, I must commit you. The Alderman told her he had seen her in the Streets at Night.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person304">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person304" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person304" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to Rachel North.) Where do you live?</p>
               <p>North. I live at Hackney, overagainst Justice Mark's.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come to charge the Prisoner at the Bar, when you say there were two Women?</p>
               <p>North. One of them went before, she ( the Prisoner) stood up close by me .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you find your Pocket was pick'd ?</p>
               <p>North. That very Instant, my Lord .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first examine your Pocket?</p>
               <p>North. After this Accident .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person305">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person305" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person305" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Will you ask this Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I have known the Witness these twenty Years; she has been try'd several Times here; she has stood in the Pillory three Times: My Lord, she charg'd another Woman with the Robbery as well as me. She ask'd me to go to drink with her. Enquire her Character. Coming down Honey-Lane Market, the Prosecutor standing by the Door, she ask'd me to go and drink with her; she insisted I should go and drink along with her. I follow'd down all Cheapside: As I came down there, there came along a Man with a Link in his Hand. The Prosecutor insisted I should drink with her, or else, she told me, it would be the worse for me. Says she, here is the Watchman, I'll charge you with stealing two Half-Crowns, and a new Sixpence, and three Halfpence. I said, You Watchman, see I throw nothing out of my Pocket. When I came into the Watch-house the Constable search'd, me and search'd the other young Woman. When we came in to the Watch-house, he says, What Rachel, the Jew , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person306">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person306" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person306" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person307">
                  George 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person307" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person307" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman.) What do you know touching this Matter?</p>
               <p>Mason. I was in the House when she was brought down into the Watch-house: I was in the House all the Time she was there along with the Man she was charg'd with. What the Prisoner says is all false ; she was not search'd in the Watch-house by the Constable, nor any one else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she search'd at the Compter?</p>
               <p>Mason. She offer'd rather to give twenty Half-Crowns than go to the Compter .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person308">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person308" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person308" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) You have said that the Witness, 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person309">
                  Rachel 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person309" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person309" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , has been convicted of Perjury; if you object that against her, you must prove it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, she stood once at the End of Fetter-Lane ; once at the End of Fleet-Lane; and once at the End of Fleet-Market. She has been tried several Times at the Old-Baily .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person310">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person310" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person310" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Have you any Witnesses to call?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. What, do you call these Witnesses to your Character?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. To my Character, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person311">
                  Mary 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person311" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person311" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person311" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Please you, my Lord, I was along with my Mistress; we had been out at Dinner. We met the Prosecutor; she ask'd my Mistress to drink a Dram: She said, if she did not drink a Dram it would be the worse for her. She follow'd us down Foster-Lane; there she charg'd her with the Watch; there the Prisoner at the Bar was search'd, and they found no more than a Six-pence, a Thimble, and a Knife .</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the Constable search her?</p>
               <p>Harrison. In the Watch-house .</p>
               <p>Q. Were you search'd too ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. Yes, please you, my Lord. I had two Shillings in my Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person312">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person312" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person312" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person313">
                  George 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person313" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person313" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Was this 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person314">
                  Mary 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person314" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person314" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the Watch-house?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes; but what she says is all false, for she was not search'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person315">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person315" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person315" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to Mary Harrison.) What farther have you to say ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. The Constable search'd us, but found no such Money about us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to the Compter with her the next Day?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No; only to see her. When we were in the Watch-house the Prosecutor charg'd me as a Party concern'd; but afterwards she said, I have nothing to lay to her Charge. But when I was coming out, she charg'd me again; then the Constable would not take her Charge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Watchman charg'd with you as well as with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, my Lord, she did not charge me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner your Mistress?</p>
               <p>Harrison. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business does your Mistress follow?</p>
               <p>Harrison. She deals at Rag-Fair in buying and selling old Clothes .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260019"></xptr>Q. Who is the next Witness?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person316">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person316" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person316" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person317">
                  John 
                  Halberd 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person317" type="surname" value="Halberd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person317" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What are you?</p>
               <p>Halberd. I am a Diamond-cutter by Trade; but I have been a Porter for some Years behind the Royal-Exchange .</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say to this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Halberd. I had been home with my Master that I did Business for; he had been drinking at the Angel, at one Mr. Pauling's; he order'd me to attend upon him with a Link. I was coming home to Crowder's-Well-Alley: As I was coming along, over-against Row-Church, I saw this Woman and the Prisoner at the Bar: So, says I, how do you do. I had known her by coming up and down the Street. Phillis, said I, how do you do; if you think proper to go my Way, you shall partake of the Light of my Link: With that, this Woman insisted upon the Prisoner at the Bar to drink; the Prisoner made Answer, she would not drink with her at all, she did not like her. The Prosecutor answer'd, If you won't drink with me it will be worse for you by and by. With that, I said to Phillis at the Bar, I can't stay, God bless you, I wish you good Night. In about two or three Days after she sent for me to Wood-Street Compter: That is all I know of it .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person318">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person318" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person318" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prosecutor) Did you see this Porter?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Please your Honour, there was no Man with her, 'till they came to the Watch-House; there was no Man there with a Link nor any Thing else .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person319">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person319" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person319" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person320">
                  Anne 
                  Higham 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person320" type="surname" value="Higham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person320" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person320" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Higham. I know nothing of it, but I come to give the Prisoner a Character. I never heard any Thing against her in my Life. I have trusted her in my House, and left her in my House .</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her ?</p>
               <p>Higham. I have known her these six or seven Years , my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. You take her to be an honest Woman.</p>
               <p>Higham. I never heard of her being dishonest.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever trusted her?</p>
               <p>Higham. Yes, my Lord .</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Higham. I rent a House in Chiswell-Street of 12 l. a Year, opposite the Sash and Rising-Sun.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person321">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person321" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person321" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person322">
                  Margaret 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person322" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person322" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Fisher. Nothing but what is very honourable. I take in Gentlemen's Linnen to wash. I have trusted her in my Place often, and I know nothing to the contrary of her being a very honest Woman in all Respects.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Fisher. In Whitecross-Street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person323">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person323" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person323" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person324">
                  Walter 
                  Buckling 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person324" type="surname" value="Buckling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person324" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know ?</p>
               <p>Buckling. Please you my Lord, I have known the Prisoner these five or six Years. I have trusted her in my House, and I never saw any Thing against her.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character does she bear in the Neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Buckling. She liv'd within ten Doors of me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business does she follow?</p>
               <p>Buckling. Buying of Cloathes, and China to sell and change, and Things of that Kind .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person325">
                  William 
                  Garret 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person325" type="surname" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person325" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Constable of Aldersgate-Ward.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Time that the Prisoner was brought into the Watch-House?</p>
               <p>Garret. Sunday Night about Five o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Prisoner charg'd with?</p>
               <p>Garret. She was charg'd with picking the Pocket of one 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person326">
                  Rachel 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person326" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person326" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember whether the Prisoner at the Bar was search'd?</p>
               <p>Garret. Yes, her Pockets were search'd, and she would have suffer'd herself to be stripp'd .</p>
               <p>Q. What was in her Pocket?</p>
               <p>Garret. A Sixpence and a few Halfpence. The other Woman has as bad a Character as she. One charg'd the other to be a Sodomite . This Prosecutor and Defendant were in Cheapside all the Evening .</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to you by any Thing the Prosecutor said, that she was coming from the other End of the Town. Did she confess she had been with her in the Evening?</p>
               <p>Garret. She stood talking with her in Cheapside, that was all she confess'd.</p>
               <p>Q. You said just now, you found they had been together all the Evening.</p>
               <p>Garret. I enquir'd how they came to be brought down to me. I said, was there not a Watch in Cheapside to charge this Woman with. She said, they were bearing the Round.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the Prisoner was search'd at the Watch-House.</p>
               <p>Garret. Yes, she and the little one; and I found about the value of 3 s. and some Half-pence; but not a Half Crown</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person327">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person327" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person327" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Watchman) What is your Name?</p>
               <p>Watchman. 
               <persName id="t17460226-27-person328">
                  George 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person328" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person328" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. You carry'd her to the Watch-House, was she search'd in the Watch-House?</p>
               <p>Mason. I cannot say whether she was or not. I saw 6 d, that dropp'd out of her Pocket.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174602260020"></xptr>Q. Was there no Search at all? was her Companion search'd ?</p>
               <p>Mason. No, my Lord, she was not.</p>
               <p>Court. The Constable says she was; that he took Money out of both Pockets himself .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Discourse between the Prisoner and her?</p>
               <p>Mason. The Women came down talking together; I heard their Discourse, but could not well tell what they said: But the Prosecutor said, I charge you with this Woman for picking my Pocket of two Half-Crowns. The Prisoner did say, that she would rather give any thing than go to the Compter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460226-27-person329">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460226-27-person329" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-person329" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Have you any thing more to say?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing more to say, than that I had no more Money about me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460226-27-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460226-27-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
