<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490705-48">
               <interp inst="t17490705-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-48" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490705"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-48" type="date" value="17490705"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-48-off239-c223" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-defend311 t17490705-48-off239 t17490705-48-verdict242"></join>
         
               <p>425. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490705-48-defend311" type="defendantName">
                     Uriah
                      Creed, alias <rs id="t17490705-48-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-defend311 t17490705-48-alias-4"></join>Morgan</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-defend311" type="surname" value="Creed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-defend311" type="given" value="Uriah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-defend311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17490705-48-defloc238">Hawkhurst</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-48-defloc238" type="placeName" value="Hawkhurst"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-48-defloc238" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-defend311 t17490705-48-defloc238"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17490705-48-off239" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-off239" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-off239" type="offenceSubcategory" value="taxOffences"></interp>
               he in company with divers others to the number of thirty persons were assembled together in the parish of <placeName id="t17490705-48-crimeloc240">Recculver</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-crimeloc240" type="placeName" value="Recculver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-crimeloc240" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-off239 t17490705-48-crimeloc240"></join>,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050016"></xptr> being armed with fire-arms and other offensive weapons. in order to be aiding and assisting in running and landing uncustomed goods
            </rs> on the <rs id="t17490705-48-cd241" type="crimeDate">30th of March, 1747</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-off239 t17490705-48-cd241"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-48-person312">
                  Christopher 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17490705-48-person312" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person312" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In the year 1747, March 30, there might be about a hundred of them; there must be fifty and upwards, and about thirty arm'd with carbines and pistols.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account of what you saw at that time.</p>
               <p>Barret. There was a cutter came ashore with about ten ton of goods, tea and other things; the tea was packed up in oil-skin bags containing 25 pounds a bag; I saw the prisoner there, he had a brace of pistols and a carbine or blunderbuss; I saw him at work with others in landing and loading the tea: when the custom-house officers came there were three pieces fir'd, then they drew up 12 in a rank; he was then amongst the horses loading them, I saw him carrying the tea away, he drove 3 horses from the beech, there were above fifty horses went away loaded, the prisoner went into the rank the second firing; there were I believe 60 or 70 pieces discharg'd by the smuglers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-48-person313">
                  Michael 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17490705-48-person313" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person313" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember this 30th of March there were near sixty persons arm'd, the prisoner had a brace of pistols and a carbine or blunderbuss, I know not which; there was a cutter lying off there call'd the Old Molly, there was tea brought on shore from on board her in oilskin bags, about the quantity of eight ton; I saw the prisoner help load the horses, and drive some before him from the beech; I was just gone away as the custom-house officers came, but heard the firing at a distance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-48-person314">
                  Robert 
                  Cheesman 
               <interp inst="t17490705-48-person314" type="surname" value="Cheesman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person314" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember this gang of smuglers very well, there must be upwards of fifty; I am a custom-house officer, I went down with the other officers: I believe there were five or six and twenty arm'd when we came down, and about 12 or 14 fired upon us at first. There were about 18 or 20 custom-house officers of us, and some country-people to assist us; we got behind a marsh wall, then we fired at them, and they fired at us, I believe upwards of seventy pieces; they gave ground, and at last drop'd their goods, and went away two or three upon a horse; the prisoner rode by me with a man behind him; the man had a pistol in his hand without hat or wig; the prisoner had a brass piece flung behind him, he was on a bayish horse; we made a seizure of upwards of 3000 weight of tea, there were some half anchors of brandy, some cambrick and a deal of old cloaths, and some rack that I suppose came from the Indies.</p>
               <p>Jervice Cooper. I am a custom-house officer, I was there when this seisure was made; there were 60 or 70 of the smuglers, and many gone away loaded before we came; we took some of their arms and 3664 pounds weight of tea in the usual paccage of uncustomed goods, and some other goods. I did not know one person there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-48-person315">
                  Matthias 
                  Swan 
               <interp inst="t17490705-48-person315" type="surname" value="Swan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person315" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there the same time, I saw a great number of people there; we fired with them an hour, or an hour and half. (He gave the same account the others had done.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I know nothing of these people, and believe they never saw me before; I believe they'll swear any thing for the lucre of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-48-verdict242" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-verdict242" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490705-48-punish243" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-48-punish243" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-48-defend311 t17490705-48-punish243"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
