<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490906-67">
               <interp inst="t17490906-67" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-67" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-67" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-67" type="date" value="17490906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490906-67-off267-c263" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-67-defend389 t17490906-67-off267 t17490906-67-verdict268"></join>
         
               <p>559. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490906-67-defend389" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Godard 
                  <interp inst="t17490906-67-defend389" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-defend389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-defend389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17490906-67-defloc266">St. Paul's, Covent-garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-67-defloc266" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's, Covent-garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-67-defloc266" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-67-defend389 t17490906-67-defloc266"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17490906-67-off267" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-off267" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-off267" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17490906-67-person390">
                        Mary 
                        Godard 
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person390" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person390" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   alias Blare, not yet taken, at the assizes, holden at Croyden in Surrey, in August last, wherein 
                     <persName id="t17490906-67-person391">
                        Thomas 
                        Supple 
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person391" type="surname" value="Supple"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person391" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   was convicted for a robbery upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490906-67-victim393" type="victimName">
                           Adam 
                           Wright 
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-victim393" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-victim393" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-victim393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-67-off267 t17490906-67-victim393"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , taking from him a watch and other things, and that the said 
                     <persName id="t17490906-67-person394">
                        John 
                        Godard 
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person394" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17490906-67-person395">
                        Mary 
                        Godard 
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person395" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person395" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-67-person395" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   alias Blare, did feloniously receive these things, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-67-person396">
                  John 
                  Hains 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person396" type="surname" value="Hains"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person396" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produc'd the record, from the office of the clark of the ossize for the county of Surrey .</p>
               <p>The record to this purport .</p>
               <p>August the 3d before Sir 
               <persName id="t17490906-67-person397">
                  Thomas 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person397" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person397" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Knt. and Sir 
               <persName id="t17490906-67-person398">
                  Thomas 
                  Abney 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person398" type="surname" value="Abney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person398" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Kt. July 1. 
               <persName id="t17490906-67-person399">
                  Thomas 
                  Supple 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person399" type="surname" value="Supple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person399" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for that he, on the king's highway, upon 
               <persName id="t17490906-67-person400">
                  Adam 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person400" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person400" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did make an assault, putting him in bodily fear and danger of his life, one silver watch, val. 3 l. 1 cornelian seal set in gold, 1 cornelian seal set in silver, 1 polish'd steel watch-chain, 2 pieces of gold coin, call'd a quarter of a moidore, from the person of the said Adam did steal, take and carry away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-67-person401">
                  James 
                  Mackhey 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person401" type="surname" value="Mackhey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person401" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know the prisoner, he lives in Fenix-ally by Long Acre; on the 30th of June Supple and I went out, on the 1st of July we met Mr. Wright, Mr. Renolds and Mr. Hughs, on the foot of Gallows-hill , within a mile and half of Kingston; Supple went and stop'd the first Chaise, in which was Mr. Hughes; Mr. Wright and Mr. Renolds were in the other; we took from Mr. Hughes a gold watch, 3 diamond rings, 2 diamond ear-rings, 2 of these were mourning rings, the other a rose diamond; to the best of my knowledge there were 5 diamonds in each of these rings, the ear-rings had 9 diamonds in each ear ring. We took from Mr. Wright a silver watch with a steel-chain, a gold seal with a cornelian set in it, and a silver one with a cornelian in it: from Mr. Renolds we took 2 rings, and I believe about 6 or 7 shillings in silver, but upon his desiring the rings, we gave him them again; after we had committed this robbery, we went that very night to the prisoner's house, about 12 at night; he ask'd us what luck, we told him pretty well; the next day, being Sunday, we brought the goods and lodged them in his hands, till Monday morning, and then he bought them of us; this was about 10 o'clock ; we agreed with the prisoner and his wife for 13 l. for the whole of these goods; my wife came in at the time of the paying 5 l. of the money to Supple; the prisoner took her by the shoulder and turn'd her out, saying, she had no business ther e: we had 6 l. 10 s. each, he did not pay me till 3 or 4 days after; Supple gave him order to pay his other 30 s. to nobody but himself, and he received it afterwards. The prisoner said, the goods might have been had for 10 l. and blam'd his wife for offering so much. I heard the prisoner say, he would take the watch to pieces, and take the name and number out of it; he took the pistols and lodged them in his house for 3 days and nights; I gave the same account before justice Clark and justice Hammond, which I do now. Supple is since executed, and hangs in chains on Gallows-hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-67-person402">
                  Jane 
                  Mackhey 
               <interp inst="t17490906-67-person402" type="surname" value="Mackhey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person402" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-person402" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3d of July I was at Mr. Godard's house, he had a scarlet night-cap on, I ask'd him if my husband was there, I went in, and he took me by the shoulder and said I had no business there; I came out again and the prisoner shut the door , the upper part of which was glass; I went near and saw three persons together,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174909060016"></xptr> and a gold watch with a black ribbon lying on the dresser; I saw the shagreen case, in which were the rings; I saw the prisoner take out a silver watch, and take off a seal, and said it was worth a crown; I saw him have, two diamond rings on his little finger, and one on his fore-finger , and he was looking at them. Mr. Supple said he wanted 5 l. the prisoner said he could not make up 5 l. he took out some money, and I saw him give Supple the 5 l. I never saw my husband receive a penny. After this the prisoner came out of that room, and said he might as well have bought them for 10 l. for they, ( meaning my Husband and Supple) were but young in the affair .</p>
               <p>Mr. Wright. July the 1st Mr. Reynolds was with me in a chaise, Mr. Hughes was by him also in a chair; as we were coming from Kingston to London this Mackhey and Supple did the robbery; my watch was worth 6 l. and the gold seal about 15 s. the other silver one about 7 s. 6 d. and the steel polish'd chain I gave half a guinea for it: Mackhey gave the same account before Justice Clark he does now; but Supple was tried upon another indictment for a robbery near Vaux-hall and cast; so, no need to try him upon the other.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hughes. The 1st of July, about six in the morning, I happened to be first, a man started out of the thicket with a horse-pistol, and said, damn you, sir, your money. That was Supple; he made me turn all my pockets, he took my gold watch that had a black ribbon to it, with a Pinchbeck seal and a Cornelian stone; then he said, open the seat of your chair, swearing at each sentence: in that was a band-box tied up in a handkerchief: said I, here is nothing but a few things; he made me untie them, and there were two shagreen cases; he cry'd d - n you, sir, give me them: in the one was three diamond rings, two of them mourning ones; in the other case were two earings.</p>
               <p>Q. What might the value of all together amount to?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hughes. They cost upwards of 100 l. the gold watch cost 25 l. the gold of it weigh'd 13 l. The ence , Mackhey, gave the same account before the Justice he has done now.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-67-verdict268" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-verdict268" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-67-punish269" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-67-punish269" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-67-defend389 t17490906-67-punish269"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
