<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480115-30">
               <interp inst="t17480115-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-30" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-30" type="date" value="17480115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480115-30-off179-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-30-defend350 t17480115-30-off179 t17480115-30-verdict181"></join>
         
               <p>106. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Mascall 
                  <interp inst="t17480115-30-defend350" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-defend350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-defend350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17480115-30-defloc178">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-30-defloc178" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-30-defloc178" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-30-defend350 t17480115-30-defloc178"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17480115-30-off179" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-off179" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-off179" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     <persName id="t17480115-30-victim351" type="victimName">
                        Esther
                         his wife
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim351" type="surname" value="his wife"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim351" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-30-off179 t17480115-30-victim351"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , by throwing her out of a window, up two pair of stairs, in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17480115-30-person352">
                        John 
                        Palmer 
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person352" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-30-person352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-30-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , upon a stone pavement in Red Lion Yard, and thereby giving her several mortal bruises on the head, breast, back and sides, of which she shortly after died
            </rs>. <rs id="t17480115-30-cd180" type="crimeDate">Jan. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-30-off179 t17480115-30-cd180"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the coroner's inquest, for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person353">
                  John 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person353" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person353" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Yesterday was sev'night, the Prisoner at the bar came home a little before eleven o'clock at night, (I was in bed.) He desired to have a halfpenny dram, or a halfpenny worth of gin, I can't say which: which he had; and my wife desired him to go up to his own apartment . He had not been up stairs above five minutes, before she cried out, Palmer, Palmer, come up stairs: and the Prisoner said, G - d d - n you, you b - b.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know his voice?</p>
               <p>Palmer . Yes, perfectly well; my wife would have had me have gone up, as I had several times before: but I refused. A little time afterwards, I heard a rattling of the sashes , as if they had been dashed to pieces; and I heard something fall lump upon the ground, in the yard; and thought something was thrown out of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any struggling before you heard something fall to the ground?</p>
               <p>Palmer . No. I heard somebody say afterwards, my dear Esther has fell out of the window . I sat up in my bed and said, d - n you for a rogue, you have thrown your wife out of the window yourself, and murdered her at last.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason had you to suspect any such thing ?</p>
               <p>Palmer . Because he was always beating and abusing her in a most barbarous manner. Then he came down stairs, I don't know who opened the door, the Prisoner or I: but we dragged her into the house; she had her shift and cap on, her shift was up to the reins of her back, and her nose bloody: but I did not observe what bruises she had. Mr. Tate the surgeon was sent for, and he came .</p>
               <p>Q. What was done afterwards?</p>
               <p>Palmer . I can't tell, for I was gone out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner go for a surgeon?</p>
               <p>Palmer . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before he returned?</p>
               <p>Palmer. About a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun . What house do you keep? Are you a distiller, or a publican?</p>
               <p>Palmer . If my Lord asks me, I will answer him.</p>
               <p>Q. You say he often quarrelled with her; I would ask you, whether the woman was not strong enough to get the better of him? Whether you did not think the woman to have more strength than the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Palmer. I have seen them fighting often; she was a lusty woman to be sure .</p>
               <p>Q. Was she a strong, robust woman?</p>
               <p>Palmer. I don't know, I never tried her strength. He was standing at the head of his wife, after he came back from the surgeon's: and I said, if your wife dies, you shall be hanged; will that satisfy you, said he?</p>
               <p>Palmer . If it does not, says I, you shall be gibetted; will that satisfy you, says he?</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, whether he lamented the misfortune , and seemed sorry or concerned for his wife?</p>
               <p>Palmer . He did not shew any sorrow at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Palmer . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any washing-tub found upon the ground?</p>
               <p>Palmer . No; there were two hoops found there the next morning .</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a sound was it?</p>
               <p>Palmer . As if somebody plump'd naked upon the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any clothes on?</p>
               <p>Palmer . No; she had nothing but her smock on.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never any quarrel with him?</p>
               <p>Palmer. I never had any quarrel with him, only for preventing him from beating his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no quarrel with him at this time?</p>
               <p>Palmer . No; I only do this to do justice between God and man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person354">
                  William 
                  Carwell 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person354" type="surname" value="Carwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person354" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was sent for to measure the sash in the room, where the Prisoner lodged.</p>
               <p>Q. Now give us an account of the height of the sash from the floor.</p>
               <p>Carwell. It is two foot seven inches and an half from the floor to the bottom of the sash; the height of the sash is two foot, one inch and an half; and the width in the clear is two foot eight inches.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174801150036"></xptr>Pris. Coun. Don't you think that a person by leaning too much over, may fall out?</p>
               <p>Carwell . I can't think it: it is not impossible, but it is very impropable.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there not a seat to the window?</p>
               <p>Carwell. Yes, it is about eighteen inches high.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person355">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person355" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person355" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to Palmer .) You said there was a very great noise with the sash, was any part of the sash broke?</p>

               <p>Palmer. No, nor the glass that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. You heard the sash fly up?</p>
               <p>Palmer. Yes .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person356">
                  Edward 
                  Close 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person356" type="surname" value="Close"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person356" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Prisoner came home, I was at work up one pair of stairs; the Prisoner came and knocked at the door, and called to his wife to let him in; accordingly she got out of bed and let him in: not in at the street-door, but the door of his chamber. A little after he had been in, he and she came to the head of the stairs, and they were struggling together; accordingly she called out to my landlord for help, my wife was tainting the child at the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that?</p>
               <p>Close. Changing a clout. The Prisoner's wife called out, Mr. Palmer; my landlord did not come up; so the Prisoner and his wife went into their room together. After that, there was a little sort of a rusling with feet about the room; and when the rusling was over, the Prisoner at the bar run out of the room, and said, Oh my Esther ! Oh my jewel! I was hammering, I left my hammering, and looked out of the window, and saw the poor woman lying on the ground upon her face.</p>
               <p>Pris. Council . Was there a tub found in the yard?</p>
               <p>Close. There was a tub found in the yard, near the deceased's feet.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think any body put the tub there ?</p>
               <p>Close . I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the tub broke?</p>
               <p>Close. It was not much broke.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person357">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Close 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person357" type="surname" value="Close"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person357" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner when he came home, knocked at the chamber-door, and said, Esther , Esther, and she made answer and said, where he had been, he might go again ; with that, he made answer and said, it was her best way to open the door; with that she jumped out of bed directly , and opened the door for him. There was a little struggle before they came to the head of the stairs , and she cried, Mr. Palmer, for God's sake help me ; I made answer, and said, 
               <persName id="t17480115-30-victim358" type="victimName">
                  Mrs.
                   Mascall
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim358" type="surname" value="Mascall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim358" type="given" value="Mrs."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-victim358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-30-off179 t17480115-30-victim358"></join>
                  </persName>
             , who do you call to? She made answer, and said, Mr. Palmer; they went into the room again, and in a little time, I heard something fall. I looked out of the window , and saw her lying on the ground, with her smock up above her thighs; she was brought up stairs , lived about an hour, and died upon my bed. There was a midwife sent for, and she said, there was a child within her, which she could not have gone with three days, but the child was dead before her. He was no more daunted than any thing.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did not he lament over her?</p>
               <p>Close Yes, but I believe it was only a pretence; I have seen her beat in a barbarous manner before, with a child in her lap, and another in her womb: for I nursed one for her.</p>
               <p>Q. I don't blame you for taking the woman's part; what provocation did she give him?</p>
               <p>Close. None at all; she was as mild a woman as could be, and when he contradicted her, she would not contradict him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person359">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person359" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person359" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three weeks or a month before, she said, her husband threatened to throw her out of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him strike her?</p>
               <p>Palmer. No; but I have seen her have very black eyes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person360">
                  Richard 
                  Sale 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person360" type="surname" value="Sale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person360" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of Jan. a little time after I was in bed, I heard the poor woman squeek, and afterwards I heard her fall upon the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a squeek was it?</p>
               <p>Sale. As if she was crying out for help; then I looked out of the window, and saw the deceased lying upon the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any scuffle between them?</p>
               <p>Sale. I have sometimes heard a great noise in the room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person361">
                  Henry 
                  Waldron 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person361" type="surname" value="Waldron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person361" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I heard a noise, and got out of bed: and in a few minutes I heard the deceased fall to the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Before you heard the deceased fall upon the ground, did you hear any thing between her and her husband?</p>
               <p>Waldron . Nothing at all; and at the same time she fell, I heard water fall; they lived very badly together , and I have heard her cry out murder in the night. I believe, ten or twenty times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person362">
                  James 
                  Bryan 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person362" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person362" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a lodger in the same house, one pair of stairs above them ; I was in bed, and I heard the deceased call to Mr. Palmer to come up, four or five times, and heard some disturbance in the room; and I imagined that they were throwing water at each other. Afterwards I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174801150037"></xptr> heard the Prisoner go down, and he said, his dear wife or dear-Esther , or something like that; afterwards Mr . Palmer accused him of throwing his wife out of the window , and killing her.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Prisoner and his wife live together ?</p>
               <p>Bryan . I can't tell, I had not lived there long.</p>
               <p>Joseph James, surgeon . I was called upon last thursday to examine the body of the deceased; I attended the coroner's inquest: there was a cut over the right eye, upon the forehead, which seemed to be done by a stone, or something ragged. There was another upon her right knee, and a cut upon her nose; and both bones of the nose were all to pieces , and her tongue was cut, and hung out of her mouth; and her knees were broke. These wounds seemed to be done all at one fall, because the wounds were all on one side .</p>
               <p>Q. The question is , whether you think she did die of the fall?</p>
               <p>James . Yes, I believe she did die of that fall.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, and gentlemen of the Jury, if I was guilty in the least of this misfortune , I would not give you any trouble. I am a shoemaker, my master brought me some work, and said, if I would go with him to the Three Cups, he would give me some work, and he gave me a tankard of beer ; I said, I would be my three pence, and we would have another tankard. Afterwards I went to my brother at Newport-market, we had four pints of beer, and for fear I should be looked out , I came home the sooner. I called out several times, Esther let me in; at last the street-door was opened , and I went up stairs to my own door, and called Esther, and she let me in, and said , so you are come; I said, don't be angry, for I am not: and laughed at her. She took and threw up the sash, (being angry, as I thought ,) and was going to throw out a tub of water; said I, what do you throw the water out for? Said she, I will throw it out, and she did throw it out; and she went to throw it as far as she could, and threw herself out. I went to catch hold of her, but could not reach her; and I said, Oh my dear jewel! she is gone out of the window: and my landlord said, Oh you rogue! you have killed her . When she was brought in, she was all over bloody, and could not speak; says Mrs. Palmer, fetch a halfpenny worth of hartshorn drops , which I did; then my landlord fell a cursing and swearing at me, as much as he could: and then I went to surgeon Tate, and afterwards he got some of the watchmen, and took me Prisoner. I never touched my wife all the time I was in the room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person363">
                  Edward 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person363" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person363" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner four years and a half, and I know him to be a very civil fellow, and in his way of living is honester than a great many tip top people; his wife was a very hasty woman, and a very desperate woman. Please to hear me one word I have to say, it is neither a help to the man nor the woman; she said to me, my husband goes on in a terrible way, he destroys and sells all he can, and if he goes on this way I will make away with myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person364">
                  Daniel 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person364" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person364" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner four or five years, he lodged with me about three quarters of a year, his wife was at service part of the time, and then he brought her home; he was as good a tempered man as any in the world, and his wife was a cross ill-natured woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person365">
                  Thomas 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person365" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person365" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner six years, he lodged at my house twice, and he was as civil a man as any body could have in his house, mild tempered, and far from spending his money as some people do, and I never knew him apt to quarrel.</p>
               <p>Eliz . Morris. I have known the Prisoner six years, he is a very sober honest young fellow, and kept very good hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person366">
                  Thomas 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person366" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person366" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner five years, and he is a very good tempered man. I have bought work of him, and sometimes we would go and get a pot of beer, and sometimes she has come in cursing and swearing, damning and sinking, and she has taken a pot up and cut him down. One time I went to his house , and they were fighting, her gown and stays were off, and I took her to be master; it is as much impossible for him to throw her out of the window , as it is for me to take my Lord out of his seat , for she would beat three of him.</p>
               <p>Eliz. - The Prisoner is a very sober man, and his wife was a very turbulent and troublesome sort of a woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-30-person367">
                  Mary 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17480115-30-person367" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person367" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did lodge in the same room as the Prisoner; I had been washing, and was going to throw some water out of the window, and endeavouring to throw it a great way from the wall, I should have fallen out, unless my husband had taken hold of me, <rs id="t17480115-30-verdict181" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-30-verdict181" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was likewise acquitted on the Coroner's Inquest.</p>
            </div1>
