<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-47">
               <interp inst="t17400116-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-47" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-47" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-47-off222-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-defend390 t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-verdict226"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-47-off222-c284" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-defend392 t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-verdict226"></join>
         
               <p>135, 136. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-defend390" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Burges 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend390" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend390" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-defend392" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Hill 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend392" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend392" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-defend392" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted, (with 
               <persName id="t17400116-47-person393">
                  Ann 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person393" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person393" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person393" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken) for <rs id="t17400116-47-off222" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-off222" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-off222" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-47-victim395" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Moody 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-47-victim395" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-47-victim395" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-47-victim395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-victim395"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17400116-47-person396">
                        Sarah 
                        Burges 
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person396" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-47-person396" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-47-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Hat, val. 6 s. a Cane, val. 1 s. a Silk Handkerchief, val. 1 s. a pair of Gloves, val. 1 s. and 4 l. 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-47-cd223" type="crimeDate">December 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-cd223"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person397">
                  George 
                  Moody 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person397" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person397" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came out of the country, 20 Miles off, and on the 10th of Dec. about 4 or 5 o'clock, I came from my Son's in St Giles's. I had desired him to shew me the Way to Lincoln's-Inn, but he only directed me down this Lane, (<placeName id="t17400116-47-crimeloc224">Drury-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-crimeloc224" type="placeName" value="Drury-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-crimeloc224" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-crimeloc224"></join>) and when I came to the <placeName id="t17400116-47-crimeloc225">Globe Tavern</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-crimeloc225" type="placeName" value="Globe Tavern"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-47-crimeloc225" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-47-off222 t17400116-47-crimeloc225"></join>-Door, there were 3 Women standing there. I asked them the Way to Lincoln's-Inn? One of them took hold of me and said, - This is the Way; and they carry'd me to the farther End of the House. I told them, I thought it had been a Thorough-fair; No, said they, but we must have a Glass of Wine before we part. I refus'd to have any Wine, and said I would not drink any, for I had no Money to pay for Wine. Nan Hill said, she would find Money. 
               <persName id="t17400116-47-person398">
                  Sarah 
                  Burges 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person398" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person398" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (the Woman who keeps the House) Nan Hill, and Nan Holloway were then present; and Hill fell immediately to rifle my Pockets, while Burges and Holloway held me down in a chair. This was done in a Back Room, the farthest from the Street: and they took from me the things mentioned in the Indictment. - 4 s. 6d. in Money, a Handkerchief, and a Bundle of Writings which were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160034"></xptr> in my Pocket. After this I went into the Street, and enquired who kept that House, but no body would tell me, - I believe they were all of a Sort, and would not betray one another. Hill came after me into the Street, with the Writings in her Hand, and said, If I would come in again, I should have them. I follow'd her for my Writings, and I had no sooner got into the House, but she took the Hat off my Head, and gave it a Fellow to keep for the Recitcning; though I saw no Man in the House 'till I came back again.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. What did you drink in the House?</p>
               <p>Moody. Burges told me 4 Pints had been drank, but I don't know what became of them, I don't know that I saw any one of them. I believe I might drink one Glass, and I believe that was all, - I can't be positive. They left me 3 penny-worth of Halfpence in my Pocket, and that was all. With this Money I went over the Way to a publick House, and called for a Pint of Beer, and asked the Names of the People at the Globe over the Way, but they would not tell me, and made me pay the Three-Pence (the others had left me) for the Pint of Drink. The next Morning I went to Burges, to ask her for my Writings; but she call'd me old Rogue, and told me there were 3 Pints of Wine to be pay'd for. Why, says I, you serv'd your selves; what Money I had, you took from me; but I could not get my Writings, so I went and got a Warrant for them; and 2 or 3 Days afterwards I sent 3 Men to the House, and desired them to call for Wine, and Women, and I would come (I said) and surprise them with a Constable. The Men went thither, and had each of them a Woman, but when I came, I found they were not the Women who had robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Burges. How long after this was it, before you took us up?</p>
               <p>Moody. I went the next Day to enquire for my Things, and took out a Warrant for them the next Day, but I could not take them presently, for they all kept out of the Way; and I live in the Country, and could not stay in Town. Beside, Burges desired me to stay a Week, before I put the Warrant in Execution, that she might find out my Things, and accordingly I did.</p>
               <p>Burges. Did you pay no Money that Night towards the Reckoning?</p>
               <p>Moody. No; I had no Money to pay any Reckoning with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person399">
                  Moses 
                  Moody 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person399" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person399" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Father call'd upon me when he came up out of the Country, and after he had stay'd about 2 Hours with me, he ask'd me which was his nearest Way to Lincoln's-Inn ? It might be then about 4 o'Clock, or a little before. I live in Belton-Street, so I directed him to Long-Acre, and a-cross Drury-Lane to Princes-Street. The next Morning he told me, he had been robb'd at the Globe in Drury-Lane, and desired me to go with him to the House. When I came there, Burges was in the Bar, and she abused us, and called him old Rogue, upon his asking her for the Things she had taken from him. She said he had taken his Things away himself; but I told her I would get a Warrant for her, and for the People who had been concerned in the Fact; and accordingly I went in order to get one, but not knowing all their Names, it was to no Purpose. So I went back again to Burges, and she sent for Hill and Holloway, and told me their Names, and then I got a Warrant: I had desired them to let me have the Writings, else they would all come into Trouble. Hill said, she had given my Father the Writings again; but Nan Holloway told me, before Burges's Face, that Burges kept them for a Halfcrown Reckoning: though Burges said she had them not, nor knew any Thing of them. When the Warrant was taken out, they sent for me to the Nag's-Head-Tavern, in Prince's-Street, where I found Burges, and she desired me to stop the Execution of the Warrant, and said, perhaps she might get the Writings again.</p>
               <p>Burges. When you came the next Morning, did not I tell you the other Womens Names?</p>
               <p>Moody, jun. I had some Words with her, and told her the Justice said, if she would not tell their Names, he would send for Her. I knew her Name; it is under the Sign of the Globe.</p>
               <p>Burges. Pray what were these Writings?</p>
               <p>Moody, sen. There was a Bill of Sale for 60 l. and a Note for 20 l.</p>
               <p>Burges. Moody came into the House, and asked for a Pint of Wine, I was very ill at the same Time. - He went into a Room behind the Bar, and said he wanted to drink with a Woman [Holloway] who was with me in the Bar. She went to him, and they had a Pint of White, and a Pint of Red, and after this they had 2 Pints more, and when he went away he paid me half a Crown, and told me, if he was alive and well, he would come again, and pay me the other Eighteen-Pence. As for my Name, it has been wrote under the Sign, ever since I left off keeping a Brandy-Shop. When he came to me, he desired me to advertise the Writings, and said I should be at the Expence of it; and accordingly his Writings were advertised three Weeks in the Papers; and when the Justice sent for me, I went to him, and came back again<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160035"></xptr> to my own House. This is the Paper which his Son wrote with his own Hand.</p>
               <p>Moody, jun. When they sent for me to Graham's, at the Nag's-Head in Prince's-Street, they desired me to advertise the Writings, and Graham desired me to write the Advertisement my self. While I was with them at this House, I sent a Letter to my Father, to know what I should do; but he did not come to me before next Morning, and then he said, he did not care what they did, so he had but his Papers again. They told me, if I would write the Advertisement, they would be at the Charge of publishing it. My Father knew nothing of my Writing the Advertisement, for he was out of Town.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person400">
                  William 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person400" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person400" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Journeyman Bricklayer, and my Master's Name is Ridge. I was at work that Evening in Colson's Court, and my Master ordered me to wait for him when I had done Work, at the Bar of the Globe-Tavern. 'Twas on Monday the 10th or 11th of December, and I remember I went thither, and looked at the Clock, and saw it was between 5 and 6 o'Clock. Mrs Burges told me, I might as well sit down by the Bar-Fire; so I went in, and Hill and another Woman came in, and Moody followed them. Moody said, Pray don't let me disturb you; I said, No, you don't disturb me, and so I went and sat down in the Bar. Burges carry'd them in 3 Pints of Wine, and when she had carried in the third, she told me, she believed she should lose some part of her Reckoning, for the Man (said she) has but half a Crown in his Pockets. When he came out, he asked her her Name; she told him, her Name was at the Bottom of the Sign; so he went out, and said he would call again, and pay her what he had left to pay. He followed the Gentlewomen into the House voluntarily, and not as if he was enquiring his Way. He was in the House about an Hour with the Women, and seemed to be a little in Liquor, but did not say one Word, either pro or con, about being robb'd, when he went away. I stay'd in the House 'till within a Quarter of 12, and supp'd with Burges upon Sausages; and no Man came into the House, from the Time he went out, to my going Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person401">
                  Mary 
                  Broderick 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person401" type="surname" value="Broderick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person401" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person401" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been a Servant to Burges upward of 7 Years. I remember the Time when Moody came into our House, Hill came in with him, and no body else*. They went into the Parlour, where Norman the Bricklayer was sitting, and drank 2 or 3 Pints of Wine, which Moody called for himself.</p>
               <p>* See Norman's (the Bricklayer's) Evidence.</p>
               <p>Burges. Was any Force made Use of toward him?</p>
               <p>Broderick. No, none at all. He came forcibly in, without asking any Questions, and Hill was with him. Our House is no Thorough-fair: but he did not pretend to want a Thorough-fair: he stay'd about an Hour, bid us good Night, as then went away very friendly and kindly  ask'd my Mistress her Name; telling her,  call again and pay her, the next Time he  Town. I did not see any Money pay'd,  be sure he pay'd half a Crown, for my M Burges would not say it, if he had not. I am  Servant there, - my Business is sometime above, and sometimes below, - well, I am Cook who and I am sure there was no other Woman made  Company that Night, but my Mistress, and the Prisoner Hill. There was no one else in the House, but this Norman, and another Servant, at that Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person402">
                  Margaret 
                  Nokes 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person402" type="surname" value="Nokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person402" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person402" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Burges's, at the Globe-Tavern, and when the Countryman came in, I was sitting in the Back-Room with her and Norman. He came in with Nan Hill and Nan Holloway, and did not ask the Way to any Place, but called for Wine, and they had 4 Pints; and when he went away, he said nothing, but only wish'd my Mistress a Good-Night. - I can't tell whether he was drunk or sober, - I take it he was a little in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Burges. If there had been any hauling him, and holding him, while his Pocket was pick'd, should not you have heard it?</p>
               <p>Nokes. He did not complain of it then. But next Morning he came and ask'd my Mistress, if he had not left a Bundle of Writings there? She told him no, - but he had left Eighteen-Pence to pay. Upon which he told her, that he had no Money at all about him when he came in there over-Night, so (he said) he could not have paid any Thing. He came indeed the second Time the same Day, and then he said he had been robbed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person403">
                  Sarah 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person403" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person403" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person403" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go that Night to see what a-Clock it was, by Mrs Burges's Dial. Just as I was at the Door, the Countryman came out, and trod upon my Toe. He asked my Pardon, and said he hoped he had not hurt me; no Sir, says I, if you have not hurt your self. Then he turned about and said, your humble Servant, I wish you a good Night. After this I went across the Way to speak to a Woman, - I do not know her, but I take it she keeps a publick House, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160036"></xptr> I saw him go into the same House, and speak to a Woman, - but I do not know her neither, and there was no complaint that Night, but he went away very civilly. This was as I take it to be, on the 10th or 11th of December.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person404">
                  Alexander 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person404" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person404" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All I know of the Matter, my Lord and Gentlemen of the Jury, is this. On Tuesday I saw this Moody walking about our Court, with his Hat on; - I live in Windsor Court over against Mrs Burges's. - Says one of my Neighbours, that Man has been walking here this Hour. What's the Matter with you, Friend, says I? Why says he, I have been out late, and have lost some Papers of some Consequence to me. Where was it you lost them? I was over the Way at the Globe (says he) and at 2 or 3 more Places; but I don't know where I lost them. I asked him if he had left any Money? No, he said he had none to lose. Can you recollect, says I, whether the Woman of the House took any Money from you? No, said he, she did not. Well, says I, I'll go over the Way and ask her. I did so and she said she knew nothing of his Papers. When I came back, I saw this young Fellow (Moody, jun.) walking with him; and I told them the Woman of the House knew nothing of them, but she said he had left Eighteen-Pence to pay. Why, says the old Fellow all we want is to know her Name, then we shall do very well, for she has Money enough; and he told me likewise, that I was one of them, and that we were all alike. - I was an Upholsterer by Trade, but I am an Officer now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person405">
                  John 
                  Lawley 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person405" type="surname" value="Lawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person405" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick House; the Sign of the Greybound, over against Burges's. This young Man came into my House, and the old one followed him. The young one asked if a Man had not left a Hat, Cane, and Papers there last Night? I said not as I know of, but I'll call my Wife: And the old Man told her, he believed he was a little in Drink, and left a small Matter to pay. My Wife told him no, he had left nothing there. Then, says he, I am not positive, but I am sure I left them somewhere hereabouts. I won't accuse you, for I don't know where they were left.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person406">
                  William 
                  Lorrington 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person406" type="surname" value="Lorrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person406" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Burges 8 or 9 Years; I have worked for her, and she has paid me honourably. I have been in her House abundance of Times, - I have been there late, and have been used well, and with good Manners indeed. - I do not know Hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person407">
                  George 
                  Mascal 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person407" type="surname" value="Mascal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person407" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Burges about 3 Years. I never knew any ill of her, as to pilsering and thieving; and I have spent many a Pound there too. As to Hill, I know no harm of her, in that way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person408">
                  William 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person408" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person408" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have served Burges with Bread about a Twelve-month, and she has paid me honestly. I know nothing of Hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-47-person409">
                  William 
                  Raven 
               <interp inst="t17400116-47-person409" type="surname" value="Raven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person409" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Turner's Shop within 3 Doors of Burges: I have known her about 8 or 9 Years. What Goods she had of me, she always paid me for. I can't say I have heard of her being a Pick-pocket.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17400116-47-verdict226" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-47-verdict226" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoners.</p>
            </div1>
