<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-7">
               <interp inst="t17400903-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-7" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-7" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-7-off48-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-7-defend81 t17400903-7-off48 t17400903-7-verdict52"></join>
         
               <p>370. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-7-defend81" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-7-defend81" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-defend81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-defend81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-7-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Watch and Chain, val. 3 l. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17400903-7-victim82" type="victimName">
                        Patrick 
                        Mooney 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-victim82" type="surname" value="Mooney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-7-victim82" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-7-victim82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-7-off48 t17400903-7-victim82"></join>
                     </persName>
                    , in the Dwelling-house of John Hill
            </rs>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400903-7-defloc49">St Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-7-defloc49" type="placeName" value="St Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-7-defloc49" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-7-defend81 t17400903-7-defloc49"></join>, <rs id="t17400903-7-cd50" type="crimeDate">August 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-7-off48 t17400903-7-cd50"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-7-person83">
                  Patrick 
                  Mooney 
               <interp inst="t17400903-7-person83" type="surname" value="Mooney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-person83" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and I were in a Room together, (last Monday Morning was Seven-night) in the House of 
               <persName id="t17400903-7-person84">
                  John 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17400903-7-person84" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-person84" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17400903-7-crimeloc51">Parker's-Lane, St Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-7-crimeloc51" type="placeName" value="Parker's-Lane, St Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-7-crimeloc51" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-7-off48 t17400903-7-crimeloc51"></join>; and between one and eight in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030007"></xptr> the Morning, I lost my Watch. Mrs Parker, the Prisoner, carry'd me there, - I was not rightly in my Senses, but was a little Matter in Liquor. I met her between 10 and 11 at Night, (to the best of my Knowledge) and staid with her till between 9 and 10 the next Morning; and while I was with her, I lost a Silver Watch, Chain, and Seal. I am sure I carry'd it into the Room with me, and to my certain Knowledge I had it in the Room, for I looked at it at one Clock, (in the Night) and said I would go Home, but she would not let me, - she said it was too late. So I slept there, and miss'd my Watch between 7 and 8 in the Morning. I met her that Night at a Beer-house opposite her Lodgings, and there was a Man in her Company who came with us to her Room; I slept upon her Bed, and the Man staid in the Room, till between 6 and 7 in the Morning. I don't know that the Prisoner took my Watch, - but I am sure I lost it in her Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether he was not very drunk, when he came to me at the Alehouse ? And whether he did not pawn his Buckles, because he had no Money after the Gentleman and he came to my Room? Mr Mooney is no Stranger to me; he and I have been acquainted these two Years and a half.</p>
               <p>Mooney. I have known her these two Years; and though I lost my Watch in her Room, I can't say who took it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was very drunk when he came to my Room, and I would not let him go Home for Fear he should be robb'd. I have been acquainted with him a great while - to my Disadvantage.</p>
               <p>Mr Brown. (Constable and Pawnbroker.) On Monday Seven-night (about half an Hour after nine in the Morning) the Prisoner came to me with this Watch, to pledge for three Guineas. I asked her whose it was? she said it was her own. I told her, I supposed she did not wear a Silver Watch and Chain; but she still said it was her's, - she should fetch it again, and what was that to me. I told her I must know who was the Owner of the Watch, and where he liv'd, before I parted with it: and then she said, she was at present with a Gentlewoman in Piccadilly , who knew where she liv'd. That (says I) is no Satisfaction to me. Why then (reply'd she) 'tis my Husband's Watch, and he is gone to Sea, - give me the Watch again. I refused to do it, and took her before Mr Justice Frasier, where she said the Watch belonged to one Mooney a Cabinet-maker, and that Mooney had been gone to Sea a Month. She was asked where she lived? She told us she liv'd in Long-Acre : upon which I offered to go to Long-Acre, to enquire after her, but she then said she liv'd in Parker's-Lane, and finding I was resolved to go to her Lodgings, she desired to go with me, and said she would go to an Alehouse , and would send for the Person who owned the Watch. Then it came out, that the Owner of it was in Town, and lived by the New-Church in the Strand; but when we came to the New Church , she could not shew me where he lived. Prithee, says I, let's go and see if you can find out your own Lodgings. Accordingly she went with me, and would have carried me into an Alehouse , in her Neighbourhood, ( Parker's-Lane ) but seeing a Parcel of mean People there. I refused to go in; and so she went with me to the House where she lodged, and her Landlady informed me, that the Prisoner had lived there upwards of a Quarter of a Year, and that this was but the second Quarter. While we were talking together, a Messenger came from the Alehouse over the Way, and told the Prisoner there was one at their House desired to speak with her. I insisted upon it, that whoever wanted her, must come over to her; upon which Mooney came and said, - He had lost his Watch, and that it was picked out of his Pocket the Night before. Then I carried the Prisoner before Mr Frasier, and Mooney made the same Information he has made here.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr Brown, whether Mooney was not desirous to recal what he had said, knowing he had done me Injustice?</p>
               <p>Mr Brown. So far from that, that he insisted upon her having taken it; and she said, Mooney was a Villain, and had ruined her; and if she had taken 10 Watches from him, he ought not to have sworn against her. She called him ill Names, and he said, she had brought it all upon herself.</p>
               <p>Defence. Last Sunday was Se'nnight at Night, Mooney came to the Alehouse where I was drinking, and I was surprized to see him so fuddled; and not having seen him for a fortnight before, - pray sit down says I, you are very welcome. I was just going home to bed, but he was resolved to drink before he stirred; so he called for a Pot of Beer, and not having any Money, he took out his Knee-Buckles and pawned them for the Beer. Then we went to my Room, and had another Pot there. About One he wanted to go Home; I thought it was too late, and as he was in drink, I perswaded him to lie down. Then says I, my Dear, I want a pair of Shoes, lend me a Crown to buy a pair. Dear Nanny says he, You know I have no Money; - I pawned my Knee Buckles to pay for the Beer: However (says he) take this Watch, and pawn it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030008"></xptr> for a Guinea; for I can't go home without my Buckles. Ask him if I have not had this Watch in my Custody very often, before that Time.</p>
               <p>Mooney. Yes, she has often had it; and she might have made bold with it before, as she has done now. - I missed it about 8 o'clock on Monday Morning; and she said, she knew nothing of it. The other Man who had been with us, was gone, when I missed it, and she never pretended that He might take it; she only said, she would go out and enquire of Him, if he knew where it was: and accordingly she went out, about the Time she offered it to Mr Brown, and I waited for her Return till between 9 and 10. <rs id="t17400903-7-verdict52" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-7-verdict52" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
