<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-4">
               <interp inst="t17400116-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-4" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-4" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-4-off17-c52" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>85. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-defend61" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hawkins 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-4-defend61" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-defend61" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-defend61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-4-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-4-victim63" type="victimName">
                           Matth.ew 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-4-victim63" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-4-victim63" type="given" value="Matth.ew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-4-victim63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-victim63"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain publick Street, and common Highway, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400116-4-defloc18">
                        <placeName id="t17400116-4-crimeloc19">St. Sepulchre</placeName>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                        <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-crimeloc19"></join>
                     </placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-defloc18" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-defloc18" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                     <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-defloc18"></join>, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 3 l.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400116-4-cd20" type="crimeDate">Dec. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-cd20"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person64">
                  Matthew 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person64" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person64" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been to Hanover Square, last Sunday was a Fortnight, to see my Brother, and I staid with him, 'till between 6 and 7 in the Evening; then I came directly homewards. It was a dismal cold Night, and very snowy, so I had a great Coat on with the Cape under my Hat, and pull'd over my Face, and my Hands were wrapp'd up in my Coat. As I came up <placeName id="t17400116-4-crimeloc21">Chick-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc21" type="placeName" value="Chick-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc21" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-crimeloc21"></join> in my way Home, between 7 and 8 o'Clock, the Prisoner came out of an Alley, (<placeName id="t17400116-4-crimeloc22">Thatch'd Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Thatch'd Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-4-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-off17 t17400116-4-crimeloc22"></join>) and gave me a Blow with his Fist, (I believe) which knock'd me down. The Prisoner was the Man, and no Man else; I am sure of it, for I took particular Notice of him. I fell down with the Blow, and the Prisoner fell upon me. We struggled together, and just as I got from him, he drew my Watch out of my Fob Pocket. I call'd out Thieves! but he ran away with the Watch into the Alley: I pursued him, and made two or three Strokes at him, but he got<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160005"></xptr> away, and ran into a House. As I ran down the Alley after him, I cry'd Thieves! Murder! I am robb'd of my Watch! But 2 Women held out their Arms and stopp'd me; I gave one of them a Blow on the Breast and knock'd her down; then I ran past them and followed the Prisoner into the House. As soon as I got in, the Prisoner turn'd himself round, look'd me in the Face, and then laid himself down on a Bed, in the Ground Room. I charged him with taking my Watch, and would have taken him off the Bed, but some Men and Woman (who were in the Room) would not suffer me to take him. The Landlady of the House said, d - mn you, you Son of a Bitch, bring a Guinea or 20 Shillings and you shall have your Watch again To-morrow Morning. Says the Prisoner, (who lay all this while on the Bed) if the poor Man will bring 10 Shillings he shall have it again. I insisted upon having my Watch, or the Prisoner off the Bed, upon which they all fell a thumping me, and knock'd me out of Doors. They would not let me have the Prisoner, but thump'd me and beat me upon the Breast and under the Ribs, and turn'd me out of the House. Then I call'd out for Assistance, and a Soldier coming by, I told him a Thief was gone in there, who had robb'd me of my Watch, and I would give him Half a Crown, if he would call a Constable. Another Soldier came up at the same Time, and bid me give 'em the Money first. I said, I would give them a Crown, as soon as they brought me an Officer, but I did not care to give 'em the Money before-hand. Upon this, they likewise began to thump me about: I told them I believ'd they were all alike, and ran Home to my Wife: She saw I was very much frighted, and upon my telling her what had happen'd, she advised me to go to Mr. Robinson, (my Neighbour) and by his Directions I got a Search-Warrant from Justice Wroth, and went with it that same Night to St.Sepulchre's, where I got a Constable who went with me to the House, and took the Prisoner. I shew'd him likewise, the Woman who bid me bring a Guinea or 20 s. if I would have my Watch again. I did not see the Prisoner when I first went in with the Constable; but upon taking a Candle, and looking round the Room, I found him creeping round a Table, to get to the Door. I am positive I had the Watch in my Fob, when the Prisoner and I struggled together, and I saw it in his Hand, when he ran from me into the Alley. To the best of my Knowledge he put it in his Coat Pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person65">
                  Philip 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person65" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person65" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Watchman. I know nothing of the Robbery, but as Mr. Brown had subscrib'd (de scrib'd) the Man, I call'd the Constable, and we went and took the Prisoner, as he had subscrib'd him, in Thatch'd Alley, in Chick-Lane. He did not own the Fact himself, but there was a Woman went with us to the Pump Alehouse (who pass'd for the Prisoner's Wife) and she told us, that in case her Husband should not be prosecuted, she would produce Mr. Brown's Watch. The Prisoner was present, and in the Hearing of this, but he said nothing at all to it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he ever knew any Harm by me?</p>
               <p>Price. I don't know, - he lives with a Woman who makes it her Business to go a-whoring and thieving. I never knew him do any thing himself. He formerly was a Post-Boy, and used to ride post; but he has liv'd about a Year in these Alleys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person66">
                  Tho 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person66" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person66" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nothing to say, not I; no farther than this: My Landlord (Brown) on Sunday was a Fortnight came home about 8 o' Clock very much 'frighted, and said he had been knock'd down in Chick-Lane, and had been robb'd of his Watch, by a short thick fresh coloured Man, in a light colour'd Coat, and that he should know him again from an Hundred. He asked me and my Bedfellow to go with him, to the House, and assist him in taking the Man. We agreed to go with him; but we first went to Mr Robinson, (our Neighbour) and he sent us to Mr Justice Wroth, who order'd us to go that Night, to the Watch-house, and take the Constable with us. When we had got a Constable, Mr Brown carry'd us to the House where we found the Prisoner; and as soon as we got in, Brown said, - this is the Woman that told me I should have my Watch To-morrow Morning, if I would bring her a Guinea, or 20 s. There was one 
               <persName id="t17400116-4-person67">
                  Sarah 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person67" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person67" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the Room at the same Time, and she jump'd up at the Constable, and said, - d - mn you, I'll cut your Nose; but he gave her a Thump on the Breast and said, - d - mn you, you B - ch, whose Nose will you cut? Upon which she sat down and was quiet. We did not see the Prisoner when we first went into the Room, but Brown took a Candle, and found him creeping round a Table behind the Door, and gave the Constable charge of him for stealing his Watch. He deny'd the Fact, but we carried him to the Counter that Night, and next Morning we had him before the Alderman at Guildhall, where he deny'd the Fact again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person68">
                  Tho 
                  Allbrook 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person68" type="surname" value="Allbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person68" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave exactly the same Account with the former Witness.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160006"></xptr>Mr Roomer. Constable, Mr Brown came to me, and begg'd I would assist him to take the Prisoner, who had robb'd him of his Watch. I asked him how he lost it? He gave me the same Account of the Robbery, as he has now done, and described the Prisoner. I bid him be cautious in what he was about, and asked him if any Women had been in his Company? He told me, no; and insisted upon it, that the Prisoner was the Man who robb'd him, and no one else. Upon this I went with him to the House, and he charg'd me with the Prisoner, who denied the Fact, both at that Time and before the Alderman; but Mr Brown being positive to the Man, he was committed.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person69">
                  Robert 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person69" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person69" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came home, as near as I can guess, about 8 o'Clock, - nearer 8 than 7, on Sunday before New Year's Day, at Night: and coming home, I saw a Tumult about my Door in the same Alley. I ask'd what was the Matter, and a Gentleman in a light colour'd caped Coat, and in his own Hair, made answer and said, that the Bitches had robb'd him of his Watch. I made answer again, - what Business had you in Bitches Company? If you have been in Bitches Company, you must take Bitches doings. Then I knock'd at my Door; my Children open'd it, and I went in. This is the Gentleman that made answer to me at the same Time. 'Tis very true, - and God forbid I should take a false Oath. I have been a Tubman at Mr Dickenson's Brewhouse these 30 Years, and my Friends before me. I deal there for Hundreds a Year, tho' I am a poor Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person70">
                  Martha 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person70" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person70" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were three of us sitting by the Fire that Night, and we heard a Noise in the Alley. A Man's Voice said, I will give you half a Crown when I have done, and do you hold my Watch. Presently after I heard a Man say, you Bitch where's my Watch? The Woman said, indeed Sir I have not got it; the other Woman has it. I don't know who these Women were, for I was below in the Kitchen, and we did not come to the Door, 'till my Father, (the former Witness) knock'd. Then I went out, and saw the Gentleman, in a caped Coat and his own Hair, and he was mussled up in his Cape, for fear any body should see him. I saw him turn up his Cape; it was not done up when I came first out. This is the Man, (pointing to Mr.Brown) and he cried out Murder! Good People of this House! and knocked at our Window-Shutters, but we were afraid to answer. I did not hear him say any Thing about a Man, but presently after we heard a Woman cry out Murder, and People ran out to see what was the Matter. - I know the Prisoner to have been a <rs id="t17400116-4-deflabel23" type="occupation">Postman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-deflabel23"></join>, but I don't know how long he has lived in that House. The People of the House, are good honest People, as far as I know. We live next Door to them, but my Father and Mother are not People who go gossiping about to other People's Houses.</p>
               <p>Mr Brown. I never saw a Woman all the Way in the Lane, till I was opposed in going after the Prisoner into the House, by two Women in the Alley; and those Women I afterward saw in the House with the Prisoner: and they curs'd and damn'd me, and called me Son of a Bitch. These People did not appear when the Prisoner was carried on the Monday after the Robbery, to Guildhall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person71">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person71" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person71" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person71" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am 17 Years old, the 3d of June; I was at Harrison's House that Night, and heard a Bustling up the Alley, and heard a Man say, he would give half a Crown, and hold my Watch. I heard Women; and by and by I heard the Man say, where's my Watch? A Woman said, indeed I have it not; the other Woman has it. Then they cried out Murder, and the Neighbours came out to see what was the Matter. The Woman that got his Watch, ran away, and the Man ran up and down the Alley, - Where's my Watch! Where's my Watch! I'll give 4 Crown for my Watch! After Mr Harrison came home, I saw the Man; this is he, in his own Hair: He had a whitish caped Coat on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person72">
                  William 
                  Blake 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person72" type="surname" value="Blake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person72" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (a Soldier.) I and my Friend [Houghton] were drinking that Night at the Castle at Cow-Cross, and as we were coming home thro' Black Boy Alley, we saw this Mr Brown have hold of the Prisoner, between 7 and 8 o'Clock. He said to me, Brother Soldier assist me, I have lost my Watch with two Women, and I believe this is the Man that has got it, but my Comrade and I went home directly, we would not trouble our selves about it.</p>
               <p>Jury. Do you lodge in the Prisoner's House?</p>
               <p>Blake. No, I quarter at the Bull and Butcher, at Cow-Cross.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person73">
                  Thomas 
                  Houghton 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person73" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person73" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with Blake at the same Time; as we were coming thro' Black Boy Alley, we heard a Noise: Blake asked what was the Matter? The Gentleman said, he had been robbed of his Watch by two Women, and he would give us half a Crown to get a Constable, for he believed that Man had got it, and belonged to them: but we went away, and I went to my Lodgings at Westminster. I saw no farther, upon my Word, - if you'll believe me. The Gentleman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160007"></xptr> was a tall Man, with a caped Coat tucked round his Ears, in his own Hair. This is the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person74">
                  George 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person74" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person74" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 7 and 8 that Night, I heard a Noise of Women crying out Murder. - I live in Thatched Alley, - I am a Shoemaker. - I heard the Gentleman say, he had been robbed by two Bitches, and two Women. Several Times he expressed himself in that Manner.</p>
               <p>Jury. Do you live in the same House with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Collins. Yes: and I am certain he was in the House, when the Man was robbed. There were several Men and Women too, in the Court, when the Noise of Murder was made. - The Prisoner was three Hours in the House before the Gentleman was robbed. I live one story higher than he. - I was sometimes above Stairs, and sometimes below. - I was in his Company just before the Man was robbed, and heard the Prisoner run out of the House, when he was complaining he had lost his Watch. I am sure the Prisoner was in the House from 4 to 8, when the Outcry was made. - I was below Stairs, and sometimes I was (perhaps) half a Minute, not more, above Stairs. - No: I know nothing of any Wife of the Prisoner's - I was not out of the House all Day, for I was ill of the Tiffick; I sat below at their Fire, because it was cold, and was not above Stairs for above half a Minute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person75">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person75" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person75" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday Night after Christmas-Day, about 7 or 8 o'Clock at Night, I was going to the Pump Alehouse, for a Pot of Purl. - I live next Door to the Prisoner, in the same Alley, - Thatched Alley. The Prisoner was sitting at the Fire, when I went out for the Purl. I am sure I had been there all the Afternoon, for Elizabeth Carter (the Landlady) and I had join'd for Tea. When I came back with the Purl, I heard Murder cry'd in the Alley, and a Woman ran past me, by the same Token, she dash'd the Pot of Purl out of my Hand. I asked what was the Matter? The Woman that ran past me said, she did not know, and while I was asking about it, the Prisoner came running out of the House. I saw one Woman upon the Ground, and the Prosecutor too, with his Breeches down. I bid him get up, and put up his Breeches, for 'twas very cold. Upon my Word 'tis true: I never took an Oath before, in my Life. The Woman was upon the Ground, and her Cloak, - a dark colour'd Cloak lay upon the Snow. The Prosecutor said, give me my Watch. The Woman upon the Ground said, the other Woman had got it. The Man's Cloaths were all open, &amp;c. and I bid him get up, the Weather was not so hot, that he should lie there in that Manner; and if he wanted a Whore, I bid him go Home to his Wife, for he told us he had a Wife and Children upon Windmill-Hill. I can't tell who the Woman was, who lay upon the Ground, for I did not see her. - No, she got away while the Prosecutor was putting up his Cloaths. - She was none of us, - not one of our Neighbours, as I know of: and I am sure the poor Man at the Bar ran out of the House when Murder was cried, and that the Robbery was committed before he went out to see what was the Matter: for the Prosecutor was at that Time pulling open the Woman's Breast, in a violent Manner; and calling out, - where's my Watch! Upon which I told him the Weather was so cold, that I wanted something warm, and I bid him get up, and not lie there in the Snow. - No; the Man was not quite down upon the Ground; he only had one Knee down, and the other up, and I found him pulling open the Woman's Breast, to see for his Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person76">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person76" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person76" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , [The Landlady.] The Prisoner at the Bar lodged at my House: he has lived 2 Years with me. On Sunday Evening, before New-Tear's Day, he and I were sitting by my Fire, by ourselves; We sat together 2 Hours before the Outcry was made, and no one interrupted us. No Body came in, for 2 Hours before, - because 'twas very cold, and it snowed very hard. But presently after, I heard Murder cried, very terribly: upon that the Prisoner run out of Doors, and I followed him: and at the Bottom of 2 Steps under Harrison's Window, I saw the Gentleman that made the Noise, in his own Hair, and 2 Women with him. - Whether one of the Women was getting away, or not, I can't tell. But they struggled together; They cried Murder, and be cried, give me my Watch. After I had seen this, I went in again, and sat down by the Fire. I am sure there were 2 Women with him: but People might be passing and re-passing. He stood struggling with the two Women, and I believe he had one of them by the Breast. He was not undressed then, for the Gentlewoman (Oliphant) says, he put up his Breeches before I got out of Doors. I am sure I heard the Consequence of the Thing, and then I ran in Doors again directly, but the Prisoner staid out in the Alley longer. The 2 Women were upright upon their Legs; I did not see any of them on the Ground, for it snowed very hard. I am very sure the Prisoner and I had been together by<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160008"></xptr> ourselves, for 2 Hours before the Noise was made. I have Lodgers in the House indeed; there was a Woman suckling a Child, and 2 other Women; but they were all above, up one Pair of Stairs. Collins (a former Witness) lodges up 2 pair of Stairs, and he was above Stairs too. He (Collins) was but a very little Time with the Prisoner and me, below Stairs; he was in his own Apartment, and did not stay above a Minute below Stairs; he only came down, and took a Candle, and then he went up Stairs. He was not above a Minute with us. When the Prosecutor came afterwards with the Constable, he was asked [by the Constable] what he called him out of Bed for, to this poor Postman. - I believe the Prisoner has a Wife, - I do not know. - I do not know where she is.</p>
               <p>The Constable. When I apprehended the Prisoner there was not any Talk of this Kind: there was not one Word of a Squabble with Women. I asked Mr Brown if no Women had been concerned in the Robbery, and he said, no: he had not been in Company with any Women, but that it was the Prisoner alone, who knocked him down and robbed him: and when he charged me with the Prisoner, he (the Prisoner) never mentioned a Syllable of Brown's having complained of being robbed by 2 Women. There was not one Word of this Defence, set up then.</p>
               <p>Mr Brown. As to these 2 Soldiers, I cannot say I remember them: but there was a Soldier came up to the Door of the Prisoner's House, and I offered him Money to get a Constable. Another Soldier came up afterwards, and I offered them a Crown, but they pushed me about, and beat me. Carter, the Landlady, (the former Witness) was the very Woman that punched me on the Breast, and said, d - mn you, you Son of a B - ch, bring me a Guinea, or 20 s. and you shall have your Watch, to-morrow Morning.</p>
               <p>Carter, [the Landlady.] Mine being the first Door which was opened in the Alley, the Prosecutor came in, and says he, God bless you, good People, can none of you tell me any Thing of these Women? I will give you 10 s. if you can. I ran to the Door, to the Prosecutor, and said if you would give 10 s. or a Guinea, or ever so much, no one here can tell you any Thing of your Watch. He might as well take away my Life; or any other poor Creature's, as the Prisoner's. He offered 10 s. for his Watch, and I said, if he would give 20 s. or a Guinea, or 10 Guineas, none there could help him to it. My Husband's a Shoemaker, and I have a Child to Nurse, and do what I can to keep the Wolf from the Door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person77">
                  Philip 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person77" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person77" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Watchman). This Woman [Carter] keeps a common Bawdy-House, (in Thatch'd Alley) and entertains all Manner of Whores and Thieves. We have several Times taken lewd People out of her House. The Constable knows it, as well as I.</p>
               <p>The Constable. I know Carter's House, and have been several Times called to take Persons from thence. - 'Tis a House of no Reputation at all. That Man (Harrison) is a Tubman, I believe him to be an honest poor Man: One of these Girls is his Daughter. The two Soldiers I know nothing of; and as to Oliphant, I have seen her at Carter's House several Times, and likewise about this Alley. How she gets her Living, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-4-person78">
                  William 
                  Lascells 
               <interp inst="t17400116-4-person78" type="surname" value="Lascells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person78" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Saracen's-Head, on Snow-Hill: I am Chamberlain there, and the Prisoner used to ride post from our Inn; but we not having had Occasion for so many <rs id="t17400116-4-deflabel24" type="occupation">Postmen</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-deflabel24"></join>, as formerly, he was discharged. Since which he has come to the Postboy's Room, which is on the left Hand of mine, and I have left my Door open, and have had 300 Pound's-worth of Money and Goods therein, but I never lost any Thing. He went by the Name of Dumplin; and Gentlemen who used to ride post, enquired for him by the Name of bonest Dumplin, and have said, he was the honestest <rs id="t17400116-4-deflabel25" type="occupation">Postboy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-deflabel25"></join> that ever they rid with in their Lives. <rs id="t17400116-4-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-4-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-4-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-4-defend61 t17400116-4-punish27"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
