<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470715-26">
               <interp inst="t17470715-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-26" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-26" type="date" value="17470715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470715-26-off107-c183" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-26-defend230 t17470715-26-off107 t17470715-26-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>296. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470715-26-defend230" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Bright 
                  <interp inst="t17470715-26-defend230" type="surname" value="Bright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-defend230" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-defend230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470715-26-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               feloniously, on the <rs id="t17470715-26-cd108" type="crimeDate">26th of Jan.</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-26-off107 t17470715-26-cd108"></join> last, at the Parish of <placeName id="t17470715-26-crimeloc109">Tottenham</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-crimeloc109" type="placeName" value="Tottenham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-crimeloc109" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-26-off107 t17470715-26-crimeloc109"></join>, assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470715-26-victim232" type="victimName">
                           Anne 
                           Lucy 
                        <interp inst="t17470715-26-victim232" type="surname" value="Lucy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470715-26-victim232" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470715-26-victim232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-26-off107 t17470715-26-victim232"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17470715-26-viclabel110" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-26-victim232 t17470715-26-viclabel110"></join> ; and for feloniously ravishing, and carnally knowing her against her Will, against the Statute
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person233">
                  Anne 
                  Lucy 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person233" type="surname" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person233" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What have you to say, as to any Abuse you receiv'd from 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person234">
                  Daniel 
                  Bright 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person234" type="surname" value="Bright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person234" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 26th of Jan. last .</p>
               <p>A. Lucy. This young Gentleman was at Dinner at the George and Vulture at Tottenham. My Master and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150015"></xptr> Mistress was at Dinner with him; and Mr Fawsey ask'd , If that Gentleman's Bed was made ?</p>

               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was this?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Between two and three o'Clock, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What Answer did you give?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I made Answer, that it was, Sir. He ask'd me, if it was turn'd down? and I said, No. He said, I must go and turn it down , and lie down by the young Gentleman. And I said, I would not. He said, I must, I said, indeed I should not. My Mistress said, I might take it as a great Honour to lie down by the young Gentleman .</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Mistress say so?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir. When I brought the Things away from the Table, this little Boy came to me, and said, my Mistress wanted me at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you so?</p>
               <p>Lucy. This little Boy, 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person235">
                  Tom 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person235" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person235" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; and I sent Word I would not come, and Mr Bright came out and fetch'd me in.</p>
               <p>Q. What Room did he bring you into?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Into the Room where they din'd. And he said to my Mistress, must not Nanny turn the Bed down ? And my Mistress said, I must go up and turn it down. I promis'd to go up if she would keep the young Gentleman below; and she promis'd me she would. But before I got halfway up Stairs she let him follow me; and I run into the Dining-Room , and down into the Kitchen; and he ran after me down Stairs. When I came into the Kitchen my Master and Mistress, and Mr Fawsey were all in the Kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Who made you go up Stairs?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Mr Bright, and Mr Fawsey stood at the Bottom of the Stairs , and would not let me come down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he pull you up Stairs against your Will?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What happen'd then?</p>
               <p>Lucy. He push'd me into my Mistress's Room, where she lay, and lock'd the Door, and put the Key into his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a Bed in that Room?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir; and he beat me in a very violent Manner , and abused me.</p>
               <p>Q How did he abuse you?</p>
               <p>Lucy. He called me a common Whore, and B - h twenty Times.</p>
               <p>Q. What happen'd after this?</p>
               <p>Lucy. He swore he would lie with me, and I call'd out to my Mistress. And he said I might call, but she would not come, nor nobody else.</p>
               <p>Q Was this a single House, or other Houses just by?</p>
               <p>Lucy. They are a little Distance , they might join .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any House within thirty Yards of the Room where you was ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Really, Sir, I can't tell exactly, indeed .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call to your Mistress ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir .</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come ?</p>

               <p>Lucy . No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call loud to your Mistress ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir, several Times .</p>
               <p>Q. What happen'd then?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Then he throw'd me on the Bed, and he look'd for his Handkerchief to stop my Mouth with , but he could not find it.</p>
               <p>Q Did you cry out ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir. So, Sir, he lay with me .</p>
               <p>Court . Are you sure he enter'd your Body.</p>
               <p>Lucy . Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court . And this was against your Consent absolutely , and by Force and Violence.</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q When did you first complain of this Abuse?</p>
               <p>Lucy . Directly.</p>
               <p>Q To whom did you complain ?</p>
               <p>Lucy . To my Master and my Mistress, and the Cook, and the Gardener, and all of them; and my Mistress said , I was not hurt she suppos'd .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you complain of this to Mr Fawsey?</p>
               <p>Lucy. He said I made a Noise for nothing.</p>
               <p>[Cross examin'd.]</p>
               <p>Council . Who came up to you in the Room?</p>
               <p>Lucy . Potter the Gardener .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you off the Bed when you saw him first?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I was off the Bed, but the Prisoner was upon the Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you? Did he come into the Room?</p>
               <p>Lucy. 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person236">
                  William 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person236" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the Man that first came into the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you very well acquainted with him?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No, not so much, I knew the Gardener a great while longer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not well acquainted with Norton? Recollect yourself, all these People are in Court; recollect , whether you complain'd to any one ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I did, and the Cook said, I was much to blame if I did not make the Gentleman suffer for what he did to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not live with Mr Jaques, when he first took the House?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it to pass, that your Master and Mistress were so barbarous, not to assist you. They tell<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150016"></xptr> me you ran up and down Stairs like two Cats after one another. They tell me, you came in two or three Times ; that you popp'd up and down several Times into the Room, and play'd the Gambles before them ; yet for all that the poor young Man would not touch you. Now this is a different Sort of a Story you told in another Place. Pray explain this Story, of his getting you up Stairs; you say he pull'd you up, Did any Body assist him?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Fawsey stood at the Bottom of the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Stairs did he pull you up? You swore in another Court it was seventeen Steps. Do you insist upon it, that you never lived in that House when Jaques was Drawer?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Name of the Hostler ?</p>
               <p>Lucy. 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person237">
                  William 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person237" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, Whether the Hostler did not bring you down Stairs in his Hand?</p>
               <p>Lucy . Yes, Sir; he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Hostler say to you, when he handed you down?</p>
               <p>Lucy. He said nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Then I ask you, Whether he did not say positively to you, that you should swear a Rape? And did not you say, the Gentleman had not done you any Hurt; and that you would not swear?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the Hostler and the Gardener follow you down Stairs?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I don't know, whether they went behind me or before me.</p>
               <p>Council . Now, I would refresh your Memory with what pass'd at Hickes's Hall, because you swore positively they followed you down Stairs.</p>
               <p>Lucy. I never swore any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, Whether or no this Hostler did not carry you before the Justice against your Will?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No, Sir; there was no Justice in the Town.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it to pass, that this Gentleman that was so very fond of you, to get you up Stairs, that he should call you B - h and Whore; what, had he let you into his Intention? If he had said nothing to you, what made you refuse to go to turn his Bed down? But I find you was very free and merry together; how came he to change the Scene, that he should lock the Door and beat you?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Because I would not comply with his Desire.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you cry out for?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I cry'd out for my Master to come up to my Assistance , because I did not choose to be lock'd into the Room .</p>
               <p>Q. When you came out of the Room, did you once complain he had beat you, to those that were in the Kitchen? They tell me the Hostler and you are very intimate .</p>
               <p>Lucy . I never had no Acquaintance with him till I went to live there.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you take upon you to swear you were a Virgin before this happen'd?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, Whether you have not sat up with 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person238">
                  William 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person238" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , the Hostler, more than once , twice, or thrice?</p>
               <p>Lucy. I never set up with him on purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you positively, Whether the Hostler was in Bed with you, or was not?</p>
               <p>Lucy. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell Mr Cooper this young Man had actually lain with you?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you apply to Mr Cooper?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-26-person239">
                  Lucy 
                  That 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person239" type="surname" value="That"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person239" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             very Night, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Room over the Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you find in the Kitchen, when you came down?</p>
               <p>Lucy. The Cook was in the Kitchen , and Mr Fawsey, and my Mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the Bed from the Door?</p>
               <p>Lucy. Almost facing the Door.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person240">
                  William 
                  Norton 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person240" type="surname" value="Norton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person240" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Norton. I was at Dinner when the Thing happen'd, and I heard a Noise over my Head.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of Noise was it?</p>
               <p>Norton. I heard this young Woman cry out Murder, and I went up Stairs directly by myself. When I went up Stair I push'd the Door open.</p>
               <p>Q. When you broke the Door open, did you go into the Room?</p>
               <p>Norton . Yes; and I saw them both a-top of the Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Posture were they?</p>
               <p>Norton. She with her Coats up; and his Breeches were down, and a-top of her. As soon as ever I came into the Room I took hold of him, and draw'd him off from the young Woman, and never spake a Word to him, good, bad, or indifferent.</p>
               <p>Court. How came you not to speak to him, when you heard the Cry of Murder?</p>
               <p>Norton . I never spake to him, but took her down Stairs directly, and never chang'd one Word with him at all.</p>
               <p>Court . As you went down Stairs with her, Did she say any Thing to you?</p>
               <p>Norton. She cry'd, and said, she would fetch a Warrant for him , and have him before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150017"></xptr>Court. When she went into the Kitchen , what did she say before the Company there?</p>
               <p>Norton. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q Who was in the Kitchen ?</p>
               <p>Norton. There was the Cook, the Gardener, and this little Lad.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else there?</p>
               <p>Norton. No, Sir, not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your Master and Mistress at that time ?</p>
               <p>Norton . I believe they were in the Parlour .</p>
               <p>[Cross examined.]</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with you when you went up stairs?</p>
               <p>Norton. Neither of them went up with me.</p>
               <p>Council. How came they not to go up, when they heard such a dreadful Cry of Murder; you say there were three in the Kitchen at the time of this out-cry, and none of them stired.</p>
               <p>Norton . I had her off the Bed, before I saw any of them.</p>
               <p>Q. I would ask you whether you did not swear they were at the stairs-head , when you forced the Door open?</p>
               <p>Norton . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never any Discourse with any body, that you wanted 100 Guineas to make up this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Norton. No, not to my Knowledge , I did not.</p>
               <p>Council . I will put you in mind, whether you did not say so to your Mistress.</p>
               <p>Norton . I don't know that I did, not to my Knowledge, I did not.</p>
               <p>Council . Did you or did you not?</p>
               <p>Norton . I did not as I can remember .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner's Master, had you any Discourse with him upon it?</p>
               <p>Norton. Yes, Sir, and he would have had me have made it up; he asked what the young Woman would have to make it up; I said I did not know what she would have to make it up; I was ordered to go by Mr Cooper .</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you whether you did not tell the Prisoner's Master, you would have 100 Guineas ?</p>
               <p>Norton. Not to my Knowledge, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was to have been your Share of the 100 Guineas; what would you have got so much and you have nothing of it; supposing they had entrusted you with the 100 Guineas , what would you have done with them?</p>
               <p>Norton . She was to have them; Mr Cooper came along with me, to see if I could make it up.</p>
               <p>Council. You are sure she cry'd Murder?</p>
               <p>Norton. I heard her cry out Murder once or twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before you got up Stairs, or after ?</p>
               <p>Norton. Before.</p>
               <p>Council . And when you had brought her down, I ask you whether you did not insist upon it, that she should swear a Rape, and she refused it before the People?</p>
               <p>Norton. No.</p>
               <p>Q I ask you upon your insisting upon this, whether the Cook did not take her into the dark Room?</p>
               <p>Norton . I never saw the Cook take her into this dark Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the Cook and she go somewhere?</p>
               <p>Norton . I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Council . Recollect whether you miss'd her for any Time.</p>
               <p>Norton. Yes she might, while I was out about my Business .</p>
               <p>Q. What, did you leave this poor Girl in the same bad Company that would not come to her Assistance?</p>
               <p>Norton . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you that he had beat her?</p>
               <p>Norton . She did not tell me so.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you pulled her off the Bed?</p>
               <p>Norton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Then you do not agree in the Story that she was in, that she was off the Bed when you came up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner . What do you say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am absolutely innocent of what I am charged with; I had rather be excused speaking if your Lordship pleases .</p>
               <p>Q to - Potter. Do you remember this Girl's going up Stairs?</p>
               <p>Potter. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went up with her?</p>
               <p>Potter. The Prisoner followed her.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you apprehend she was up , before she was down again?</p>
               <p>Potter. To the best of my Knowledge about 5 Minutes.</p>
               <p>Council. During the Time that you was at Dinner in the Kitchen, did you hear any Out-cry of Murder ?</p>
               <p>Potter. I heard her Cry out William, I heard her laugh at the first .</p>
               <p>Court. You did not think there was any Force of Violence.</p>
               <p>Potter. No; I heard no Cry of Murder, but William , William, upon which William went up-stairs ; and I followed him up-stairs, and went directly into the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150018"></xptr>Potter. I saw the young Woman upon the Bed, upon her Knees , with her Cloaths under her.</p>
               <p>Council . So then her Cloaths were not up.</p>
               <p>Potter. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the young Gentleman's Breeches down?</p>
               <p>Potter . No.</p>
               <p>Council . Then you say upon your Oath, his Breeches were not down, nor her Petticoats up.</p>
               <p>Potter . They were not; Norton abused the Gentleman, he was in a great Passion, I thought he would have struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. I would ask you whether the young Woman complained of being beat, or any other Injury.</p>
               <p>Potter. She told before us all in the Kitchen, that the Gentleman had never meddled with her, and what should she go before the Justice for.</p>
               <p>Court . Who urged her to go before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Potter. Norton, he said she should go before the Justice, and if she wanted Money, he would supply her ; she declared that the Gentleman had done her no manner of Harm.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present in the Kitchen or in the dark Room, when there was some Conversation past between Lucy and the Cook.</p>
               <p>Potter. Mr Cook took her into the dark Room, and Norton flew into a Passion , and insisted upon her going before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask you how you came to follow the Hostler up-stairs, when you heard no Noise but the Cry of William .</p>
               <p>Potter. Only because he flew into such a Passion, upon her crying out William , William.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be so jealous?</p>
               <p>Potter. He was very intimate with her.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you think he had Conversation with her ?</p>
               <p>Potter . He had as often as they could.</p>
               <p>Council. I have heard Stories of Haylosts , and Stables , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Potter . She bears the Character of a very loose debaucht Girl, in the Town.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-26-person241">
                  Thomas 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person241" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person241" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was at Dinner , upon the Cry of William, William, Norton the Hostler and the Gardener ran up-stairs, and I after them ; we were both at the Door before it was open; Norton the Hostler pushed it open, and we went in directly with him .</p>
               <p>Q. He said he had been in the Room , and he met you at the Stairs</p>
               <p>Morgan. We came in directly after him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you discover when you came into the Room?</p>
               <p>Morgan. The Girl was on her knees , getting off the Bed , and the young Gentleman was by her at the Bed .</p>

               <p>Q. Were her Coats any way disordered?</p>
               <p>Morgan. No, not at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Were his Breeches down or up?</p>
               <p>Morgan. They were up.</p>
               <p>Q How long did they stay in the Room?</p>
               <p>Morgan. They came down directly, Norton brought Lucy down by her Arms, and she sat down at the Dresser, and eat her Dinner, and the Hostler spoke to her and said, she should swear a Ravishment against him ; but she said to the Cook , that the Gentleman had not hurt her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-26-person242">
                  Ann 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person242" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person242" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . As the Hostler, the Gardener , the Boy, and I, were all of us at dinner, the Hostler said there was laughing above stairs, with that he listened again and we all heard the Cry of William, William; so the Hostler ran up-stairs , and the Gardener , and the Boy immediately followed, and the Hostler burst the Door open, and she came down in about 2 Minutes ; I asked her what was the Matter with her, and she said nothing at all, she said she was not hurt; the Hostler Norton, insisted upon her going before the Justice ; she then insisted upon dressing herself first, but he would not let her; upon his insisting that she should go before the Justice, I took her into another Room, to know why she would go before the Justice ; but the Hostler Norton shewed himself very angry, and insisted upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. When she came down was she in Tears , did you hear any thing of his beating her ?</p>
               <p>Fisher. No, but she said positively that the Gentleman had not hurt her.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character does she bear?</p>
               <p>Fisher. But a very indifferent Character , we did not intend to keep her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-26-person243">
                  John 
                  Fawsey 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person243" type="surname" value="Fawsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person243" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was at the House at this Time, the young Man was a little drowsy after Dinner, with that the Maid was called to let down the Bed, they ran up and down stairs, one after another ; I thought one to be as willing as the other ; by-and-by the Landlord came into the Room, and said there was something a doing above-stairs , for Nan was crying out; when I went into the Kitchen, the Girl was come down ; I said you don't seem to be hurt, she seemed very lively and pert, and said she cry'd out that she might not be hurt; but the Hostler was very forward to prosecute , she did not seem to have any Inclination for it herself.</p>

               <p>- Cooper. This 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person244">
                  Ann 
                  Lucy 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person244" type="surname" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person244" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and Norton, and an old Woman, came to me and informed me, that there was a young Gentleman at the George and Vulture , that had attempted to commit a Rape ; I asked her how he behaved; Lucy said he behaved well for a Day or two , but that Afternoon he had some Complaint , and he wanted to have his Bed let down; she said he attempted to lie with her, she said he took up he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150019"></xptr> Coats ; I said if they come to me , she must tell the Truth ; she said he did put his Hand up her Coats\ and took hold of her private Parts ; I said did he lie with you, or did he not; and the Girl declared he did not lie with her; I says, do you know this Gentleman; she said she did not; I said, if the Hostler could find out his Friends, and get something of Satisfaction . I found, upon enquiry, this Girl had but an indifferent Character ; I went to the Prisoner's Master, and told him, I thought it most adviseable , to go down and endeavour to make an End of it, and the Hostler asked 200 Pounds ; I said to them, I believed his Friends would be willing to offer some little Compliments for Incivilities ; they applyed to me to carry on the Prosecution, if they could not make it up with the Prisoner's Master; upon my refusal , they applied to one Mr Moore, of Holborn.</p>
               <p>This Solicitor or Attorney, was called upon several times, and sent after, but could not be found, in order to be brought into Court, to answer for his undertaking such a Cause .</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Cooper . Do you know any thing of this young Woman's Character ?</p>
               <p>Cooper. She has a bad Character in our Neighbourhood, I had it from my Father and her own Mother.</p>
               <p>- Walker. This Lucy and the Hostler, came to me some Time after this Affair happened , and the young Woman told me her Mistress had turned her away; she said this young Gentleman had pull'd and haul'd her about ; I said, what he has run up and down-stairs after you; she held down her head, and said, there was something more than that; I said, has he lain with you; and she said, no Madam he has not. The Man was without, so I call'd him in, and I said, what have you to say in this Affair , concerning this young Spark; I don't know (says he) Madam, he has used herill ; I said you have an honest Wife, and what Business have you with it; he said it was hard; I said here she stands, she says he has not lain with her; I said I fancy you make a Mistake , 'tis you that have lain with her; for he owned to me, that he had lain with her .</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person245">
                  Esther 
                  Moulds 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person245" type="surname" value="Moulds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person245" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person246">
                  Ann 
                  Lucy 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person246" type="surname" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person246" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Moulds . Yes, Sir, I have known her for about half a Year.</p>
               <p>Q What Character does she bear?</p>
               <p>Moulds. A very indifferent one .</p>
               <p>Q. What Character did she bear before January last ?</p>
               <p>Moulds . A very bad one .</p>
               <p>Court to Mrs Jaques . She says when this young Gentleman exprest an Inclination to go and lie down , you bid her go and turn down the Bed ; and she expresses something , as if you incouraged these Freedoms; did you use such an Expression , that it would be an Honour for her to lie down by a young Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Jaques. Upon my Oath I did not ; the young Gentleman said he was very sleepy, and he wanted to lie down; I said to him, yes, you may lie down, there are Beds enough in the House, you may lie down upon any; so the young Gentleman went up one Pair of Stairs; she went up I believe to turn the Bed down , so she run backward and forward, but I did not imagine any thing of this Affair; afterwards I went to her, and asked her what had been the Matter ; she said he frighted me a little bit, but he has not done me any Harm; I said if he has not done you any Harm, don't take any Notice of it; I heard the Hostler say he would have a Warrant for him; I said if you should have any Warrant, you shall got out of the House directly; I asked her if the young Gentleman had lain with her, (and she sat down and eat her Dinner) and she said he had not.</p>
               <p>Q And what past after this?</p>
               <p>Jaques. So I took the Prisoner into the Yard, and talked to him, and said I was surprized ! Could not he let the young Woman alone?</p>
               <p>Q. Was she present at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Jaques . She was in the Brewhouse , and he was at the Door; and he declared to me, that he had not lain with her, any more than put his Hand up her Petticoats ; so they wanted to fetch a Warrant, and I turned them both out of Doors directly ; I was but a Stranger to them, and the House; I had not been in the House above three Weeks by myself; this Girl has had a bad Character from 11 or 12 Years of Age .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear of that before ?</p>
               <p>Jaques. No, if I had I never would have had her in my House.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470715-26-person247">
                  John 
                  Archer 
               <interp inst="t17470715-26-person247" type="surname" value="Archer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What Character does this young Woman, this Lucy bear?</p>
               <p>Archer. She is a bad disorderly Person , that's her general Character ; I have an Apprentice that has kept her company for a considerable Time . There were several more Witnesses in the Behalf of the Prisoner , and against the Prosecutrix , but the Court did not judge it at all necessary to examine any more. The Prisoner was <rs id="t17470715-26-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470715-26-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> . The Court hoped this would be a Warning to him, and every one in Court , to be careful of their Company and Conducts .</p>
            </div1>
