<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-62">
               <interp inst="t17401015-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-62" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-62" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-62-off334-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-defend418 t17401015-62-off334 t17401015-62-verdict335"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-62-off334-c336" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-defend419 t17401015-62-off334 t17401015-62-verdict335"></join>
         
               <p>499, 500. + 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-defend418" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend418" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend418" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17401015-62-defloc332">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-62-defloc332" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-62-defloc332" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-defend418 t17401015-62-defloc332"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-defend419 t17401015-62-defloc332"></join>, <rs id="t17401015-62-deflabel333" type="occupation">Tobacconist</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-defend418 t17401015-62-deflabel333"></join>, and 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-defend419" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend419" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend419" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-defend419" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of the same, Widow, were indicted, for that they <rs id="t17401015-62-off334" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-off334" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-off334" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously and falsely made, and caused to be made and procured, a certain Writing, sealed with the Name of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17401015-62-victim421" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Sandys 
                        <interp inst="t17401015-62-victim421" type="surname" value="Sandys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-62-victim421" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-62-victim421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-62-off334 t17401015-62-victim421"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , purporting to be the last Will of the said Henry Sandys, in the Words and Figures following
            </rs>, viz.</p>
               <p>In the Nam of God, Amen:</p>
               <p>I Henry Sandys, of the Parish of St. Giles in the Fields, Painter, being somewhat infirm, &amp;c. do make and ordain this my Last Will and Testament, commending my Soul to the Creator, and my Body to the Earth, to be decently interr'd, &amp;c. my Temporal Estate I dispose as follows, my Debts being first paid.</p>
               <p>Imprimis, I give and bequeath to 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person422">
                  Frances 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person422" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person422" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person422" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Sum of 80 l. to be paid in Quarterly Payments; the first Payment to be made the Quarter Day after my Decease; and in case she die before the same be fully paid, then the Remainder shall be divided among the Children of Richard Sandys.</p>
               <p>Item, I give and bequeath to 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person423">
                  Bridget 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person423" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person423" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my Sister-in-law, 10 l. To 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person424">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person424" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person424" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 5 l.</p>
               <p>Item, I give and bequeath to 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person425">
                  Matthew 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person425" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person425" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my Brother-in law, and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person426">
                  John 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person426" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person426" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , One Guinea to buy Rings.</p>
               <p>Item, I give and bequeath to the Children of 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person427">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sandys 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person427" type="surname" value="Sandys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person427" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person427" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 20 l.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150030"></xptr>Item I give and bequeath to the Children of 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person428">
                  Richard 
                  Sandys 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person428" type="surname" value="Sandys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person428" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             40 l. a-piece, at 21 Years of Age; and in case any of them die, their Parts to be divided among the Survivors of them.</p>
               <p>Item, I give to 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person429">
                  Francis 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person429" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person429" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Sum of 30 l.</p>
               <p>Item, I give to Elizabeth Bates the Interest of 500 l. out of my South-Sea Stock, for her natural Life, and her Husband shall not intermeddle there-with, but it shall be for her own Maintenance, without Controul of her said Husband; and I give the said Principal 500 l. among the Children of my Brother Sandys ; and in case any happen to die, then their Share shall be divided among the Survivors of them.</p>
               <p>Item, I give to Thomas Bates 10 l. for his Care and trouble in executing the same Will. All the rest not bequeathed, or disposed, I give to Elizabeth Bates, to enjoy the same during her natural Life; and after her Decease , it shall go among the Children of Richard Sandys.</p>
               <p>And I do hereby appoint Thomas Bates, and Elizabeth Bates, joint Executors of this my Last Will and Testament, revoking all former Wills whatsoever by me made. In Witness whereof, I have set my Hand and Seal, in the Fourth Year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord George the Second, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Henry Sandys.</p>
               <p>Sign'd, seal'd and declared in the Presence of 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person430">
                  Alexander 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person430" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person430" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person431">
                  Richard 
                  Curtis 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person431" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person431" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . With Intent to defraud 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person432">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person432" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person432" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>They were a second Time indicted for publishing the said Will, knowing it to be forged, false, and counterfeit, April 7.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution set forth, that the Prisoners were indict ed on a late Act for Forgery; and that this Prosecution was set on foot, to bring to Punishment two Persons, who had offended against the Act, in publishing a Will for a true one, which when it was looked on, would appear to be a manifest Erasure.</p>
               <p>That there was no positive Evidence against the Prisoners, of their forging this Will; and without that it would be hard to say they were guilty of it; but that the Crime of publishing it, knowing it to be forged, is equally the same; and if the two Prisoners should happen to be guilty of that only, it would be within the Meaning of the Statute.</p>
               <p>It was farther observed on the same Side; that as transactions of this Nature are of the worst Consequence to the Publick, where People are so hardy as to alter Mens Wills, to alter the Sums, to increase or diminish them; so there was an absolute Necessity for putting a severer Punishment on the Crime. That a Will was made by Mr. Sandys , and the old Gentleman having had Prosperity in the World, did intend to make an equal Distribution of his Effects, and consider all his Relations. That it happened some Time before this, that Mr. Sandys was afflicted with Blindness, so that he could not write: I hat he was got into the Hands of an artful Woman, one of the Prisoners, and nothing was done without her Consent; and that the 2 Prisoners prevailed so much over him, that he made them Executors of his Will. That some little time before his Death, as his Relation Mr Grimes, was a Man of worth, he had taken an Affection to him. and had promised him a Legacy; and that it would be proved, that the Old Man declared before his Death, that he had left Mr Grimes 50 l. That Mr Sandys dying soon after, no one was privy to it, but the 2 Prisoners, and they never gave notice of it to any of the Relations; but Mr Grimes afterwards hearing of his Uncle's Death, went to the Prisoners; that he asked them, why they did not let him know, that he might come and search; that the Prisoner Thomas Bates reply'd, '' there is '' no Occasion for that, for I am one Executor, '' and here is the other, (meaning Mrs Bates) he '' has left you 5 l. and here is the Will.'' That Bates then produced a Will, and on Inspection, there appeared to have been a manifest Erasure , and in another Hand, a 5 put in the Place.</p>
               <p>It was again observed, that the ink on this alteration was fresh, the Sand was on the 5, and crumbled off when touched. That Mr Grimes was tender of what he did, and went to Curtis, who was then in Goal, and enquired of him whether there had been any Directions given about the alteration of the Will; that Curtis owned, that he had some time before made a Will for this Mr Sandys, and that it was a Rule with him, when he made an alteration on an Erasure, he always made a Memorandum on the Back. That this gave a strong Presumption, and put Mr Grimes on sifting into the thing, and when the Man came to be buried, a Person came to Mr Grimes for Wine, and entered into Discourse with him about this Will, and said that Mr Bates sent for him, the Day after the Man died, to break open a Box; that he did open the Box, and saw the Will in the same Condition, as when given to Mr Grimes.</p>
               <p>It was likewise offered, that on examining this Will, it appeared that the 5 in several other Places was wrote in a different Manner, which could not be done by Mr Sandys himself, because he was blind; that notwithstanding this, it was insisted on by the Prisoners Thomas Bates , that the writing was all the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150031"></xptr> same, but it would be proved that he saw the Sand fresh on the 5, and must know that somebody had made an Erasure. That as this was a Case wherein Life was concerned, it required the strictest proof to be given, and it was presumed that what should be offered against the Prisoners, would be a sufficient Proof of the Publication, and within the Act of Parliament.</p>
               <p>Mr Grimes sworn.</p>
               <p>It was here urged on the Part of the Defendants, that it appeared from the Face of the Indictment, that Mr Grimes was a Party interested in the Cause, therefore could not be a legal Evidence.</p>
               <p>The Case of Mr Barton *, who was prosecuted by one Collins for forging a Bond, (where the Court was of Opinion that Collins could not be an Evidence) and 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person433">
                  William 
                  Judd 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person433" type="surname" value="Judd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person433" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for a promissory Note, were mentioned as Cases of the same Nature with this.</p>
               <p>* See his Trial in the Sessions Book for April last, p. 133. No. 231.</p>
               <p>In Answer to which, it was said by the Counsel for the Prosecution, that the Cases which had been mentioned were quite different from this, for if Mr Grimes should give Evidence, it would be to over-throw the Will, then consequently he could have no Part of the Man's Estate, and would swear to his own Prejudice, therefore must be allowed to destroy his own Interest.</p> 
               <p>On the Part of the Defendants it was offered in reply, that this was not an Answer to the Objection, for, according to the Tenour of the Indictment, his Testimony would be to prove that there had been an alteration in the Will, from 50 to 5, to his Prejudice; and if that should be proved, the Court of Equity would give him what was originally intended him.</p>
               <p>Upon the whole, it was the Opinion of the Court that Mr Grimes was a Party interested, therefore could not be admitted a legal Witness.</p>
               <p>Couns. We call Mr Justice De Veil to prove that the Will was produced before him, and that the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person434">
                  Thomas 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person434" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person434" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , insisted on it, that it was a true Will.</p>
               <p>Mr De Veil . This Will was produced before me, in order to take out a Warrant for the Prisoner, but he came without. Mr Grimes brought the Will.</p>
               <p>Couns. When the Prisoner was before you, did not he say that it was a true Will?</p>
               <p>Mr De Veil. Yes; he said he had no concern in it; Mr Grimes produc'd the Will before me, and the Prisoner said he thought it was in the same Manner as it was left, and insisted on his Innocence. There came 2 Neighbours, and told me he was incapable of this thing. I saw the Will, and it appear'd just as it does now; I took a great deal of Notice of it, and thought some Part of it to be fresh done, because the Sand appear'd to me to be still on it.</p>
               <p>Couns. How did Mr Grimes use the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mr De Veil. Mr Grimes treated him with deal of good Nature when he was before me.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you see the Prisoner Mrs Bates ?</p>
               <p>Mr De Veil. I think she was before me, and said it was the same, but I can't be positive.</p>
               <p>Mr Needham sworn.</p>
               <p>Couns. Look on that Paper.</p>
               <p>Mr Needham. I saw it about 5 or 6 Months ago; I live opposite to Mr Grimes, and he told me his Uncle was dead, and he was going to Long-Acre to see what was left him. When he came back, he shew'd me this Paper.</p>
               <p>Couns. Look on it where those two fives are wrote.</p>
               <p>Mr Needham. I observ'd it then, and it appear'd just as it does now. I did not observe any Sand, but Ink appear'd to me to be fresher in that Place than in any other. Mr Grimes shew'd me the Will within an Hour after he came from Bate's, and after he had been to Mr De Veil.</p>
               <p>- Curtis sworn.</p>
               <p>Couns. You were sent for to make a Will for Mr Sandys in the Year 30; is this your Writing?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you draw all this Will?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes; I engross'd it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Have you ever seen those Figures? look on them; 5 l. to 
               <persName id="t17401015-62-person435">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person435" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person435" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Curtis . I believe it was so when the Will was made; there was a Paper which was wrote by Sandy's Order found with the Will, wherein all the Legacies were set down.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not Mr Grimes come to you about an Erasure?</p>
               <p>Curtis . Yes; I told him I knew nothing at all of it; it had escap'd my Memory. I commonly made a Memorandum if any Erasure should happen. They shew'd me the Will but I could not charge my Memory with it.</p>
               <p>Couns. On your Oath, did not you say that those two fives were not your Writing.</p>
               <p>Curtis. I said nothing at all like it, to the best of my Remembrance; I did not say so.</p>
               <p>Couns. On your Oath, are they your Writing or not.</p>
               <p>Curtis. I do believe them to be mine.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150032"></xptr>Couns . How came you to write that Word Five with a small s?</p>
               <p>Curtis . I said I could not charge my Memory with it ; I could not be positive in it so long as ten Years.</p>
               <p>Couns . Are they your Writing or not .</p>
               <p>Curtis. I do believe them to be mine .</p>
               <p>Couns. On your Oath, were they wrote on an Erasure?</p>
               <p>Curtis. It is an Erasure plain.</p>
               <p>Couns. How came that Word Five to be in a different Ink?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I can't tell that; there was something I believe wrote before the Word Five was there.</p>
               <p>Couns . Did not you declare, that when an Erasure happened, you always made a Memorandum on the Back?</p>
               <p>Curtis . I did not say so, I usually did, I could not say I always did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did you mention to Mr Grimes, when he apply'd to you, that there was another Paper?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I did not at that time. After Mr Bates brought me the Paper, I said it was my Writing. The Testator desired me to make a Memorandum of the Legacies.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was not Mr Grimes at the Expence of a Rule in Easter Term last, to bring you to Westminster?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes; I went in a Coach; the Tipstaff's Man paid for it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. For what Purpose was it?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I can't tell what; to be a Witness on his Behalf I believe, but I told him then that a Paper of all the Legacies was found, and I could not be a Witness for him. Upon that he gave me some opprobrious Words, and I walked back again. I believe it was the Day before Term ended.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did he say any thing to you about an Indictment?</p>
               <p>Curtis. There was a Parchment Writing at that time produc'd, but he did not tell me what it was. We had a great deal of Talk, and I said there was such a Paper found, it is my Writing by the Testator's Directions , and it settles in my Mind that you have no more than 5 l. left you. Here is a Man that has a Copy of the Will, I prepar'd the other from this; the Alterations here are my Writing; this was a former Will, dated 1729.</p>
               <p>Couns. How came you not to write the 5 l. in this Will, as fair and plain as the other Words?</p>
               <p>Curtis. There was a Mistake but how I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was that Paper which was found, your Instructions to draw the Will?</p>
               <p>Curtis. No; I wrote it by the Testator's Desire, that he might know how much the Legacies amounted to.</p>
               <p>Couns . Did not you copy that Paper from the old Will?</p>
               <p>Curtis. No, I took it from the new one.</p>
               <p>Couns. Your Memory is very good in every thing, but you can't tell us, whether there was an Erasure made.</p>
               <p>Curtis . I can't remember, but there must be a Mistake.</p>
               <p>A Witness . I was present drinking with Curtis, when Mr Grimes came in with the Will. I will tell you how it was. On Easter Monday I was with Curtis; Mr Grimes and Mr Bambridge came in and wanted to speak with Curtis; they laid the Will down on the Table, and ask'd him if he made that Erasure; they bid him look carefully over it; and he said he could not remember that he did. The Question was asked him, whether he made that Erasure, and he answer'd he knew nothing of it; he could not charge his Memory with it. He said nothing of there being a Paper that would set Things right, but that the Alterations were not his own Writing. This was in the King's-Bench, and I always call'd to see him when I went that Way.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not Curtis say that he could not charge his Memory with Facts?</p>
               <p>The Witness. I can say no more than I have told you.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not he say that it was a great while ago?</p>
               <p>The Witness. Yes, 10 Years ago, and he could not remember so long. I believe Curtis to be an honest Man, and I do not think he would be guilty of Perjury.</p>
               <p>Mr Bambridge. Mr Grimes came to my Chambers in Easter Holidays, and said there had been an Erasure made in a Will to his Prejudice; he desired me to go with him to the Man who made the Will; I went with him, and we found Curtis with two Men; I called him out, and told him what we came about, but he did not remember any thing. We went in and opened the case before them all, and then he said he did remember the making of the Will; are the Figures which stand on that Erasement your's (said I) or not? He said, I think not, and gave us a Reason, that he always made a Memorandum on the Back; and he made no Hesitation. I cannot be so particular, as to remember whether he made use of the Word usually or always.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-62-person436">
                  Webb 
                  Sworn 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person436" type="surname" value="Sworn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person436" type="given" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150033"></xptr>Couns. Did you know Mr Sandys in his Life-time?</p>
               <p>Webb. Yes.</p>
               <p>Couns. When was it that you heard him say he had left Mr Grimes any thing.</p>
               <p>Webb. He dined at Mr. Grimes's House, and Mr Bates was there at the same time.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was there any talk about a Will?</p>
               <p>Webb. Mr Sandys told my Master, that he had left him 50 l. and it would be the last time he should see him; he said he left Mr Grimes's Sister 50 l. There was no mention made of Mr. Grimes's Mother, what Sum he had left her, only that he had left Mr Grimes and his Sister 50 l. Our Bar-keeper was present, it was the 22d of February.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Do you live with Mr Grimes?</p>
               <p>Webb. I have lived with him as a Cellar-Man these four Years; he deals in Wine by wholesale, in Princes-Street, Drury-Lane.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Then you are not his Servant in the Capacity of an Attorney.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-62-person437">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17401015-62-person437" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person437" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-person437" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Sworn.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you remember Bates and Sandys at your House.</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes; he died the latter end of February, and was at our House the 22d. He had fell down in the Dirt, and my Master asked him if he had hurt himself, and why he would not take a Coach when he came out; he said if ever he came out again he would have a Coach, but he believed he should never see my Master any more. He said he had left him and his Sister 50 l.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Do you live with Grimes?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes; I have lived with him as a Bar-keeper about 2 Years; and Mr Sandys said at our House, that he had left my Master something to remember him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. How came he to say afterwards 50 l.</p>
               <p>Smith. After Dinner, my Master asked him how he did, he said indifferent, and that he had left him and his Sister 50 l. a piece. The Conversation was almost the same as before Dinner.</p>
               <p>The Evidence for the Prosecution rested here; and it was urged on the Part of the Defendants, that what has been offered to support this Indictment could not in the least affect them with respect to the Publication of the Will, knowing it to be forged.</p>
               <p>Juryman. The Will had been some time out of Mr Bates's Hands; a five might have been erased, and another wrote thereon. <rs id="t17401015-62-verdict335" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-62-verdict335" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
