<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480224-32">
               <interp inst="t17480224-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-32" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-32" type="date" value="17480224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-32-off180-c241" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-32-defend297 t17480224-32-off180 t17480224-32-verdict182"></join>
         
               <p>154. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480224-32-defend297" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Cooley 
                  <interp inst="t17480224-32-defend297" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-defend297" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-defend297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17480224-32-defloc179">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-32-defloc179" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-32-defloc179" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-32-defend297 t17480224-32-defloc179"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17480224-32-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480224-32-victim299" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Poole 
                        <interp inst="t17480224-32-victim299" type="surname" value="Poole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-32-victim299" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-32-victim299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-32-off180 t17480224-32-victim299"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him, with both his hands, several mortal bruises on the head, breast, stomach and sides
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480224-32-cd181" type="crimeDate">Jan. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-32-off180 t17480224-32-cd181"></join>.</p>
               <p>Somerfield Wright. The deceased came the twenty-second day of January to drink a parting pot with me and the Prisoner, for he was going the next morning to his ship, and we had three quarts of beer between five of us; the Prisoner and the deceased fell into a discourse about the fighting men that fought at Broughton's Booth , and the deceased said he believed he could fight ever a one of them for a guinea; and moreover, he said he would fight the Prisoner at the bar for a guinea; the Prisoner at the bar said done, and pulled off his clothes; the deceased rose up, and took out two half crowns , and put them into my hand; the Prisoner had no money, but he pulled a ring off his finger, to bind the wager of a guinea, and they were to fight the next morning; then I stopped between them, and said let us have no more of it; then I went to give the deceased his two half crowns again, but before I could do it, he gave the Prisoner a little sort of a push; with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240029"></xptr> that the Prisoner gave him a slap on the face, and they went to fighting directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there many blows exchanged?</p>
               <p>Wright. There were not many blows exchanged, for they did not fight above two minutes; there might be about a dozen blows exchanged between them: The deceased had two falls, and after the second fall the deceased gave out, and said he would fight no more; with that the Prisoner insisted upon his ring again; I told him I had none of it: I looked about the house for the ring, and while I was looking for it the deceased went out of the room; presently a woman came into the room and brought word, that the deceased lay dead in the entry.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased make any complaint before he went out of the room, of any blow that affected him?</p>
               <p>Wright. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any marks of violence upon him?</p>
               <p>Wright. None at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been out of the room before the woman came?</p>
               <p>Wright. About six or seven minutes . I went out to see for him, and the deceased lay upon his back in the entry at full length; then we brought him into the room and laid him upon the bed, and I went for a surgeon to bleed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bleed him?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, the surgeon pricked him in both arms, but he would not bleed at all.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first saw him upon the floor, did you think him to be actually dead?</p>
               <p>Wright. I cannot say he was actually dead when we brought him into the room, because there was some movement in him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take off his clothes, to see whether there were any marks of violence, or any wounds on his body?</p>
               <p>Wright . I did not take his clothes off at all, for his coat and waistcoat were off before, and I did not take off his shirt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine his face and head, to see if there were any marks of violence?</p>
               <p>Wright. Not that night; the next day I saw he had a blow under his left ear, and there was a little bruise.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it your opinion, that the deceased came by his death by that blow?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, I cannot think that at all; I cannot think that was the occasion of his death in any shape. I did not see any other blow.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he had been out any where, between the time of his going out of the room and your seeing him in the passage ?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, unless he went into the yard; for the knees of his breeches were dirty, and one side of his face was dirty.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine he had any fall any where?</p>
               <p>Wright. He must have had a fall by the dirt.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it possible, that the bruise which you saw under his left ear might proceed from the fall?</p>
               <p>Wright. Upon my word I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it look like street dirt?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I help to lift the deceased in upon the bed?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, you did, and I went for a doctor to bleed him, and he bled as free as could be, about a spoonful out of each arm.</p>
               <p>Q. You said just now, he would not bleed at all.</p>
               <p>Wright. He bled a little drop.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun . Were they not old ship-mates?</p>

               <p>Wright. They were old acquaintance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-32-person300">
                  Susanna 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person300" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person300" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person300" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person301">
                  Henry 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person301" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person301" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to take his leave of the deceased, 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person302">
                  James 
                  Poole 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person302" type="surname" value="Poole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person302" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was my husband's cousin, for the Prisoner was to go the next day on board a ship, and he said we will have a pot of beer together; we had three pots in all: The deceased said to the Prisoner, he had lost a pot of beer about two Men's fighting, and the deceased said afterwards, I think I can fight as well as ever I could, and the Prisoner was for going; the deceased said to the Prisoner, do not go yet, Harry, you may as well be hanged for a sheep as a lamb, it is but a flogging bout, but the Prisoner said he would go: Said Jemmy Poole, I wish you and I had a touch at fighting before you go; then said 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person303">
                  Henry 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person303" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person303" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Jemmy, what makes you give me a challenge to fight? but since you have given the first challenge, if you have a mind to fight, I will fight you; with that the deceased took two half crowns out of his pocket , to lay the wager of a guinea to fight the next day, as they thought (but they fought directly;) says 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person304">
                  Henry 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person304" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person304" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have no money, but I will give you my ring to bind the bargain, it is worth a guinea, and he took it off his finger and put it upon the two half crowns into my husband's hand; said my husband, I would not have you fight , take your ring again; with that 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person305">
                  James 
                  Poole 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person305" type="surname" value="Poole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person305" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came up to 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person306">
                  Henry 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person306" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person306" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Cooley pulled off his clothes; then the deceased said to the Prisoner, foolish boy, put on your clothes, and I will fight you to morrow . I am able to whip your a - e at any time, for I have licked you many a time when you was a boy, and gave the Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240030"></xptr> a little push; with that the Prisoner being aggravated, he hit the deceased a slap o n the face, and they fell to fighting directly; they had very few blows between them , for the man that is dead had been a sick man a good while, and was in the Hospital, for he had a ball in his thigh, and was discharged from his ship .</p>
               <p>Q. How many blows passed between them?</p>
               <p>Wright . I cannot tell, there might be a dozen between them, and there were two falls , the deceased was thrown , and I believe the last fall hurt him; then they left off fighting, and 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person307">
                  Henry 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person307" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person307" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, will you fight any more? and the deceased said, no; then said the Prisoner I have done, and the deceased got up and went out of the room, whether he went into the yard or into the street I cannot say; then Polly Fowler came into the room and said, Jemmy Poole is dead in the entry: this was about five or six minutes after he went out of the room; then the Prisoner went out of the room, and said, oh Lord God! is he dead that I loved so dearly, and clapped his two hands together, and cried like a child whipped with a rod: then we got him into the room, and laid him upon the bed; and I went for a surgeon, but could not get any; so I got a barber, and he bled him, and he bled about a spoonful; I think I can swear to that, and not hurt myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the body at that time?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, not till the next day, and then I perceived a little bruise under his ear, one side of his face was all muddy , and his back was dirty and the knees of his breeches; there was no dirt upon him when he went out of the room, and I cannot tell how he came by the dirt; he must either have got it in the street or in the yard, and I suppose by a fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what he went out for?</p>
               <p>Wright . His shirt hung out of his breeches, whether he went out to make water , I cannot tell, for it is impossible for me to know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks of violence or bruises upon him?</p>
               <p>Wright . Yes, there was a bruise under his left ear, a very little one, but not likely at all to be his death's wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any wound or bruise about him that might be the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Wright . No, but he was an aiding man a long time, and the falls might hurt him.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he have got that bruise by a fall, you suppose he got the dirt by a fall ?</p>
               <p>Wright . I do not know whether he could or not; there was a surgeon came, and he bid us take a looking-glass and put to his mouth, but there was no breath in him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a good harmony between the deceased and the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, there always was, they were as loving as two brothers, they went to school together .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any quarrel between them before this you are speaking of?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, I believe there was no thoughts of malice between them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-32-person308">
                  Edward 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person308" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person308" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             [a young lad about fourteen.] I was there that evening with the Prisoner and the deceased, and 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person309">
                  James 
                  Poole 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person309" type="surname" value="Poole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person309" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said I believe I can fight as well as ever, and I believe I can fight any man upon the stage; and he said to the Prisoner at the bar I think I can fight you, so they disputed, and the young man that is dead put a crown into Mr. Wright's hand, and the Prisoner pulled a ring off his finger to answer it; one said he would fight the other, and then the deceased gave the Prisoner a shove, and they pulled off their clothes and fell to fighting; the Prisoner gave the other a fall, and he that died sat down upon his a - e, and the Prisoner asked him whether he would fight any more, and he said he would not; a lit tle after that 
               <persName id="t17480224-32-person310">
                  Polly 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person310" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person310" type="given" value="Polly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person310" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in with a pot of beer, and said, Lord, Mrs. Wright, Jemmy Poole is dead; and the Prisoner said, is he indeed? and the Prisoner said, what a misfortunate young man I was to come here; and then the Prisoner and Mr. Wright helped to lift him into the room, and I did as much as I could, and we laid him upon the bed; then a surgeon was sent for, and he bled him in both arms.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any bruises?</p>
               <p>Holder. Yes, I perceived a bruise under his left ear , and when we brought him in he had dirt upon his back, dirt upon both his knees, and dirt upon his left cheek.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you think he could get this dirt?</p>
               <p>Holder . He must get the dirt either in the yard or in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he could get all this dirt without falling?</p>
               <p>Holder . No, he must have a fall to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. And you saw no wound or bruise but under his left ear?</p>
               <p>Holder . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he complain of any particular hurt after he had done fighting?</p>
               <p>Holder . No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-32-person311">
                  Joseph 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17480224-32-person311" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person311" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a surgeon called by the Prisoner.) I examined the body when the Coroner's Inquest sat upon it; when they viewed the body they perceived<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240031"></xptr> a bruise under the left ear, which they thought was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take that bruise under his ear to be the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>James. I take that under his ear to be a settling of extravasated blood, as there was in his back and sides, but I do not take that to be a bruise, neither could it be the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you scalp him?</p>
               <p>James. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And was there any dangerous wound on his skull ?</p>
               <p>James. There was no hurt done to the skull that could occasion his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any wounds on any part of his body ?</p>
               <p>James. There was a mark on his breast, but that was an old wound.</p>
               <p>Q. So you did not find any wound or bruise that could occasion his death?</p>
               <p>James. No, not in the least.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you think he came by his death?</p>
               <p>James. He was out of the room five or six minutes, and it is possible that a person being drunk, or through passion, or in a fit, may drop down dead, for I am sure that his death was not from any blow; I have known persons to have fallen down stairs, and have died in a fit .</p>
               <p>Q. What do you take it to be?</p>
               <p>James . I take it to be a fit of the apoplexy .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take those places where there was extravasated blood to be a sign of an apoplexy?</p>
               <p>James . Yes, Sir, I believe it was from a stoppage in the small vessels, and that was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480224-32-verdict182" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-32-verdict182" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
