<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-8">
               <interp inst="t17400227-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-8" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-8" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-8-off44-c69" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-defend88 t17400227-8-off44 t17400227-8-verdict49"></join>
         
               <p>158. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-defend88" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Surridge 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-defend88" type="surname" value="Surridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-defend88" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-defend88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17400227-8-defloc43">St. Marin's in Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-defloc43" type="placeName" value="St. Marin's in Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-defloc43" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-defend88 t17400227-8-defloc43"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-8-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Kneebuckle, val. 1 s. a Stuff Purse, val. 1 d. a Moidore, and 5 Guineas, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-8-victim90" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Neal 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-8-victim90" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-8-victim90" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-8-victim90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-off44 t17400227-8-victim90"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17400227-8-cd45" type="crimeDate">February 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-off44 t17400227-8-cd45"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person91">
                  Thomas 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person91" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person91" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was Sevennight, I was coming from my Horses, which I had put up at the White Hart, in Shug lane, near Piccadilly, and as I came by the <placeName id="t17400227-8-crimeloc46">Rose</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-crimeloc46" type="placeName" value="Rose"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-crimeloc46" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-off44 t17400227-8-crimeloc46"></join> in <placeName id="t17400227-8-crimeloc47">Oxenden-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-crimeloc47" type="placeName" value="Oxenden-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-8-crimeloc47" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-off44 t17400227-8-crimeloc47"></join> , (kept by one * 
               <persName id="t17400227-8-person92">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Bignell 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person92" type="surname" value="Bignell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person92" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17400227-8-person93">
                  Rose 
                  Mabone 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person93" type="surname" value="Mabone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person93" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) the Prisoner stood at the Door, and asked me to give her something. It was about 8 o'Clock at Night, and I told her I could not stay. She ask'd me to give her a Quartern of Brandy; I comply'd, and went into the House (the Rose) with her; and she took a Candle off the Bar, herself, and carried me into a Room up two pair of Stairs. The Drawer brought up a Quartern of Brandy, and I gave him 6 d. for it; then he retired, and left the Prisoner and me together, and she told me I must give her Half a Crown for obliging me with her Company. I gave her 6 d. but she thinking that too little, I believe I gave her another. I was sober, tho' I can't be sure how much Money I gave her, - I believe 18 d. was the outside. While we were together, I put my Hand in my Pocket, and miss'd my Purse. I charg'd the Prisoner with having pick'd my Pocket; and she said, she had none of my Purse, she would assure me, nor my Money neither. When the Drawer came up, I told him she had robb'd me: He said, he did not understand the Nature of it, - as we came in we must go out, and so the Prisoner went down Stairs with him into the Kitchen. I follow'd, and told the Landlady, that she had pick'd my Pocket: She said - Perhaps you have dropp'd it above Stairs, go up with the Drawer, and look for it, and I'll be bound for the Prisoner's staying here, till you come down. But while I was hunting about the Room for my Money, she let the Prisoner escape; and as I imagined they had it among them, I offered them a Guinea to let me have it again. When I found there was nothing to be done, I went home; and the next Morning I told my Master's Landlord (where we lodged) what had happened; and we went directly to Col. De Veil for a Warrant to take the Prisoner; but not knowing her Name, we came away without one. Afterwards, as I was coming along Covent-Garden, I saw the Prisoner and another Woman with her in the Street, and told our Landlord, that was the Person who robbed me. I crossed the Street in order to pursue her, and a Cart coming by at the same Time, she turned to avoid the Cart, and came directly upon me. Then I caught hold of her, and said, Now, Madam, I have you. Both she and the other<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270009"></xptr> Woman immediately desired me not to expose her, and I should have my Money again, but as she had squandered some of it away, they hoped I would allow her something hand-some, for herself. Upon this I went with them again to the Rose , and asked her to give me my Money; but there being 3 or 4 Bullies in the Kitchen , one of them, - a Great Fellow, - said the Prisoner was his Wife, and that he would knock me through the Wall; and immediately they sell upon me, 2nd the Man that was with me; but I got out of the House first , and he got from them afterwards. Then I stood at the outside of the-Door, while my Friend went for a Constable; and as I stood at the Door, the Landlord of the House would have fain persuaded me to come in again, and drink with him: I refused, and when they found I would not come in again, one of the Fellows in the House cried, - d - mn you, Madam, come out with me: which she did, and I followed them cross the Hay-Market, and he put her up a pair of Stairs; then he came down to me and said, - there, d - mn you, now get her if you can. People about me said, she could not get out from that Place without being seen, so I got my Land-lord to stand at the bottom of the Stairs, while I went to Mr. Justice Frasier for a Warrant. After which we took her, and carried her before Colonel De Veil, who committed her. She made no Confession at all.</p>
               <p>* See the following Trial</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person94">
                  Thomas 
                  Corner 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person94" type="surname" value="Corner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person94" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the Person who assisted in taking the Prisoner) confirmed part of the former Evidence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he did not say, he had but 2 Shillings in the World, when he paid for the Quartern of Brandy?</p>
               <p>Neal. I might say so, because I did not care such Company should know what I had about me. I had a Moidore, 5 Guineas, and some odd Silver in my Purse, which was in my Pocket when I came from my Horses, for I had some Beer at that Place, and saw my Money when I paid for it: and when I gave the Prisoner some Silver in the Room, I fumbled in my Pocket, and pulled out a Six-pence or two from the Gold, without pulling out my Purse. While I was with her, I felt her Hand in my Pocket, and bid her keep them above board.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said he would swear a Robbery against me, because I would not let him be uncivil: and in less than a Quarter of an Hour afterwards, he picked up 2 Women, and carried them to the next Door, and drank Wine with them: telling them he had been with an ill-natured Girl, but they, he hoped, would be better tempered.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person95">
                  Sarah 
                  Hilliard 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person95" type="surname" value="Hilliard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person95" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner and the Prosecutor come together out of the Rose, in Oxendon-street , between 8 and 9 o'Clock. He told her, he would be even with her, for the 2 s. which he gave her, because she had not stood to her Bargain. Two Women, who were coming by at the same Time, told the Prosecutor, it would go with them they would make a sure Bargain; so they brought him to our House, [we h just the next Door to the Rose] and 
               <persName id="t17400227-8-person96">
                  Ribecca 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person96" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person96" type="given" value="Ribecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I being at the Door, she went in and served them with Wine: after which, she went out for some Sugar, and I being called in, to take the Reckoning, I heard him say, you are good-natured; but as for that other B - ch, I'll be even with her. When he went out, he asked me, if he could lie in the House all Night? But I told him the Gentlewoman that kept it, (one Mrs Brown) was out, and I could say nothing to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person97">
                  Ann 
                  Pollard 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person97" type="surname" value="Pollard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person97" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore much to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Neal. Upon my Oath, all these two Women have said is false: I never was in that House in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person98">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Poulter 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person98" type="surname" value="Poulter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person98" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Washerwoman, and live in Wardour-street, Old Sobo . I have known the Prisoner a great while; she is a <rs id="t17400227-8-deflabel48" type="occupation">Mantua-Maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-8-defend88 t17400227-8-deflabel48"></join>, and I never heard any Harm of her in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-8-person99">
                  Mary 
                  Whilt 
               <interp inst="t17400227-8-person99" type="surname" value="Whilt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person99" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on swore she had known the Prisoner a great while: she had never heard of her having done an ill Thing, and was surprized she should have done so now. <rs id="t17400227-8-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-8-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
