<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480224-40">
               <interp inst="t17480224-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-40" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-40" type="date" value="17480224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-40-off218-c285" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-defend356 t17480224-40-off218 t17480224-40-verdict220"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-40-off219-c285" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-defend356 t17480224-40-off219 t17480224-40-verdict220"></join>
         
               <p>162. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480224-40-defend356" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Parkes 
                  <interp inst="t17480224-40-defend356" type="surname" value="Parkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-defend356" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-defend356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , late of <placeName id="t17480224-40-defloc214">London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-40-defloc214" type="placeName" value="London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-40-defloc214" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-defend356 t17480224-40-defloc214"></join>, <rs id="t17480224-40-deflabel215" type="occupation">labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-defend356 t17480224-40-deflabel215"></join> , was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17480224-40-cd216" type="crimeDate">fifth day of February, in the 21st year of his Majesty's reign, at London</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off218 t17480224-40-cd216"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off219 t17480224-40-cd216"></join>; that is to say, at the parish of <placeName id="t17480224-40-crimeloc217">St. Mary Staining, in the ward of Aldersgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-40-crimeloc217" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Staining, in the ward of Aldersgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-40-crimeloc217" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off218 t17480224-40-crimeloc217"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off219 t17480224-40-crimeloc217"></join>, in London aforesaid, <rs id="t17480224-40-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously did falsely make, forge and counterfeit, and did cause and procure to be falsely made, forged and counterfeited, a certain paper writing, with the name of 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person357">
                        Paul 
                        de Lamerie 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person357" type="surname" value="de Lamerie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person357" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   subscribed thereto, and directed to Mr. Foxall, refiner in Oat-Lane, purporting to be an order, under the hand of 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person358">
                        Paul
                         de Lamerie
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person358" type="surname" value="de Lamerie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person358" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , to 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person359">
                        John 
                        Foxall 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person359" type="surname" value="Foxall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person359" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person360">
                        Peter 
                        Floyer 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person360" type="surname" value="Floyer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person360" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , copartners in trade, (the said 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person361">
                        Peter 
                        de Lamerie 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person361" type="surname" value="de Lamerie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person361" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   being a Person well known to the said 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person362">
                        John 
                        Foxall 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person362" type="surname" value="Foxall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person362" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person363">
                        Peter 
                        Floyer 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person363" type="surname" value="Floyer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person363" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ) for the delivery of two hundred ounces of sterling (meaning sterling silver) and directed to the said 
                     <persName id="t17480224-40-person364">
                        John 
                        Foxall 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person364" type="surname" value="Foxall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person364" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>; which said false, forged, and counterfeited paper writing is as follows, to wit :</p>
               <p>To Mr. Foxhall and company.</p>
               <p>'' Please to deliver to the bearer two hundred '' ounces of sterling. I promise to pay in '' fourteen days after date.</p>
               <p>Feb. 5, 1747-8.</p>
               <p>'' 
               <persName id="t17480224-40-person365">
                  Paul 
                  de Lamery 
               <interp inst="t17480224-40-person365" type="surname" value="de Lamery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person365" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .''</p>
               <p>To Mr. Foxhall, refiner in Oat-Lane .</p>
               <p>He was also indicted for <rs id="t17480224-40-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously uttering and publishing the said false, forged and counterfeited order, knowing it to be false, forged, and counterfeited , with an intent to defraud the said 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480224-40-victim367" type="victimName">
                           Paul
                            de Lamerie
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-victim367" type="surname" value="de Lamerie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-victim367" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-40-victim367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off218 t17480224-40-victim367"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-off219 t17480224-40-victim367"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  
               
                  </rs> .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240034"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-40-person368">
                  John 
                  Roumieu 
               <interp inst="t17480224-40-person368" type="surname" value="Roumieu"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person368" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am apprentice to Mr. Foxall, who is partner with Mr. Floyer, but they do not live in the same house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Prisoner's coming to you at any time?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . Yes. On the fifth of February, about two o'clock in the afternoon, the Prisoner came to my master's shop in Oat-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . He gave me a letter, which he said he brought from Mr. de Lamerie , in Gerrard-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any such gentleman that used to trade with your master, and lived in that street?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . Yes, and I had a suspicion of its being a counterfeit, upon account that neither Mr. Foxall's name nor Mr. de Lamerie's name were spelt right.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon that order, is that the order you received from the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Roumieu. Yes . I gave it to Mr. Foxall, and he ordered me to acquaint Mr. Floyer with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that discovered to be a forgery, and not Mr. de Lamerie's hand?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe that to be his hand?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . I do not; I know his hand, and I do not believe any part of it to be his writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to Mr. Floyer?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . I went to him, and he came immediately to our shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prisoner say when Mr. Floyer came?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . I was not present, but Mr. Floyer is here, who can inform you. I went to Mr. Scott's and some other refiners , who had been defrauded, to know if it was the same person. When I came back, Mr. Floyer had stopped the Prisoner; the Prisoner said he had the letter from Mr. Giles, Mr. de Lamerie's Clerk, and that he had known him several years; and afterwards he said it was given him by Mr. Giles, or somebody very much like him; the Prisoner was carried before my Lord Mayor, and committed.</p>
               <p>The order was read at the request of the council .</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say, that this order was delivered to you by the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . I saw my master open it, and I can take upon me to say that it is the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner tell you whether he knew the purport of the contents?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . He told me it was to deliver two hundred ounces of sterling for Mr. de Lamerie.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. de Lamerie write his name with an a or an e ?</p>
               <p>Roumieu . He writes it de Lamerie ; it is wrong spelt in the order, and Mr. Foxall's name is wrong spelt; there is an h more than is needful.</p>
               <p>Peter Floyer sworn .</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. de Lamerie use to deal with you?</p>
               <p>Floyer. Yes, many years. Our servant came to me, and said there was a man wanted me; I went to Mr. Foxall's, and seeing nobody in the passage I went to look for him, and I saw a man peeping in at the door; I asked him what he wanted, and he said he came for two hundred ounces of sterling, and had a letter with an order for it; and he said Mr. Giles, Mr. de Lamerie's clerk, gave it to him, at the Faulcon in Holborn; he hesitated a little, and told me the contents of the letter exactly. I was willing to keep him a little, and I told him our silver would be ready in about ten minutes; he said he would step into Wood-Street and come again; I took him by the collar and said, I believe I have somebody that wants to speak with you; then Mr. Foxall came up. The Prisoner said he had known Mr. Giles a great many years, that he had a weakness in his eyes, and was willing to get a little money as he could, and so came on this errand.</p>
               <p>Q. How does Mr. de Lamerie spell his name ?</p>
               <p>Floyer. In the forged Letter it is ry at the end of the name which should be rie.</p>
               <p>Mr. Floyer delivered into Court the letter and order that the Prisoner brought him .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he acknowledge the bringing the letter or note?</p>
               <p>Floyer. He acknowledged the bringing the letter, and an order, for the delivery of the two hundred ounces of silver enclosed.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take this to be Mr. de Lamerie's hand?</p>
               <p>Floyer. Neither the letter nor the order are like Mr. de Lamerie's hand, and Mr. Foxall's name is not spelt right. Afterwards he began to vary in his story, and said, that as he had a weakness in his eyes, he could not tell whether it was Mr. Giles that gave it him or not, but if it was not Mr. Giles, it was somebody like him. I said I would go with him to the Faulcon in Holborn; and when he came to a house, which he said was the sign of the Faulcon , the house was shut up, and seemed to have been so for a considerable time, for the sign was very blind, and he seemed to have as good eyes as I have, for he saw the sign sooner than I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240035"></xptr>Q. to the Prisoner. What questions would you ask Mr. Floyer with respect to this transaction?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has given an account of every transaction, and he says right.</p>
               <p>Q. What questions would you ask him?</p>
               <p>Pris. Nothing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner never out of your sight, from the time of his coming out of your compting-house to the time of your carrying him before my Lord Mayor?</p>
               <p>Floyer . No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-40-person369">
                  Isaac 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17480224-40-person369" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person369" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am book-keeper to Mr. de Lamerie , and have been twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever give any order to that man, to go to Mr. Foxall's for silver?</p>
               <p>Giles. Never, nor never saw him till he came to offer his service to Mr. de Lamerie, but his character was not approved of. I never spoke to him in my life that I know of, but I am sure I have not spoke to him for seven years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was a little out of business at that time , and there was a gentleman like sort of a man very much like Mr. Giles, with a white coat and brass buttons, gave me this letter at the door of the Crown alehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this man with the white coat and brass buttons?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I cannot tell, I wish I knew where he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you farther to say?</p>
               <p>Parkes. I have no witness, for I did not know what time my trial would come on, and being in this cursed place Newgate, I had not money to send for my friends.</p>
               <p>The Jury acquitted him of the Forgery , and found him guilty of publishing the order, knowing it to be forged.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480224-40-verdict220" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-verdict220" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480224-40-punish221" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-40-punish221" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-40-defend356 t17480224-40-punish221"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
