<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450530-20">
               <interp inst="t17450530-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-20" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-20" type="date" value="17450530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450530-20-off128-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend274 t17450530-20-off128 t17450530-20-verdict131"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450530-20-off128-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend276 t17450530-20-off128 t17450530-20-verdict131"></join>
         
               <p>283, 284. + 
               <persName id="t17450530-20-defend274" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret 
                  Greenaway 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend274" type="surname" value="Greenaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend274" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
              and 
               
                  <persName id="t17450530-20-defend276" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Rush 
                  <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend276" type="surname" value="Rush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend276" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-defend276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of the Parish of <placeName id="t17450530-20-defloc127">St. Bridget otherwise Saint Brides</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-20-defloc127" type="placeName" value="St. Bridget otherwise Saint Brides"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-20-defloc127" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend274 t17450530-20-defloc127"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend276 t17450530-20-defloc127"></join> in London, were indicted for <rs id="t17450530-20-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450530-20-victim278" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Thorn 
                        <interp inst="t17450530-20-victim278" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-20-victim278" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-20-victim278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-off128 t17450530-20-victim278"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him, a hat, value 3s. and 8s. in money
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17450530-20-cd129" type="crimeDate">April 25th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-off128 t17450530-20-cd129"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-20-person279">
                  George 
                  Thorne 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person279" type="surname" value="Thorne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person279" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of April last, about a quarter before ten at night, I was going by the New Market, and enquired for Shoe Lane: I asked those two gentlewomen the way, and they said, they would shew me the way: they took me down a passage, which, as I have been informed since, was <placeName id="t17450530-20-crimeloc130">George Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-20-crimeloc130" type="placeName" value="George Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-20-crimeloc130" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-off128 t17450530-20-crimeloc130"></join>; when they came about the middle of the place, one of them said, that is the way to Shoe Lane, and said, Sir, won't you give us something to buy a dram; I put my hand into my pocket, and I had but a penny, which I gave her; she said, D - n your blood, that is not enough to buy a dram; I said, I had no more half-pence; she said, D - n you, you have got money enough, and we will have it before you go. I laid hold of them, with a design to take them to the watch; I did not think they would rob me. Then a fellow in a white frock very dirty came up with a stick, knocked me up against the wall, and gave me several blows with the stick, I was very ill used by him, and in a very bloody condition. Then Rush came up with a penknife, and said, D - n your blood, if you don't deliver your money, I'll cut the ball of your eye out; then a fellow came up in a blue waistcoat, with a long knife in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Greenaway any thing in her hand?</p>
               <p>Thorne. No, I did not see any thing; then they robbed me of 8 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took the money from you?</p>
               <p>Thorne. Greenaway took the money, for her hand was in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any thing else?</p>
               <p>Thorne. Yes, they took my hat off my head, then Mr. Keys came up, and the man in blue followed him.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that the man in blue came up?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I was robbed before he came up, but he came up immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do?</p>
               <p>Thorne. He only held up a knife, and said, D - n you, what are you doing here? and Greenaway said, it is but seven or eight shillings, and the man in blue said, D - n you, I wish it had been as many pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you robbed when Mr. Keys came up?</p>
               <p>Thorne. Yes, and I told him, one of those women had robbed me; I had hardly spoke<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174505300023"></xptr> the words before the man in blue came up. I had hold of both the women, and should have kept them, if those fellows had not come up.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you hold of both the women?</p>
               <p>Thorne. Yes, I had hold of them both.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you was not robbed till the man in the dirty frock came up?</p>
               <p>Thorne. No, I was not; and when he came up, he said, D - n you, what are you doing of? And Rush said, D - n this country cull, I'll cut the ball of his eye out, if he don't deliver his money.</p>
               <p>Q. How long time was there between the fellow in the dirty frock coming up, and Mr. Keys coming?</p>
               <p>Thorne. Mr. Keys came up presently.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the man in blue come up, when Mr. Keys came?</p>
               <p>Thorne. He was not; but there was not a moment's difference between their coming. When I told Mr. Keys I was robbed, he said, he was very sorry for it: he went away, and said, he would run to the watch, and acquaint them with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Keys run away?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I believe he was frightened, for there was a desperate fellow that came up to him?</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after that?</p>
               <p>Thorne. After the Prisoners had robbed me, they went away. I met Mr. Keys coming from the watch-house, and he said, the watchmen told him, they were vile wicked creatures, and I had better come and look after them in another manner. Mr. Keys told me where he lived, and advised me to come, when I was in a better condition, for I was very bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take the Prisoners?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I took them the 7th or 8th of May.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you take them?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I went into Black Boy Alley, and heard of them; I went to Mr. Berry, who lives in Chick Lane, and told him, I was robbed by two women, and described them, and he ordered me to go to the Pump ale-house in Chick Lane, and Mr. Berry came to me: he went and shewed me several women; I fixed upon the two Prisoners, and told him, those were the two women that robbed me: he said, don't say a word now, for there are a parcel of sad cattle live here, and if you do, there will be murder committed; but about two o'clock in the morning, the constable and the watch secured them, and Mr. Berry sent to me about eight, to let me know they were taken.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know the Prisoners are the women?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I took particular notice of them by the lamps, I saw them very distinctly for a considerable time, and I know their voices, and I know them by their gowns.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the Prisoners before that time?</p>
               <p>Thorne. I never saw them before the 25th of April.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-20-person280">
                  Matthias 
                  Keys 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person280" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person280" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of April, between nine and ten at night, I was going up the Fleet Market, and in George Alley I saw two women and a man, the man was very bloody, and told me, he had been robbed by those two women; one of the women had a penknife in her hand; they were telling some money over, and they took his hat off his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them take it off?</p>
               <p>Keys. Yes, they took it off his head just before I came up to them.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they telling the money?</p>
               <p>Keys. One of them was telling it out of her hand into the other's hand.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money was there?</p>
               <p>Keys. There were about seven or eight shillings. I went to lay hold of one of the women, and up came a fellow behind me in a blue waistcoat, and a tall fellow in a greasy frock, like a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the fellow in the greasy frock there when you came up?</p>
               <p>Keys. No, he was not there then; one of them (he in the blue waistcoat) had a knife in his hand, like a butcher's knife; he swore a great oath, that he would be the death of me, if I assisted the Prosecutor in taking the women. I went into Shoe lane, and called out watch, and said, there was a man robbed. I met the Prosecutor in Shoe Lane; and he told me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174505300024"></xptr> the women were run away; he would have pursued them then, but I said, I will not go after them now, for they have knives, and we shall be in danger of our lives: he asked me my name, I told him I lived at the Cross Keys Tavern in the Strand; and when the Prisoners were taken up, he sent me word of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the women?</p>
               <p>Keys. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the Prisoners, are you sure those are the women?</p>
               <p>Thorn. I know the Prisoners, are the women. That woman in the checked gown [
               <persName id="t17450530-20-person281">
                  Ann 
                  Rush 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person281" type="surname" value="Rush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person281" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] had a knife in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know them before that time?</p>
               <p>Keys. I did not know them before that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the men that came up say any thing to the women?</p>
               <p>Keys. The women said to the men, they had got but seven or eight shillings; and one of the men said, D - n you, I wish it had been as many pounds; and the women said so too; and one of the women threatened to stick me with a knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took the hat off?</p>
               <p>Keys. 
               <persName id="t17450530-20-person282">
                  Ann 
                  Rush 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person282" type="surname" value="Rush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person282" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took it off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-20-person283">
                  John 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person283" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person283" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Chick Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Berry. I deal in horses.</p>
               <p>[
               <persName id="t17450530-20-person284">
                  Henry 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person284" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person284" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was in the bail dock, called out aloud, he is a thief-taker, my Lord.]</p>
               <p>Berry. I have detected some of them in Black Boy Alley, because they were a pest to Gentlemen who go that way; but I am a great dealer in horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who that is that says you are a thief-taker?</p>
               <p>Berry. I believe that is Gentleman Harry, he is as great a rogue as any in the world. I have known him these twenty years; I knew him when he was postilion to Mr. Hide.</p>
               <p>[Sims cried out again, he is a very great thief-taker, my Lord.]</p>
               <p>Berry. He is a very great rogue, 'tis a pity he had not his deserts as some others have had. The Prosecutor came to me, and informed me, he was robbed such a time by two women; gave me a description of them, and told me they used Black Boy Alley and Chick Lane. There is a hill near that place, where twenty or thirty will fit together, may sometimes forty or fifty of them will fit together in the day time, smoaking their pipes and drinking. I took him to a place, where there were I believe four or five of them together; he fixed upon the Prisoners, and said, they were the two women that robbed him: I said, if we were to attempt to take them then it would be dangerous, and we might run the risque of our lives (for they are a pesterous sort of people, there is a great resort of them there, and they grow very troublesom; indeed there are more women than men now, because the men have been pestered very much lately) so I did not think it safe to take them then, and we took them about two o'clock in the morning in Chick Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-20-person285">
                  Philip 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17450530-20-person285" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person285" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman in Shoe Lane. On the 9th of May, between one and two in the morning, one Lloyd laid hold of the Prisoners in Chick Lane. I know these are the women that were taken then.</p>
               <p>Greenaway. I know none of these persons but Mr. Price the watchman. I know nothing of it; I never do concern myself with any of the men kind whatsoever.</p>
               <p>Rush. I was going that night into Field Lane, two men met me, and would have dragged me about; I called Mr. Price to come to my assistance, but he did not come; I am innocent of the robbery they charge me with. <rs id="t17450530-20-verdict131" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-verdict131" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17450530-20-punish132" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-20-punish132" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend274 t17450530-20-punish132"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-20-defend276 t17450530-20-punish132"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
