<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-33">
               <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-33-off153-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-33-defend296 t17420428-33-off153 t17420428-33-verdict155"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-33-off154-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-33-defend296 t17420428-33-off154 t17420428-33-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>38. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-defend296" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Rhodes 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33-defend296" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-defend296" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-defend296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he, after the 24th of June, 1736, viz. <rs id="t17420428-33-cd152" type="crimeDate">Sept. 3 d</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-33-off153 t17420428-33-cd152"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-33-off154 t17420428-33-cd152"></join>. made and <rs id="t17420428-33-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forg'd, and did willingly act and assist in forging and making a certain Paper, partly printed, and partly written, sign'd with the Name of 
                     <persName id="t17420428-33-person297">
                        John 
                        Thompson 
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person297" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-33-person297" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-33-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , purporting to be the last Will and Testament of the said Thompson
            </rs>, which said Paper-writing is contain'd in the Words and Figures following, viz</p>
               <p>In the Name of God, Amen. I 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person298">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person298" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the Parish of St. Giles's in the Fields, in the County of Middlesex, Mariner, being in bodily Health, and of sound and disposing Mind and Memory, considering the Perils and Danger of the Seas, and Uncertainties of this transitory Life, do, for avoiding Controversies after my Decease, publish and declare this my last Will and Testament. in Manner and Form following. First, I recommend my Soul to God that gave it, and my Body to the Earth or Sea as it shall please God. As for, and concerning all my worldly Goods, I dispose them as followeth. I give to my Friend, 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person299">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person299" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person299" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , all my Wages, Sum and Sums of Money, Goods, Chattels and Tenements whatsoever as shall be any Way due, owing and belonging to me at the Time of my Decease: I give, devise and bequeath the same to my Friend 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person300">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person300" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person300" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             aforesaid, and I do hereby nominate and appoint him to be my lawful Executer, revoking all former Wills. And I do ordain and ratifie these Presents to be my only last Will and Testament, in Witness whereof I have set my Hand and Seal, the 6th of September 1736, in the 10th Year of his Majesty's Reign.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person301">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person301" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Sign'd, Seal'd, publish'd and declar'd in the Presence of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person302">
                  Mary 
                  Sempson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person302" type="surname" value="Sempson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person302" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person303">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person303" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person303" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person304">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person304" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person304" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>He was farther Charg'd for <rs id="t17420428-33-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               uttering and publishing the same, knowing it to be false forg'd and counterfeit
            </rs>.</p>
         
               <p>Note, The great Number of Prisoners tried this SESSIONS, and the Length of their respective CASES, oblig'd the COURT to sit a Day longer than in the last: We have therefore been under a Necessity of dividing this into TWO PARTS, without which it would have been impossible to have given the Public a fair and impartial Account of the Proceedings. The Second PART, which will, among several Others, contain the Remainder of the Trial of 
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person305">
                     Robert 
                     Rhodes 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33-person305" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person305" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ; Pryor Green, and 
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person306">
                     John 
                     Bolton 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33-person306" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , a Custom-House Officer for Murder, will be publish'd on FRIDAY next.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17420428-33">
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS AT THE Sessions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, FOR THE CITY of LONDON, AND County of MIDDLESEX, ON</p>
                  <p>WEDNESDAY the 28th, THURSDAY the 29th, FRIDAY the 30th, of APRIL, SATURDAY the 1st, and MONDAY the 3d, of MAY.</p>
                  <p>In the 15th Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER IV. Part II. for the YEAR 1742.</p>
                  <p>BEING THE Fourth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY OF THE</p>
                  <p>Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person307">
                     Robert 
                     Godschall 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-33-person307" type="surname" value="Godschall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-33-person307" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-33-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed and Sold by T. PAYNE, in Bishopsgate-Street, near the South-Sea-House. M,DCC.XLII.</p>
                  <p>Where may be had any of the former Numbers in this Mayoralty.</p>
                  <p>(Price SIX-PENCE.)</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS AT THE</p>
                  <p>Sessions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, For the CITY of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>THE Councel for the King having opened the Indictment, proceeded to take Notice that this Prosecution was founded on a late Act of Parliament, which was made to punish those who were guilty of a Crime of the first Magnitude, destructive to Trade, and all that Security which every one ought to have for their Estate and Property: That the Pers on mention'd in the Indictment by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person308">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person308" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was originally a Taylor, but that in March 1737, he enter'd on board his Majesty's Ship the Flamborough: that being indebted to one Carter in the Sum of 14 l. and being going on board the Ship, he gave a Letter of Attorney to this Carter, to receive his Wages: that he likewise made a Will, wherein he appointed Carter his general Legatee, and that he afterwards died on board this Vessel in August thirty-nine. Carter hearing of Thompson's Decease, applyed to Doctor's Commons to prove the Will that was left with him: that upon his coming there, he found that another Will had been proved, which was the Will in Question, and wherein Thompson was said to have appointed the Prisoner his Legatee, who must (in order to have been entitled to receive a Probate) have taken an Oath that that was the true Will of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person309">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person309" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That, as soon as Carter found this Fraud had been committed, he made what search he could to find out this Rhodes, and at last received Information of him at Mitchell's Coffee-House near the Navy-Office, and he was afterwards taken up for this Fact. It was farther observed, that it was a great Misfortune attending this Sort of Men, that they are not only subject to greater Casualties than other People, but also leave their Effects under great Uncertainty; that upon the Probate of a Will's being produc'd, the proper Officer of the Navy is bound to deliver a Ticket for the Wages of the Sailor to that Person who appears to be entitled to it, and that it has been too much a Practice lately for Persons to set up Wills which never were real, to get into their Custody, that Pay which these honest Men have earn'd with the Sacrifice of their Lives, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Counc. We shall call Mr. Roseindale to prove the Death of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person310">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person310" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Roseindale. I am chief Clerk of the Ticket Office in the Navy-Office; this in my Hand is the Muster Book of the Ship Flamborough. The Captains of the Men of War are enjoin'd as convenient Opportunity offers, to send their Muster-Books and Tickets as frequently as possible to the Navy-Office, and we endorse and enter them into such a Book as this, and they are assign'd once or twice in a Month to the Executors.</p>
               <p>Counc. Have you not there the Names of all the Persons on board the Fleet?</p>
               <p>Mr. Roseindale. Yes, all that are living, dead and run away.</p>
               <p>Counc. If any body dies on board, does not that Book take Notice of it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Roseindale. Yes, and it appears by this, that 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person311">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person311" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person311" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , an able Seaman, died the 22d of August, 1739, at Turtle Bay, on board the Flamborough, and the Ticket was made out for his Wages, and sent to the Navy-Office.</p>
               <p>Jury. When was the Ticket made out?</p>
               <p>Mr. Roseindale. I presume, presently after the Man died.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280023"></xptr>It was here urg'd by the Council for the Prisoner, that this was improper Evidence to be laid before the Jury, and not sufficient to prove Thompson's Death; that a Fact of this Kind should be prov'd by Persons who were on board the Ship, for that the Captain or other Officers of the Ship might through Mistake or Design, return the Man dead when he was really alive.</p>
               <p>In answer to which, the Councel for the Prosecution said they were surpriz'd to hear this Objection made; for that according to the known Course of the Navy, the Names of all the Sailors that die, are regularly enter'd in a Book for that Purpose; that this Book was given in Evidence in December last in the Case of Fitzgerald and Lee; the Evidence of Perry's Death being only a Book of this Kind. That the Person who dies is always enter'd in this Book, and when it comes over here, the Consequence of that is, there is a Ticket made out for the Wages, and according to the known Course of the Navy, deliver'd to the Person who brings the Probate: That as the Prisoner stood indicted for publishing a Will, it was an Acknowledgment by himself that the Party was dead, unless he could go and swear he was dead, and prove his Will, when he is alive: That the Prisoner had actually receiv'd the Pay of that Man, and therefore he thought him dead or certainly he would not have gone to Doctor's-Commons to prove the Will; that if this was not Evidence to prove his Death, no Seaman could be secure of one Shilling which he was venturing his Life for every Hour he lives, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>By the Prisoner's Councel in Reply it was offer'd that there were a great many People on board the Ship who best knew whether the Man was alive or no, and that the Proof ought to be fuller in this than in other Cases; that notwithstanding the Prisoner might have prov'd this Will, that was not sufficient; for that a great many People had prov'd Wills, when it has appear'd that the Person was alive.</p>
               <p>It was farther observed by the Councel on the same side that there was no such Thing as a Will while a Man was alive, for that he might controul it every Moment: That no Person appear'd here, upon the true Survey of the Ship to prove this Man dead, and therefore 'twas hop'd that what had been offer'd against the Prisoner, was not sufficient Evidence of the Death of a Man in a Case of Felony.</p>
               <p>Upon the Whole, the Court were of Opinion that the Councel for the Prosecution should go on with their Evidence.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you make out any Ticket for Wages due to 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person312">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person312" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Roseindale. No Sir, it was made out by the Captain of the Ship. I deliver'd it out of the Office to 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person313">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person313" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person313" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Executor, a Cheese-monger, at the Corner of King-street, St. Giles's I can't say I know his Face, by reason I see so many People coming backwards and forwards.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. When did you deliver out the Ticket?</p>
               <p>Roseindale. This is the Ticket; I deliver'd it to Mr. Rhodes, Sept. 3, 1741.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person314">
                  John 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person314" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This in my Hand is an original Will.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who deliver'd it to you?</p>
               <p>Goodwin. I had it in my own Custody, as being Clerk to the Register in the Prerogative Office.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person315">
                  Joseph 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person315" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person315" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Will was brought to me by the Prisoner, in order to his proving it.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go with him to prove it?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I wrote the Oath on the back of it, and went with him before Doctor Chapman to get him Sworn to it, and he did Swear to it. Here is a Copy of the Oath on the back of it; I dated it the 3d, of September 1741. I have seen the Prisoner before this, and since, for he has been to me, with People upon other Occasions.</p>
               <p>Dr. 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person316">
                  Robert 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person316" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person316" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is my Name on the back of the Will.</p>
               <p>Counc. What was the Oath that was administer'd to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dr. 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person317">
                  Robert 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person317" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person317" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Oath he swore was, that he believ'd this to be the last Will and Testament of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person318">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person318" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deceas'd; that he was nam'd Executor, and that he would give a just Account of his Executorship when call'd to it by Law. This is only a short Jurat on the Back of the Will. He swore that this was the Will of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person319">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person319" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person319" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deceased, and the rest was a Promissary Oath that he would duly pay the Debts and Legacies; and here is likewise wrote on the Back, that the Effects don't amount to 20 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hughes. They bring the Will first, and the Jurat is wrote on the Back; then we carry them to a Doctor to be sworn, and this Will was prov'd according to the Prisoner's Directions.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hughes. Yes, I went with him myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280024"></xptr>[The Will was read.]</p>
               <p>Counc. We shall now call 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person320">
                  Samuel 
                  Boyden 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person320" type="surname" value="Boyden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person320" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to prove that this is not the Will of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person321">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person321" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person321" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he was not a Mariner, nor of this Parish at the Time the Will bears Date; - Are you acquainted with the Hand-writing of 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person322">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person322" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person322" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Boyden. I was so far acquainted with it, that I took particular Notice of his signing the Will to Mr. Carter, and to the best of my Knowledge this is not his Hand.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you never see him write but that Time that he sign'd the other Will which you witness'd?</p>
               <p>Boyden. I have seen his Writing, but never was by when he wrote: except when he made that Will which I witness'd. - I can't remember when that was.</p>
               <p>Counc. I ask you whether in September 1736, he was a Mariner?</p>
               <p>Boyden. No, he was not, he was a Taylor, and liv'd in the Parish of St. Mary le Strand.</p>
               <p>Counc. I ask you whether he did, or did not live in St. Giles's Parish.</p>
               <p>Boyden. Not to my Knowledge; I never heard that he liv'd there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live when you saw him make the Will?</p>
               <p>Boyden. In White hart yard, in the Parish of St. Mary le Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live when that Will was made in 1736.</p>
               <p>Boyden I don't know; he came out of Yorkshire as near as I can judge, about two Years before he went to Sea, and I sign'd that Will for Mr. Carter the Night before Thompson went on board.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. What Day did you sign the Will for Carter?</p>
               <p>Boyden. It is impossible for me to remember that; I know the Time; but I can't remember the Day or the Year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person323">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person323" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person323" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person324">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person324" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person324" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in his Life Time. I can't say I ever saw his Writing before he sign'd a Will to which I was a Witness; - the Will that he made to Carter.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Time was that?</p>
               <p>Gibson. I believe in 37 or thereabouts; it was a little after the Queen's Mourning; - he was a Servant to me then as a Taylor.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was he a Seaman at that Time?</p>
               <p>Gibson. No, nor never had been a Seaman before.</p>
               <p>Counc. Look at that Hand-writing there.</p>
               <p>Gibson. It is nothing like his Hand. I saw both the Wills before Mr. Deveil, and that which I witness'd I can swear was his Hand-writing, but this is not.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q Did you ever see him write since that?</p>
               <p>Gibson. Yes, once at my own House; it was his Name to a Note of Hand: This Will is dated March 7, 1737. this is my Hand, and I saw Thompson write that at the Time it bears Date.</p>
               <p>Pris. How long after that Will was made did you see him write his Name to the Note.</p>
               <p>Gibson. The same Day.</p>
               <p>Boyden. This Will is Mr. Thompson's Hand; I sat by him when he wrote it, and look'd particularly at it; I am a subscribing Witness to it, and it is not like the pretended Will at all.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carter being call'd by the Councel for the Prosecution, it was urg'd on Behalf of the Prisoner that he was a Person interested, and therefore could not be admitted to give Evidence; that this was the same as a Case of a Note of Hand, where the Party who is bound by that Note comes to prove it forg'd, to secure his own Interest.</p>
               <p>In answer to which, it was said, that the Consequence of this Suit could in no shape affect Carter, the other Will being already prov'd in the proper Court, and supposing the Will which the Prisoner stood indicted for should really prove a good one, yet Carter's Will being subsequent would destroy it. The Prisoner's Will bearing Date in the Year 36, and Carter's 37, making it indisputable: That this was not a private Prosecution, but a Prosecution in the Name of the Crown for the Benefit of the Public, that the Prisoner might be punish'd according to Law, therefore exactly agreeable to a common Case of Felony.</p>
               <p>It was observed by the Prisoner's Councel in Reply that this was no Answer to the Objection; that Carter (who had a Will) was called to prove which was the real one, the 1st, or the last; that he was call'd to prove the Prisoner's Will false, and certainly he must have Benefit by that, for that then his own would stand without doubt. The Court being of Opinion that Carter was not a competent Witness, the Councel proceeded to call 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person325">
                  Sarah 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person325" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person325" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Russel. Yes Sir; I purchas'd this Ticket<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280025"></xptr> of him, I think it was the fourth of September last: it was the very Day after the Ticket was delivered out of the Office.</p>
               <p>Counc. Had you any Meeting with the Prisoner in relation to this Affair</p>
               <p>Russel. He us'd to call very often at my House and drink a Glass of Wine.</p>
               <p>Counc. What did he say upon this Occasion?</p>
               <p>Russel. He shew'd me the Ticket, and ask'd me to buy it: I said I would if it was a good one: I sent over to the Office and had it cast with the Books, and paid him the Money for it.</p>
               <p>Counc Did you ever see him with Carter?</p>
               <p>Russel. Yes, I believe I have: I heard him say to Carter, if he could prove his Will to be good, he would make any just Agreement with him, for they both said that Thompson ow'd them Money.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. How long have you known me?</p>

               <p>Russel. I can't remember; I don't take such Notice of Strangers, but I believe I may say a Year.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. What do you take me to be?</p>
               <p>Russel. A Man; I suppose.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. Do you suppose me to be a good Man.</p>
               <p>Russel. I don't suppose any Thing at all ar.</p>
               <p>Pris Ask her whether she never heard of Sailors making three or four Wills to defraud different People of Sums of Money?</p>
               <p>Russel I have heard People talk so to be sure, but I never had any Proof of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goodwin. Sometimes I have 2 or 3 Wills from different Persons, and when we meet with any, we stop them.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. Did you never hear of a third Will of Thompson coming to your Office?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goodwin. No, I never heard of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person326">
                  Barnabas 
                  Honeychurch 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person326" type="surname" value="Honeychurch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person326" type="given" value="Barnabas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person327">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person327" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person327" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I was very well acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever see him write?</p>
               <p>Honeychurch. No Sir, I was acquainted with him within a few Days after he came to London, which I take to be about 7 or 8 Years ago: He was a Taylor, and liv'd at the Swan and Apple-Tree in White-Hart-Yard, in the Parish of St. Mary le Strand.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever know him live in St. Giles's?</p>
               <p>Honeychurch. No, never. I remember when he first went to Sea; it was about four Years ago last January, in the Year thirty-seven. He never was a Seaman before that, by what I have heard him say, and he work'd with me within a Day or two before he went to Sea. He has apply'd to several People who had been at Sea to inform him about the Business, for he was going Taylor to Captain Pierce of the Flamborough. He din'd with me almost every Day in the Week, and frequently supp'd with me except his Business call'd him another Way.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Do not these Parishes join?</p>
               <p>Honeychurch. No, St. Martin's Parish crosses them. St. Giles's is above Long-Acre.</p>
               <p>Here the Ticket was read, - '' 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person328">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person328" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person328" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , '' able Seaman, aged ( Blank) Years, died on '' board the Flamborough Man of War, Aug. 22, '' 1739, at which Time he was discharged by '' Reason of Death.''</p>
               <p>19 l. 18 s. 1 d.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>If your Lordship pleases, I can call one Man who was in the House when the Will was made to me.</p>
               <p>Call 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person329">
                  Robert 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person329" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person329" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Jones.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you know Mr. Thompson that is dead?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, his Name was 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person330">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person330" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person330" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I knew him no farther than just happening into the Alehouse where the Will was making, and that was in Church-Court, by St. Martin's-Church, and I think it was at the Chequer Alehouse. I went in to drink a Pint of Beer, and there was Mr. Rhodes. I knew him when he liv'd at the Seven-Dials some Years ago, and for that Reason he spoke to me. At that Time the Will was making, it was fill'd up by one 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person331">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person331" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person331" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I did not see it witness'd.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was there any Thing desired by Thompson or Rhodes at that Time?</p>
               <p>Jones. Nine Pounds Mr. Rhodes disbursted at that Time to Thompson, as I understood, it was to sit him out, or something in that Way, and Thompson was to make a Will to him, and he was to receive his Pay; according to my Understanding it was so.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. How long ago was this?</p>
               <p>Jones. I take it to be about Michaelmas Time in 36 or 37; I was there present, and paid my Reckoning, and went away and left them together</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280026"></xptr>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Jones. At the Back of St. Clement's; sometimes I work in Coals, and sometimes in the Plumbers Way as a Porter; I have work'd at Mr. Thomas's Wharf at Dowgate, and for Mr. Wardell and Colwell the Bottom of Dowgate hill, and sometimes I have been in a Branch of Leather-dressing.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who did you live with last in the Plumber's Way?</p>
               <p>Jones. Mr. Deval in Piccadilly; he has one Shop in Holborn, and another in Piccadilly: I have not been at Work that Way since three Months before Christmas.</p>
               <p>Counc. Have you never work'd in the Plumber's Way since then?</p>
               <p>Jones. I can't be particular to a Day: I have not work'd with any body since, as a Plumber, but I have been employ'd by Mr. Jones in Clement's-lane, who is what we call a Leather-dresser. I have work'd for him 2 Months since Christmas.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long did you work for him?</p>
               <p>Jones. Ten Weeks or two Months perhaps, as near as I can remember: the last time I work'd for him was about 2 Months ago: I came from Mr. Deval's, and went to Mr. Jones's, and work'd for him 3 Months before Christmas: I can't tell when I work'd last for Mr. Jones, for I had no Occasion to take Notice of the Day.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you work with him all the Time, from the Time that you first began with him?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, till just now.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long had you been acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person332">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person332" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Only the Time of the Will's making: I don't know that I have seen him before or since.</p>
               <p>Counc. How do you know it was 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person333">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person333" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person333" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Because the Man that fill'd up the Will call'd him so.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was this in the Year 38.</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I take it to be about 36 or 37: I can't justly say to an Hour, a Day, or a Month, because I only chanc'd (to go) in for a Pint of Beer, and I sat down in the Company.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you read the Will?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person334">
                  Jones 
                  No 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person334" type="surname" value="No"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person334" type="given" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am not Scholar enough I believe to read a Will.</p>
               <p>Counc Who told you it was a Will?</p>
               <p>Jones. I understood according to my Understanding, that the Will was made to Mr. Rhodes on disbursting so much Money.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who told you this was Thompson's Will?</p>
               <p>Jones. Mr. Thompson and 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person335">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person335" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person335" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were together, and I saw him writing on the Paper: - I staid there half an Hour or better. I saw nobody else there but Thompson, Williams and Mr. Rhodes</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you see the Will sign'd?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I only saw 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person336">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person336" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person336" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (as Mr. Thompson call'd him) writing on the Paper: I saw nothing at all sign'd. I can read a little, but I did not read the Will, for I had no Concerns to ask any Questions.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person337">
                  Mary 
                  Sempson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person337" type="surname" value="Sempson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person337" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person337" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, nor I did not know 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person338">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person338" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person338" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , only hearing Thompson call him by his Name.</p>
               <p>Counc. What sort of a Man was this Thompson?</p>
               <p>Jones. He was a long visag'd Man, not so thick as I am: I take him to be a blackish swarthy Man: I can't say whether he wore his own Hair or a Wig, because I had no Occasion to take Notice.</p>
               <p>Counc. How do you know this was 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person339">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person339" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person339" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Williams call'd him by his Name.</p>
               <p>Counc. About what Age did Thompson seem to be?</p>
               <p>Jones. About thirty: I can't guess at a Man's Age so long ago.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he wear a Wig or his own Hair?</p>
               <p>Jones I can't tell.</p>
               <p>A Witness. This Will was brought to me by Rhodes. He likewise brought another Will of Thompson's which I have in my Pocket; I think it is made to 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person340">
                  Mary 
                  Vaughan 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person340" type="surname" value="Vaughan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person340" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Thompson's Will being prov'd, a Citation was taken out against Rhodes to bring it in, and shew Cause why a Will of a later Date should not be prov'd. Sometime after that, the Prisoner said he had found out a Will of a later Date than the other. I look'd upon it, and told him, he must bring his Witnesses if he intended to support it. He said, he knew but little of that Affair; but that one Mrs. Glass could inform me farther of it. He left me the Will and the Letter in which it was inclos'd, and I went to Mrs. Glass, who told me, she had received that Will enclos'd in the Letter from Mrs. Vaughan at Portsmouth, and desir'd every Thing might be done that was necessary to support it; but Rhodes's Wil l never was prov'd by Testes, therefore it was revok'd, and the other granted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person341">
                  James 
                  Cockran 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person341" type="surname" value="Cockran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person341" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I have known Rhodes between 7 and 8 Months coming and going; I never saw any thing by the Gentleman but Honesty. He has gone in my Parish under the Character of an honest Man, and it is more than I know if he would do such a Thing as this. I use the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280027"></xptr> Holland Trade, and have sold him Stockings and Linnen, and have trusted him for a Month together. He is a Cheesemonger, and lives at t'other End of the Town. I have liv'd in St. Katherine's Parish these 9 Years, and he us'd to call upon me at my Chandler's Shop, and paid for what he wanted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person342">
                  Peter 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person342" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person342" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 8 or 9 Months: I keep a Barber's Shop on Tower-hill: He always paid me 6 d. a Time, and I never saw nothing but what was honest and just by him.</p>
               <p>- Harper. I have known him these 2 or 3 Years: He has been gone out of the Neighbourhood 4 or 5 Months, and then he bore a good Character: He used me handsome, and paid me for what he had: I liv'd over-against him.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. Have you any Suspicion that I would do so soul a Crime as I am accused of?</p>
               <p>Harper. The Man behav'd very well.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Character did other People give him?</p>
               <p>Harper. I have heard People whispering about that he was concern'd in these Wills 5 or 6 Months ago; the first Occasion of it was some Papers from the Commons being hung up at his Door before Christmas.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was that on Account of this Will or another?</p>
               <p>Harper. I never heard of any Will but this: He was a Cheesemonger in King-street, by the Seven Dials.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person343">
                  John 
                  Hastings 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person343" type="surname" value="Hastings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person343" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about ten or a dozen Years. He liv'd in Little St. Andrew-street, near the Seven-Dials, and from thence he mov'd to the Corner of Earl-Street, in King-street. When he liv'd in St. Andrew-Street, he behav'd very well, and was respected by the Neighbourhood, and was a very industrious Man; but when he mov'd into Earl-street, he became a Headborough, which a great many People believe was of no Service to him, for he has been accus'd of a great many foolish Things not to his Credit, with regard to Thief-taking, which is not a creditable Thing for a House-keeper. By following these Practices, his Business was reduc'd to such a low Ebb, that at last I believe he was driven to his Shifts; and there was something stuck up against one of his Window-Shutters, but what it was I can't tell. His Character is really a very bad one.</p>
               <p>Pris. Did you ever hear that I wrong'd any one in the Neighbourhood of a Farthing?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I know nothing no farther than there was something stuck upon his Window-Shutter about a Will, something above 3 Months ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person344">
                  Henry 
                  Brows 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person344" type="surname" value="Brows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person344" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 2 or 3 Years; I liv'd directly over-against him when he liv'd in King street. When he came into the Neighbourhood, we took him to be a very honest Man which was about two Years ago; but since that, he was a Headborough, and hang'd two Men, which got him a bad Character. His general Character at first was very Honest; but by being guilty of these Facts, we could not think any other Thing but what was bad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person345">
                  Wm 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person345" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person345" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner liv'd over against me, and his Character at first was very good, but lately very indifferent; for there was something stuck up against his House, and there was a Talk of his forging a Will.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person346">
                  Thomas 
                  Trout 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person346" type="surname" value="Trout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person346" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 2 or 3 Months, and his general Character is very bad, in forging Notes and Wills: it came once to my turn to arrest him, about 3 or 4 Months ago: I never heard a bad Character of him before that Time for I never knew him.</p>
               <p>Pris. Ask him how I behav'd when he arrested me?</p>
               <p>Trout. I took his Word, and one Mr. Young paid me the Debt and Costs in 2 Days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person347">
                  Walter 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person347" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person347" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner above three Months, and by an intimate Acquaintance of his, one 
               <persName id="t17420428-33-person348">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person348" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person348" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Leather-dresser, I have heard a very bad Character of him.</p>
               <p>Pris. I arrested this Man for a Note of Hand for 26 l. and he has mov'd the Cause out of the Marshalsea into the Court of King's-Bench or Common Pleas.</p>
               <p>Burton. It was a forg'd Note, and therefore I would not pay it: I never gave a Note of Hand in my Life.</p>
               <p>- Spradley. I never saw the Prisoner till the 30th of Sept. last, but since I have had the Occasion to know him, he has borne a very bad Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-33-person349">
                  Francis 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17420428-33-person349" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person349" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him a pretty while, and dealt with him, and he then bore a good Character, but since I have heard an indifferent one: he bore a good Character in the Neighbourhood, and when I was Overseer he paid me my Taxes last Year.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Character has he borne since?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280028"></xptr>Jordan. I won't go by Hearsay; I will swear nothing but what I can prove.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-33-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17420428-33-punish156" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-33-punish156" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-33-defend296 t17420428-33-punish156"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
