<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-44">
               <interp inst="t17400416-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-44" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-44" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-44-off252-c288" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-44-defend377 t17400416-44-off252 t17400416-44-verdict256"></join>
         
               <p>237. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-44-defend377" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Cooth 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-44-defend377" type="surname" value="Cooth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-defend377" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-defend377" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-44-off252" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-off252" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-off252" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Gold Watch, value 10 £. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-44-victim379" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Millar 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-44-victim379" type="surname" value="Millar"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-44-victim379" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-44-victim379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-44-off252 t17400416-44-victim379"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-44-cd253" type="crimeDate">March 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-44-off252 t17400416-44-cd253"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Millar. On the 21st of March, about 10 o'clock at Night, I was laid hold of by a Girl in <placeName id="t17400416-44-crimeloc254">Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-44-crimeloc254" type="placeName" value="Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-44-crimeloc254" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-44-off252 t17400416-44-crimeloc254"></join>, who desired me to give her a Pint of Wine: I refused; and while I was talking to the Girl who had stopped me, and held me by the Sleeve, the Prisoner came up; and getting between the first Woman and me, she (the Prisoner) put her Hand into my left Breeches Pocket, and pulled out a Specimen of Minerals, which she dropped in the Street. I was sensible of it, and pulled her Hand immediately out of my Pocket, and told her to take Care of herself, for if she persisted in such Actions, she would come to the Gallows: and for Fear my Watch should be taken, I kept my Right-hand upon my Fob. The other Girl, who then stood on my left Side, picked my Handkerchief out of my Pocket, and told the Prisoner, she had got it. Hearing this, I took my Hand from my Fob, to feel whether my Handkerchief was gone, and, in the mean Time, the Prisoner picked my Watch out of my Fob. Upon this I seized<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160043"></xptr>them both, by the Handkerchiefs which they had about their Necks: and the Woman who took my Handkerchief slipped away, and left her Handkerchief in my Hand, but the Prisoner, who took my Watch, I secured. I felt in my Fob, the Moment the other Girl fled, and my Watch was gone. I missed it in half a Minute after I had taken my Hand from my Fob. When I laid hold of the Prisoner, she would have got away, and her Handkerchief came off in my Hand, with a Piece of her Shift: but I held her, and called Watch! She then desired me to go with her up the Alley, to see for her Accomplice, who (she said) had got the Watch: and I went with her to a House in the Alley, but the Woman of the House would give us no Information, either of the Woman or the Watch. The Prisoner I am sure took my Watch, and I apprehend handed it to the other who got away: and the Reason of my certainty is, because the other Woman was at a Distance from me, and behind me, and the Prisoner was the sole Person that was nigh me, and her Hands were about me. The other Person, who took my Handkerchief, was towards my left side, behind the Prisoner, who stood right before me, and her Hands were constantly about my Pockets. When I had got the Prisoner to the House where she carried me to look for her Accomplice, she desired me to search her, but I knew it was to no Purpose, because I believed she had handed it away to the other Woman behind her: but I can't say I saw her hand it away. It was a Gold Watch, and worth upwards of 10 £.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I in company with the other Woman?</p>
               <p>Mr Millar. She was not standing with her at first. The other Woman was standing by her self, at the End of a court, and gave me a Pull by the Sleeve as I passed by; and after she had stopped me, the Prisoner came up immediately. She was carried that Night to the Gatehouse, and the next Morning before a Magistrate, who committed her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As I was coming down the court, I met this Gentleman, running after a Woman; he snatched hold of my Handkerchief and said I belonged to the Woman who had got his Gloves and Handkerchief. I told him I did not; and desired him not to take my Handkerchief, but go with me to the House, where I saw the other Woman go in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-44-person380">
                  Dorothy 
                  Churchman 
               <interp inst="t17400416-44-person380" type="surname" value="Churchman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-person380" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-person380" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had known the Prisoner about a Year, and deposed that she was <rs id="t17400416-44-deflabel255" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Truss-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-44-defend377 t17400416-44-deflabel255"></join>, and lodged with her in Fleet-Lane, that she always kept good Hours, and did not go out to pick Gentlemen up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-44-person381">
                  Mary 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17400416-44-person381" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-person381" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave an Account, that Mr Millar came with the Prisoner to her House in the court, and said he had lost his Watch; and after he had secured the Prisoner, he took a candle, and search'd about the court, and under a Stone which the Paviours had taken up to mend the Pipes: and that he did not say the Prisoner had it, but that they had got it among them; and that it was a fault of his, <rs id="t17400416-44-verdict256" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-44-verdict256" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
