<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-47">
               <interp inst="t17430907-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-47" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-47" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-47-off242-c367" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-defend452 t17430907-47-off242 t17430907-47-verdict244"></join>
         
               <p>422. + 
               <persName id="t17430907-47-defend452" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Emyns 
               <interp inst="t17430907-47-defend452" type="surname" value="Emyns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-defend452" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-defend452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17430907-47-defloc241">Harefield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-47-defloc241" type="placeName" value="Harefield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-47-defloc241" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-defend452 t17430907-47-defloc241"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17430907-47-off242" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-off242" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-off242" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               driving against 
                     <persName id="t17430907-47-victim453" type="victimName">
                        Lucy, the Wife of 
                           <persName id="t17430907-47-person454" type="victimName">
                              Joseph 
                              Cook 
                           <interp inst="t17430907-47-person454" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17430907-47-person454" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17430907-47-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-off242 t17430907-47-person454"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-victim453" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-victim453" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-victim453" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-off242 t17430907-47-victim453"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , on the Highway; (she being in a Cart drawn by one Horse) with a Cart drawn by four Horses, laden with Chalk; by which the Cart, in which the said Lucy was, overturned; whereby the said Lucy was thrown out of the Cart; and that he, the said 
                     <persName id="t17430907-47-person455">
                        John 
                        Emyns 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person455" type="surname" value="Emyns"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-person455" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did drive the Wheel of the said Cart over the left Leg of the said Lucy, by which he gave her a mortal Wound and Bruise, on the <rs id="t17430907-47-cd243" type="crimeDate">8th Day of June</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-off242 t17430907-47-cd243"></join>; of which she languished, in the Parish of Uxbridge, till the 11th Day of June, and then died; and that he, the said 
                     <persName id="t17430907-47-person456">
                        John 
                        Emyns 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person456" type="surname" value="Emyns"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-person456" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-47-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said Lucy did kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-47-person457">
                  Joseph 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17430907-47-person457" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person457" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of June, I was going along the Road to Harefield, in a Cart, with one Horse, with Mrs Horabin, Mrs Hildersry, and my Wife; I was going down the Hill, and saw three Carts coming up; the Road was there fifteen Foot and an half wide; I got off the Cart, and drawed out of the Track which I was in, three or four Inches, and stood up against the Bank; so that I think the Prisoner might have gone by without coming upon the Cart we were in; and if he had gone on the other Side of the Lane, there would have been Room enough for a Man to have stood between the Wheels of the two Cart; the Road was not at all dangerous; it was a dry Time; I never knew an Instance of any Cart being overturned there: About five Yards before he came up, to me, I said, honest Friend, or Fellow, he so good as to bold to; with that he took hold of his Horse's Head - he was on the right Side, where he ought to be; he took hold of his Thill Horse Halter, but never spoke a Word; when he came nearer to me, I said or for God's Sake, hold off; but instead of that, he hold nearer to me, and pushed the batt End of his Whip against the Horse's Head, and drove him towards me; and the Wheel went out of the Track, and came against my Wheel; I cried out, for God Sake, stop your Horses - I thought he was very sober, it was about eleven o'Clock in the Morning - the Woman that were in my Cart were sitting in Chairs, and I thought they were very safe then, for the Wheel was locked in; but the Wheel of his Cart drew mine up upon the Bank - one of which was upon the Ground, and the other up in the Air; and then the Women fell out before his Wheel; I had hold of my Horse all that Time - the Women slid out at the Back-Side of the Cart, and so fell before his Wheel - not above a Yard before the Wheel.</p>
               <p>Court. I ask you, whether or no he ever stopp'd at all?</p>
               <p>Cook. He never stopped at all; - his Cart went over my Wheel, and so over the Women.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw the Wheel so close to your Cart, did you say any thing to him?</p>
               <p>Cook. I called to him, but there was not Time for an Answer. - I saw the Wheel go over that young Lady, Mrs Horabin, and I thought she could not have lived; I turned her Coats on one Side, and the fleshy Part of her Leg was tore in such a manner that it was surprizing.</p>
               <p>Court. Do you think that after the Women were upon the Ground he could have stopped his Cart?</p>
               <p>Cook. I do not think he could, time enough to prevent the Mischief - my Wife died<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070028"></xptr> of the Wounds, to my very great Loss: The prosecuting of this Man will be no Recompence to me, but I think I ought to do it in Justice to my Country; as soon as my Wife was dead, I went to enquire after the Prisoner, and he was gone off; the Monday after my Wife was buried, I offered five Guineas to have him taken, and desired a Person to take my Horse, and if he rode 20 Miles that he should endeavour to find out the Prisoner; we could not then hear of him, but the first Time I heard of him at his Master's I had him taken up.</p>
               <p>Mrs Horrabin confirmed Mr Cook's Evidence, and said, that the Cart run over her Thigh and her Arm, and broke her Thigh, and that there was Room enough on the other Side of the Road for the Prisoner to have pulled off. - I was in a covered Cart, but not so covered but that I could see through the Hoops.</p>
               <p>Mrs Hildersly gave an Account very consistent with Mr Cook's, and that he called to the Prisoner a dozen Yards before he came up with them, that he looked into their Cart, as he was going by, drove on, and said nothing; but cannot be positive whether his Wheel was out of the Track, she being so frightened, that she could not tell whether she fell cut of the Cart, or not, nor how she escaped sowell</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-47-person458">
                  Joseph 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17430907-47-person458" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person458" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know that part of the Road is fifteen Foot and an half wide, and that the Prisoner might very easily, and without any Danger, have gone on the other Side; and that the Ruts were not above four Inches deep.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-47-person459">
                  Ralph 
                  Sheppard 
               <interp inst="t17430907-47-person459" type="surname" value="Sheppard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person459" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drove one of the Carts that were on the Road at that Time, and where Mr Cook drew out of the Cart-Ruts, there was Room for two or three Carts to pass there, without any Danger; and after he got off, he led his Horse two or three Pole, and drew his near Wheel upon the Bank, the Value of two Foot; which occasioned the off Wheel to lean towards the Wheel of the Chalk Cart, and by that Means the Top of the two Wheels rubbed against one another - the Women fell down behind the loaded Cart of Mr Jefferies's - I was four or five pole behind the Cart.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no part of the Wheel of Mr Jefferies's Cart that run over these People?</p>
               <p>Sheppard. No, they fell behind the Wheel.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of the Women hurt?</p>
               <p>Sheppard. Yes, they were hurt - by the Fall of the Cart - by the Wheel of their own Cart.</p>
               <p>Coun. Did not you say, if they gave the Women a good Spank on the Arse, they might get up, and go well enough?</p>
               <p>Sheppard. No, I did not say so - the Prisoner could not get out of the Track without over-turning his Cart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-47-person460">
                  William 
                  Braint 
               <interp inst="t17430907-47-person460" type="surname" value="Braint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person460" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was mowing at the Time this Accident happened; the first Thing I heard, was the Voice of Women, who said, they were all killed; I saw Emyns's Team of Horses run; and I saw him lay hold of the Thill Horse; and the Cart had then gone over the poor Woman's Legs; the Wheel was never out of the Rut - Mr Cook's Cart was down before I saw it; I got over the Hedge, and said, Lord have Mercy upon me, what are you at; I said, Master Cook, how came this Accident, and, he said, he could not tell - the loaded Cart was above Cook's Cart, when I saw it; (that is, past Cook's Cart, one Woman was lying in the Rut; and the that had her Thigh broke was lying athwart the Rut.</p>
               <p>Jury. Do you think it was possible for the Boy to stop the Horses at that Time?</p>
               <p>Braint. There was no Possibility of stopping them, for the Womens crying out frightened the Horses, and they run.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not you, if you had seen Cook's Cart there, have turned out of the Rut?</p>
               <p>Braint. No, I could not, the Rut was a Yard deep. <rs id="t17430907-47-verdict244" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-verdict244" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-verdict244" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430907-47-punish245" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-punish245" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-47-punish245" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-47-defend452 t17430907-47-punish245"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
