<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-9">
               <interp inst="t17400709-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-9" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-9" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-9-off54-c85" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend97 t17400709-9-off54 t17400709-9-verdict58"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-9-off54-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend98 t17400709-9-off54 t17400709-9-verdict58"></join>
         
               <p>294,295. 
               <persName id="t17400709-9-defend97" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Grazeff 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend97" type="surname" value="Grazeff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend97" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17400709-9-deflabel51" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend97 t17400709-9-deflabel51"></join>, and 
               <persName id="t17400709-9-defend98" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth
                   Grazeff 
                  <rs id="t17400709-9-deflabel52" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend98 t17400709-9-deflabel52"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend98" type="surname" value="Grazeff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend98" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-defend98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17400709-9-defloc53">St James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-9-defloc53" type="placeName" value="St James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-9-defloc53" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend97 t17400709-9-defloc53"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-defend98 t17400709-9-defloc53"></join> , were indicted for <rs id="t17400709-9-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silk Scarf, val.19 s. a Linnen Shirt, val.18 s . and a Linnen Gown, val.25 s. the Goods of the <rs id="t17400709-9-viclabel55" type="occupation">Reverend</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-victim100 t17400709-9-viclabel55"></join> 
                  
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-9-victim100" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Lumley 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-9-victim100" type="surname" value="Lumley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-9-victim100" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-9-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-off54 t17400709-9-victim100"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , Clerk, in the Dwelling-House of Edward Darling
            </rs> , <rs id="t17400709-9-cd56" type="crimeDate">Dec.2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-off54 t17400709-9-cd56"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Rev. Mr Lumley. What I have to say in the Affair is this. That the Goods contained in the Indictment were my Property. That those Goods were actually locked up in a Box. That in that Box were a Scarf, a Gown, and a Shirt. That they broke open - A - Box belonging to me. That the Box was in the House of Edward Darling. I can't positively say his Name is Edward Darling,- but his Name is Darling, and I take it to be Edward Darling. I have more Reason to apprehend his Name is Edward, than the contrary. That this Box was broke open, and it was in the House of Edward Darling, in the House where the Prisoners lodg'd. That this house is in <placeName id="t17400709-9-crimeloc57">Queen-street, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-9-crimeloc57" type="placeName" value="Queen-street, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-9-crimeloc57" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-9-off54 t17400709-9-crimeloc57"></join>, by the Haymarket,- by Piccadilly. The Things were in that House on the 2d of December; that is, the Box in which the Things were contain'd. Besides,- several other Things were then,- and there,- deposited in the Custody of the 2 Prisoners. I my self consented to have them put into their Custody: and in their Possession they were,- and they were so by my Consent. Now what I have to observe farther is,- I have already observed that these Goods were mine, and I do declare, as I am upon my Oath, that the 2 Prisoners at the Bar did say, They broke open this Box, and took the Goods out of the Box, in order to pledge them,- in order to raise a certain Sum of Money upon them. I did not lodge in the same House,- I came from Portsmouth,- I am Chaplain of the Centurion Man of War; and when I came to Town, I put the Box into their Possession. My Spouse was acquainted with them,- I never was acquainted with them above a Month, or 6 Weeks, tho' my Spouse had known them some time before. This particular Box was sent to them, by my Direction.- It was not only directed to them, but was left in their Custody. This Box did not come from Portsmouth, for the Box,- this Box, my Lord, was a Box that my Wife had to put her Linnen in, and several other necessary things; and when I took it to Town, I put in my Scarf, and the Shirt, and the Linnen Gown; and this Box (my Lord) was broke open. Now this Box I did not send it from Portsmouth,- My Wife took it from Lambeth: and this Box had afterwards a Lock put to it, after it came from Lambeth. That this Box was lock'd,- is out of the Question,- it was sent immediately from Lambeth to Darling's House, and my Wife sent it. I have already told you,- that this Box did not come from Portsmouth; that these Things were not contained in the Box, when it came from Lambeth; but I put these Things into it, in the House of Darling, and locked it with my own Hands.- I put them in with my own Hands, after the Box came there. If I might be so bold as to trouble the Court with a long Detail, as Sir Edward Hill is not here,- but if Sir Edward Hill was here, he could inform you, that if I did not prosecute them, they would prosecute me; for they had a Warrant out against me: I went before Sir Edward, and he discharged a Warrant they had against me. I have no Malice in the Thing, but if I would not prosecute them, they would prosecute me. My Lord, this Box was in their Custody, and it was locked both then, and before, and, my Lord, I lock'd it with my own Hands, after I had put the Things into it; and the Key I have now,- I took it away with me. Sir, With regard to the Shirt that I put into the Box, my Servant was present, when I put it in, but he is at Portsmouth. The 2 Prisoners were then present, and this was on the 2d of December, as I was telling you before,- if I was to go into a Detail of the thing. I missed them on the 3d of December,- the Day following; for I lodged in the same Street, and on coming there for my Shirt, as I came from Portsmouth with but 2 Shirts, I went for this, and on my coming there, the Box was broke open,- I found it broke open; and on finding the Box broke open, I told my Spouse, I was surprized at a thing of that Nature; and my Spouse was gone to Breakfast with the 2 Prisoners at the same Time. What I observe farther on the Affair, is this,- finding myself deprived of my Effects, I probably made a Noise, and so a Warrant was granted against me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090015"></xptr> by Sir Edward Hill, on Account of that Noise I made, about these things. But (with Submission) I made so much Noise, that Sir Edward discharg'd me, he did not think proper to commit me. Afterwards I sent to the Prisoners at the Bar.- I told them,- provided they would let me have my Effects again, I was willing not to prosecute them.- This I did say; and upon this, in order that I should not prosecute them, they arrested me, in an Action for 50 s. on Account of my Brother and my Wife; which Action I have their full Discharge for. All I have to say, is this,- they did actually declare they pawned these things at one Mr Grubb's, and this I know by their own Confession, when I went before Sir Edward Hill; and to the best of my Remembrance it might be about the 14th of Dec. then or thereabouts. But, as I observed before,- they confessed the thing at first,- they confessed it the 3d of December. I have already observed what they said the 3d of December. They both said, they had actually taken a Scarf, a Gown, a Shirt, and had pawn'd them actually, in the Hands of Grubb; and they had nothing to say in Excuse, more than this,- That my Wife was consenting to it. That I suppose they will say now, and That is all the Case I suppose.</p>
               <p>Jury. How long is it since you was arrested for 50 Shillings? And when did you pay it?</p>
               <p>Mr Lumley. It was paid to the best of my Remembrance, last Good Friday. My Agent's Clerk - Mr Jasper's Clerk paid it. They actually arrested me, and put me into the Marshalsea, to prevent the Prosecution.</p>
               <p>Defence. Grazeff jun. Mr Lumley being at Portsmouth, I used to visit Mrs Lumley; and while I was there one Day, her Landlady seized her Goods; upon which she begged, I would let her come home and lie with me. I took her home, with her Brother-in-Law, and her Servant. Mrs Lumley lay with me for a fortnight; and I helped the Brother to a Lodging in the Neighbourhood, where he continued 3 Weeks, Mr Lumley promising to pay for it. He had Stockings, Handkerchiefs, Gloves, and other Things of us before he went to Portsmouth; and signed the Bill, that we might receive it at Mr Jasper's; but Mr Jasper refused to pay it unless the Prosecutor was present: Yet Mr Lumley wanted a Receipt from us in full; and one Sunday Night he made such a Riot in the House about this Bill, cursing and brawling, that the Landlord of the House came, and begged he would not make such a Noise; but he persisted in making the Riot, and threatened to break a Glass, which cost us Four Pounds. He never demanded any Goods, for the Box was delivered to him. And, on Account of this Riot, Mr Darling got a Warrant for him, but Sir Edward Hill would not commit him, because he was a Clergyman. As to the Goods, Mrs Lumley would never trust us with any, for fear we should stop them; and all the Things that were pawned, she pawned herself; and those which he charges us with, were never at our House at all.</p>
               <p>Mr Lumley. By those whom they presume to call to their Characters, it will be found on their Examination, that they were in the House.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. We never pawned any of the things. We are near Neighbours to Mr Grubb, and he might have had him here to have proved it, if we had done it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-9-person101">
                  William 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-person101" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person101" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Prisoners, but happened to be casually going by this Place, and heard, that Mr Lumley was carrying on a Prosecution, I came in; and all I have to say, is this, That I know him, his Wife, and his Mother, and know them to be a very base, vile People. I take him to be a very vile Fellow, and do believe that he would not speak Truth upon Oath.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-9-person102">
                  Mary 
                  Crossman 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-person102" type="surname" value="Crossman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person102" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr Lumley and his Wife lodged at our House between 5 and 6 Months. Elizabeth Grazeff the younger used to come to see them; she was a particular Acquaintance of theirs, and, as I thought, a Friend. To my Knowledge, she has lent them Things to pledge, to serve them in their Necessity.(The Box was produced.) This small Box was all they brought to my House, with all the Materials they had; and it was in the same Condition as it is now, without a Lock, and but one Hinge to it. He went away in December, and his Wife went in the same Month.</p>
               <p>Mr Lumley. I desire she may be asked, if I had not a Scarf in that Box, which cost me 19 s. and 9 d. half-penny.</p>
               <p>Crossman. He had a Scarf, but that was gone: and he had another which he brought from Portsmouth, and that was not worth Half a Crown.</p>
               <p>Mr Lumley. Why, which way did the Scarf go?</p>
               <p>Crossman. Why, I believe the Way that all the rest of his Things went;- they had pawned them all, and had nothing to put on their Backs. I seized what was left, for my Rent, and here is an Inventory of all the Goods that I seized .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-9-person103">
                  Tho 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-person103" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person103" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Grazeff the Younger was acquainted (I know) with Mrs Lumley; she used to come to see the Lumleys, and I believe was a Friend to them. He gave an Account of Mr. Lumley's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090016"></xptr> trifling with him on Account of a Debt, but this had no relation to the Matter in Question.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-9-person104">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hoskins 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-person104" type="surname" value="Hoskins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person104" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Some Time ago, I was going along the Strand, and saw Mr Lumley and his Mother. The Mother said, this is one of Mrs Grazeff's Kinswomen. Mr. Lumley damned and cursed both Mrs Grazeff, and her Daughter; and said, he would do their Business for them. He said he had got one of them in Newgate, and that he would have them both transported.</p>
               <p>Mr Lumley. I desire she may be asked, whether she did not come to me once or twice, in order to make up this Affair.</p>
               <p>Hoskins. I came to your House to speak to your Mother about it, but it was at your own Request.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-9-person105">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400709-9-person105" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person105" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the two Prisoners at the Bar, for some Time. They know nothing of my being here; nor did I know any thing of this Affair, till now but as I happened to be here, I can say, they live not 100 Yards from me, and bear as honest Characters as any People in the World. They keep a Milliner's Shop, and sell Gloves; I never heard the least ill Thing of them in the World.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17400709-9-verdict58" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-9-verdict58" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoners, and the Court granted them a Copy of the Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
