<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-33">
               <interp inst="t17431012-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-33" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-33" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-33-off153-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-33-defend402 t17431012-33-off153 t17431012-33-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>498. 
               <persName id="t17431012-33-defend402" type="defendantName">
                  Greenliff 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-defend402" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-defend402" type="given" value="Greenliff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-defend402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17431012-33-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a hundred of Bricks, value 18 d.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-victim404" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Simpson 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-33-victim404" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-victim404" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-victim404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-33-off153 t17431012-33-victim404"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17431012-33-cd154" type="crimeDate">March 26, 1742</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-33-off153 t17431012-33-cd154"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person405">
                  Samuel 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person405" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person405" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17431012-33-viclabel155" type="occupation">keep a Yard in Petticoat-Lane, and belong to the building Business</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-33-victim404 t17431012-33-viclabel155"></join>, I have missed at a great many Times a pretty deal of Stuff, Timber, Tiles, and Bricks, and I never could hear who robbed me, though I have set People to watch several Times; the Prisoner worked for me about twelve Months before; I asked my Apprentice if he had never seen any Body about the Yard, he said, he did once see Greenliff Taylor take some Bricks out of the Yard. I asked him the Reason why he did not tell of it before, and he said the Prisoner had threatned to do him a Mischief if he spoke of it:</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120047"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person406">
                  Lewis 
                  Lecroke 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person406" type="surname" value="Lecroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person406" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about two Years and six Months. On the 26th of last March was Twelve Months, I met him coming out of my Master's Yard, in Petticoat-Lane, with a Basket of Bricks; I asked him what he was going to do with them; he said, What is that to you? I told him my Master knew nothing of it, and I would acquaint him with it; he said, if I did acquaint my Master with it, he would do my Business for me, and that was the Reason I did not inform against him sooner; and I was afraid to go about my Business after I had made a Discovery, till the Bill was found. - I cannot swear to any more than this Basket of Bricks.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Bricks do you think there were?</p>
               <p>Lecroke. I believe there were eighteen or twenty; the Basket was pretty well filled, and it will contain about that Quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you fix the Time to be the 26th of March was twelve Months?</p>
               <p>Lecroke. I remember I had been at work in Love's-Court that Day, and I turned to the Book and found it to be the 26th of March that I was at Work there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person407">
                  Henry 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person407" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person407" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 26th of last March was Twelve-Months, I met the Prisoner carrying a Hod of Bricks out of the Tabernacle-Yard in Petticoat-Lane, belonging to Mr Simpson, after I left Work in the Evening; I asked him what he was going to do with them; he said it was no Business of mine, and that he had as much Business with the Bricks as I or my Master had, and he said if I did trouble myself about it, he would turn me out of my Business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him carry any Bricks out more than once?</p>
               <p>Newton. I saw him carry Bricks out at several Times, I am within Compass in swearing to an hundred of Bricks.</p>
               <p>Q. What Reason have you to fix on the 26th of March was twelve Months?</p>
               <p>Newton. I know it by being at work in Love's-Court that Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Why should you be afraid of being turned out of your Master's Business, for discovering to your Master that he was wronged?</p>
               <p>Newton. I was as much afraid of being abused as I was of any Thing else.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I cannot help what he swears; I am very ignorant of the Affair.</p>
               <p>W. Green. The Prisoner has worked with me ever since the 26th of December last, and always behaved in a very sober Manner; I never heard any Body say but that he was very honest excepting this Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person408">
                  James 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person408" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person408" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about six Months; he always bore a very good Character; I live near him; he is an Acquaintance of mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person409">
                  Joseph 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person409" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person409" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these eight Months; I always heard that he was an honest Man never and any [I] of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-33-person410">
                  William 
                  Lyne 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person410" type="surname" value="Lyne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person410" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17431012-33-person411">
                  Joseph 
                  Sally 
               <interp inst="t17431012-33-person411" type="surname" value="Sally"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person411" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said he bore the Character of an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This was never thought of till I sued him for my Wages; I got an Attachment against him in the Court of Conscience, and when I recovered my Money then this Thing was trumped up upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to this? Is it true.</p>
               <p>Simpson. There was an Agreement between the Prisoner and me; and I was to give him a Guinea a Week, if he behaved as he should do; but instead of coming in Time, he used frequently to come at nine or ten o'Clock in the Morning, and I only stopped the Money for lost Time, and he got an Attachment against me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there an Attachment against you in the Court of Conscience?</p>
               <p>Simpson. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pay the Money upon it?</p>
               <p>Simpson. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you missed any Thing before?</p>
               <p>Simpson. Yes, a great many Times, he has robbed me of a great deal more out of my Cellar. <rs id="t17431012-33-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-33-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
