<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400522-29">
               <interp inst="t17400522-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-29" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-29" type="date" value="17400522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-29-off145-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-defend228 t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-verdict149"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-29-off145-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-defend230 t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>281, 282. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-defend228" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Pooley , alias <rs id="t17400522-29-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-defend228 t17400522-29-alias-8"></join>Debenham</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend228" type="surname" value="Pooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend228" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-defend230" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Miller 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend230" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend230" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-defend230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17400522-29-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17400522-29-victim231" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17400522-29-victim231" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-victim231"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a Hat, val. 20 s. and a Whip, val. 10 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400522-29-cd146" type="crimeDate">April 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-cd146"></join>.</p>
               <p>F - . On Friday April 25, I had been in the Country, and came to Town about 9 o'clock, but I staid in Leicester Fields till after 12. I live in the Strand, and as I was coming along the Strand, those Ladies met me, and I being a little warm in Liquor, they both took hold of me, and said, I should give them a Pint of Wine: I being a little merry, went with them, to a private House in Benner's Court, over against the <placeName id="t17400522-29-crimeloc147">Fountain Tavern</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-29-crimeloc147" type="placeName" value="Fountain Tavern"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-29-crimeloc147" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-crimeloc147"></join> in the <placeName id="t17400522-29-crimeloc148">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-29-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-29-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-29-off145 t17400522-29-crimeloc148"></join>, and gave them a Pint; but seeing what they were, and what House I had got into, I threw down a Shilling, and was going away: But the Prisoners, and another Woman, came up to me, and I was in danger of my Life in the House. They told me, that I had Six Shillings more to pay, so I threw down 6 s. upon the Table, and they took it up among them; for if they had demanded a Guinea, I should have given it them, because of the Danger I was in. Then I went to the Door, and the Man of the House came up, and looking at me, he cry'd, - Why you have 4 s. more to pay! Pray let me go out, says I, and I'll give it you, and pray go home with me; for I was not far from my own House. Upon this he let me out, and followed me; presently I heard the Women say, - d - mn him there he is. Seeing no Watchman near, I thought my self in Danger, and went to the Watch-house in Strand-Lane, but missing the Door, the two Prisoners came up and caught me (on each side) by the Collar, and the Man fell to beating me on the Stomach at the same time. I called out Murder as long as I could speak, and the Man hearing somebody coming up, gave me a Slap on the Face, and said, d - mn you, take that, and one of the Women cry'd, - take what you can get; so some of them took my Hat and Whip, which were given to the Man, and he ran away with them. I am positive to the Prisoners; for Pooley I held till<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220020"></xptr> the Watch came to my Assistance, and the other I described so well, that she was taken next Morning, when she came to bring Pooley a clean Gown. I could distinguish their Faces very well by the Moonlight, and positively swear to them both.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-person232">
                  Thomas 
                  Edlin 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person232" type="surname" value="Edlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person232" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Constable, swore he found Pooley, and the Prosecutor, between 12 and 1, struggling together in Strand Lane, they charged him with each other, and he kept them both, tho' he knew the Prosecutor to be a sufficient House-keeper. He charged her with robbing him of a Hat and Whip, and found her in 20 different Stories. The Witness said, that the Prosecutor gave the same Account of the Robbery, that he had now done; and that he had promised to pay the Man the last Demand which was made on him, in the House the Prisoners carried him to, if he would go home with him: But afterwards, not thinking it proper to carry the Man home, he intended to have gone with him to the Watch-house, but missed the Door: He added, that Pooley's Apron was bloody, when she was taken, and that Miller was apprehended next Morning, when she came to bring the other a Gown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-person233">
                  John 
                  Higgins 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person233" type="surname" value="Higgins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that about 3 Weeks ago, between 12 and 1 o'clock in the Morning, he was wak'd by a Cry of Murder; that the Noise growing fainter and fainter, he got up, and looked out of the Window, and heard somebody a cursing and swearing, and a Woman, (as he judg'd by the Voice) say, d - n it, push off, or go off; and at the same Time he heard the Words. - Hat, - and he thought - Wigg; and saw a Man running up the Lane after a Woman; and the Man took something out of her Hand. He likewise heard a Woman swear, she would go back, and rescue, or relieve her; after which, he saw a Woman coming down the Lane, who ran away upon the Appearance of the Watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-person234">
                  James 
                  Britles 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person234" type="surname" value="Britles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person234" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a private Watchman, heard the Cry of Murder, and coming up saw a Man and two Women, (one of which was Pooley) with the Prosecutor, who charged him with Pooley, and she charged the Watchman with the Prosecutor. Upon this, he went to call the Watch,; but when he returned, the Man and the other Woman was gone. He added, that he took Notice the Prosecutor had his Hat on, and his Whip in his Hand, when he left him; but when he returned, and found him alone with Pooley, they were gone. He swore to Pooley, but not to Miller.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-person235">
                  James 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person235" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person235" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400522-29-person236">
                  John 
                  Gerrard 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person236" type="surname" value="Gerrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (for the Prisoners) deposed, that they had been drinking in the City, and coming home between 12 and 1 o'Clock, they heard a Noise, and going to see what was the Matter, they saw Pooley without her Cap; she had hold of the Prosecutor, and he had hold of her: that a Man coming from the Water-side, asked the Prosecutor how he could use the Prisoner in that Manner? upon which he replied, - You Rascal, are you one of her Bullies? That the Prosecutor and the Man, went to fighting, and the Witnesses then left them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-29-person237">
                  Catherine 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person237" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person237" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400522-29-person238">
                  Judith 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person238" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person238" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400522-29-person239">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wilks 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person239" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person239" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400522-29-person240">
                  Mary 
                  Plummer 
               <interp inst="t17400522-29-person240" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person240" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave Pooley a good Character. Both <rs id="t17400522-29-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-29-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
