<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400522-8">
               <interp inst="t17400522-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-8" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-8" type="date" value="17400522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-8-off51-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-8-defend91 t17400522-8-off51 t17400522-8-verdict54"></join>
         
               <p>257. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-8-defend91" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-8-defend91" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-defend91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-defend91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, (with 
               <persName id="t17400522-8-person92">
                  Alexander 
                  Afflack 
               <interp inst="t17400522-8-person92" type="surname" value="Afflack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person92" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken) for <rs id="t17400522-8-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a quilted Petticoat, val. 10s. two Silk Gowns, val. 3l. a Silk Petticoat, val. 10s. and a Pair of Stays, val. 20 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400522-8-victim94" type="victimName">
                           Susanna 
                           Peck 
                        <interp inst="t17400522-8-victim94" type="surname" value="Peck"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-8-victim94" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-8-victim94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-8-off51 t17400522-8-victim94"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in her Dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400522-8-cd52" type="crimeDate">April 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-8-off51 t17400522-8-cd52"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs Peck. I live in <placeName id="t17400522-8-crimeloc53">Jermyn-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-8-crimeloc53" type="placeName" value="Jermyn-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-8-crimeloc53" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-8-off51 t17400522-8-crimeloc53"></join>, and missed the Goods mentioned in the Indictment, out of an Escrutore in my Dining-room, on Sunday the 27th of April last. I heard nothing of them till the Thursday following; and then Crates, (the next Witness) came; between 3 and 4 o'Clock, and desired to know if I had not lost any Cloaths? I told him I had. He described the Things I had lost, and I shewed him a Piece of Silk, which he said was of the same Sort with some of them. Then a Man, who came with the Evidence, told me, I must go to Colonel De Veil's, where I might see the Goods and swear to them: but when I got there, I was informed they had been sold to one 
               <persName id="t17400522-8-person95">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17400522-8-person95" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Holborn, on the same Day they were stole. The Colonel sent for him and the Cloaths, and he refused to come. He sent for him a second Time, and threatened to fetch him with a Warrant; upon which he promised to come that Night, or next Morning. The Messenger went for him again, and then both Johnson and his Wife were abroad; but upon the Colonel's sending for him next Morning, he came; and I saw my Things and swore to them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her if she lost no more Things?</p>
               <p>Mrs Peck. There was another quilted Coat stole, but that was not mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She said, before Colonel De Veil, she had lost a Handkerchief and a Pair of Stockings.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Peck. No; it was Coates said so. I did not know that I had lost the quilted Coats, till I came home; and I could not swear to them, till after I had been at home: then I found the white Coat was mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-8-person96">
                  George 
                  Coates 
               <interp inst="t17400522-8-person96" type="surname" value="Coates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person96" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About five Weeks ago, the Prisoner and I, and Alexander Flack +, were going along Jermyn-street, about one o'Clock in the Afternoon, and the Street-door of this Lady's House being open, the Prisoner went up Stairs, and brought down 3 Petticoats, 2 Gowns, a Pair of Stays, and old Handkerchief, and an old Pair of Stockings. They were brought out, in the Middle of the Day, and we carried them to 
               <persName id="t17400522-8-person97">
                  Arthur 
                  Bethell 
               <interp inst="t17400522-8-person97" type="surname" value="Bethell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person97" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            *, who said, he could dispose of them, if they were worth 50 l. The Handkerchief and the Stockings we gave away: the rest of the Things Arthur Bethell carried into Holborn. We bid him ask 5 Guineas for them, but he brought us no more than three. He told us he could get no more, so we had a Guinea a-piece, and gave him 2s. for his Trouble.</p>
               <p>+ See last Oct. Sessions. No. 512.</p>
               <p>*See the following Trial.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Peck. These are the Things, and they are the same which I lost.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I went for them, by the Prisoner's Direction, and found them.</p>
               <p>Coates. Arthur Bethell, who disposed of them for us, is in Custody for robbing a Man of his Watch and Money, in the Street. These are the very same Things which the Prisoner brought out of Mrs Peck's House. We tied them up in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220010"></xptr> two Bundles at Flack's Room, and then carried them to Bethell to dispose of them for us.</p>
               <p>Arthur Bethell. I know nothing of the Lady's Cloaths, - I know nothing of Coates, (the Evidence; but I know his Wife. 'Tis she that has sworn against me about a Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr Perry, and Mr Miller, got this Robbery Sworn against me, for the Sake of the 2 Guineas Reward, which the Lady was to give to have her Cloaths again.</p>
               <p>Perry. When I took the Prisoner, he fell down on his Knees, and desired to be made an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Miller. He did endeavour to be made an Evidence against Coates, and did not deny the Fact, when he was before Colonel De Veil. <rs id="t17400522-8-verdict54" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-8-verdict54" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
