<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410116-2">
               <interp inst="t17410116-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-2" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-2" type="date" value="17410116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410116-2-off6-c31" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-defend34 t17410116-2-off6 t17410116-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>2. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410116-2-defend34" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Shooter 
                  <interp inst="t17410116-2-defend34" type="surname" value="Shooter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-defend34" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-defend34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17410116-2-defloc5">St. Botolph Bishop's-gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-2-defloc5" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph Bishop's-gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-2-defloc5" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-defend34 t17410116-2-defloc5"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17410116-2-off6" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-off6" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-off6" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Worsted Purse, value 2 d. two 3 l. 12 s. Pieces, 28 36 s. Pieces, 4 Guineas, and 1 half Guinea, the Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410116-2-victim36" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Barnard 
                        <interp inst="t17410116-2-victim36" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-2-victim36" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-2-victim36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-off6 t17410116-2-victim36"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in his dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17410116-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">Dec. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-off6 t17410116-2-cd7"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-2-person37">
                  Robert 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17410116-2-person37" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person37" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a <rs id="t17410116-2-viclabel8" type="occupation">Weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-victim36 t17410116-2-viclabel8"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17410116-2-crimeloc9">Peter-Street, Bishop's-gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-2-crimeloc9" type="placeName" value="Peter-Street, Bishop's-gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-2-crimeloc9" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-off6 t17410116-2-crimeloc9"></join> Parish. I was out of Doors when this was done; but when I came Home, I found the Chest open in my Chamber, (into which I had put my Money) with the Keys hanging in the Lock. The Money was taken away, but the Bag, and a Silver Spoon which likewise lay in the Chest were left behind. I imagin'd that somebody who knew the House must be concern'd, and the Prisoner who had serv'd me as a <rs id="t17410116-2-deflabel10" type="occupation">Quill-Boy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-defend34 t17410116-2-deflabel10"></join>, being observed to be pretty full of Money, I suspected him; he was taken and brought to the Magpye-Tavern , where he confess'd that he got over the Wall, into the Yard, and open'd the Back Door; then went up Stairs into my Chamber, and took my Keys out of the Table-Drawer; that he found the Key of the Chest, and took the Purse out of the Bag, and a little Box, in which were four Guineas and a half I can't tell whether he was so wise as to know what Pieces they were, but he own'd he took all that he found there. There were no Promises of Pardon, or any thing like it, made Use of to get this Confession from him, but we desired him to speak the Truth to the best of his Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was the Prisoner acquainted with your House?</p>
               <p>Barnard . Yes; he liv'd with me about a Quarter of a Year, as a Quill-Boy, and left me in February last. I believe he is between 13 and 14 Years of Age.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am not 13 yet.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was any of the Money found on the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Barnard . We did not search him, but he told his Brother where some of it was hid, and we found it accordingly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-2-person38">
                  Peter 
                  Nettle 
               <interp inst="t17410116-2-person38" type="surname" value="Nettle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person38" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Friday the 2d of January, Wilson the Officer, told me he had a Woman at the Watch-House, and desired me to go with him; I accordingly did, and while we were examining her, the Boy (the Prisoner) who had absconded , was brought to us. We took him into a Room by himself, and ask'd him if he would not relate something to us; he was desired to declare the Truth, and if any Mercy was to be expected, it must be by such Methods. At first, he said, he found the Money in Moorfields; but I told him, that was nothing but an Evasion of his, and if he did not declare the Truth, it would be the worse<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174101160003"></xptr> for him: He then fairly own'd that he got over Barnard's Wall into the Garden, open'd the Back-Door, and went up Stairs into the Bed-Chamber; that he open'd the Table-Drawer, and took out a Bunch of Keys in a String; he went into the Closet where the Chest stood, and after he had try'd several Keys, at last found the right; that he took the Purse with the Money, and likewise a little Pill-Box, in which there was other Money, and a Pair of Buttons; that he threw them away, and kept the Money for his own Use. I ask'd him whether any Body was concern'd with him, and that Night he refus'd to tell me; but on examining him again next Morning, he burst in Tears, and said, if he confess'd, we should hang his Mother. I said, if she had been so inhuman as to put the Rope about his Neck, he had better be an Evidence against her: He then said, his Mother help'd him over the Wall, and waited till he came back again, and that they both went Home together. He said, he made his Sister a Present of four of the 36 s. Pieces, and gave his Mother the Remainder, all but one Guinea, with which he bought a Pound of Butter, that he might get it chang'd; that he threw the Butter away, and appropriated the Money to his own Use. The Mother and the Daughter, both abscond for this Affair.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They took me to the Magpye, and made me fuddled , and I did not know what I said.</p>
               <p>Nettle. He was very sober; - he had some Bread and Cheese, and Small Beer there, and but one Glass of Wine.</p>
               <p>John Malton. Mr. Barnard told me he had been robb'd of all the Cash he had in the World, and shew'd me the Place from whence it was taken. I ask'd him if he suspected any Body; he told me he had a little Boy lived with him about 3 quarters of a Year ago, and he could suspect no one else. About a Fortnight after this, we got a Warrant and the Mother and Daughter absconded, but the Boy was brought to us at the Magpye, by his Uncle, and he own'd before several People that he got into the House, and took his Master's Money. The next Day he was brought to Mr. Nettle's House, and I desired him to tell the Truth, '' I did (said he) get over the Wall, and go into my '' Master's Chamber ; I have seen where he put his '' Keys, so I open'd the Chest, and took out the Purse, '' and the Box, with a great deal of Money in them, '' and a Pair of Buttons, which I threw away.'' I ask'd him what Money it was? he said it was brave large yellow Money, and there were two Pieces as big again as the rest, and a great many alike. I took a Moidore out of my Pocket, and shew'd him that, but he said the Money was bigger than that. He likewise said, that he gave four Pieces to his Sister, and the rest to his Mother, all but one Guinea, with which he bought a Pound of Butter, in order to get Silver. After the Prisoner was in the Compter, he told his Brother he hid some of the Money under a Shed in the Tenter-Ground, and going to take it from thence, some of it dropp'd into a Crevice, and he could not get it out again: We went to this Place, and dug out these four 36 s. Pieces.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-2-person39">
                  Richard 
                  Shooter 
               <interp inst="t17410116-2-person39" type="surname" value="Shooter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person39" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner's Brother. I am 13 Years old, and know if I take a false Oath, I shall go to Hell. I went to see my Brother in the Compter, and ask'd him if he had spent all the Money; he said No, for he had hid some of it in the Tenter Ground, and going to take it away, part of it roll'd into a Hole, and he could not get it out again: I went to the Place with Barnard and Malton , and look'd into the Hole, and saw one of the Broad Pieces; I try'd to get my Hand in, but could not, so they got a Pick-Axe, and dug them out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-2-person40">
                  David 
                  Shooter 
               <interp inst="t17410116-2-person40" type="surname" value="Shooter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person40" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am the Boy's Uncle: I went down to Chatham , and found him with another Brother who is bound to a Hoy-Man. I took him on Shore, and ask'd him what he had done to bring his Friends into so much Trouble? he said at first, that he gave his Mother the Money, but told her he had found it. When we came to Stroud , he told me he found it in the Tenter-Ground; I desired him to tell the Truth , and he said he did commence (commit) the Robbery, and all the Way as we were coming to Town, he said his Mother did not know but that he found it; but on the Saturday following, he own'd his Mother assisted him in the Robbery. - He is about 13 or 14 Years old.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I found it in the Tenter-Ground, wrapp'd up in a Rag: - I have no Witnesses, for I was by myself.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17410116-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-2-verdict11" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, <rs id="t17410116-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17410116-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-2-defend34 t17410116-2-punish12"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>; but desired he might be recommended by the Court to his Majesty's Mercy
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
