<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-33">
               <interp inst="t17471014-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-33" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-33" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-33-off156-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-33-defend370 t17471014-33-off156 t17471014-33-verdict158"></join>
         
               <p>418. + 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-defend370" type="defendantName">
                  Anne 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-defend370" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-defend370" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-defend370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17471014-33-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing, on the 9th of September, two Guineas
            </rs>, from 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-person371">
                  George 
                  Manly 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person371" type="surname" value="Manly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person371" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Property of 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-victim372" type="victimName">
                  Humphry 
                  Higgins 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-victim372" type="surname" value="Higgins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-victim372" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-victim372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-33-off156 t17471014-33-victim372"></join>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-33-person373">
                  George 
                  Manly 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person373" type="surname" value="Manly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person373" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Humphry Higgins I had the Money of. 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-person374">
                  Richard 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person374" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person374" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I want to Holborn, to Gray's-Inn Lane. We went there to take the Lodgings for Humphry Higgins, and we stay'd in Gray's-Inn Lane till past ten o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. In what House?</p>
               <p>Manly. At the Sign of the Magpie.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Manly. From thence we came home directly, and coming along Katherine Street, <placeName id="t17471014-33-crimeloc157">Little Katherine Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-33-crimeloc157" type="placeName" value="Little Katherine Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-33-crimeloc157" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-33-off156 t17471014-33-crimeloc157"></join>; this Street crosses Great Katherine Street, we met this Woman very near the Door. She caught hold of me by the Coat, and ask'd me, What I would give her I ask'd her, What she would have me to give her? She said, will you give me a Dram? I said, I very seldom drink any Drams. I refused, but she said, I should come in, and there was very good Dorchester Beer, or Ale, or Brandy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go in?</p>
               <p>Manly. Yes, we follow'd this Woman, both of us, in. She went into a Room, and she call'd for a Quartern of Brandy, and I pull'd my Money out of my Pocket in the Room; I had three Guineas and half a Crown in my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with your Money?</p>
               <p>Manly. I put it into my Pocket very safe; I pull'd it out to be my share with this Man for the Brandy; I had no small Money, and this Man, 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-person375">
                  Richard 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person375" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person375" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , paid for it.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Manly. We sat two or three Minutes after I had pull'd my Money out; and, my Lord, I found this Woman's Hand in my Breeches very busy about my Pocket, and I pull'd her Hand away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss your Money after you found her Hand about your Pocket?</p>
               <p>Manly. About half a Minute after this, the Woman jump'd by the Room, and she call'd Landlady, bring me up a Chamber-Pot directly, and this Woman went down Stairs. I can't say I heard her go. There was none brought, but she went down directly, and we waited in the Room about half a Minute. After she was gone out I said, I will go out and see what is become of this Woman. We went down Stairs directly, and ask'd, Where was the Woman that came down Stairs? The Woman said to us, she did not know the Woman, neither did she belong to her House.</p>
               <p>Q. Who made you that Answer?</p>
               <p>Manly. The Landlady. The Woman of the House, I believe. My Lord, we went out directly. I put my Hand in my Pocket, and I miss'd my Money. This Man, that was along with me, said, we will find this Woman out. We went into another House facing of it, and there were several Women there; and I said, there was a Woman very like this Woman. Another Woman came with a Candle in her Hand,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140038"></xptr> and said, Am I the Woman? So this Woman hearing this she run through a small Door and got off.</p>
               <p>Q. What, the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Manly. No, another Woman. This Richard Davis follow'd this Woman, but that other Woman was gone. Just as I was coming out of that House facing this Woman's, where I lost the Woman, this Woman, that over-run us in that House, fell through a Skylight, and broke the Window down; we took that Woman upon Suspicion, but this Woman, the Prisoner, I was in Company with, and no other Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What Reason have you for charging the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Manly. She was in Company with us, and because her Hand was busy about my Pocket; that is the Reason I charge this Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-33-person376">
                  Richard 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person376" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person376" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have no farther to say, than what he has said. I saw him pull Money out, but I did not know what it was. The Woman that we took up upon Suspicion, she discovered this Woman. I was out of the Room part of the Time: She bid me go out of the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you take up with this Woman?</p>
               <p>Davis. As we were coming along this Woman took hold of us. We had drank a little.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-33-person377">
                  Ann 
                  Holbridge 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person377" type="surname" value="Holbridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person377" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person377" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>

               <p>Holbridge. No; but they took up a Lodger of mine, and kept her in Custody all Night; and they said, that was the Woman; and the next Morning I went and cleared my Acquaintance out of the Round-house, and they said all Night it was that Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-33-person378">
                  Mary 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person378" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person378" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person378" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner had been washing with me all that Day that he swore against her. I can say no more. I have known the Prisoner for five Years I have never known her to wrong me or any body else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-33-person379">
                  Martha 
                  Tinsley 
               <interp inst="t17471014-33-person379" type="surname" value="Tinsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person379" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-person379" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her upwards of seven Years, and never heard a bad Character of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-33-verdict158" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-33-verdict158" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
