<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-43">
               <interp inst="t17400709-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-43" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-43" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-43-off221-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-43-defend366 t17400709-43-off221 t17400709-43-verdict223"></join>
         
               <p>334. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-defend366" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Batchelor 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-43-defend366" type="surname" value="Batchelor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-defend366" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-defend366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400709-43-defloc220">Christ Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-43-defloc220" type="placeName" value="Christ Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-43-defloc220" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-43-defend366 t17400709-43-defloc220"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400709-43-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Green Silk Purse, val.1 d. and 4 Half Guineas, and 10 s.6 d. in Silver
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-victim368" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Dalby 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-43-victim368" type="surname" value="Dalby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-victim368" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-victim368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-43-off221 t17400709-43-victim368"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17400709-43-cd222" type="crimeDate">June 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-43-off221 t17400709-43-cd222"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs Dalby. On Saturday the 7th of June, about 6 in the Evening, I went to Mrs Cole's in Newgate Market for Butter, and from thence to Mr. Trueman's , to buy some Bacon. I asked Miss Trueman if she could change me a 36 s. Piece? She telling me she could, I pulled the Piece out of my Purse, and then laid my Purse down upon the Board, where they lay their Bacon, and from whence it could not fall. You never go into those Shops in the Market, so I stood on the outside,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090034"></xptr> while she was changing my Money; and in the mean time the Prisoner ran away with the Purse, in which was 4 Half-Guineas, a Diamond Ring, and some Silver. The Prisoner owns it was 8 s. and a Half-Crown; I did not know she had it; nor what Silver there was in it,'till she mention'd the particular Pieces; for Mr Trueman's Shop, and one of his Maids were searched, and I made a great deal of Enquiry after it, the Moment I missed it, but to no purpose. The Prisoner was taken up about a Week afterwards, and was carried to an Alehouse in Purple-Lane , where I saw her, and did not charge her with the Fact; but when I had told the Gentlewoman of the House how I lost my Purse, she said,- Madam, you do not tell your Story right,- that won't do,- for I found it couragiously, and if there had been an hundred Guineas in it, I would have gone away with it. You don't tell your Story right,(says she) for there was 4 Half-Guineas, and 8 s. and 2 Half-Crowns in it; She found it couragiously , and I might do my worst.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-person369">
                  Thomas 
                  Rushworth 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person369" type="surname" value="Rushworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person369" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I received the Purse in which the Gentlewoman's Money was contained, from 
               <persName id="t17400709-43-person370">
                  James 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person370" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person370" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-person371">
                  James 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person371" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person371" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After we had taken up the Party's (the Prisoner's) Mother, she told us, as how we ought to take up Mrs Piper. I went to Mrs Piper, and asked her if she had received a Purse from 
               <persName id="t17400709-43-person372">
                  Sarah 
                  Batchelor 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person372" type="surname" value="Batchelor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person372" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? She gave it me, and said the Prisoner would leave it with her; and she was advised to keep it, in Hopes an Advertisement would come out about it. I received the Purse from Piper, and gave it to Rushworth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-person373">
                  Sarah 
                  Piper 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person373" type="surname" value="Piper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person373" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came one Night into my Shop in Church-Lane, St Giles's, to light her Pipe; and pulling out the Purse, she said,- the Money is all gone, will you have the Purse? And down she flung it, at the same Time. The next Morning the Prisoner's Mother came and asked me for it again. I keep a Barber's Shop, and was then shaving two Men:- I gave her the Purse, and she presently said,-- Here, as my Daughter gave it you, take it and welcome; but should you know it if you see it again. This is the Purse, I'll take my Oath on it.</p>
               <p>Mrs Dalby This is the Purse which was taken from me at Mr Trueman's .</p>
               <p>Prisoner to Piper. Tell the Gentlemen, you don't know no hurt of me.</p>
               <p>Piper. No; but she brought the Purse to me, and said, the Money that was in it, was left her by her Mother's Uncle; but afterwards she said she found it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-person374">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person374" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person374" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know the Prisoner,- I can say nothing against her, nor for her. I keep a Chandler's Shop in St Giles's, and last Saturday was a Month, she and her Mother (who lodges within three Doors of me) came and had some Bread and Beer of me, and said she was afraid of losing what she had at home, so she bid the Prisoner give me the Purse, and then it would be safe. Accordingly the Prisoner gave me a green silk Purse with 3 Half-guineas and a Ring in it, and 3 Shillings in Silver. The Mother said, she had got a new Gown, new Shoes and Stockings now,- thank God for it; telling me she had a Brother died and left her some Money. But some People being angry with me for taking it, and telling me they supposed the Girl had lain with some body and had robbed him, I delivered it to her again. This was the Purse, I know it again,- here is a Darn in it with green Silk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-43-person375">
                  Mary 
                  Anniball 
               <interp inst="t17400709-43-person375" type="surname" value="Anniball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person375" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-person375" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Butter-Shop, just by Mr. Trueman's Bacon-shop : and I saw the Prisoner go by my Shop a Minute before the Purse was lost. On Sunday the 15th of June, I went with Mrs Dalby to the Prisoner. She told us she knew what we came about,- You come about the Purse that was lost in Newgate Market,- I wish (say she) I had found it, and I would have new cloathed myself. I knew her no otherways, than by singing Ballads about the Market.</p>
               <p>Mrs Jones. I have known the Prisoner six Months: She has been in the Neighbourhood longer. She has been several Nights in my Shop, early and late, and I received no Damage by her.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner in her Defence said she found it, and thought it belonged to her. <rs id="t17400709-43-verdict223" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-43-verdict223" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
