<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-35">
               <interp inst="t17431012-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-35" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-35" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-35-off163-c365" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-35-defend435 t17431012-35-off163 t17431012-35-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>500. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-35-defend435" type="defendantName">
                     Dorothy 
                     Christian 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-35-defend435" type="surname" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-defend435" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-defend435" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17431012-35-off163" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-off163" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-off163" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assault"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17431012-35-victim436" type="victimName">
                        Mrs 
                        Wingfield 
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-victim436" type="surname" value="Wingfield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-35-victim436" type="given" value="Mrs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-35-victim436" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-35-off163 t17431012-35-victim436"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-35-person437">
                  Isabella 
                  Kendall 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person437" type="surname" value="Kendall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person437" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person437" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the <rs id="t17431012-35-cd164" type="crimeDate">5th of September</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-35-off163 t17431012-35-cd164"></join>, Mrs Wingfield came to drink a Dish of Tea with me, I bid my Servant (the Prisoner) put the Things in Order for the Tea, and cut some Bread and Butter; she brought in some; says Mrs Wingfield, I desire a little more Butter upon the Bread. I called my Servant; said I, Dorothy, what Sort of Bread and Butter is this? You have not cut it as it should be; I spoke to her in a mild Manner for she never saw me out of Temper; to this she said it was well enough; I smiled at it, and shewed her the Bread and Butter, said I, is this fit to bring into Company; said she, What is the Matter with it? It is well enough. I went into the Kitchen, and asked her how she could serve me so; said she, Madam, you eat none yourself, and I think it is good enough for your Company. Why, said I, is it good enough? Do you know any Thing of my Company? Yes, said she, I know them better than you do, and knew them before you did; said I, it is very impudent in you to use my Friend in this Manner. When I went into the Parlour again, said Mrs Wingfield, Why do you trouble yourself about the Bread and Butter? I don't matter whether I have any: Said I, Madam, my Maid says she, knew you before I did, and knows you better than I do; said Mrs Wingfield, My Dear, with your Leave, I will go out and speak to her, and ask her how she came to know me, for I do not remember ever to have seen her. Mrs Wingfield went out of the Parlour, and presently I heard somebody cry out, I went to the Kitchen, and found Mrs Wingfield on the Ground, upon her Back, her Head rais'd a little Way off the Ground; said I, Lord, have Mercy upon me, what's the Matter; Mrs Wingfield said, my Maid had beat and abused her in a very gross Manner.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120051"></xptr> Mrs Wingfield was in a very bad Condition, and very much bruised.</p>
               <p>Mrs Wingfield. I went to pay a Visit to Miss Kendall; she ordered the Tea to be brought, and called for a Plate of Bread and Butter. I desired she would order her Maid to put a little more Butter upon the Bread; there was very little Butter upon it, and she brought it in, in a very unhandsome Manner; it seemed as if Children had been biting it. I smiled at the Bread and Butter; Mrs Kendall called her Maid in, and said, What is the Matter that the Bread and Butter is cut in this unseemly Manner? The Maid said, it was well enough; Mrs Kendall ordered her to cut some more, and that was cut much in the same Manner; said she, I'll go out, and speak to her about it; said I, Madam, don't trouble yourself; said Mrs Kendall, I can speak to her without being in a Passion; she went, and when she came in again, she told me, her Maid said, it was good enough for her Company; and that, she said, she knew me before she did, and better than she did; said I, I will go out and speak to her; I went to the Kitchen-Door, said I, pray, young Woman, do you know me? She came flying towards the Kitchen-Door, with a brass Ladle in her Hand, and said, D - n you for a Bitch, I don't know you, and I do not desire to know you; with that she fell upon me, flung me upon the Ground, tore my Cloaths, struck me, and beat me in a violent Manner with the Ladle, and, I believe, kicked me, but I cannot say positively, being in a Fright, whether she did or no; Lord have Mercy upon me; said I, my Sister (
               <persName id="t17431012-35-person438">
                  Ann 
                  Grignion 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person438" type="surname" value="Grignion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person438" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person438" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) hearing my Voice, and that I cried out; she called to this young Lady (Mrs Kendall) and when they came, there was I lying upon the Ground, my Heels in the Kitchen, my Head in the Passage; said my Sister to the Maid, What have you done to my Sister? She then flew upon her, and fastened her Hands in her Hair - I was bruised so, that I have not been well a Day since.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not do any such Thing; here is a Woman that was in the Kitchen at the same Time, that knows, I did not; I have been in Goal six Weeks to Day for nothing at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-35-person439">
                  Hannah 
                  Fewlis 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person439" type="surname" value="Fewlis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person439" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person439" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had lived with Mrs Kendall, and was there accidentally; when I came, I heard there had been some disobliging Words; my Mistress called to me to fill the Pot, and bid me cut some Bread and Butter; and by that Time I had cut four Pieces, Mrs Wingfield opened the Door, came into the Kitchen, and said, to the Prisoner, Do you know me? Or, how do you know me? I saw the Maid down in a Chair, and Mrs Wingfield was o'top of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear a Bustle?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. Yes, there was a Sort of a Bustle, and presently Mr Waldo and Mrs Wingfield's Sister came.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that at the End of the Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. No, it was at the Beginning of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had Mrs Wingfield been in the Kitchen before you saw this?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. I had cut one Piece of Bread and Butter.</p>
               <p>Q. As you were cutting Bread and Butter, how could you see what they did?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. Immediately upon the Lady's coming into the Kitchen, I turned my Face round towards them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Maid doing of?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. She was washing her Dishes - when Mrs Wingfield came in, she was rincing a Plate, and had just sat it down upon the Table; and when Mrs Wingfield asked her, whether she knew her, she said, Get out you Slut.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done next?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. I cannot tell what was done next, for then I turned about to cut another Bit of Bread and Butter.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Maid said, Get out, you Slut, did you turn your Head from them?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did this Fray continue?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. It was only while I was cutting a Piece of Bread and Butter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear a Crying out?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. I heard no crying out, but only a Bustle.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, tell us what you saw of the Matter?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. I saw this Maid thrown down in the Chair, and Mrs Wingfield upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Chair stand?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. The Chair was quite thrown back. - Mrs Wingfield had hold of her, and Mr Waldo was striving to part them, and I went directly to them, and he said I will undo her Hands, and they rose up; and then there was the Lady's Sister, and an Apprentice came into the Kitchen; - All the Bustle was at once.</p>
               <p>Q. What Part of the Room did you see them in?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. It was all at one Place - just by the Kitchen Door.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Defendant, when Mrs Wingfield asked her what she had to say to her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120052"></xptr>Fewlis. At the Sink.</p>
               <p>Q. Then she went to the other End of the Room to Mrs Wingfield, and bid her go out of the Kitchen, and called her Slut ?</p>
               <p>Fewlis. Yes, she did go to her, to be sure - I did not see any Ladle in her Hand - nor hear any Body cry out - nor see any Body upon the Ground; nor any Blows struck at all - there was no body in the Kitchen, besides me and the Maid, when Mrs Wingfield came in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-35-person440">
                  Hannah 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person440" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person440" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person440" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This young Woman, before she went to live with Mrs Kendall, was my Lodger, she was a good Girl, and behaved in a very pretty Manner; I have known her a Year and an half, and all the Neighbours gave her a good Character.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs Wingfield. 
               <persName id="t17431012-35-person441">
                  Hannah 
                  Fewlis 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person441" type="surname" value="Fewlis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person441" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person441" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             says, the Maid was down in the Chair, and you upon her, is that Fact?</p>
               <p>Mrs Wingfield. Upon my Word, I did not see her down, for I was glad to get away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-35-person442">
                  Ann 
                  Grignion 
               <interp inst="t17431012-35-person442" type="surname" value="Grignion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person442" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-person442" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard my Sister (Mrs Wingfield) cry out, and went into the Kitchen, and saw her lying upon the Ground with her Hands up; and, she said, Lord have Mercy upon me; I turned about to the Maid, and said, what have you done to my Sister; upon that she fastened upon me, tore my Cap off, twisted her Hands in my Hair, and did not let me go, till Mr Waldo came into the Kitchen - My Sister had got loose from her then.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Prisoner stand?</p>
               <p>Mrs Grignion. She stood over my Sister with the Ladle in her Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Maid down in the Chair, and your Sister upon her?</p>
               <p>Mrs Grignion. No, she was not down at all, either in the Chair, or otherwise; Mr Waldo was called up to rescue my Sister from her.</p>
               <p>Mr Waldo. I was below in the Shop, and hearing a Noise above Stairs, I went up, and found Mrs Grignion down on the Ground, and the Defendant's Hands in her Hair; and I did, with some Difficulty, get her Hands out of her Hair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Defendant down in a Chair, and Mrs Wingfield upon her?</p>
               <p>Waldo. No, she was standing up against the Wainscot. <rs id="t17431012-35-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> * .</p>
               <p> * The Prisoner had withdrawn her Plea of Not-Guilty, and confessed the Indictment; the Evidence was given in Aggravation: The Court were inclinable to think the Prisoner was disordered in her Senses, or in Liquor; for it did not appear to them, that Mrs Kendal telling Mrs Wingfield, she was about parting with her Maid, Mrs Wingfield was recommending one to her; and the Servant being backward and forward in the Room, heard their Discourse: This however is said to be the Case, and will in some Measure account for this violent Outrage.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17431012-35-punish166" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-punish166" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-35-defend435 t17431012-35-punish166"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17431012-35-punish167" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-punish167" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-35-punish167" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-35-defend435 t17431012-35-punish167"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
