<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-1">
               <interp inst="t17471014-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-1" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-1" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-1-off1-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-1-defend29 t17471014-1-off1 t17471014-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>378. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Chapman 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-defend29" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-defend29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, and the Indictment sets forth, <rs id="t17471014-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               That he, not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, on the <rs id="t17471014-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">16th of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-1-off1 t17471014-1-cd2"></join>, in, and upon 
                     <persName id="t17471014-1-victim30" type="victimName">
                        Jane
                         his 
                        <rs id="t17471014-1-viclabel3" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-1-victim30 t17471014-1-viclabel3"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17471014-1-victim30" type="surname" value="his"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471014-1-victim30" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471014-1-victim30" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-1-off1 t17471014-1-victim30"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , feloniously, and with Malice afore-thought, did make an Assault, and with a certain Pistol charged with Gunpowder, and a leaden Bullet, did discharge and shoot, well knowing the said Pistol to be charged, and on the left part of the breast, near the left Pap, did strike and penetrate, and did give the said Jane one mortal Wound, the breadth of one Inch, and the depth of nine Inches, of which Wound the said Jane instantly died.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was likewise charged a second time by the Coroner's Inquisition with the said Murder.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-1-person31">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17471014-1-person31" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person31" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of the Fact the Prisoner stands charged with ?</p>
               <p>Foster. I happened to be in the House where this unfortunate Accident happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lodge there?</p>
               <p>Foster. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the House?</p>
               <p>Foster. In <placeName id="t17471014-1-crimeloc4">East-Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-1-crimeloc4" type="placeName" value="East-Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-1-crimeloc4" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-1-off1 t17471014-1-crimeloc4"></join>, in the Parish of St John, Wappin.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see ?</p>
               <p>Foster. Please you, my Lord, she was sitting at the Foot of the Bed, with her Child sucking at her Breast.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the Night was this ?</p>
               <p>Foster. It was about a Quarter before five in the Afternoon; I sat just facing of her; it was up two pair of Stairs, on the 9th of September.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Husband?</p>
               <p>Foster. Her Husband had been a board of a Ship for a Fortnight or three Weeks. He comes up; as he got up half way the Stairs, he cry'd, Hollo ! before he came into the Room; he cry'd, Hollo ! two or three times, Are you all dead or alive? So he came immediately into the Room with an empty Quart-Bottle in one Hand, and a Pistol in the other.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say when he came in ?</p>
               <p>Foster. He never said another Word, but shot her dead; she was dead directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give no Reason why he did it?</p>
               <p>Foster. He said nothing. As soon as ever he had shot her, he said, Lord Jesus Christ have Mercy upon me. I have killed my Wife accidentally !</p>
               <p>Q. Did he point the Pistol to her ?</p>
               <p>Foster. He pointed it to her left Breast directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this Man before?</p>
               <p>Foster. My Lord, I believe I know'd him better than eight Years; his first Wife lodged in the House where I lived.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of any Quarrel between them ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140003"></xptr>Foster. If they quarrell'd, they made it up again: She wanted all Necessaries both as to wearing Apparel and every thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Man before this seem to be in his Senses, or out of his Senses?</p>
               <p>Foster. When he was drunk, he was very nonsensical as others.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he when he was sober?</p>
               <p>Foster. I can say nothing of his being out of order.</p>
               <p>Q. At that time was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Foster. He was drunk. After he had shot her, he went down Stairs, and resign'd himself up to this Man 
               <persName id="t17471014-1-person32">
                  Robert 
                  Jefferys 
               <interp inst="t17471014-1-person32" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person32" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. Then he did not stay to take Care of his Wife ?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, my Lord, he went down Stairs directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was design'd by him, or an Accident?</p>
               <p>Foster. Please ye, my Lord, he never said a Word when he enter'd the Room, but he clapp'd the Pistol up to her left Breast.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Pistol touch her Breast?</p>
               <p>Foster. I believe it did.</p>
               <p>Court. Besides those Words, that he made use of, did he seem to be in a great Confusion ?</p>
               <p>Foster. He seem'd to be in a great Confusion when he had done the Murder.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing more,</p>
               <p>Foster. She dy'd immediately, and fell down upon her Knees, with the Child at her Breast, never groan'd nor sigh'd, but was dead in half a Minute.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave himself to his first Wife ?</p>
               <p>Foster. My Lord, he never quarrell'd with his first Wife.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been married to this Wife?</p>
               <p>Foster. He has been married to this Wife seven Years, to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Court. You say he never quarrell'd with his first Wife; did he ever quarrel with this?</p>
               <p>Foster. They might have Words. I did say that she wanted all Necessaries of Life; I speak of all Wearing Apparel, and the like.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-1-person33">
                  Robert 
                  Jefferys 
               <interp inst="t17471014-1-person33" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person33" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Barbar and Peruke-maker. This young Woman is mistaken in the day of the Month, it was on the 16th of September, of a Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. About what Time of the Night was it?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. Between five and six o'Clock, I was sitting by my Door, and I saw the Man with a Bottle in one Hand, and a Pistol in the other.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you saw him before?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. Yes. I saw him go up the Court with a Bottle in one Hand, and the Pistol in the other.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him return?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. In a Minute's Time I heard an Outcry, Jefferys, Jefferys, from the Court.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who it was that cry'd out?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. No, I can't, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Court. You can't say it was him?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I can't, my Lord. Then I immediately ran up the Court, and saw the Prisoner come down with one of his Hands bloody, but which it was I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any Thing in his Hands, either Bottle or Pistol ?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. Nothing, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What might he say?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. Lord, says he, I have kill'd my Wife, I have shot my Wife dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say, how, or why he did it?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. He said he did it accidentally. He said, I have shot my Wife dead, dead. I said, if he had done such an Action as that I should not part with him. He said, I will surrender myself to you.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem much concern'd?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. No, my Lord, not much concern'd; he seem'd something in Liquor. I told my Servant to take care of him while I went and got an Officer. I ask'd him, What Business he had with that Pistol? And he told me, that the Mate of a Ship had set him on Shore with it, to have a Rammer put to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any Thing else?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. He told me, that he had try'd to let it off two or three Times, as he came along, but it would not go of.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known this Man ?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I have known him some time, but I never chang'd two Words with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he out of his Senses?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I take it, if he was out of his Senses he would not be sit for the Business he was in, but I believe the People were necessitated pretty much.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-1-person34">
                  Edward 
                  Newy 
               <interp inst="t17471014-1-person34" type="surname" value="Newy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person34" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the chief Mate of the Ship where this Man was; he was an Officer on Board of us for some time.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Man ?</p>

               <p>Newy. I know nothing of the Murder. This Man said, I gave him a Pistol to get a Rammer put to it which I did not; he was boarded about eight or ten Days before this happen'd. He came on Board at Evening commonly, and I observ'd when he came on Board he came often in Liquor, and he would talk a little at random.</p>
               <p>Isabella Newland. He (the Prisoner) came up the Court with a Bottle in one Hand, and a Pistol in the other, but he did not say any Thing to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him come back again?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140004"></xptr>Newland. He came back again in about two Minutes Time, and cry'd out, he had shot his Wife undesignedly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem to be under a great Concern?</p>
               <p>Newland. Yes, he seem'd in a great Confusion.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any Thing more ?</p>
               <p>Newland. No more my Lord, but that he had shut his Wife undesignedly. Mr Jefferys laid hold of him, and I went and took up the Deceased, which was shot through her Breast, with her Child under her Arm.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17471014-1-person35">
                  John 
                  Eades 
               <interp inst="t17471014-1-person35" type="surname" value="Eades"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person35" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. At the Time the Coroner's Inquest sat, I was sent for on the Saturday, and I found the Wound just above the left Breast penetrared into the Thorax; and I found another where the Ball went through. I apprehend the Pistol I was clapp'd close to her Breast, because the Skin was burned for about two Inches round the Wound; the Skin was like a Parchment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17471014-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-1-verdict5" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
