<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450227-17">
               <interp inst="t17450227-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450227-17" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450227-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450227-17" type="date" value="17450227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450227-17-off83-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-defend183 t17450227-17-off83 t17450227-17-verdict89"></join>
         
               <p>177. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450227-17-defend183" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Reese 
                  <interp inst="t17450227-17-defend183" type="surname" value="Reese"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-defend183" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-defend183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17450227-17-defloc82">St. Mary Lestrand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450227-17-defloc82" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Lestrand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450227-17-defloc82" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-defend183 t17450227-17-defloc82"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17450227-17-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450227-17-victim185" type="victimName">
                           Andrew 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17450227-17-victim185" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450227-17-victim185" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450227-17-victim185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-off83 t17450227-17-victim185"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him a mortal wound with a certain piece of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174502270013"></xptr> wood called a cooler oar, upon the hinder part of the head, near the left ear, of the length of one inch and a quarter, and the breadth of half an inch
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450227-17-cd84" type="crimeDate">January 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-off83 t17450227-17-cd84"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450227-17-person186">
                  Henry 
                  Elers 
               <interp inst="t17450227-17-person186" type="surname" value="Elers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-person186" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased was a <rs id="t17450227-17-deflabel85" type="occupation">
                     <rs id="t17450227-17-viclabel86" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-victim185 t17450227-17-viclabel86"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-defend183 t17450227-17-deflabel85"></join> of mine, and so is the Prisoner. About six weeks ago in the morning I was in the boiling-house (I am a sugar refiner, I live in <placeName id="t17450227-17-crimeloc87">the Savoy</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450227-17-crimeloc87" type="placeName" value="the Savoy"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450227-17-crimeloc87" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-off83 t17450227-17-crimeloc87"></join>) I was with them two hours, from eight to ten, and did not hear of any dispute between them: when I came home between two and three o'clock, I heard of this misfortune that had happened. The deceased was a <rs id="t17450227-17-viclabel88" type="occupation">pan-man, a superior workman, and had double the wages of the Prisoner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450227-17-victim185 t17450227-17-viclabel88"></join>. I heard that this happened about twelve or one o'clock, when nobody was there but themselves. I went up to the deceased and spoke to him as he lay upon the bed, but he was not able to give me any answer with relation to what had happened.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the deceased in his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Elers. He was always addicted to quarrelling, but as to the Prisoner, during the time he lived with me, he always behaved civilly, and was not given to quarrel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450227-17-person187">
                  Daniel 
                  Deickman 
               <interp inst="t17450227-17-person187" type="surname" value="Deickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-person187" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (surgeon.) On the 22d of January I was called between two and three in the afternoon to visit a patient who was very much hurt, and they believed the man was dying. I made haste, and found the patient in a dangerous condition; the blood ran out at his left ear, and out at his mouth too: upon the left side of his head behind the ear there was a contusion wound, of an inch and a quarter in length, and half an inch in breadth. I asked the deceased how he came by this misfortune, but he would give me no answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in a condition to speak?</p>
               <p>Deickman. It will come by and by. I asked the people of the house how he came by that wound; they said he was fighting with the Prisoner at the bar. I asked the Prisoner if he had not given him this dangerous blow, and told him, I was afraid the man would die: the Prisoner answered me, he was very sorry for it if he should die, but he could not help it, for the deceased struck him twice before he struck him again. I asked the deceased, whether it was true what the Prisoner said; the deceased would not answer me the question, but doubled his fist, and said, Hounsfoot , (that is a word of resentment) and I believe if he had had strength he would still have sought with him; so the Prisoner himself said, Did not you strike me twice before I struck you? he would not answer that question neither, but repeated Hounsfoot. When he was in bed he vomited a vast quantity of blood; the convulsions seized him so strong, that three or four men could not hold him. I told Mr. Elers how it was, and desired he would send for another surgeon; so Mr. Pye was called, but he only assisted me; so we consulted, and I scalped his head in order to have trepanned him the next day, but he died that night.</p>
               <p>
             The same as if he had called him dog in English. The deceased was a Swede.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think by the manner in which he pronounced the word Hounsfoot twice, that he could have spoke more if he had pleased?</p>
               <p>Deickman. Yes; I believe he could; for he asked afterwards, whether his master was come home.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend the contusion was occasioned by a blow or by a fall?</p>
               <p>Deickman. I believe it was by a blow, for he vomited so much blood, that I believe the internal sinus was broke.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the blow was given by a fist or by an instrument?</p>
               <p>Deickman. I believe it was given by an instrument: the Prisoner had a hurt upon his hand, - it was done by an instrument to be sure.</p>
               <p>Elers. There were two wooden oars broke - they are things that we stir the sugars with. <rs id="t17450227-17-verdict89" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450227-17-verdict89" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> of the murder, and acquitted on the Coroner's Inquisition.</p>
               <p>The Jury found that the deceased died a natural death by the visitation of God.</p>
            </div1>
