<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-26">
               <interp inst="t17400903-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-26" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-26" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-26-off172-c185" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-defend222 t17400903-26-off172 t17400903-26-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>394. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Rachael 
                     North 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-defend222" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-defend222" type="given" value="Rachael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-defend222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-26-defloc171">St Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-defloc171" type="placeName" value="St Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-defloc171" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-defend222 t17400903-26-defloc171"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-26-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, val. 3 l. from the Person of 
                     <persName id="t17400903-26-victim223" type="victimName">
                        Samuel 
                        Ellington 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-victim223" type="surname" value="Ellington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-26-victim223" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-26-victim223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-off172 t17400903-26-victim223"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17400903-26-cd173" type="crimeDate">August 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-off172 t17400903-26-cd173"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person224">
                  Samuel 
                  Ellington 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person224" type="surname" value="Ellington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person224" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of August, I had been in the City about a little Business, and as I was coming home, between 11 and 12 at Night, the Prisoner met me, just by <placeName id="t17400903-26-crimeloc174">Kingsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-crimeloc174" type="placeName" value="Kingsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-crimeloc174" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-off172 t17400903-26-crimeloc174"></join> , in <placeName id="t17400903-26-crimeloc175">Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-26-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-26-off172 t17400903-26-crimeloc175"></join>, and catch'd me by my Right-hand, - How do you do, says she? Pretty well, says I; shall we buss, says she? No; get away, or I'll lay my Stick over your Back. No; you won't, says she, and immediately she clapped hold of the Chain of my Watch, drew it out, and ran away with it, as soon as she had got it. I felt it go at once. I pursued her about 20 Yards, or somewhat less, and caught hold of her; which I had no sooner done, but 3 Fellows came from the other Side of the Way, and one of them struck me on the Forehead, with so much Violence, that it immediately swelled up as big as my Fist. They knock'd me down, and beat my Hatt off. As soon as I was recovered, I saw her running off, so I pushed from the Men, and got hold of her again, and called out for the Watch, as hard as I could call. I resolved I would not loose my hold, nor let her go, but the Fellows came up again to me, and swore d - n my Bl - d they would beat my Brains out, if I did not let her go. However, I held her till the Watch came up to my Assistance; for in her running from me. She happened to run nearer the Watch-house: and I held her till I got her there. As soon as I had got to the Watch-house, one of the Men, who used me ill in the Street, cry'd out, d - n him, he has lost no Watch, search him. Aye, says the Pri- soner, search him, and I will be searched too. Up- on this, I felt down my Pockets, and found my Watch in my Left-hand Coat-pocket. Then one of the Men, who was on the outside of the Door, clapp'd himself between the 2 Doors of the Watch-house, and swore she should not stay there, for there was no Constable, (he said) and she should not be stopped there. I bid the Watchmen take Care of the Door, and then the Constable was sent for. The Watch was found before the Constable came.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if he charged me with any Thing, before the Constable of the Night?</p>
               <p>Ellington. Yes, I alledged she had robbed me of my Watch: my Hat was lost in the Skirmish.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you in Drink?</p>
               <p>Ellington. I had been drinking, but was not drunk.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you complain that you had lost your Hat in the Scuffle, which cost 10 s. and say, - if I would give you 5 s. you would make it up?</p>
               <p>Ellington. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person225">
                  John 
                  Mackerel 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person225" type="surname" value="Mackerel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live by Bloomsbury, in Holborn, near the Place where this happened. I was coming home that Night, about a Quarter after 10, and hearing the Prosecutor cry out, I ran up to him, and found he had hold of the Prisoner. There was one 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person226">
                  John 
                  Mar 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person226" type="surname" value="Mar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person227">
                  Clem 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person227" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person227" type="given" value="Clem"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there at the same Time. Webb said, d - n you, what Business have you with the Woman? d - n you, you shan't hold her. Ellington said he had lost his Hat first; then, that he had lost his Watch. D - n you, says one of the Men, you're a Fool, you don't know what you've lost; you have lost nothing, and you shan't hold the Woman: So they all cross'd the Way, and went about 5 or 6 Yards farther; and then they rescued the Prisoner from the Prosecutor; cursing him at the same Time, and telling him, if he did not let the Woman go, they would knock his Brains out. Marr said this, and he had a Poker in his Hand, about 2 Foot long at the same Time. Webb said the same, and that if the Prosecutor would not let the Prisoner go, he would lick him. So they rescued her from him, and she ran away about 20 Yards, but he followed, and caught her, and pushed her into the Watch-house. The Constable not being there, they swore she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030026"></xptr> should not stay there; for they said, he had no Authority to keep her; and Marr, with the Poker, opened the Half-door, and put the Poker in, to get it open. I saw the Prosecutor had had a Blow; he had a Lump upon his Head, near as big as a Goose-Egg, but I can't tell who gave it him. I went into the Watch-house with him; and was there when the Constable came: The Prosecutor charged her, before him, with taking his Watch. When I first came up to him in the Street, he was feeling for his Watch with one Hand, and held the Prisoner with the other; and after he had felt about him, he said he had lost his Watch. The Constable came in 10 Minutes after he got her into the Watch-house, and he said, he had lost his Hat, but he did not charge her with that, only with his Watch. I don't remember what the People said in the Watch-house; but when he came in there, his Coat Pocket stood open, and in a little Time, he found it in that Pocket. I believe they might slip the Watch into it. Neither of the Men who took the Woman's Part were then in the Watch-house; only an old Man they call the Governour of the Watch-house, the Prisoner and the Prosecutor were there at that Time: I was close to the Door, but afterwards I went in.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not the Prosecutor in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Mackarel. I never saw the Prosecutor before that Time, in my Life. Upon my Oath I don't know that he was fuddled; he had been drinking he said, but I did not observe that he was fuddled. The Blow perhaps might disorder him a little just then, but in a Quarter of an Hour afterward, he was as well as any Man in the World.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was he not willing to make it up, if I would give him Five Shillings for the Loss of his Hat?</p>
               <p>Mackarel. There was one of the Men threaten'd to go to Law with him, and the Man seemed not to know what to do. I did not hear him offer to make it up, but I heard them offer him Money for that purpose, and he did not say he would take it. As to his Hat I never saw it at all; it was gone before I saw him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How did the Prosecutor at that Time say he was attacked?</p>
               <p>Mackarel. He said he came from the Cock-Inn, in Aldersgate-street, and gave exactly the same Account of the Thing, as he has done now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person228">
                  John 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person228" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 10 and 11 I was standing at my own Door, just by Kingsgate-street , in Holborn, and hearing an Outcry , and a Noise, I went to see what was the Matter. And about 2 or 300 Yards from my Door, I observed 2 or 3 Men with a Woman, who was striving to get away. One Man insisted upon keeping her, and would not let her go; but 3 Men endeavoured to get her off. He that held her, said she had robbed him of his Hat and his Watch. I stood a little while, and saw a lusty Man, pretty well dressed, who said she should go, - this was at the End of Kingsgate-street , and as she was going to the Watch-house, he said, she should go away, for there was no proper Officer to detain her there. The Man that held her in Custody, said, he was an Officer himself. The other Men said he had no Power to take her, or detain her, because the Cause was his own. I made answer, and said, - every Man is an Officer to detect a Thief; upon which they were silent a little, and the Woman immediately ran away from him. I imagine the Man was held while she elop'd, but he followed her sharply, and caught her again. Then I went home to my own House; but hearing a Tumult again, I ran cross the Way, and found the Men were holding him who would have kept the Woman, and she ran away from him the second Time. But some of the People saying if she was a Thief, she ought to be brought to Justice, she was at last got to the Watch-house. What passed there I know not, for I then went home again. I never saw the Prisoner before that Night, but I am pretty sure she is the same Person. I have no Doubt but she is the same. The Man, I am positive, said, he had lost his Hat and his Watch; but he charged her with taking his Watch only.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did the People, who were with me, pretend to be my Acquaintance?</p>
               <p>Mr Ball. No; but I apprehend they were her Acquaintance.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was the Prosecutor drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Mr Ball. Upon my Oath I apprehend he was sober, and that's what I would not say for any Man in England, if I thought he was not so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person229">
                  Thomas 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person229" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person229" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - I don't know the Prisoner, if I was to see her; so I have no Occasion to look at her. All I have to say is, that on Thursday Se'ennight, in the Evening, I was in Company with Samuel Ellington, at the Cock-Inn in Aldersgate-street. I parted with him at the Gate about 10 o'clock, and he was very capable of going Home; - I know he was very sober.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Quantity of Liquor did you drink?</p>
               <p>Barret. Why some Men drink more, others drink less; - I believe we had a Shilling a-piece in Punch, and some Beer, I believe: but he (upon my Oath) is a Man not given<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030027"></xptr> to drinking. He was capable of going Home, I do assure you.</p>
               <p>Mr Smith, the Master of the Cock-Inn, gave much the same Account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person230">
                  James 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person230" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person230" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was not there when the Fact was committed; but I was at Moore the Constable's, the next Day, with the Prosecutor, and the Prisoner was there at the same Time. When we had talk'd there a little while, in came one 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person231">
                  John 
                  Gascoigne 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person231" type="surname" value="Gascoigne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person231" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he sollicited for the Prisoner, and in her Presence would have had the Prosecutor to have made up the Affair, but he refused. I asked her whether she was a marry'd Woman? She told me she was a Widow; but when she was before Colonel De Veil, she said she was a marry'd Woman ; that her Husband was a Soldier, and followed some Business in Leadenhall-Market , and that she was not willing, on that Account, to be expos'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I happened to be at Mr Harris's House in Holborn, till 10 at Night, and was going Home. The Prosecutor came up to me in the Street, and insisted upon my going with him. I refused; he seemed drunk, and said he was an Officer. I told him I was a very honest Woman, and never went with a Man in my Life; but he took hold of my Handkerchief, and began to be rude; upon which I cry'd out, and some Gentlemen came up, and asked him what he wanted with me, and if he had lost any Thing? First, he said he had lost his Handkerchief, afterwards he had lost his Watch, and the Minute he came into the Watch-house, he pulled it out of his Pocket. Then the Gentlemen called him Rogue, and asked him how he could serve the Poor Woman so, when he had got his Watch? He said he had nothing to alledge against me, but he had lost his Hat among the Mob, and I should give him a Crown, for it cost him 10 Shillings. A Man afterwards came into the Watch-house, and persuaded him to swear for the Sake of the Reward *.</p>
               <p>* In this Case there was no Reward at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person232">
                  Clement 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person232" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person232" type="given" value="Clement"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember the Prosecutor. This Day Fortnight in the Evening, I saw him at the End of Kingsgate-street a little after 10. He had got that Woman there, - I believe, - I never saw her before, - till Yesterday, - I believe it to be that Woman. - It was very Moonlight; - He had her by the Handkerchief, and 3 or 4 People were with her. I believe there were 3 Men with her, - I will take upon me to say there were 3 Men with her: and I coming along, asked what was the Matter, seeing a Man hold a Woman by the Throat, and the Prosecutor was drunk at the same Time. He said the Woman had robbed him, and had robbed him of his Hat. There were 2 or 3 Gentlemen more with me, and I said, Gentlemen, Which Way possible could the Woman rob the Man of his Hat? I asked him, Which Way he lost his Hat? With a good deal of Discourse, he signified, that he intended to be very free with her; then I concluded, that his attempting to be rude with her, might occasion his Hat to be dropped. I said, Why don't you loose the Woman and look for your Hat? He said, D - n her, he was a Constable of St Giles's, and would not loose her; but drew her over the Way to a Soap-Boiler's Shop, and there by the Perswasion of the People, and of me among the rest, - we persuaded him to let her go, that she might go to the Round-House. Accordingly we went, to go to the Round-House, and the Woman ran away from him, just above Queen-street. When he was got on the other Side Queen-street, the Woman was gone a little Way before. Then he said, d - n her, he had lost his Watch, and immediately he ran after her, and catch'd her by both her Hands, and pull'd her into the Round-House. There was an Old Man, who they call the Round-house-keeper, he let them in. She told him, she had not his Watch; I will be searched, says she, - or search me, - one or the other. Accordingly she goes to search her self, and in searching herself, she said, let somebody search him, and see if his Watch is not about him. Then he searched himself, and I believe it was out of his Left-hand Coat or Waistcoat Pocket, - I can't tell which, - he pull'd out his Watch. After this, I wanted to get into the Round-house, but the Old Man who keeps it would not let me come in, but sent away for a Constable. The Constable I happened to know, and so I was let in: after which there was Brawling and Noise for an Hour, and to no Effect, for the Prosecutor was so drunk, that what he said one Minute, he did not know the next. At last he concluded, that if the Prisoner would give him five Shillings, he would excuse her, and let her go about her Business. I should have said, - there was some other People came in, and the Woman would have been clear'd, if they had not perswaded him to charge her, - and that when I asked him how he could lose his Hat with her, he said, he 'went to - (The Witness made Use of a very indecent Expression) and this the Prosecutor admitted, when he was with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030028"></xptr> Woman in the Round house. My Name is Webb, and I am an Ironmonger in Long-Acre.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person233">
                  Thomas 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person233" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person233" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Constable of the Night; this Day fortnight I was sent for, about a Quarter, or Half an Hour after 10, and was told there was a Bustle about a Robbery. Upon which I went down, and found the Prosecutor and the Woman in the Watch-house; Webb was at the Door, and desired to come in; I ordered him to be let in, and then I asked the Prosecutor what he charged the Woman for. He said he had lost his Watch, but found it again in his Pocket. Says I, Do you suspect she took it? I can't say that, and I am sure, (says he) she could not take it, for I held both her Hands. What do you charge her for then? Why, says he, I have lost my Hat, I don't suspect she took it, I believe it was lost in the Scuffle. Then says I, you have nothing to charge the Woman with. No, not I, says he, the Hat cost me Half a Guinea; and if she will give me 5 s. she may go about her Business. I asked him, what he charg'd these Gentlemen for, and Mr Webb? He said, he had nothing to say to them, only begged they would appear next Morning to go before a Justice; but Webb was obliged to go out of Town. After this, by somebody's Perswasion, he persisted in the Charge, and that the Woman should be sent to the Round-House, or some other Prison: she begged to go to the Round-House, and I took the Prosecutor's Word, and Webb's Word 'till next Morning. The Prosecutor said he had got a Knock, and he had received a Blow, but he said he could not tell how he came by it. If it had been given with a Poker, it would have made an Impression in the Man's Head. I did take the Prosecutor to be in Liquor. I have known Webb 20 Years; he is a Man of Worth and Credit.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Ask Moore, upon his Oath, if he did not say in the Watch-house, that he thought the Blow was give me with the Poker?</p>
               <p>Moore. I should have done myself a great deal of Injury to think so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person234">
                  Thomas 
                  Reeve 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person234" type="surname" value="Reeve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person234" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Watch-house, and saw the Prisoner and the Prosecutor there; she ask'd him several Times if he had lost any Thing? He said he had lost his Watch, but that he could not alledge she took it, for he had found it in his Pocket. The Constable asked him over and over, if he had lost any Thing? He told him, he had lost nothing but his Hat, which cost Half-a-Guinea, and if she would give him five Shillings, he would not trouble his Head with her. But there was a Man in the Watch-house would have him insist upon charging her, and said it might be something in his Way. The Prosecutor was pretty much in Liquor to my thinking.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person235">
                  Thomas 
                  Kilburn 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person235" type="surname" value="Kilburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person235" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Constable asked the Prosecutor whether he charg'd the Woman or not? He said, Yes; but I don't know that you have robbed me of any Thing, but I have lost my Hat, and if you'll give me a Crown, I'll release you. He said he had found his Watch in his Left-hand Coat-Pocket; I did not hear him say any Thing about it's having been taken from him. He was so much in Liquor, that if he spoke one Word - in a Minute or two, he could not remember it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-26-person236">
                  John 
                  Marr 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person236" type="surname" value="Marr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave much the same Account with 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person237">
                  Clement 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person237" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person237" type="given" value="Clement"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Sarah Green, 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person238">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Joseph 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person238" type="surname" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person238" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400903-26-person239">
                  Honour 
                  Barrington 
               <interp inst="t17400903-26-person239" type="surname" value="Barrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person239" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Prisoner a good Character. And a Gentleman being called to Webb's Character, said he knew no Harm of him. <rs id="t17400903-26-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-26-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
