<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-1">
               <interp inst="t17441205-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-1" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-1" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-defend30 t17441205-1-off2 t17441205-1-verdict8"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-1-off4-c31" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-defend34 t17441205-1-off4 t17441205-1-verdict8"></join>
         
               <p>1. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Philpot 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Philpot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend30" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend30" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of the Parish of <placeName id="t17441205-1-defloc1">St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-defend30 t17441205-1-defloc1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17441205-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch with a stone seal set in silver, of the value of 3 l. 3 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441205-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Audrey 
                        <interp inst="t17441205-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Audrey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-1-victim32" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-1-victim32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">November 12th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off2 t17441205-1-cd3"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off4 t17441205-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>2. And 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-1-defend34" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Butler 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend34" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend34" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-defend34" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17441205-1-off4" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-off4" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-off4" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-1-person35">
                  Thomas 
                  Audrey 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person35" type="surname" value="Audrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person35" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday was three weeks as I was going from <placeName id="t17441205-1-crimeloc5">St. Giles's pound</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-crimeloc5" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's pound"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-crimeloc5" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off2 t17441205-1-crimeloc5"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off4 t17441205-1-crimeloc5"></join> to <placeName id="t17441205-1-crimeloc6">Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-crimeloc6" type="placeName" value="Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-1-crimeloc6" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off2 t17441205-1-crimeloc6"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-off4 t17441205-1-crimeloc6"></join>, the prisoner, who had followed me from a house where I had been, hugged me round the neck and insisted I should stay with her all night. I told her I had an honest wife of my own, and I would not stay in any shape; then she pulled me down an entry where she lodged, but I would not go in with her; then I missed my watch, which I am certain I had when I went into her company: I took hold of her and kept her in the street above an hour till I could get a Watchman to take care of her; she said I should have my watch again: the prisoner carried me to her house in Brown's Gardens. - I went with her because she promised me my watch. She said I should have my watch again next morning. - I am a <rs id="t17441205-1-viclabel7" type="occupation">Drum-major</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-1-victim32 t17441205-1-viclabel7"></join> in Colonel 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person36">
                  Haughton
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person36" type="given" value="Haughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Company at Gibraltar, and an lately come from thence. I offered to spend 10 s. if she would let me have it, rather than cause any uneasiness between me and my wife, but she would not let me have it; the next morning about 10 or 11 o'clock she was charged, and when she was in the Constable's hands, she owned she took the watch from me: 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person37">
                  Ann 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person37" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person37" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person37" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had the watch in her custody.</p>
               <p>Q. How did 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person38">
                  Ann 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person38" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person38" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person38" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , say she came by the watch ?</p>
               <p>Audrey. She said she had it from the thief that stole it from me. Philpot said before the Justice she did not take the watch by way of designing to keep it, but seeing me in liquor she took it with a design to return it the next morning - She never denied the having it from first to last, and said, I should have it again.</p>
               <p>Philpot. Mr. Audrey was at Mr. Dun bar's's in St. Giles's, and a person came in, and said that my cousin was come to England, and would be glad to see me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she any relation to you?</p>
               <p>Audrey. A great way off.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050003"></xptr>Q. Is she any Kin to you ?</p>
               <p>Audrey. She is no kin at all, I believe, but she pretend to be so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-1-person39">
                  William 
                  Barron 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person39" type="surname" value="Barron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person39" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of November, about 11 or 12 at noon, I was going into St. Giles's with a friend, and in Brown's Gardens the back of Monmouth-street, 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person40">
                  Jane 
                  Philpot 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person40" type="surname" value="Philpot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person40" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Butler were quarrelling ( Butler lives in a sort of a rag shed) about a watch; 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person41">
                  Jane 
                  Philpot 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person41" type="surname" value="Philpot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person41" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person41" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to demand the watch, and Butler would not let her have it; Butler said, I will deliver the watch into any of these Gentlemens hands, but I will not give it to you, for you are a thief; and 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person42">
                  Jane 
                  Philpot 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person42" type="surname" value="Philpot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person42" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person42" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said she had it of a man she met in the street, and lent him half a crown upon it; I said it was a very unreasonable thing to suppose that she should lend half a crown upon a watch; and then she owned she took it from a man in the street, and if Butler would let her have it again, she would return it to the man, and make matters easy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she took it with a design to return it?</p>
               <p>Barron. I did not hear that, she owned she took it out of his pocket; Butler said she would deliver it to any one of us, and we advised her to go into the George, and deliver it to the man of the house; a constable was fetched, and Butler delivered the watch into his hand: when Philpot came before the Justice, she was very impudent. Butler said, she did not design to keep it.</p>
               <p>Philpot. Did you hear me say I stole the watch?</p>
               <p>Barron. You said you picked his pocket of it, and that you would carry it to him again, and make it up with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-1-person43">
                  Christopher 
                  Audrey 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person43" type="surname" value="Audrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person43" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners came next morning to me at Mr. Dunbar's, and Philpot said, I have got your brother's watch, but I did not take it with a design to keep it, but to return it again - she came voluntarily. Butler was very sulky, and said but little. Philpot said to Butler, Deliver the watch to the gentleman of the house; but she would not deliver it. And Philpot said, Hussy, you have got the watch, deliver it. Said Jane, Christopher, don't let 
               <persName id="t17441205-1-person44">
                  Ann 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17441205-1-person44" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person44" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-person44" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             go, but keep her till you have got the watch; and as Philpot came voluntarily to me, I think it shewed she had no design of keeping it - we are related to Philpot at a distance. I have known her from her birth, and I never heard her to be suspected of any theft.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I went to see my cousin Tom, as he had been abroad a great while, and he was glad to see me, and asked me to drink with him when he was going away. I saw he was very much in liquor, and I desired him to leave his watch with Mr. Dunbar; but he would not leave it. And I said, Tommy, we will have another pot of beer; he said, he had no money. Said I, I'll go and pawn your watch for a trifle; for I was willing to get it from him, for fear he should lose it, as the times were very dubious. I took the watch and gave it to Butler. Next morning I went to her, and desired a quartern of gin, and asked her what she had done with the watch. She said she had pawned it. I went to Kit Audrey, and desired him to go with me to Butler's, to get his brother's watch; but she would not deliver it.</p>
               <p>Q Did Philpot desire you to leave your watch with Mr. Dunbar?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes, she did. I was pretty much in liquor. <rs id="t17441205-1-verdict8" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-1-verdict8" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
