<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-41">
               <interp inst="t17421208-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-41" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-41" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-41-off211-c360" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-41-defend439 t17421208-41-off211 t17421208-41-verdict214"></join>
         
               <p>44. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-defend439" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Remue 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-41-defend439" type="surname" value="Remue"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-defend439" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-defend439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17421208-41-defloc210">St John the Evangelist</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-41-defloc210" type="placeName" value="St John the Evangelist"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-41-defloc210" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-41-defend439 t17421208-41-defloc210"></join> , was indicted, that <rs id="t17421208-41-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               he not having the Fear of God, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17421208-41-cd212" type="crimeDate">17th of September, in the Sixteenth Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-41-off211 t17421208-41-cd212"></join>, in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-41-victim441" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Simmonds 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-41-victim441" type="surname" value="Simmonds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-41-victim441" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-41-victim441" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-41-off211 t17421208-41-victim441"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, did feloniously make an Assault, and her, the said Mary, wickedly, unlawfully, and feloniously, carnally did know and abuse, against the Peace, &amp;c. and against the Form of the Statute
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person442">
                  Mary 
                  Simmonds 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person442" type="surname" value="Simmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person442" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person442" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17421208-41-viclabel213" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-41-victim441 t17421208-41-viclabel213"></join> to Mr Bodicoat; my Mistress had been out of Town for two or three Days; on the 17th of September, between Eleven and Twelve at Night, the Prisoner knocked at the Door; I did not ask who was at the Door; I opened the Door, thinking it was my Mistress; but she did not come Home that Night, nor till eleven o'Clock next Day; he asked me whether my Mistress was at Home; I said No, and believed she would not come Home that Night. - My Master was in Bed suddled; I was ironing, and thought to sit up all Night; he came in and sat himself down by the Fire, and when I came to take an Iron out of the Fire, he put his Hand into my Bosom, and used me in a very rude Manner. I desired he would let me alone, and go Home to his Wife; that I thought it much more proper for him and every Man to be at Home. - I knew him by his coming frequently to my Master's and Mistress's House. - Still he continued to use me very ill; and at last laid me down on the Floor, and used me in a very violent Manner.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he use you?</p>
               <p>Simmonds . He forced it into me, and if I had not cried out Murder, he would have drove it into the Soul of me.</p>
               <p>The Necessity of the Case requiring the Prisoner to be very explicit, she gave sufficient Evidence to maintain the Indictment.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080032"></xptr>Q. How did you find yourself afterwards?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. I found myself hurt in such a violent Manner, that I could hardly get to Bed: I was hardly able to wag. - I found myself very bad.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this done by Force, or did you give your Consent?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. It was all Force, I gave no Consent at all .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you acquaint your Mistress with it?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. I acquainted her with it about an Hour after she came Home the next Day. - The Prisoner went away between Twelve and One .</p>
               <p>Q. You say you were very bad, how long did you continue so?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. About a Fortnight .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you complain to any Body?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. To none but my Mistress. - Dr Mead, the Man Midwife, ordered me Medicines upon the Account of this Disorder. After the Prisoner had committed the Fact, he would have had me have promised to have gone with him, or to have met him at the Water-side, either the next Day in the Afternoon (which was Saturday) or Sunday in the Afternoon , or Monday in the Afternoon. - At Millbank ; but I did not go: I said to him, Mr Remue, What! now you have got your Ends of me, you want to murder me. - I do really believe he had a Design to murder me.</p>
               <p>Court. Have you any Questions to ask her?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have Council, and I beg that Gentleman may ask the Questions for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one Mr Debat?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. Yes; he used me very rudely the Thursday before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you complain of what Mr Debat did to you?</p>
               <p>Simmonds . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you complain of a Strain?</p>
               <p>Simmonds . Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, if you were not brought to Bed of a dead Child a little before?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. No. - I am very positive of it. - I never had one.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to say Mr Debat used you ill?</p>
               <p>Simmonds. Because he used me very rudely .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person443">
                  Martha 
                  Roebank 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person443" type="surname" value="Roebank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person443" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Mr Bodicoat's on Saturday Night, the Day she came Home, for I heard that Mrs Boddicoat wanted to speak with me: When I came, she told me, the Girl was ill, and said, she had been ill used; and desired me to go up Stairs; that it was her Opinion, the Girl was ravished. I told her, it was my Opinion that the Girl had miscarried; I nursed her; the Medicines she had , were ordered by Dr Mead, a Man Midwife ; and Medicines I believe proper for such a Case.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she bad?</p>
               <p>Rocbank . I do not think she was very bad after the first Night. - I have been in private with the Prisoner and never saw any Harm by him. - I had Reasons to think it was a Miscarriage. - I am not a Maid, I have had five Children. I hope you will not ask me any Questions that immodest . I have nursed People before in there Cases, and I have been so myself; and for that Reasons I believe it to be a Miscarriage. - I do not know what the Medicines were.</p>
               <p>Mrs Bodicoat . (The Girl's Mistress.) I came Home on the Saturday in the Forenoon, and found the Girl in a very great Disorder. I asked her what was the Matter; she told me, she believed she had over-reached herself; but after some Time, she said, she had undergone a great deal of Fa since I had been gone. Then I asked her, if anybody had been there that had abused her? I taxed her home whether she had not miscarried; for I never saw any body in such a Condition, unless it was a Miscarriage. She said it was no such Thing I threatned to turn her out of Doors if she would not tell me; then she said, Mr Debat had used her very ill the Thursday before; it was a good while before she would tell that the Prisoner had lain with her; but after I had pressed her very hard to tell me, she said, If I must tell you the Truth, it was Mr Remue. - I did not examine her so close as to know whether any Damage had been done to her Body. - She had been with me about two Months, but I have known her four Years, and never knew any Ill of her. - She is a giggling Girl; I never saw any Immodesty by her in my Life - I never had a Miscarriage my self so I cannot be so good a Judge as those that have.</p>
               <p>Isabella Walker . I never knew any thing of Dishonesty by her, and have known her from a Child down to this Time, and she always behaved me destly .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person444">
                  Ursula 
                  Major 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person444" type="surname" value="Major"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person444" type="given" value="Ursula"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person444" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The young Woman was in at my House the Night before this Thing happened, and was as well as ever I saw her in my Life. The Prosecutrix sent a little Boy for me next Morning, after this Thing happened; I found her very she told me her Mistress was not at Home, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080033"></xptr> desired me to get her something to do her good; I told her I could not do her any good.</p>
               <p>Mrs Handford. I was sent for to 
               <persName id="t17421208-41-person445">
                  Mary 
                  Simmonds 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person445" type="surname" value="Simmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person445" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person445" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a married Woman, and have had three Children, so I know what Condition she was in: I found her in a very bad Way; there was a Flooding by her Bed-side, and great Clods of Blood, which no body, but Women that have been married, can know any thing of. It is my Opinion, she had been ill used by some Man. - I never saw any Thing ill by the Girl in my Life. She has lived by me but a little while. - Her Mistress came Home about Eleven o'Clock on Saturday Morning, and asked me how she did; I told her as I have related it.</p>
               <p>Mrs Handford cross-examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you found her in a very bad Way, do you mean from the Effect of a Miscarriage, or from what?</p>
               <p>Handford. No, I do not mean from a Miscarriage; I know nothing of any Miscarriage; I believe it was from being forced.</p>
               <p>Q. Might there not have been the same Consequences attending the lying with a Man, if it was done by Consent, as if it had been done by Force?</p>
               <p>Handford. Indeed, Sir, I never had the Trial of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person446">
                  Ursula 
                  Major 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person446" type="surname" value="Major"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person446" type="given" value="Ursula"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Opinion is, that it was occasioned by Forcing; for I never saw any ill of the Girl in my Life.</p>
               <p>Mr Remue's Defence.</p>
               <p>My Lord, about the 18th or 19th of September last, the Prosecutrix was in a great Disorder, by the great Effusion of Blood. Here are two Persons who were sent for by the Prosecutrix, and they were the first Persons that examined her, and asked her the Occasion of the Disorder; she said, she had over-strained herself by lifting an Ox's Head. They told her they thought it incredible, that such a great Flow of Blood should come from a Strain; and believed that she had miscarried, and very much pressed her to tell the Truth. She said she had not miscarried, and that no Man had ever lain with her. Mrs Handford and Mrs Sampson know this, and they said her Case was so bad, as to require the Opinion of a Man-Midwife: Accordingly they sent for Dr Mead, and he gave his Opinion, that she had miscarried. When she found they could not be persuaded to believe that it was a Strain, she acknowledged, that a Day or two before, 
               <persName id="t17421208-41-person447">
                  James 
                  Debat 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person447" type="surname" value="Debat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person447" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Butcher, came into the House, tied down the Latch of the Door, pushed her into a Chair, and had to do with her, and broke the Chair in committing the Violence; and Women, who are experienced in Child-bearing, say, that if there had been Violence committed, it is impossible that could be the Cause of such an Effusion of Blood. They told her they believed she had had a Child, and that she had secreted the Child, and believed the Child might be at seven or eight Months Growth. This Mrs Boddicoat and others have consulted how to fix it upon me, because I had been pretty much backward and forward in the House, and in order, as I believe, to extort some Money from me. They sent for Dr Mead; when they told him of it, he said it proceeded from a Miscarriage: When they talked to him of the Prosecution , he said it would be a most enormous Case and a Sin, and the Indictment must of Consequence fall to the Ground. They said, we shall never be able to make our selves Satisfaction, without commencing a Suit against him; and so these People swore against me, and indictment me here. I beg Leave to observe another Thing; they have made Overtures from Time to Time, that if I would give them any Thing for Satisfaction, as they pretended, for their Charge and Trouble, the Prosecution should be stifled ; and 
               <persName id="t17421208-41-person448">
                  Martha 
                  Roebank 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person448" type="surname" value="Roebank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person448" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person448" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, they would take five Guineas, of which Mrs Boddicoat was to have one Guinea, and the Girl four; and on Sunday Night they sent Mr Barnes to Mrs handford, and told her Mrs Boddicoat was miserable poor, and that they wanted something to support themselves, and if I would give four or five Guineas, there should be no Prosecution.</p>
               <p>Lody Handford. I was desired to go to Mrs Boddicoat's, and I went there; I was the first Person that took this Creature's Information with Relation to the Affair; said I, Mary, what is the Matter with you? She said, I have lifted an Ox's Head, and have done my self a great deal of Damage; but I believe it was a Miscarriage; I have had a Miscarriage my self: This Flowing was in such a Quantity, that no body, unless it was a Woman that miscarried, or was delivered of a Child, could have so much. I was a Maid once, and was married pretty soon, about Fourteen Years of Age, and I never knew the like, but in these Cases. Molly, said I, How can this be? I am sure you have known a Man for it is a Thing quite contrary to Nature, without you have known Man; and I am afraid there is a Murder at the Bottom. - This was the next Day, between Nine and Ten o'Clock, on Saturday Morning; she said, as God should judge her, she never knew any Man in her Life:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080034"></xptr> Said I, Hussey , you are a Liar; and I told her, my Lord, it could not be so with her without a Child or a Miscarriage, and I believe a very large Miscarriage: She would not own any Thing with respect to the Prisoner at the Bar for a good while: She said one Debat , a Butcher, had to do with her one Afternoon; that he pushed her into the Parlour, tied down the Latch of the Door, and broke a Chair in the doing it: I still persisted in it that it was a Miscarriage. Well , said she, if you must have the Truth , I will tell you; it was Debat; and to tell you the Truth, he has been great with me ever since I came into the House. Her Mistress said, I always told you, Debat was an impudent Fellow. I will speak the Truth for I think it is a Pity an innocent Man should suffer; when Dr Mead came into the Room, he said, there was either a Child, or a very large Miscarriage, and after she had abided by this a long Time, that it was Debat, she said, If you must know the Truth, it was Mr Remue. Mr Remue is a very modest Man: I have a Child here in Court, that I have trusted with him all Parts of the Day, and he never offered any Thing amiss to her in his Life.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any Offers made of taking Money?</p>
               <p>Handford . Yes. - By Mrs Boddicoat and the Prosecutrix; the Prosecutrix said, if he would give her some Money, she would not appear against him; and I said, The Man will not give you a Shilling: I believe Mrs Boddicoat would have been willing to have taken what she was out of Pocket; I have heard her say, she would take ten Guineas, and not trouble herself about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Now as you have had a Miscarriage, do you take this to be the Effect of a Miscarriage?</p>
               <p>Handford. I really do believe it to be so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person449">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sampson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person449" type="surname" value="Sampson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person449" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to see Mrs Boddicoat's Maid; she was in Bed, and I found her a great deal worse than I thought she was; she had concealed a great deal of Blood, her Camblet Gown and Petticoat were spread over the Floor to conceal it; said I, Mary, what is the Matter with your Arm it is so bloody: Says she, I am all over so, I have hurt myself in lifting an Ox's Head. Said I, If you had lifted a whole Bullock, you could not be worse. I turned down the Bed, and that was in a bad Condition; I thought she had been delivered of a Child. I looked all over the Room, into the Cradle and Trunk, and every where, to see if there was a Child concealed. I charged her with making away with the Child, and she protested with a great many Vows, she did not know what a Man was, before the Midwife examined her; then she said, one Debat had forced her into a Room, and fastened the Latch down, &amp;c. They charged her with having a Child, which she denied; but she said, if she must tell the Truth, Mr Debat had to co with her ever since she came to Mrs Boddicoat's ; she said so for a great many Hours, and then she said it was Mr Remue; and Mrs Boddicoat said, if he would give the Girl fifty Pounds, and give her ten Pounds for spoiling the Bed, she would say no more of it.</p>
               <p>Court. Who proposed to take the Money?</p>
               <p>Sampson. I had it from the Mouth of her Mistress; she said the Girl would not make it up under fifty Pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you take this to be the Effect of?</p>
               <p>Sampson. I take it to be the Effect of a Miscarriage; but I never was in the Time of Child-Birth, in so bad a Condition as she was in.</p>
               <p>Dr Mead. On the Saturday, about eleven o'Clock, I went to Mrs Boddicoat's to see the Maid; when I came into the Room, I declared my Opinion, that there had been a Child, or a large Miscarriage; there was a great flooding, and all the Symptoms that could be of it; the Girl protested she had never known Man. I told her, that her Word would signify nothing, there were such Symptoms to the contrary; at length she said one Debat had to do with her; the Bed was so wet with Blood and Water that flows at these Times; there are very few Names for Smells, but there is a very indifferent Smell attending these Cases; there were Cloaths bloody, and Blood in a great Quantity about the Room; it is my positive Opinion, that there was a Child, and that it must be at least seven Months Growth.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any external Appearance besides Blood and Water?</p>
               <p>Dr Mead. No, there was not: I passed my Hand into her Body, and there was nothing unusual.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not the Forcing a Woman such an Effect?</p>
               <p>Dr Mead. Not to the fiftieth Part of what was in this Case.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a Talk of the Prosecution being stopped, if they could have got a Sum of Money.</p>
               <p>Dr Mead . Yes, there was a Talk of fifty Pound . - And something intimated, that if they could get it, it would be the Way for me to be paid, but I never had a Fathing. - I have followed this Business about thirteen Years.</p>
               <p>Q. I think you said you searched her Body?</p>
               <p>Dr Mead. I did so. - She had Clods of Blood in her Shift , she was bloody from the Fingers End to the Elbow, and over the Mons Veneris. -<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080035"></xptr> They wanted me to give a Memorandum, or Note under my Hand, that the Girl was in Danger of her Life: Said I, I will not do any such Thing for an hundred Guineas; they said, Do you think the Girl is able to go abroad? No, said I, And I will give you any Thing under my Hand, that she is not able to go abroad. - But they took her abroad in a Day or two for all they desired that: I really believe it to be an iniquitous Affair.</p>
               <p>Mrs Hoare . I have been acquainted with Mr Remue , about a Year and a half, his Wife is a particular Acquaintance of mine; he has waited for her several Hours, and I never saw any Thing but what was very modest by him, nor ever heard any thing of this Nature before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person450">
                  Frances 
                  Pooley 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person450" type="surname" value="Pooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person450" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person450" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mr Remue seven Years; he lodged with me several Times, and always behaved civilly; I have a Girl about fifteen Years of Age, who has frequently sat with him when I have been out, and he never behaved amiss to her.</p>
               <p>Miss Handford . I have known Mr Remue about three Years. I have been frequently with him a great while together, Morning and Evening, when Nobody has been in the House but him and me, and I never knew him behave amiss, and never heard him talk unhandsomely.</p>
               <p>- Wilcox. I was sent for to the Prosecutrix; I examined her, and found her in a very great Disorder, and that she had either had a Child, or a Miscarriage. I have followed Midwisry four Years, and do not think there could be any Thing like it, if there had not been a Child, or a Miscarriage.</p>
               <p>Miss Pooley. I am about Fourteen Years of Age. I have been frequently with Mr Remue, within these two Years; I have been with him by my self, and he never offered any Thing rude to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-41-person451">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Keate 
               <interp inst="t17421208-41-person451" type="surname" value="Keate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person451" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-person451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three Months; he sometimes spent an Evening at our House, and I never knew him behave amiss.</p>
               <p>Mrs Boddicoat called again.</p>
               <p>Court. Here have been some Witnesses that mention'd Sums of Money being demanded by you; I ask you, whether you ever demanded any Money or not?</p>
               <p>Boddicoat. That Saturday Morning, Mr Remue wanted to speak with that Gentlewoman, and asked how the Maid did? Says she, had enough, Mr Remue; there is but a Span between her and Death: He desired proper Care might be taken of her, and it should be paid for: and that is a very reasonable Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Some of the Witnesses spoke as to the requiring of Money relating to the Prosecution, was there any Thing said about that?</p>
               <p>Boddicoat . I did say, I had not Money to go on with the Prosecution, and the Girl had none, and I was willing to right her if it lay in my Power.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17421208-41-verdict214" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-41-verdict214" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
