<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470604-1">
               <interp inst="t17470604-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-1" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470604"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-1" type="date" value="17470604"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-1-off1-c31" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-defend32 t17470604-1-off1 t17470604-1-verdict5"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-1-off1-c32" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-defend34 t17470604-1-off1 t17470604-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>132, 133. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-defend32" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Dennis 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend32" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend32" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend32" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-defend34" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ryley 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend34" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend34" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-defend34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17470604-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470604-1-victim36" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Holloway 
                        <interp inst="t17470604-1-victim36" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-1-victim36" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470604-1-victim36" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-off1 t17470604-1-victim36"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, in a certain Place called <placeName id="t17470604-1-crimeloc2">White-horse Alley</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-crimeloc2" type="placeName" value="White-horse Alley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-crimeloc2" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-off1 t17470604-1-crimeloc2"></join>, putting her in bodily Fear and Danger of her Life, and taking from her one Cotton Gown, value 10 s. one Pair of Stays, value 3 s. one Handkerchief , value 6 d. one Apron, value 6 d. one Cap laced, value 2 s. &amp;c.
            </rs> the Goods of the said 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person37">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person37" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person37" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person37" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17470604-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">May 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-off1 t17470604-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they both together?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, please your Lordship; I ask't my Way to Queen-street, and they directed me into this White-horse Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they go with you?</p>
               <p>Holloway . They followed me, my Lord, and stript me, they came up, and fell a stripping of me directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they say nothing to you?</p>
               <p>Holloway . They said nothing to me, but fell to stripping of me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this?</p>
               <p>Holloway . It was between the Hours of eleven and twelve at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>

               <p>Holloway . I live in Queen-street in Lincoln's-Inn Fields.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be out so late?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Please your Lordship, I went to see some Friends that were come to Town, at an Inn in Smithfield , they were then upon going out of Town .</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you know your Way into Queen-street ?</p>
               <p>Holloway . No, my Lord, I was a Stranger in London; I am a <rs id="t17470604-1-viclabel4" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-victim36 t17470604-1-viclabel4"></join> in Queen-street to one Mr Sharp .</p>
               <p>Q. Was it Light or Dark?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Please your Lordship it was Star-light.</p>
               <p>Q. Now let us know what they did to you; they stript you, you say, what did they take from you?</p>
               <p>Holloway. They stript my Cap off my Head , and my Gown and Petticoat, and my Handkerchief<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040003"></xptr> from off my Neck, and my Stays, and my Shift from my back. I met the Prisoners in Smithfield the first Day of May, and I ask'd them my Way to Queen-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you cry out?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, my Lord, I cry'd out Murder. They beat me to such a Degree that I was not able to stir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body came to your Assistance?</p>
               <p>Holloway . No, and please your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. What follow'd upon this?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Please your Lordship, I cry'd out Murder; and when nobody came to my Assistance I cry'd out Fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of them and you then?</p>
               <p>Holloway . The Woman d - d me for a B - h, and said, she would kill me. What became of them afterwards I can't say, they run away.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Please your Lordship, I crept into a waste House that was there in the Place. I was ashamed to be seen by any body.</p>
               <p>Q. How do know that these Prisoners at the Bar were the Persons that stripp'd you?</p>
               <p>Holloway . My Lord, I knew them when I saw them again.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to be taken? How came you to find out these Persons?</p>
               <p>Holloway . There were some People came about me the next Day to see me, and they asked me, if I could tell the People that stripp'd me? I said, I could give a Description of the Woman in particular , and of the Gown upon her Back.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you tell the Colour of her Gown?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, she had that Gown on she has now. And I described the Man. I can't say particularly I could discern the Colour of his Coat, but I thought it was dark; and I describ'd him for that same Person he is.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how they came to be taken up?</p>
               <p>Holloway . The People are here that took them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Are any of the Cloaths you were stripp'd of here?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoners. Will either of you ask Mrs Holloway any Questions?</p>
               <p>Dennis the Prisoner. Ask her, if she did not say to the Constable, that she could not swear positively to me, for she was very much in Liquor, for there were four or five of them?</p>
               <p>Holloway . After they struck me in the Eyes I thought there was more, for I saw double; but I believe it was owing to my Eyes.</p>
               <p>Court. The Prisoner asks, whether you was not in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Holloway . No, please your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you tell this too? And, how soon did you tell it?</p>
               <p>Holloway . I told it to the first Person that came to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, in what Manner did you get home to Queenstreet ?</p>
               <p>Holloway . My Mistress was so good as to send me some Cloaths. I sent a Woman that was in this waste House to one 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person38">
                  Sarah 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person38" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person38" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person38" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , an Acquaintance, in Fleetstreet ; but I don't know who the Woman was I sent.</p>
               <p>Q. This waste house you speak of, does nobody live in it? Pray, how did you get any body to you?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Please your Lordship, there were two or three Woman in the waste House, they don't live there, but only they lay there.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know any Thing of these Women ? Are any of them here?</p>
               <p>Holloway . No, my Lord, nor I know nothing of them.</p>
               <p>Court. One of these Women you sent to your Friend.</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Mistress come?</p>
               <p>Holloway . She did not come, but she sent a Woman with the Things.</p>
               <p>Q. What Woman?</p>
               <p>Holloway . One 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person39">
                  Sarah 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person39" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person39" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person39" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What is 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person40">
                  Sarah 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person40" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person40" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? Is she a Servant of your Mistress's?</p>
               <p>Holloway . No, my Lord, she is an Acquaintance of mine: I sent to this 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person41">
                  Sarah 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person41" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person41" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person41" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             first, and she went to my Mistress for me; she lives in Fleetstreet .</p>
               <p>Q. Is she here?</p>
               <p>Holloway. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Court . You had as good send for her, as it is no further, while the other Witnesses are examining .</p>
               <p>Holloway . If you please, my Lord, I can step myself. (The Court desired she would.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040004"></xptr>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person42">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person42" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am the Constable's Beadle; upon the 2d of May, between one and two o'Clock (in the Night) the two Prisoners at the Bar came into the Watch house, and the Woman had a bundle in her Apron, and they call'd for a Tankard of Beer, (our Watch-house is kept in a publick House in Golden lane) and the Woman of the House draw'd them a Tankard of Beer; and while they were drinking the Beer, she heard 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person43">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person43" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person43" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say to Ryley , I am glad you are clear'd from the Old Bailey. And Ryley said, he was clear'd that Afternoon, which was on Friday the first of May. So the Woman of the House call'd to me, and said, I have heard these Persons talking together, I don't like them. While they drink the Tankard of Beer I said, keep the Door fast, don't let them go out. So I said to them, I must examine you before you go; so she broke the Windows, and struck the Watchman; and in the Struggle, having but one Watchman, Ryley made his Escape from us. In about a Quarter of an Hour Ryley came a second time, and we let him go again, and was glad he was gone, for fear he should get Hands and rescue the Woman. Having but one Watchman I detain'd the Woman till between three and four o'Clock, then I carried her down to New Prison; and desir'd the Man, if any Body came to inquire for the Prisoner to let me know, and I would pay him for his Trouble: This was on Saturday Morning, and I think, on Tuesday Morning Ryley was brought by an Officer out of Shoreditch ; I went down to New Prison, and stay'd till the Officer came and brought him there, and went with him to Justice Poulson's ; he own'd the Fact before the Justice, but where to find the Prosecutrix I could not tell . When he came to Justice Poulson's he wanted to make himself an Evidence. Mr Poulson said, what do you want to make yourself an Evidence for? He own'd that he was in Company when the Woman ask'd the Way, and that he beat her. Says Mr Poulson , as the Prosecutrix is not here I can't commit you for this Fact, but I'll send you to Bridewell. In a Day or two's time I inquir'd after the Prosecutrix, and I found her in Queenstreet , at her Mistress's; when she saw the Prisoner Ryley she said, he was the Man that robbed her.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Month was you before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Smith. The 2d of May; and Ryley was taken a Day or two afterwards, and the Prosecutrix pick'd him out among the rest that were in Prison. She was naked from between eleven and twelve o'Clock at Night till the next Day ten o'Clock, then the Neighbours lent her some one thing, and some another; she came to Hicks's Hall about two or three o'Clock in the Afternoon: When she came, says the People, Here's the Woman that was robb'd last Night. I had not a Hearing before the Justice till then.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she robb'd, did she say?</p>

               <p>Smith. In Chick-lane; one End of the Place comes into Chick-lane, and the other into Cow-cross. She said she was robb'd at such a Place of all her Apparel, and abused to a gross Degree; she could scarce see with one Eye, and was very much bruised.</p>
               <p>Q. By the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person44">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person44" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person44" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person44" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I would desire to know, whether 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person45">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person45" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person45" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person45" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to Hicks's Hall or the Alehouse ?</p>
               <p>Smith. She came to Hicks's Hall first. She heard that we were at the Black Bull Alehouse; and when she came to the Alehouse she challeng'd the Shift that was upon the Prisoner's Back ; she challeng'd it, and it is here in the Bundle.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this?</p>
               <p>Smith. It was between two and three o'Clock when the Prosecutrix came up to Hicks's Hall, and she mentioned every particular Thing before she saw them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person46">
                  John 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person46" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other Prisoner, before he was telling the Woman that he was cleared?</p>
               <p>Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person47">
                  Ann 
                  Benbow 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person47" type="surname" value="Benbow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person47" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What do you know of the Prisoners?</p>
               <p>Benbow . On the 2d of May the two Prisoners came into the Watch-house, and they ask'd for a Pot of Beer. The Woman seem'd to have a large Bundle in her Apron. When I draw'd the Pot of Beer I call'd the Beadle to me, and told him, I believ'd they were not very good People, and desired the Beadle to see what she had got in her Apron . He said he would presently;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040005"></xptr> and he sat down in the Box, the other side of them; and I heard the Woman say, that she was very glad he (Ryley) was cleared at the Old Bailey. He made Answer, and said, he had been an Hour upon his Trial. He had been try'd for two Gallon Pots*. The Beadle ask'd to see what she had in her Apron; she obstinately refused; but he did take them, and I saw they had been torn off somebody's Back: The Petticoat was fresh torn in two Places. These were the Goods taken out of her Apron. (The Goods were all produced in Court.) I said, I was afraid there was a Robbery committed, if not a Murder, for the Things did not look as if they belong'd to her. The Prisoner said she would not give any Account of herself.</p>
               <p>* See Sessions Paper in May last, Numb . IV. Part II. Trial 217.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs Holloway. Where did you see the Prisoner with the Shift upon her Back?</p>
               <p>Holloway . At the Justice's House, and he ordered me to take her into the Garden and take it off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the Alehouse? Had she the Shift on there?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, she had it there, but it was taken off in the Justice's Garden.</p>
               <p>(The Shift produc'd in Court.)</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person48">
                  Ann 
                  Benbow 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person48" type="surname" value="Benbow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person48" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . You saw the Goods open'd?</p>
               <p>Benbow . Yes, and I insisted upon the Beadle's taking her into Custody. She would not let him have the Things for some time; she struggled and broke the Windows. She was carried to Prison about three o'Clock. I am certain she is the Woman; she was in my House from a Quarter after one to a Quarter after three. Ryley was there, and he said, she was his Wife , and he had given her 6 s. the Night before. Ryley and the Woman came together.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say with respect to Ryley ?</p>
               <p>Benbow . He said, she was his Wife, and he gave her 6 s. the Night before. He seem'd to be frighten'd and in a hurry, and went out under a Pretence to call somebody to give an Account of the Things. He went out and came in again, and went out again. The Woman behaved in such a Manner that she frighten'd us out of our Wits.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing further?</p>
               <p>Benbow . I heard Ryley say before Justice Poulson, he was willing to make himself an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Name of that Man that took him up?</p>
               <p>Benbow . He lives at the Gun in Kingstand Road . When I said there was some Mischief done; Ryley said, What had any Body to do if he tore all his Wife's Cloaths off her Back.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person49">
                  John 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person49" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Austin. I am a Watchman in Golden-lane; on the 2 d of May last, after I had been beating my Rounds, I came into the Watch-house and I saw the two Prisoners at the Bar; the Woman was very turbulent, she was fighting, and broke the Windows, and I found it was about the Beadle's examining her Bundle that she had. She was very unruly, and the young Fellow slipt out, but we kept her there till the Watch was broke up, and then we carried her to New-Prison, and in the Morning, about nine o'Clock, we went to fetch her out of Prison to carry her before a Magistrate, and being Sessions time we had her to Hicks's Hall, but we could not have a Hearing before the Afternoon; and there came a Woman and ask'd, if a young Woman was not there taken up for a Robbery in Chick-lane? When the Woman saw the Prisoner, she said to her, You Jade, how could you abuse the Woman so? She is at my House almost murdered. She is in Bed and was almost naked. I said to the Woman, she must be fetch'd, and they brought Mrs Holloway the Prosecutrix, and she was in a deportable Condition; she had two black Eyes, and her Forehead bruised, and when she saw the Woman Prisoner, she swore to her as the Woman that had robb'd her; and she burst out a crying, and said, that is my Shift you have upon your Back. Then we went to Justice Poulson and had a Hearing there, and she swore to the Things there as also to the Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing of this Ryley?</p>
               <p>Austin . He was taken the 5th of May in Shoreditch ; and when he was taken he was carried<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040006"></xptr> before Justice Poulson , and he wanted to make himself an Evidence; says the Justice, I have Evidence enough already; but let us hear what you have to say, Please ye, my Lord, says he, (to tell you the Truth) on Friday in the Afternoon I was acquitted at the Old Bailey, and I went to the Twopenny House in Chick-lane, and got myself a little in Liquor, and I and the other Prisoner met the Prosecutrix, and she ask'd us the Way, and we directed her up that Alley .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-person50">
                  Henry 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person50" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person50" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman, I know nothing more, than that I help'd to carry 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person51">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person51" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person51" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to New Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person52">
                  Mary 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person52" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person52" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-person53">
                  Mary 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person53" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person53" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In White Fryars , by the Glass-house , Mrs Holloway had lodg'd with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know of this Affair?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-person54">
                  Mary 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person54" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person54" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person54" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came to see us on May-Day, being Country-folks, and went from me about nine o'Clock. I parted with her at my own House, but we heard the next Day she was not got home. Her Mistress came to my House the next Morning to see for her; and I said I knew nothing of her. She went from my House, and the next News I heard of her was, that she was robb'd and stripp'd, and beat near to Death; I went to see her, and saw her in that Condition, and sent her this Gown to come home in.</p>

               <p>Court to the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person55">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person55" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person55" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , What have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Dennis. I was coming Home about eleven o'Clock, and I met 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person56">
                  John 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person56" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; he ask'd me where I was going; and he ask'd me to go to drink a Pint of Beer with him: He said he was going with these Things to assist his Mother in her illness . He said, if I would go with him he would give me a Shift and Six-pence besides. I being willing to earn Six-pence I went along with him. We went up Golden-lane, and we drank some Beer; and there happen'd to be a young Woman that knew 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person57">
                  John 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person57" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . There happening a few Words, the Woman told him he was try'd at the Old Baily. After we went to go out she stopp'd me to see what was in my Lap. 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person58">
                  John 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person58" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             trod upon my Toe, and told me not to let them see them; and when they look'd at the Things they said, they had been torn off some Woman's back; so Ryley said, what had they to do if he did tear them from his Wife?</p>
               <p>Q. to Ryley . What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Ryley . I was going Home disguised in Liquor. I did not know where I was, I never saw the Creature nor the Things till I was before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470604-1-person59">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person59" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person59" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17470604-1-person60">
                  John 
                  Ryley 
               <interp inst="t17470604-1-person60" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , both <rs id="t17470604-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17470604-1-punish6" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-1-punish6" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-defend32 t17470604-1-punish6"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-1-defend34 t17470604-1-punish6"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
