<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-1">
               <interp inst="t17431012-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-1" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-1" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-1-off2-c27" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-defend27 t17431012-1-off2 t17431012-1-verdict4"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-1-off2-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-defend29 t17431012-1-off2 t17431012-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>461. 462. + 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-defend27" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend27" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend27" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend27" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Russel 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend29" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-defend29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17431012-1-defloc1">St Brides</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St Brides"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-defend27 t17431012-1-defloc1"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-defend29 t17431012-1-defloc1"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17431012-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431012-1-victim31" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Tomkins 
                        <interp inst="t17431012-1-victim31" type="surname" value="Tomkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-1-victim31" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-1-victim31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-off2 t17431012-1-victim31"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him three Guineas and an half, and 2 s.
            </rs> the Money of the said 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person32">
                  John 
                  Tomkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person32" type="surname" value="Tomkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person32" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17431012-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">Sept. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-1-off2 t17431012-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person33">
                  John 
                  Tomkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person33" type="surname" value="Tomkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 18th of September last, about 11 o'Clock at Night, by Fleet-Lane, 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person34">
                  Robert 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person34" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person34" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Chimney-sweeper, came up to me first and seized me, and held me fast round the Body, while 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person35">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person35" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person35" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the Money out of my Pocket; Russel run away, and then Stevens endeavoured to throw me down.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen Stevens before?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. He forced himself into my Company in a House, and scraped Acquaintance with me, and said he knew my Mother, and desired me to give him a Glass of Liquor; which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Russel do to you?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. Russel put his Hand into my Pocket, and took out three Guineas and an half, and some Silver, and run away. Stevens afterwards run away, I pursued him and took him, and told him, they had got my Money; he said he had not, but he would carry me to the Person who had it; we went into George-Yard, and when I came there, Russel knocked me down; and by the Ball in George-Alley, I was knocked down again and beat, so that I could not see out of my Eyes for several Days.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they any Weapons with them?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. I do not know, but I received a Wound across my Hand, which seemed to be like the Cut of a Knife.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know these were the Persons?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. Stevens was never out of my Sight.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Was not you drinking with us at a Brandy-Shop, and proposed to lay a Wager?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. We were there, and Stevens said he was to fight one Buckhorse, a famous Fellow for fighting - I did offer to lay a Wager, and pulled all the Money I had out of my Pocket, - there was Gold and Silver, and Half-pence with the Gold. - I pulled it out to pay the Reckoning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you offer to make this Matter up ?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. I was offered Money by a certain Person to make it up, but I would not do it.</p>
               <p>Court. Were you ever acquainted with these People before you saw them at the Brandy-Shop ?</p>
               <p>Tomkins. Never to be acquainted with them, but I have frequently seen these Fellows about the Market, as my Mother keeps the Market.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by this Money?</p>

               <p>Tomkins. I saved it up by Degrees.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120002"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person36">
                  Jonathan 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person36" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person36" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman; I was going along between Rose and Crown-Court and George-Alley, and heard an Outcry, and saw the Prosecutor, who was fell down upon his Hands; and 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person37">
                  Robert 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person37" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person37" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was coming out of the Court; he got away; but with the Assistance of Young, I took him (I know nothing of the Robbery) he run away after that; and I was forced to call another Man to my Assistance, and took him again - I know nothing of Russel, only by seeing him about, and that he keeps Company with a common Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person38">
                  William 
                  Boomer 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person38" type="surname" value="Boomer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person38" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Constable: As I was going from Guildhall to Newgate with Stevens, he said, he was not the Man that took the Money; but, says he, I know who did; and he named one they called Doctor, who lives at Cow-Cross, and is a Butcher; so I took up this Doctor, and brought him to the Prosecutor; and the Prosecutor said, he was not the Man; on the Saturday following I took this Russel; and when the Prosecutor saw him, he owned him directly, and said, he was the Person that took the Money out of his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take him up?</p>
               <p>Boomer. I took him by the Description of the Prosecutor; who said, he should know him again; he was looking about, and I thought that he was the Person; when I took him, he said, he could prove where he was that Night; I asked him where he lay, he said, he lay in Charter house-lane; and afterwards, he said, he lay in St Giles's; and there was a Woman, who belonged to him, said, that he lay in Goswell street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person39">
                  William 
                  Monk 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person39" type="surname" value="Monk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person39" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the Constable at the taking of 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person40">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person40" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person40" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one Saturday Night, in the Market; I told him, I had a strong Suspicion of his being concerned in the Robbery, on the Saturday [Sunday] Night before, he said, he could prove where he lay that Night; he said, he lay in Charter-house-lane; then, he said, he lay in St Giles's; there was a Woman, that he called his Wife, and I asked her where he lay, and, she said, he lay in Goswell-street; says I, the Woman you call your Wife, says, you lay in Goswell-street; says he, I lay in Charter-house-square; and, she said, indeed we lay in Goswell-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person41">
                  Edward 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person41" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person41" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday was three Weeks I heard a Quarrel - I cannot say whether it was the 18th of September; I think it was on Sunday was three Weeks; hearing a Quarrel, I came out of my House; and Mr Tomkins called out Watch, and said, he was robbed; I run to his Assistance, and another Man with me; the Prosecutor seemed, in all Appearance, as if he had been fighting - I only saw Stevens at that Time; I did not see any body else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prosecutor in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Young. I believe he had been drinking - I cannot take upon me to swear, whether he was in Liquor, or not; I was sent for to the Watch-house by the Constable (after the Prisoner was taken up) to ask me what I saw of the Matter; I acquainted him of what I have told you - they were rumbling and tumbling about - I know Stevens is a Chimney-sweeper; I know nothing of Russel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person42">
                  Ruth 
                  Cotton 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person42" type="surname" value="Cotton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person42" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person42" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard a Cry of stop Thief, and a Call of Watch, in George-alley; I looked out of the Window, and heard a Person ask another what he made a Noise for, and struck him, and knocked him down, but I cannot tell who did it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person43">
                  Samuel 
                  Orange 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person43" type="surname" value="Orange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person43" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been beating the Hour of twelve in Shoe-lane, and went to the Watch house; I had not been there above two Minutes, before Stevens was brought in; An't, please you, said he, to the constable, I did not rob the Man, but I know who did; Mr Tomkins, the Prosecutor, was very much beat, and his Face manl'd - I have known him a great while; he served his Time just by our Watch-house - the Prosecutor was very sober between six and seven in the Evening; I cannot tell whether he was drunk then; when a Man is beat and abused so, one cannot tell whether he is drunk or no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person44">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person44" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at Mr 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person45">
                  Abel 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person45" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person45" type="given" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, at the Vine-Tavern in the Fleet-Market.</p>
               <p>Tomkins. There is no such Tavern.</p>
               <p>Lee. On the 18th of September Mr Tomkins came into Mr Wood's House, with a Man, which I take to be Stevens the Chimney-Sweeper, Arm in Arm, in a friendly Manner; when they came in they asked for a Dram (I am Cellar-Man to the Gentleman where Mr Wood is Clerk, and Mr Wood desires me to go behind the Counter sometimes, and serve Liquor) Stevens said, he had no Money; said Tomkins, It shall cost you nothing here, call for what you please; and they ordered a Dram of Gin; in the mean Time, came in a Man, who said, Mr Tomkins, You are the Man, who offered to fight any Man upon a publick Stage, here is a Man will fight you for a Guinea; the Man was a Stranger to me; before they came in, they had a Dispute, and Tomkins said to the Man, who came in, You pretend to fight, you know nothing of fighting; said Tomkins, I can fight upon a Stage if I please, but I do not love to expose myself; says the other, Here's a Man that shall fight you for a Guinea To-morrow; Tomkins put his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120003"></xptr> Hand into his Pocket and drew out 5 s. in Silver, a Six-pence, and some Half-pence; says he, This is all the Money I have now, but I will make it a Guinea To morrow, or This shall go; taking hold of his Coat; and the other said, he should fight him for a Guinea; thereupon some Words arose; said I, This is a peaceable House, we will have no Quarrelling here; so I went to turn them out - I believe he was not very sober, nor very drunk; I know the Man was rational; because, there was a Hole broke in the Door; says he, Mrs Wood, I am a Carpenter; I will use your House, if you will employ me; said Mrs Wood, Mr Tomkins, I have no Occasion at present; but, if I had, I am engaged to another; I believe this Man staid about a Quarter of an Hour, and then I went to Bed; sometime afterwards, Mr Wood came up to me, and said, John, do you remember those Men who were in the Shop just now; Tomkins says, he was robbed; I went to the Watch-house, and saw Tomkins and Stevens both very much suddled, and quite different from what they were in the Shop; the Constable asked Tomkins some Questions; and he said, he had been in our Shop six Hours; said I, You have not been there above half an Hour, for I was there all the Time - they had two Glasses of Cherry-Brandy; said Tomkins, what is that; said I, a Penny; a Half-penny a Glass; said Tomkins, if Cherry-Brandy is so cheap, we will have two Glasses more, which they had - Mr Wood keeps a Brandy-Shop as well as a Tavern.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person46">
                  William 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person46" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person46" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Stevens these seven Years, he has the Character of a very honest Fellow; I asked him some Questions about the Robbery; he said, he knew nothing of the Money; he only knew that they were drunk together; I heard the Prosecutor say, that he would hold Stevens, and would not let him go; and, he says, Stevens held him.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. That was when I took him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person47">
                  Thomas 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person47" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person47" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Stevens sixteen Years; I have worked with him at Gentlemens Houses; I never heard any Thing amiss of him; he bore a very honest Character for any Thing that I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person48">
                  Henry 
                  Buzzine 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person48" type="surname" value="Buzzine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person48" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him sixteen Years; we were Fellow Servants and Bed-Fellows; and I never knew him to wrong Man, Woman, or Child; he is a very good honest young Fellow.</p>
               <p>Dorcas Holmes. I have known 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person49">
                  Robert 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person49" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person49" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about ten Years, he was Fellow-Servant with me about a Month, and is one of the honestest Fellows I ever knew in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person50">
                  Jane 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person50" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person50" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between seven and eight Years, and never knew him to do any Harm or Injustice to any body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person51">
                  Mary 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person51" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person51" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten or twelve Years, he is an honest hard working Man.</p>
               <p>William Beddel. On Sunday the 18th of September, at Night, 
               <persName id="t17431012-1-person52">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person52" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came Home to his Lodging at my House, in Charter-house-lane, about eleven o'Clock at Night, or it might be upwards of eleven - it might be near half an Hour after eleven; he had lodged with me between three and four Months at the Time the Robbery was committed, and behaved very well during that Time - it is about a Quarter of a Mile from George-alley to my House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person53">
                  John 
                  Rippen 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person53" type="surname" value="Rippen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Cordwainer, and so is Russel; I met him the 20th Day of last Month, and asked him where he was going, he said, he was going to try to get some Work; said I, William, I hear you are rich, can you afford to great me with a Pint of Bear; he said, he had not so much Money about him; I asked him to lend me a Half-penny; for, I said, I had not a Farthing in the World, but he could not; and he worked with my Master till he was taken up for this Robbery; I believe, if he had any Money he would have given me a Pint of Beer; he is a very honest Fellow; my Father has intrusted him to receive Money for him, and he never wronged him of a Farthing in his Life, that I know of; he learned his Trade of my Father - I have known him thirteen Years.</p>
               <p>- Baxter, and - Hullony, were next Door Neighbours to Russel, have known him eight or nine Years, and never knew any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person54">
                  John 
                  Strong 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person54" type="surname" value="Strong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Russel ever since he was a little Lad; he always worked hard for his Bread; I never heard or saw any thing of him but what was honest in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-1-person55">
                  Samuel 
                  Murray 
               <interp inst="t17431012-1-person55" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person55" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him for three Quarters of a Year, and know that he is an honest Lad, and used to work hard at his Business. Both <rs id="t17431012-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
