<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430519-9">
               <interp inst="t17430519-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-9" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430519"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-9" type="date" value="17430519"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-9-off40-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-defend96 t17430519-9-off40 t17430519-9-verdict46"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-9-off41-c79" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-defend100 t17430519-9-off41 t17430519-9-verdict47"></join>
         
               <p>256 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     Gabriel 
                     Beaugrand 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend96" type="surname" value="Beaugrand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend96" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of St Anne Westminster, was indicted for the <rs id="t17430519-9-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430519-9-victim98" type="victimName">
                           Lewis 
                           Legier 
                        <interp inst="t17430519-9-victim98" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-9-victim98" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-9-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him one mortal Wound with a Knife, on the left side of the Belly, near the Navel , of the Breadth of half an Inch and the Depth of four Inches, of which Wound he instantly died
            </rs>. And</p>
               <p>257 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-defend100" type="defendantName">
                     Lewis 
                     Brunet 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend100" type="surname" value="Brunet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend100" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-defend100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17430519-9-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               aiding, abetting, assisting, and comforting the said 
                     <persName id="t17430519-9-person101">
                        Gabriel 
                        Beaugrand 
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person101" type="surname" value="Beaugrand"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-9-person101" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-9-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   to commit the said Murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430519-9-cd42" type="crimeDate">Apr. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-off40 t17430519-9-cd42"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-off41 t17430519-9-cd42"></join>.</p>
               <p>They were a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-person102">
                  John 
                  Pillet 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person102" type="surname" value="Pillet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person102" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick House, the <placeName id="t17430519-9-crimeloc43">White Bear in Newport-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-9-crimeloc43" type="placeName" value="White Bear in Newport-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-9-crimeloc43" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-off40 t17430519-9-crimeloc43"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-off41 t17430519-9-crimeloc43"></join> . On the 27th of April, between 11 and 12 o'Clock at Night, 
               <persName id="t17430519-9-person103">
                  Lewis 
                  Legier 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person103" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person103" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into my House, with another Gentleman whom I did not know; 
               <persName id="t17430519-9-person104">
                  Lewis 
                  Legier 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person104" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person104" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             seeing a <rs id="t17430519-9-deflabel44" type="occupation">Sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-defend96 t17430519-9-deflabel44"></join> in the House, he said to the Prisoner Beaugrand How do you do, Brother Sailor; says he, I have found out a Place for you to go to Sea; says Beaugrand, Where? Legier answered, he could not tell yet: Then Beaugrand asked the <rs id="t17430519-9-viclabel45" type="occupation">Cook</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-victim98 t17430519-9-viclabel45"></join>, (that is Legier , who was Commodore Anson's Cook) if he was a Brother Sailor, he said Yes, I am as well as you; and Beaugrand asked him to shew his Hand, and when he showed him his Hand, Beaugrand said, Then we are Brother Sailors. Afterwards they began to talk about Ships, and who was most esteemed in the Ship, a Sailor or the Cook; and Beaugrand said a Sailor was more esteemed than the Cook; the Cook ( Legier ) answer'd he was not more esteemed than him: Then there arose Words, and Legier said he would Kick Beaugrand; and Beaugrand said, he did not know him yet; and Beaugrand took a Pewter (Pint) Pot up, and struck at Legier , and then Legier flew upon him.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who made the first Attack?</p>
               <p>Pillet . Beaugrand did strike first, and then they fought upon the Table.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by that, they did not stand upon the Table.</p>
               <p>Pillet. No, they struck one another over the Table.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there several Blows over the Table?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Yes, there were many Blows on both sides; I received part of one Blow upon my Eye in going to separate them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you the Blow?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190008"></xptr>Pillet . I do not know; after they were separated Brunet would take his Nephew Beaugrand's Part, and would fight with 
               <persName id="t17430519-9-person105">
                  Lewis 
                  Legier 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person105" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person105" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. You say Legier flew upon Beaugrand, what do mean by flying upon him?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Legier fell upon him with both his Hands. After Legier and Brunet engaged, they both came down upon the Floor together, so I went directly to see for the Watchman, and when I came back I parted them; and when they were parted, Legier went to one side of the Table, and Brunet to the other; then the younger one (Beaugrand) came up to 
               <persName id="t17430519-9-person106">
                  Lewis 
                  Legier 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person106" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person106" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             again, and gave him two or three Punches on the Belly thus - here on the left Side.</p>
               <p>Court. With what?</p>
               <p>Pillet. I did not see any thing in his Hand; I thought he fight de English Fashion; so says I to them, Go home; and then I heard Legier say, I am dead; and fell down and died immediately; when I said, Go home, I did not think he was hurt. - Legier went out with me, and Brunet came again to fight with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the Street?</p>
               <p>Pillet. No, it was in our Passage. I turned Brunet into the Room again, before Legier fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Legier fall down?</p>
               <p>Pillet. He fell down in the Entry, and then the Watchmen took them both away. - He fell down after the Watchmen came in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine then whether he had any Wound or no?</p>
               <p>Pillet. He bled pretty much, and did not speak any more after he fell down.</p>
               <p>Court. Was there any Distance of Time between the Scuffle with the Pewter Pot, and Brunet's quarrelling with Legier?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Not above two Minutes.</p>
               <p>Court. How long was it after you parted Brunet and Legier, that Beaugrand came and gave him two or three Thrusts at his Belly?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Presently afterwards.</p>
               <p>Court. How long might the Scuffle between Brunet and Legier be?</p>
               <p>Pillet. About half a Quarter of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know whether Legier had a Pot in his Hand?</p>
               <p>Pillet. I do not know, I cannot tell whether he had any thing in his Hand.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you observe Beaugrand's Head, whether it was bloody?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Yes, it was, I perceived it after the Struggle was over.</p>
               <p>Counc. How came his Head to be bloody?</p>
               <p>Pillet. I cannot tell how it came. - I suppose with the Pot.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who struck him with the Pot?</p>
               <p>Pillet. Why Legier struck him with the Pot.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who had the Pot in his Hand first?</p>
               <p>Pillet. I saw the Pot in Beaugrand's Hand first.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long was it after Beaugrand's Head was bloody, that he gave Legier those Punches?</p>
               <p>Pillet. About a Quarter of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you hear any thing said by any Body, to bid him take Care of his Knife?</p>
               <p>Pillet . No.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you see any Body meddle with a Poker.</p>
               <p>Pillet. No, No-body had a Poker in their Hands.</p>
               <p>Counc. Is Beaugrand an Acquaintance of your's?</p>
               <p>Pillet. He was not an Acquaintance of mine, till about three Weeks before this; I have known Mr Brunet a great while.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do not you think this was a sudden Quarrel over Liquor?</p>
               <p>Pillet . It was a Quarrel: - I did not hear any bad Expressions made Use of.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bermier examined by an Interpreter, his Evidence was, That between Ten and Eleven o'Clock, he went into Pillet's House with Legier ; and there he found the Prisoners drinking; that at first coming in, Legier and Beaugrand spoke to one another in English, which he did not understand; and afterwards, that they spoke French, in a very civil, friendly Manner; that he asked them, whether they were French, and the Prisoner said they were born at Calais , in France; that talking about Sea-Affairs, Beaugrand , said, he was willing to go to Sea, but would not go in the Station of a Cook, because it was beneath a Sailor's Dignity; with that, Legier answered, that a Captain's Cook was inferior to a Sailor; but a Commodore's Cook, was preferable to a Sailor; with that, Beaugrand , gave him the Lye, and said, he was a lying Rascal, or some such Expression as that; and that the Sailor, (the Prisoner Beaugrand) took up a Pewter Pot, and attempted to strike the Cook (the Deceas'd) with it: Upon that, the Deceas'd took hold of him, and pulled him over the Table; laid him upon the Table, and took the Pot out of Beaugrand's Hand, and struck him several Blows over the Head, with the Side of the Pot.</p>
               <p>Counc. Could not Beaugrand have hit Legier with the Pot over the Table?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190009"></xptr>Bermier . Yes, he could have hit him with it, if he had been very forward to do it.</p>
               <p>Counc . Why did not he do it then?</p>
               <p>Bermier . Because immediately as he made the Motion to strike him, Legier fell upon him, and drew him over the Table.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was Beangrand fitting or standing when he made the Motion?</p>
               <p>Bermier. He was fitting, before he made the Motion; but when he made the Motion, he stood up; and immediately Mr. Pillet endeavoured to part them, but could not; and then he went out to get a Watchman, and when he came in they were parted; and then, I said to Legier, Let us go home, is it possible that Frenchmen can fight so in a strange Country ; upon that, the Deceas'd asked for his Hat and Wig, and when I gave him his Wig to put on, the Uncle ( Brunet ) made a Motion, as if he was going to strike Legier, and, in the mean Time Beangrand came up, and gave him a Stab.</p>
               <p>Court . Ask him whether he saw any thing in Beaugrand's Hand, at the Time of his giving him the Thrust?</p>
               <p>Bermier . No, I did not, for if I had seen any thing in his Hand, I would have prevented the Mischief.</p>
               <p>Court . Ask him if he knows whether the Deceas'd had any Knife, when he came into the House?</p>
               <p>Bermier. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Wound?</p>
               <p>Mr Bermier pointed to the left Side of the Belly near the Navel. - While he was putting his Wig on, I saw the Push made at him.</p>
               <p>Court. Ask him if he saw the Wound after the Man was dead?</p>
               <p>Bermier. No.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he look upon Beaugrand's Head, to see what Condition it was in?</p>
               <p>Bermier. I saw several Blows given him upon the Head, but I did not see the Wounds: - I saw him bleed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-person107">
                  William 
                  Rawlins 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person107" type="surname" value="Rawlins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person107" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , the Watchman. I was called to Mr. Pillet's House, between Twelve and One from my Stand; and when I came in, I saw the Deceas'd standing up against the Wall, supported by two Men.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Pillet one of the two Men?</p>
               <p>Rawlins. No, Pillet was standing by, with a Candle in his Hand; I asked the Deceas'd, if he could stand, and he shook his Head, for he could not speak; and in a few Minutes he dropped down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come to himself after he dropped down?</p>

               <p>Rawlins. No, he lifted up his Hand once. I saw a great deal of Blood come out from about his Navel, and run over the Waistband of his Breeches. and my Brother Watchman lifted up his Shirt, and there was one Wound.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a Wound was it?</p>
               <p>Rawlins. It was a Sort of a pickedish Wound, and looked almost as if he had been blooded.</p>
               <p>Q. What, did it look like the Prick of a Launcet?</p>
               <p>Rawlins . Yes, I think so. I asked where the Man was that did it, and they said there were but two Men in the House, and it was one of them; and while I was talking, the Prisoners came rushing out in order to make their Escapes; the old Man (Brunet) came running out, and said he would kill him by God.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any Name?</p>
               <p>Rawlins . He did not mention any Name. I turned about and said, Sir, you have killed him already; then they went into a neighbouring Yard, and I and another Watchman apprehended them; they had shut a Door against us, and I pushed hard against the Door, and the Latch flew open ; then I spoke to the Sailor, and said he must surrender, that he was my Prisoner , and he surrendered immediately. I was told the other was in the Bog-house; I went to the Bog-house and told him he was my Prisoner; he pulled out a Pair of Scissars, (they were taken out of his Pocket afterwards) but did not do any thing with them, he said he would kill all. We took them both to the Landlord's House, and I found this Sheath and Fork under the Table; there was a Knife that was bloody found the next Day in the Horse-pond belonging to the Prince of Wales's Yard. - The Deceased had three Wounds.</p>
               <p>The Coroner produced a Knife with a sharp pointed Blade, about eight or nine Inches long. This Knife was found next Day in the next Yard, which can be proved to be the Property of the Prisoner.</p>

               <p>Counc. If a Man had a sharp Knife in his Pocket, might it not run into his Body by Accident?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-person108">
                  Stephen 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person108" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person108" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Surgeon. I think on the 28th of April, between one and two in the Morning, I was sent for to the Assistance of the Deceased, to the Sign of the White-Bear in Newport-street; I found a Man sitting upon the Ground, supported by the Chimney-Piece; I examined his Pulse first, and found he was dead; after that, I inspected the Body and found three Wounds, one within an Inch of the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190010"></xptr> left Nipple, another within an Inch or two of the Cartilage of the Breast-Bone, about four Inches above the Navel; and the third between the fifth and sixth Rib on the left Side; the next Day I opened the Body, and found that the first Wound upon the Breast near the Nipple had penetrated to the Diaphragma; the second entered into the Liver and Vena Cava; and the third entered into the Cawl: It is my Opinion that the Wound given into the Liver was immediate Death; that into the Lungs might have proved mortal; the Consequence of the third Wound was dubious.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-9-person109">
                  Isaac 
                  Eterneau 
               <interp inst="t17430519-9-person109" type="surname" value="Eterneau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person109" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have not known Beaugrand long, but I have known the Uncle two or three Years; about six in the Morning I heard there was a Man killed; I went to the Round House and saw the two Prisoners handcuffed together, and Beaugrand had a Handkerchief about his Head; and there were five Wounds upon his Head, the Pot had made Marks like Horseshoes; one of the Wounds gaped so that you might put your Finger into it, he is not well of them yet. I have been in the Uncle's Company five hundred Times, and have been out of Town with him, and played at Cards with him frequently, and never saw him in a Passion. I never heard he was addicted to quarrelling, or any malicious Action.</p>
               <p>Josias Hutchinson, Constable. There were five Wounds, all large Wounds, upon Beaugrand's Head; it was in a most terrible Condition; the Blows were given with a good Will.</p>
               <p>Beaugrand guilty of <rs id="t17430519-9-verdict46" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-verdict46" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-verdict46" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Manslaughter
            </rs>, Brunet <rs id="t17430519-9-verdict47" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-verdict47" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430519-9-punish48" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-punish48" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-9-punish48" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-9-defend96 t17430519-9-punish48"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
