<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470116-6">
               <interp inst="t17470116-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-6" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-6" type="date" value="17470116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-6-off27-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-6-defend94 t17470116-6-off27 t17470116-6-verdict30"></join>
         
               <p>75. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-6-defend94" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Belcher 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-6-defend94" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-defend94" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-defend94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-6-off27" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-off27" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-off27" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing two Gold Rings, and ten Guineas and a half, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470116-6-victim96" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17470116-6-victim96" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470116-6-victim96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470116-6-victim96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-6-off27 t17470116-6-victim96"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , at the <placeName id="t17470116-6-crimeloc28">Mermaid-Inn in Carter-lane</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Mermaid-Inn in Carter-lane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-6-off27 t17470116-6-crimeloc28"></join>
               
                  </rs> , the <rs id="t17470116-6-cd29" type="crimeDate">30th of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-6-off27 t17470116-6-cd29"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470116-6-person97">
                  John 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17470116-6-person97" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person97" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you lose any thing in October last?</p>
               <p>Walker. On the 30th of October I lost ten Guineas and a half in Gold, two Gold Rings, three Shillings, and two half Crowns.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what became of all these things?</p>
               <p>Walker. I was in my Room a little before 12 o'Clock. I live at the Mermaid-Inn; I was in my Room with another young Man with me; I was about to send some Money and two Rings into the Country: as the other young Man and I was together, this 
               <persName id="t17470116-6-person98">
                  Joseph 
                  Belcher 
               <interp inst="t17470116-6-person98" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person98" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into the Room at the same Time, he took one of the Rings and put on his Finger, and he saw my Money in the Window. I went into my Room again about five o'Clock in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174701160008"></xptr> Evening; my Room was all safe as I left it, as I thought; about half an Hour after 11 o'Clock, I saw a Pane of the Glass out, with that I was sure in my Mind my Money and Rings were gone; I went to seek for the Money and Rings, and they were gone. I went down, and there was Company in the House, and I told my Friends of it; they said they were very sorry; they said they would be searched, and they said if any Body was a Bed they should be searched; for they said it is a Friend that has your Money; there was the Prisoner and another in Bed; one of them throws out his Breeches to me, I searched his Pockets; so when we came to 
               <persName id="t17470116-6-person99">
                  Joseph 
                  Belcher 
               <interp inst="t17470116-6-person99" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person99" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner, I asked him what money he had, he said only Half a Crown and Three-half-pence; he was very unwilling to part from his Breeches: we sent for the Constable, when he came, he said to him, you must go along with me, and he said, Where to? the Constable answered, to the Compter; when he went to put his Breeches on, the Constable said, he must see what was in his Pockets, and he took out ten Guineas, and he searched in another Pocket and found the two Rings that I had but a little Time before, with that he was committed to the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Walker. First he denied it, then he said, be as favourable to me as you can, for I am ruined. The Prisoner lived a Coachman with Mr Chitty about eight Months.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470116-6-person100">
                  George 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17470116-6-person100" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person100" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What are you, Constable?</p>
               <p>Dunn . Yes, my Lord, in October last, between 12 and 1 o'Clock in the Morning, the Man came to me, and asked me whether I could not take the Charge of a Man for a Suspicion of Robbery; so I went to the House, and up Stairs along with him, so we knocked at the Door; the Prisoner at last came out of Bed, and let us in; he said he would charge me with a Suspicion of Robbery, he was unwilling we should search his Breeches ; I had a Suspicion the Money was there. I found Half a Crown in his Pocket; I searched his Fob, and found 10 Guineas and an Half, and two Half Crowns, and 3 s. and two Gold Rings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Walker lay claim to them?</p>
               <p>Dunn . Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Dunn . He seemed to be vex'd that he had done it; but he said he took it for Fun, and designed to give it him again.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoner. What have you to say for yourself ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . My Lord, when I took it first, I only took it as a Joke, only to make him take more Care of it another Time .</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Chitty . Sir, Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Chitty . The Prisoner at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17470116-6-person101">
                  Joseph 
                  Belcher 
               <interp inst="t17470116-6-person101" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person101" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was my Servant about nine Months; he lived with me at the Time when I found he was guilty of the unhappy Accident: during the Time that he lived with me, he behaved himself soberly and honestly; when I heard of this Accident, I was surprized; I am afraid 'tis very hard against him; his Family I am told is a reputable Family.</p>
               <p>Bowler Miller. The Prisoner, Belcher, lived with me, and a very sober honest Lad he was. The Prisoner used to come frequently to see his Brother; we had a pretty deal of Plate in our House, and I never missed any thing. I believe him to be a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>The Defence the Prisoner made, that he did it out of a Jest. This, together with the good Character he bore, induced the Jury not to find him guilty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470116-6-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-6-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
