<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430519-6">
               <interp inst="t17430519-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-6" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430519"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-6" type="date" value="17430519"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-6-off26-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-6-defend63 t17430519-6-off26 t17430519-6-verdict29"></join>
         
               <p>253 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-defend63" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-6-defend63" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-defend63" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-defend63" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17430519-6-defloc25">St. John the Evangelist</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-6-defloc25" type="placeName" value="St. John the Evangelist"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-6-defloc25" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-6-defend63 t17430519-6-defloc25"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17430519-6-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 24 Pewter-Plates, 2 Pewter Dishes, 1 Silver Tea-spoon, a Cloth Coat, a Waistcoat , 2 Pair of Breeches, a Hat, a Perriwig, a Camblet Gown, 1 Pair of Shoes, 1 black quilted Petticoat, 7 Shirts, 1 Sheet, 1 pair of Pockets, &amp;c. The Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430519-6-victim65" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Martin 
                        <interp inst="t17430519-6-victim65" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-6-victim65" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-6-victim65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-6-off26 t17430519-6-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430519-6-cd27" type="crimeDate">Apr. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-6-off26 t17430519-6-cd27"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person66">
                  Tho 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person66" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person66" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17430519-6-deflabel28" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-6-defend63 t17430519-6-deflabel28"></join>; she lived with me about two Years ago; had been away from me, and came again lately; she was hired to come on the 12th of April, and she pretended she had been robbed two or three Days before, going home ; that she was stripped, and had lost her Gold Ring, and that it was a great Mercy she had saved her Gold Necklace; that she had catched a great Cold, and was to come the next Day.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an Account of the Robbery.</p>
               <p>Martin. I will show you what was preceding the Robbery, and then the Robbery itself. She came the 13th; she went away the 17th, pretending to be ill of a sore Throat, and did not return again till Tuesday se'ennight following, which was the 26th; in which Interim of Time, she sent a Message to let us know, that she was ill, and desired that somebody might do her Business, and she would pay for it. On Wednesday the 27th she was to wash, (some time before this she was to have washed) and when she came to take out a ten Gallon Kettle which we wash in, there was a Hole in it, which we imagine to have been made by herself, because we never observed it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190004"></xptr> before; the perswaded my Wife to let the Kettle go to be mended, and told her that all the Pots and Kettles wanted tinning, and perswaded her to let them go to an Acquaintance of her's: She carried that great Kettle, a Pot, 5 Saucepans, and a Stew-pan, and brought home but two of the Saucepans; on Thursday Night I came home about 12 o'Clock, they had been washing that Day, and the Cloaths were hanging up to dry in the Kitchen upon a wooden Horse: I went to draw a little Small-Beer, and saw a Rush-light burning on the Stairs, and a parcel of Linnen and Plates lying there; I went up Stairs and asked her the Reason of the Candle's being left, she said she designed to clean the House, (and told my Wife she would make the House as white as a Curd) I suppose that was to prevent our minding of it if we should hear any rustling or Noise: A little after 6 o'Clock I got up, and found the Back-Door open, and the Garden-Door unbolted, which I always take Care to see fast at Night; upon returning in again (for I thought she was gone out a gossipping with some Neighbour or other, not having any Imagination of what she had done) I bolted the Door and went up Stairs; my Wife said, It is a fine Morning, I will get up too; and when she got up, she found we were stripp'd, and that the Prisoner was gone; she seem'd to have some Judgment in doing it, for she pulled these Papers out of my Coat-Pocket, and left them upon a Chair. I miss'd all the things mentioned in the Indictment, and several more; I miss'd my Shoes and Coat, which I had worn the Day before; I believe she could not well carry any more, for it was near an hundred Weight. She had taken my Wife's Keys out of her Pocket, and taken several things out of the Drawers, but she left the Keys on the Table in the Kitchen. - She was gone out of the House when I bolted the Garden-Door; then I began to recollect where her Friends liv'd; for she had told me formerly, that she lived somewhere in Whitechapel, and that her Friends lived in More-lane by Morefields. However, the next Day I advertis'd them, and described her Person; on the Monday following, three Jews came to me, pretending they could help me to take the Person that robb'd me, and told me there was some of the things sold among their Jews, and one Mylock said he had bought some of the Goods, one Jacobs came with two or three more Persons afterwards; and when she was taken up, and carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17430519-6-person67">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person67" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person67" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , she confess'd the Fact, and would have sworn it on 
               <persName id="t17430519-6-person68">
                  Jacob 
                  Lopez 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person68" type="surname" value="Lopez"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person68" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17430519-6-person69">
                  Abraham 
                  Mylock 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person69" type="surname" value="Mylock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person69" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; she said that she had part of the Goods, and that Mylock and Lopez had the rest.</p>
               <p>Counc . You tell us your Suspicions, I know you belong to the Law, and you should know that you are to speak nothing but what you are positive of; Did you take positive Notice of what Linnen lay there?</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. No indeed; I cannot say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. You say she took your Wife's Pocket, Did you see your Wife put it under her Head?</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. No: but I saw the Strings of it hang down by her Head.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Drawers were lock'd?</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. Yes, I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not your Chamber-Door fastened?</p>
               <p>Mr Martin . My Chamber-Door was fastened, but the Door between the two Rooms was not fastened .</p>
               <p>Q. You say she would have impeached Lopez and Mylock , Why did not you indict them?</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. Mylock behaved in such a manner that I did not believe him innocent, but I was not willing to part with a Person I could convict, for one that I had not sufficient Evidence to convict.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person70">
                  Tho 
                  Bretter 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person70" type="surname" value="Bretter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person70" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of April, about a quarter after 5 in the Morning, I was coming from Mr Scott's Brewhouse in the Broad-Way, with six Gallons of Beer; my Wife (for I am very dull of hearing) heard somebody say, Will you earn Sixpence ? my Wife told me of it, and I said Yes; and the Prisoner said she would pay me, and helped me up with the things upon my Back, (this was just by the Artillery-Wall near Tothill Fields Bridewell , which is about 200 Yards from Mr. Martin's House) they were tied up in a large ordinary Sheet, it was in two Parts, that Part which hung upon my Back seemed to be Copper, but it was tied so close that I could not see what was in the Inside. I carried it to the Horse-Ferry Whars, and the Prisoner went along with me, and this Waterman ( 
               <persName id="t17430519-6-person71">
                  Henry 
                  Ware 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person71" type="surname" value="Ware"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person71" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) lifted them off my Shoulder, and carried them down the Wharf himself, the Prisoner followed the Waterman down the Wharf, and I turned back; I never saw the Woman before that Time, nor since till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person72">
                  Henry 
                  Ware 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person72" type="surname" value="Ware"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person72" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Lambeth, and happened to get a Fare to Westminster Horse-Ferry , and thought to stay to get another back again, and instead of that, I happened to get one to London; this Man (Bretter) came with a Bundle on his Shoulder, and I asked him if he wanted a Sculler, he said no, but that there was a Woman coming behind who wanted one; and I asked her if she wanted a Sculler, and she said, Yes; What must I give you, said she, to carry me to the three Cranes; Nine-Pence, said I, For with that Bundle it deserves it; she said, she would not give it; then said I, If you will not give me so much, give me Six-Pence, and a Pint of Beer; she said, she would give me no Pint, she would give me but Six-Pence; when we came there, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190005"></xptr> asked her if she wanted a Porter to carry it up; she said, Yes; I said, I would carry it for her; (it was to go into Little Morefields) but, when I got it upon my Shoulder, I found it was too heavy for me, and I asked a Waterman whether he would not earn a Jobb, but he would not: The Things were tied up in a Linnen Cloth, and some of the Plates fell out, I believe there might be half a Dozen of them; I called to her, and told her, there were some of them fell out; (she said, there were Plates and Linnen) I could not get a Porter, but there came a young Man, who undertook the Jobb, and she took the Plates up, and put them into the Bundle again herself.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the Artillery-Wall, to the Ferry?</p>
               <p>Bretter . Full half a Mile.</p>
               <p>Q. To Ware. What Time was it, when the Prisoner came to you?</p>
               <p>Ware. It was full half an Hour after Five, and when I got against St. Paul's, the Clock struck Six; and, I said to the young Woman, the Clock strikes Six now; this was on Friday, and it was Monday, before I heard any more of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to recollect this Particular, that it was on a Friday?</p>
               <p>Ware. Because Mr Martin had put her into the Paper.</p>
               <p>Q. But this does not tell me, how you came to find her out?</p>
               <p>Ware. I did not find her out; I did not see her again, till I came to Guild-Hall ; I knew her as soon as I saw her, and she knew me. Mr Martin came to me, and asked me if I did not carry such a Fare.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think you could know a Fare, that you carried last Friday?</p>
               <p>Ware . I cannot tell, whether I could or no, but I know this Woman; I might not take so much Notice of every Fare I carry.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think this Man (Bretter) could carry that Bundle of Things so far in a Quarter of an Hour; 'tis above half a Mile, and he is an older Man than you?</p>
               <p>Ware . I do not know that, but I believe it may be done .</p>
               <p>Burgess Yerwood. The Prisoner came to my House, with two Sancepans to be tinned, and asked me, whether I would buy any Pots , Kettles, and Sauce-pans; she said, her Mistress sent her; I asked her, where she lived, and I would go and see them, she said her Mistress's Name was Martin , but that she would not let me see her; she brought them, and giving a very plausible Account of the Thing, (for I am as careful of buying stolen Goods, as any Body) I agreed to give her Fifteen Shillings for them; she said, she would go and tell her Mistress, and I gave her Fifteen Shillings; they were old Things, and I knocked them all to Pieces: - I cannot tell whether it was before, or after the Robbery: I cannot tell what Day of the Month it was. I think, it was on a Wednesday, that the Saucepans were tinned, and that she came on Thursday Morning, and then I weighed the Pots, &amp;c. and paid her for them.</p>
               <p>A Boy, about Fourteen Years of Age, was produced, but not being able to give the Court a satisfactory Answer, with relation to the Nature of an Oath, he was not examined .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person73">
                  Mary 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person73" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person73" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came to me on 12th of April, pretending that she came to see me; I asked her, how she came to know where I lived; she said, she came to enquire a Servant's Character for her Aunt, and so enquired after me; said I, Why don't you live with your Aunt ; she said, she would sooner live with a Stranger, than live with her; and, I did then ask her, whether she would come and live with me ; and she said she would, I hired her then, and she came the Day after: The Sunday following, she pretended she had a sore Throat, that was the 17th; I said, she might go to her Friends, and she staid till the 26th; and, on the 29th she robbed me. On Thursday Night, I went to Bed before my Husband came home; this Boy [He that was produced, but not examined] runs of Errands for us, and he went away about half an Hour after Nine ; and she desired me to go to Bed betimes, because I had had a hard Day's Work: Mr. Martin came home about Twelve o'Clock at Night, and she had laid down on the Side of the Bed by me; for I had a Servant died in the House, and , I am afraid to lie by my self. When my Husband came home, she said, she would get up very early, and wash the Kitchen before I got up, and it should be as white as a Curd; and desired if I should wake, that I would call her up at Four o'Clock; I said, it would be too soon to get up, after such a hard Day's Work.</p>

               <p>Q. What did she take from you?</p>
               <p>Mrs Martin. She took every Thing I had; I had not a Shift left, but what I had on: [She then mentioned the Things as in the Indictment; a China Tea-Pot , with a Silver Spout, &amp;c.]</p>
               <p>Q. Did you wake and call her?</p>
               <p>Mrs Martin . No, I did not?</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any of these Things to produce?</p>
               <p>Mrs Martin . No, I have none of the Things, because she had sold them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190006"></xptr>Q. Was she sober when she laid down by you?</p>
               <p>Mrs Martin. Yes, she was sober; I do not know whether she slept; I thought she was tired, and for that Reason I desired her to lie down on the Bed.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Council pleaded, that it could not amount to a Felony, because the Goods were put under the Prisoner's Care; but the Court were of a different Opinion.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence . As to the Kettle and Pot my Mistress sent me to sell them to Mr Yerwood. I carried two of the Saucepans home, and had 15 s. for what I sold, and paid 18 d. for tinning the two, and gave her 13 s. 6 d. to pay the Surgeon for curing her Hand. My Mistress harrasses me Night and Day, sending me about one trifling Errand or another; for she is either out of her Senses , or else has drank herself out of them. My Mistress sent me about to get a Nurse-Child for her; 
               <persName id="t17430519-6-person74">
                  Ann 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person74" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person74" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knows she used to be always sending me about one idle thing or another?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person75">
                  Ann 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person75" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person75" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew Mrs Martin send her about any Nurse Children, nor I never saw her out of her Senses. She has always used her well; more like a Child than a Servant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Mistress has had Money out of my Pocket, and my Cloaths off my Back, to pawn. Mrs Davis knows she carried the Spoon to pawn herself, and they charge me with it.</p>
               <p>Davis. I never did, while the Prisoner was in the House, carry any Silver Spoon to pawn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person76">
                  Ann 
                  Kidder 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person76" type="surname" value="Kidder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person76" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about twenty Years, she was Servant with me about twelve Months. I have trusted her with twenty or thirty Pound at a Time, and she never wronged me. I never heard she ever did any Wrong, or ever knew her turned away upon any Suspicion of such a Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person77">
                  Mary 
                  Avery 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person77" type="surname" value="Avery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person77" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner ever since she sucked at her Mother's Breast; she has lived with me twice; I never knew but that she always acted honestly; she always behaved well; she came twice to my House in the Time she was there, and said Mrs Martin wanted a Nurse-Child. Mr Martin was at my House on the Sunday , and told me that he was robbed on the Friday, (I ask Pardon for it dashes me) and said his Wife was a very great Drunkard, and would be the Ruin of him.</p>
               <p>Mr Martin . The Goods were carried to her Mother's House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person78">
                  Sarah 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person78" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person78" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner from a Babe; she always behaved well in the Neighbourhood. I never heard an ill Character of her in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person79">
                  Ann 
                  Hardman 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person79" type="surname" value="Hardman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person79" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived by the Prisoner's Mother these twenty Years, and never heard any Harm of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-6-person80">
                  Susannah 
                  Ramsay 
               <interp inst="t17430519-6-person80" type="surname" value="Ramsay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person80" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner the best Part of seven Years, and never heard a miss Word of her in my Life.</p>
               <p>Another Witness had known her ever since she was a little Girl in Frocks, and never heard she was turned away from any Place upon the Account of any Wrong she did, or that she was ever guilty of any such Crime. <rs id="t17430519-6-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-6-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
