<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480907-40">
               <interp inst="t17480907-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-40" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-40" type="date" value="17480907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480907-40-off213-c242" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-defend325 t17480907-40-off213 t17480907-40-verdict217"></join>
         
               <p>429. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480907-40-defend325" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Goulston 
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-defend325" type="surname" value="Goulston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-defend325" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-defend325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of the parish of <placeName id="t17480907-40-defloc212">Hessen</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-defloc212" type="placeName" value="Hessen"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-defloc212" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-defend325 t17480907-40-defloc212"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17480907-40-off213" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-off213" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-off213" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480907-40-victim327" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Day 
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-victim327" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-victim327" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-victim327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-off213 t17480907-40-victim327"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , between the hours of 11 and 12 in the night, and stealing a China tea-pot with a silver spout, value 15 s. two shaggreen cases, eight silver spoons, two silver strainers, and two pair of silver tea-tongs, one guinea and an half, and 20 s. in silver, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17480907-40-person328">
                        William 
                        Day 
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person328" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-person328" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17480907-40-cd214" type="crimeDate">August the 18th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-off213 t17480907-40-cd214"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-40-person329">
                  William 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17480907-40-person329" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person329" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17480907-40-crimeloc215">Rose and Crown</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-crimeloc215" type="placeName" value="Rose and Crown"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-crimeloc215" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-off213 t17480907-40-crimeloc215"></join> in the Parish of <placeName id="t17480907-40-crimeloc216">Hessen</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-crimeloc216" type="placeName" value="Hessen"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-40-crimeloc216" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-off213 t17480907-40-crimeloc216"></join> .</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any misfortune befel you in August last ?</p>
               <p>Day. Yes, between the hours of ten and one; for I did not know it 'till one, I found the wicket of the great gate open, and that some person had got in at the window ; the bar of the window was broke open: I was called at 26 minutes after one by one of the men that guards the mail, and was told by him that the bar was broke open; upon which I got a candle, and looked and found it to be so, and my bureau was broke open, and I had a considerable value of other people as well as my own in it; I went and found all my servants asleep, and I took the soldier in the house, and went round the town in order to see if any of the people were up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you miss?</p>
               <p>Day. A green purse with a guinea and an half in it, and 20 s. in silver, and the things mentioned in the Indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you to charge this upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Day. I went down to Portsmouth and took him on Monday-night at the play-house at Portsmouth, and he chang'd his name from 
               <persName id="t17480907-40-person330">
                  Richard 
                  Coulston 
               <interp inst="t17480907-40-person330" type="surname" value="Coulston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person330" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to 
               <persName id="t17480907-40-person331">
                  Richard 
                  Wilcocks 
               <interp inst="t17480907-40-person331" type="surname" value="Wilcocks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person331" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>Q. Then you knew the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Yes. Yes, he lived with me four or five years, and has been gone from me about two years; and I found all my things upon him at the Hercules's Club on Portsmouth Common . This is my teapot , &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any talk with the prisoner about the things?</p>
               <p>Day. Yes; and he said he was sorry for what he had done, for I had been a father to him, and wish'd he had been hanged before he had done it; he said he had been upon Hounslow-heath , and at the close of the evening he came and put back the wicket, and that he afterwards got in at the bar-window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing whether the bar-window was shut?</p>
               <p>Day. No, it was not shut when I went to bed; but it was fast before my wife went to bed .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he broke open your bureau?</p>
               <p>Day. Yes .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070019"></xptr>Mary Lanward. I was at Mr. Day's house the 18th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember shutting up the gate?</p>
               <p>Lanward. Yes, I remember the shutting it up between ten and eleven.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-40-person332">
                  William 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17480907-40-person332" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person332" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Constable at Portsmouth.) Mr. Day came to me the 19th of August between nine and ten o'clock, and ask'd me if I was not a constable, I said I was; he told me of his misfortune, and that he believed the villain was at the playhouse ; I was willing to do him all the Service I could, and ask'd him whether he knew who the villain was; he said it was a servant of his; I went with him to the play house, and told the people of the house I was come to search for a villain who was guilty of a robbery, but I would not disturb the house; and we had not been in the house above two Minutes before Mr. Day seiz'd him by the collar; and the prisoner said he did not know Mr. Day, and when he was carried before the Mayor he said his name was Wilcocks .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give any reason for changing his name?</p>
               <p>Norris. I believe he did; but it was some triffling reason which I don't remember, and the Mayor order'd me to carry him to the Town-clerk , and go and search his lodging; and as I was carrying him to the Town-clerk's he was under a good deal of trouble, and he said if I would let him go to his lodging he would give us the things ; and he gave me the tea-pot , spoons and strainers , &amp;c. He said he had been upon Hounslow-heath, and that he got in and robbed his master, Mr. Day's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how he got in?</p>
               <p>Norris. He said he got in at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you whether he opened the window, or whether the window was open before?</p>
               <p>Norris. No, he only said he got in at the window.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480907-40-verdict217" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-verdict217" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-40-verdict217" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty <rs id="t17480907-40-punish218" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17480907-40-punish218" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-40-defend325 t17480907-40-punish218"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>.
The prosecutor recommended the prisoner to the court for mercy
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
