<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-19">
               <interp inst="t17430114-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-19" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-19" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-19-off102-c232" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-19-defend272 t17430114-19-off102 t17430114-19-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>89. + 
               <persName id="t17430114-19-defend272" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-defend272" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-defend272" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-defend272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-19-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyTreason"></interp>
               feloniously and traiterously murdering her Husband, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430114-19-victim274" type="victimName">
                           Jacob 
                           Freeman 
                        <interp inst="t17430114-19-victim274" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-19-victim274" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-19-victim274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-19-off102 t17430114-19-victim274"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him one mortal Wound on the Right Breast, near the Pap, with a Shoemaker's Knife, of the Breadth of half an Inch, and the Depth of 3 quarters of an Inch, of which Wound he instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-19-cd103" type="crimeDate">Dec. 28th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-19-off102 t17430114-19-cd103"></join>. She was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest, for Manslaughter.</p>

               <p>Wm Sanders. I am a Shoemaker; I live in Seacoal-Lane; 
               <persName id="t17430114-19-person275">
                  Jacob 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person275" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person275" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Goods had been seized, and I gave him Leave to lie in my Room. On Tuesday in Christmas Week he had been out to carry home a Coat which he had to mend, and when he returned he was very much in Liquor; as soon as he came up Stairs, said she, What have you done with the Money that was to fetch Mr Gent's Coat home? with that he damn'd her for a Pitch ; then she called him vile Villain; with that he slew at her, and pulled her by her Topping, (the Fore-part of her Head) and they had a Struggle; he cried out immediately , Oh Will! Will! I am a dead Man , for I am stabbed. She had one of my Knives in her Hand, cutting a Piece of Bread. I jumped out of Bed and caught him in my Arms, and he died immediately; but whether he run against the Knife, or whether she thrust it to him, I cannot tell - there was a great deal of Blood: The Wound was just above the Pap of the Right Breast. She had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140018"></xptr> the Knife in her Hand when he entered the Room; this was the Knife. [It was produced in Court; the Blade was about 3 Inches long, and very narrow and sharp at the Point.]</p>

               <p>Q. Did she shove her Arm, or make use of any Violence towards him?</p>



               <p>Sanders. Not at all; there were no Curtains to the Bed, and the Candle was burning, so that I could see very well what passed .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person276">
                  Simon 
                  Snowd 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person276" type="surname" value="Snowd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person276" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Surgeon. At the Coroner's Inquest, Mr King (the Coroner) did insist on the Body's being opened, and the Churchwarden sent for me. I found a Wound penetrating into the Breast; I examined the Thorax , and found the Cavities all filled with Blood ; there was a Wound, as big as that Knife is capable of going into, in one of the Ventricles of the Heart - It was impossible he should survive above 2 or 3 Minutes after the receiving of the Wound.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think the Wound might be given by a Man's running against the Knife, without any Violence from her?</p>


               <p>Snowd. Really I cannot tell what to say to that; it must be left to the Jury; a little Matter would push that Knife in, it is so very sharp: The Wound penetrated the Breast-Bone.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person277">
                  Henry 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person277" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person277" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of December, a little before Six in the Evening, I was sent for to take Charge of the Prisoner: she said she had done Murder in a Quarrel with her Husband, but did not know how she did it.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person278">
                  James 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person278" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person278" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Churchwarden. On Tuesday the 28th of Dec. I was sent for from Home, on an Outery of Murder. Francis, the Constable, delivered me that Knife; the Prisoner said she had done Murder, and deserved to be hanged for it. 
               <persName id="t17430114-19-person279">
                  William 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person279" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person279" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said then, that the Prisoner had killed her Husband; that she went round the Bed to his Seat (he is a Shoemaker) and took up that Knife and stabbed him with it; I never heard that Circumstance of cutting Bread, or falling on the Knife, till I came before my Lord-Mayor - I would have had three other Witnesses examined by the Coroner, but I could not get it done. I was abused in a very opprobrious manner, and so was the Coroner; there were some noisy Fellows there, who minded drinking and smoaking, more than the Business they had to do - I did not contradict their Evidence, either before my Lord-Mayor, or the Coroner - he gave much the same Evidence then as he does now.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you not to contradict him, when he gave his Evidence so different from what he declared the 28th Dec?</p>

               <p>Townsend . I did not know I had any Business to offer to give Evidence.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person280">
                  Margaret 
                  Hart 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person280" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person280" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same House; the Prisoner owned that Night she had stabbed her Husband, and said that she must go to Newgate.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person281">
                  Anne 
                  Higgs 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person281" type="surname" value="Higgs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person281" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner said she had killed her Husband. What! said I, you vile Woman, have you killed your Husband? Said she, If he is stabb'd , I stabb'd him. You must take and send me to Newgate. There was nothing named of cutting Bread that Night the Mischief was done; but Sanders said then, that she got off her Seat, went round the Bed, took up the Knife and stabbed him. I live in the same House; when I was called up Stairs, she had stripped him naked, and laid him on the Bedstead. A little before this, Sanders said, that she had a sore Hand, by taking up a Knife to do him a Mischief.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person282">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person282" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person282" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came home that Evening about 6 o'Clock; Mrs Freeman owned she had killed her Husband; she had washed him and laid him out; she would have got away, but I would not let her.</p>

               <p>Court to Sanders. You have said now, that the Woman had a Knife in her Hand, and was cutting Bread when this Quarrel happened, some of the Witnesses say, that you said that Night, that she came round your Bed and took up the Knife; was it so in Fact?</p>

               <p>Sanders. They tell me I said so that Night, but I do not remember I said any such thing - She had the Knife in her Hand when he came into the Room, cutting a Ha'pworth of Bread which she had bought just before. As to the other Affair now mentioned, the Case was thus; he had pawned a Pair of Breeches, and came Home vastly in Liquor; she called him Rogue, and he gave her a Slap of the Face with the Back of his Hand, and made her Nose bleed; she took up a Case-Knife, held the Blade in her Hand, and hit him on the Shoulder, and so cut her own Fingers.</p>

               <p>John Hill. The Prisoner is my own Sister; she is a very industrious Creature, and really lov'd him; she is a mild, meek Creature.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person283">
                  Sarah 
                  Prinn 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person283" type="surname" value="Prinn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person283" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 7 or 8 Years, I was Servant in the House where she lived; she was an industrious, quiet, and peaceable Woman; he has spent 12 or 14 s. in a Night, and when he wanted Money, he would bid her go and pawn such and such Things, and she would only say, How can you desire me to pawn the Things , to support you in your Gaming and Drinking.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-19-person284">
                  Mary 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17430114-19-person284" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person284" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner upwards of 30 Years; her Character is that of a modest , civil Woman; she used to carry it very civil to her Husband.</p>

               <p>Eliz. Hill. She is a modest, quiet, well-behav'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140019"></xptr> Woman; I never knew her guilty of any outragious Behaviour.</p>

               <p>The Jury found her <rs id="t17430114-19-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-verdict104" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430114-19-punish105" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-punish105" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-19-punish105" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-19-defend272 t17430114-19-punish105"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
