<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430629-41">
               <interp inst="t17430629-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-41" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430629"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-41" type="date" value="17430629"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430629-41-off229-c301" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-defend396 t17430629-41-off229 t17430629-41-verdict233"></join>
         
               <p>335. + 
               <persName id="t17430629-41-defend396" type="defendantName">
                  Richard 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17430629-41-defend396" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-defend396" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-defend396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17430629-41-defloc228">St George in Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-41-defloc228" type="placeName" value="St George in Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-41-defloc228" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-defend396 t17430629-41-defloc228"></join>, was a third Time indicted, (together with 
               <persName id="t17430629-41-person397">
                  John 
                  Bunn 
               <interp inst="t17430629-41-person397" type="surname" value="Bunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person397" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17430629-41-person398">
                  Joseph 
                  Leech 
               <interp inst="t17430629-41-person398" type="surname" value="Leech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person398" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , * not taken) for <rs id="t17430629-41-off229" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-off229" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-off229" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430629-41-victim400" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Fennel 
                        <interp inst="t17430629-41-victim400" type="surname" value="Fennel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-41-victim400" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-41-victim400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-off229 t17430629-41-victim400"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Hat, value 1 s. a Perriwig, value 2 s. and sixteen Shillings in Money, the Goods and Money of 
                     <persName id="t17430629-41-person401">
                        James 
                        Fennel 
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person401" type="surname" value="Fennel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-41-person401" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-41-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , from his Person and against his Will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430629-41-cd230" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-off229 t17430629-41-cd230"></join>.</p>
               <p>* Joseph Leech was taken the 7th of July, and committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430629-41-person402">
                  James 
                  Fennel 
               <interp inst="t17430629-41-person402" type="surname" value="Fennel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person402" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17430629-41-viclabel231" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-victim400 t17430629-41-viclabel231"></join>, and lodge in Rosemary-Lane; on the 21st Day of this Month, I happened to go into the Blue Anchor Alehouse in the <placeName id="t17430629-41-crimeloc232">Back Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-41-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="Back Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-41-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-off229 t17430629-41-crimeloc232"></join>, about three Quarters of an Hour after Eleven at Night, and called for a Pint of Beer, standing, I drank it and walked off; I saw the Prisoner at the Bar, and this Burton, the Evidence, standing in the Kitchen as I came out, with two other Men; I had not come above forty Yards from the House before I saw them altogether; the first Person that attacked me (which was the Prisoner at the Bar,) gave a Stroke at me, and beat off my Hat and Wig; (I do not know what Weapon it was with:) He gave me a second Stroke, and at the second Stroke he made at me, two more came up, and made several other Strokes at me, and knocked me down; then I cried out Murder, and called for the Watch several Times. After they had knocked me down, one of them put his Knee upon my Breast, while the other rifled my Pockets, and took away my Money, which was sixteen Shillings; upon my crying out Murder the Watch came, and they seeing that the Watch were coming, they took away my Hat and Wig, and made their Escapes; when they were gone, the Watch came up; I charged the Watch with the Woman, and the next Morning she was carried before Justice Richards, and was discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you discern the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Fennel. By the Light of a Candle in the House, where I drank the Pint of Beer; and the Woman of the House said, it was a Shame to use a Man so. - I have known the Prisoner ever since April last, by living in the Neighbourhood. I do not know whether he knew me or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who kneeled upon your Breast?</p>
               <p>Fennel. Neither of these two Men.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took your Money out of your Pocket?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174306290024"></xptr>Fennel. He that kneeled upon my Breast did not take my Money, it was another. - The Prisoner was the Person that first knocked me down.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you see that the Prisoner was the Man that knocked you down first?</p>
               <p>Fennel. It was by the Light of the Candle, that was held out of the Window.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that you first cried out?</p>
               <p>Fennel. I did not cry out 'till I was knocked down.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say, that the Prisoner was the first Person that knocked you down?</p>
               <p>Fennel. Yes: I could see every Thing as plain as can be; I saw the Man's Face as plain as can be; if there was no Light but the Light of the Element, there was Light enough to see his Face.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to enquire into his Character; because they cannot hang me for what they tried me for before, they have trumped up this Thing; I know no more of it than the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430629-41-person403">
                  John 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17430629-41-person403" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person403" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of this Month, about 11 o'Clock at Night, the Prisoner, two more, and myself, went into the Blue Anchor in Rag Fair, to drink a Pint of Beer; while we were there, the Prosecutor came in, and called for a Pint of Beer; while he was drinking the Pint of Beer, there was a young Woman came to the Door, and he asked her to drink, and he wanted the Woman to pay for the Pint of Beer: The Landlady turned the Woman out of Doors, and would not let her be along with him. While he was drinking this Pint of Beer, we resolved, when he went out, to rob him; and when he got about twenty Yards from the House, the Prisoner at the Bar struck him with a Mop-stick, and knocked his Hat and Wig off first, and then the Prisoner struck him several Times more, and at last knocked him down. After he was knocked down, two of us fell upon him, and took the Money out of his Pocket; the Prisoner is the Man who took the Money out of his Pocket. In the mean Time, while he was taking the Money out of his Pocket, the Woman who keeps the Blue. Anchor, came out with a Candle, and as we were going to run away, the Prosecutor laid hold on the Prisoner; and one of the Persons, who is got off, beat the Prosecutor very much with a Mop-stick; then we all got away, and the Prosecutor pursued us a good Way afterwards.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I do not know this Evidence; I never saw the Man in my Life; I can bring Witness to prove, that I was at Home and in Bed when the Thing was done. <rs id="t17430629-41-verdict233" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-verdict233" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430629-41-punish234" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430629-41-punish234" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-41-defend396 t17430629-41-punish234"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
