<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470116-29">
               <interp inst="t17470116-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-29" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-29" type="date" value="17470116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-29-off126-c326" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-defend390 t17470116-29-off126 t17470116-29-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>105. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-defend390" type="defendantName">
                     Judith 
                     Taylor 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-29-defend390" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-defend390" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-defend390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-29-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing two Pewter Plates, one Holland Shirt, one Table cloth, one Napkin
            </rs>, &amp;c. the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-victim392" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Howel 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-29-victim392" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-victim392" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-victim392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-off126 t17470116-29-victim392"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             of Fetter lane, <rs id="t17470116-29-cd127" type="crimeDate">January 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-off126 t17470116-29-cd127"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-person393">
                  Thomas 
                  Howel 
               <interp inst="t17470116-29-person393" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person393" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I employed the Prisoner as a <rs id="t17470116-29-deflabel128" type="occupation">Washerwoman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-defend390 t17470116-29-deflabel128"></join>, and to scour my Pewter; I live at the <placeName id="t17470116-29-crimeloc129">Red-hart in Fetter lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470116-29-crimeloc129" type="placeName" value="Red-hart in Fetter lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470116-29-crimeloc129" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-off126 t17470116-29-crimeloc129"></join> ; on Saturday was Fortnight she was at my House at scouring, I think it was the 3d of this Month, and in the Afternoon the Plate was sent out of Holbourn by a Pewterer to ask if it was my Plate: one of the Pewter Plates that she took was not mine, it was a new Plate that was sent to my House with some Brawn.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you lose any thing else?</p>
               <p>Howel . That Day Week when she came to scour again, and I asked her how she could serve me so, to go to sell my Plate, she made me Answer, It was not wronging of me, it was not my Plate; I said it was wronging of me, as it was in my Possession; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174701160030"></xptr> said she should work no more for me, so I got a Warrant and took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you lost?</p>
               <p>Howel . I have lost a great many Things of Shifts and Shirts, and my Shelf stripped of all my Pewter; I went up into Holbourn among her Acquaintance where she had worked, there I found she had sold a Shirt, Neckcloth, and Napkin, and a Couple of Plates, a diaper Napkin and Table cloth; the Napkin and Table-cloth I found at Mr Gibbons in Little Turn stile, at a Pawnbroker's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find your Plates?</p>
               <p>Howel . The Plates I found at Mr Singleton's .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-person394">
                  Thomas 
                  Gibbons 
               <interp inst="t17470116-29-person394" type="surname" value="Gibbons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person394" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Pawnbroker, there was a Table-cloth and a Napkin Mr Howel had out which she brought, I lent her two Shillings upon them, she lived in the Neighbourhood, and has done many Years; any thing she brought that was not likely to be her own, she said she came from other People.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-person395">
                  William 
                  Singleton 
               <interp inst="t17470116-29-person395" type="surname" value="Singleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person395" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 12th of December, the Prisoner at the Bar brought two Plates to my House, and pawned them for 8 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-29-person396">
                  Mary 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17470116-29-person396" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person396" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner a great while, she had used my House about seven Months; about two Months ago she brought that Neckcloth to sell, she said it was her Husband's Brother's.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that was the Neckcloth?</p>
               <p>Townsend . Yes, Sir, I delivered it to Mr Howel.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy it?</p>
               <p>Townsend . I gave her for it one and twenty Pence, a Pint of Beer, and a Quartern of Gin, and a Bit of Victuals I gave her when she sat drinking of it; after that she told me she had some Shirts in pawn, that she wanted to sell them; I had lately bought my Husband Linnen, and I did not want, and I said I did not care to buy them; about seven or eight Weeks ago she came to me and said, if I would not fetch them, that such a Woman in the Neighbourhood would take them, I took Money in my Pocket, and went to Mr Gibbons , Pawnbroker, and she asked for a Shirt in her Name, and I paid 5 s. 6 d. for it; when I came Home, I looked at the Things, I said did it belong to the same Person, she said it belonged to the same Person that the Cravat belonged to, she said it was her Husband's Brother's; upon that I examined it, and she had seven Shillings for the Shirt, and it cost me one Shilling the altering, my Husband did not care to wear it, and he never had it on his Back but two Days.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. What have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say, they have said more than they can answer; I can say no more, God forgive them. <rs id="t17470116-29-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470116-29-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-29-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-29-defend390 t17470116-29-punish131"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
