<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17461015-22">
               <interp inst="t17461015-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-22" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17461015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-22" type="date" value="17461015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17461015-22-off92-c347" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-22-defend391 t17461015-22-off92 t17461015-22-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Jewel 
                  <interp inst="t17461015-22-defend391" type="surname" value="Jewel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-defend391" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-defend391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17461015-22-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Quart Silver Tankard , Value 5 l. 5 s. and one Silver Cup, Value 4 l. 10 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-victim392" type="victimName">
                  Robert 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-victim392" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-victim392" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-victim392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-22-off92 t17461015-22-victim392"></join>
                  </persName>
             , of Swithins Lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person393">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person393" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person393" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Robert Hill) Have you lost any Thing lately ?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes , my Lord, I lost a Silver Tankard , and a Silver Cup, that holds almost a Quart.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Value of the Tankard?</p>
               <p>Hill. I reckon'd it about 5 l. 10 s. and the Cup 4 l. 10 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose them from ?</p>
               <p>Hill. I lost them out of the End of the Grate; they unwired about five of the Wires that binds the Grate round by the other main Wires to keep them together .</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that they did this ?</p>
               <p>Hill. I can't say that I saw them; I had good Customers in the Shop at the same Time, that I can't say that I saw them.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was this ?</p>
               <p>Hill. A little before Twelve at Noon; the two Fellows that stole them were taken, Jewel, and the Evidence , 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person394">
                  James 
                  Norril 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person394" type="surname" value="Norril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person394" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What then ?</p>
               <p>Hill. Then we , with the Constable, took them to the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. After they were taken, was you sent for?</p>
               <p>Hill. After they were taken, they were brought up to my Shop, and I sent for the Constable, and took them to the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. What pass'd when they came to your Shop?</p>
               <p>Hill. They said nothing all that Time. About Seven or Eight o'Clock the Constable and another Neighbour went to them to the Compter, to whom they confess'd several Things. About Eight o'Clock Jewel said if they sent for me, he would tell me what they had done with my Cup and Tankard .</p>
               <p>Q. And what did he tell you?</p>
               <p>Hill. He told me he had sold the Cup and Tankard to a Jew in Houndsditch (opposite the Gullyhole ) for four Guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, please to ask him whether he minds the Jew's Name.</p>
               <p>Hill. He nam'd the Jew to me, and his Name was Cordozo .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person395">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person395" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person395" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person396">
                  James 
                  Norril 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person396" type="surname" value="Norril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person396" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Norril. Please you , my Lord, I work'd at a House in Barnaby-Street, where the Prisoner lived before he was taken up. When 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person397">
                  Philip 
                  Jewel 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person397" type="surname" value="Jewel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person397" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came home from Transportation, his Creature that he lived with lodg'd there; so he enquired her out, and came there; he ask'd me to go out with him, which I did. I was acquainted with him about a Week.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you become acquainted with him ?</p>
               <p>Norril. At this Lodging-House in Kent-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you do any thing together?</p>
               <p>Norril. We went up Kent-Street Road. We came afterwards into Swithin's-Lane ; I had a Jews-Harp in my Hand, and he saw these Things in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150032"></xptr> Grate ; he ask'd me to lend him the Jews-Harp, and he took it and broke about five of the Wires of the Grate with this Jews-Harp.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see ?</p>
               <p>Norril. My Lord, I was coming up Swithin's-Lane, so he stopt ; I did not know what he was about 'till he took the Silver Cup and Tankard, and he put them under his Coat .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do in the mean time?</p>
               <p>Norril . I stood over the Way ; I did not know he was breaking the Grate .</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Intent of you two walking together ?</p>
               <p>Norril. My Lord , I have no Friends at all; and I lodging at this House, he ask'd me to go out to take a Walk, and drink Part of a Pint of Beer, and we happened to go to Swithin's-Lane, where he saw this Grate with the Plate in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the Shop?</p>
               <p>Norril. Yes , my Lord, that Gentleman, Mr. Hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the Shop besides.</p>
               <p>Norril. My Lord, I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he about this?</p>
               <p>Norril. About Half a Quarter of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do then?</p>
               <p>Norril. He ty'd it up in the Flap of his Coat, and carried it into Houndsditch to one 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person398">
                  Aaron 
                  Cordozo 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person398" type="surname" value="Cordozo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person398" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and sold both for about 4 l. 14 s.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with the Money; had you Part of it?</p>
               <p>Norril. About a Guinea, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go after that?</p>
               <p>Norril. He would come past the same Door, Mr. Hill's Door in Swithin's-Lane ; and when we got almost to the End of the Street there were two or three crying after us, Stop Thief! and they laid hold of us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they take you?</p>
               <p>Norril. Yes, my Lord, they took us both.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Norril . Then they carried us to this Gentleman's Shop, and then to the Compter, and the next Morning before the Alderman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person399">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person399" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person399" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Would you ask him any Question?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether he stood on the other Side of the Way when I did this Fact.</p>
               <p>Court . He has sworn he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person400">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person400" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person400" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person401">
                  Edward 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person401" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person401" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable.) What do you know of this Affair ?</p>
               <p>Gregory . On the 15th of September, on Monday, I think, about Four o'Clock in the Afternoon, I was sent for to Mr. Hill's Shop , to take Charge of the Prisoner at the Bar and this 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person402">
                  James 
                  Norril 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person402" type="surname" value="Norril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person402" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I took them to the Compter, and I observed that they were obstinate , and I desired they might be kept apart, not to converse together. I went in the Evening with a Neighbour to the Compter; I thought it was proper to go and see them; and I went to this young one that is turn'd Evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night did you go to them?</p>
               <p>Gregory. I believe it was about Seven or Eight . I ask'd several Questions about this Fact, but he knew nothing of it he said . In about Half an Hour there came a Woman crying to see him (the Prisoner at the Bar ;) she told me her Name was 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person403">
                  Alice 
                  Beckstone 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person403" type="surname" value="Beckstone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person403" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person403" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she said, he should save his Neck by turning Evidence. Jewel, the Prisoner at the Bar , said, he and this 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person404">
                  James 
                  Norril 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person404" type="surname" value="Norril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person404" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to Mr. Hill's Shop , they broke open the Grate, and took out the Tankard and the Cup.</p>

               <p>Q. And what else did they say ?</p>
               <p>Gregory. That they sold it for four Guineas and a Half to a Jew; I don't remember that he knew his Name, but the young one said his Name was Cordozo, who lived over-against the Gully-Hole in Houndsditch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing else ?</p>
               <p>Gregory. When he had made this Confession, I said I must search him; he said, if I did, I should find nothing but a Jews-Harp . He said, in breaking the Wires of the Grate, he broke a Piece of the Jews-Harp, and he said, I believe if you go to look for it, you will find it there: He broke a Piece off, and he believed it fell down in the Street, at the Corner of the Shop Window; he believed that we might find it there, if we went to look for it; he said the Jews-Harp belong'd to his Companion, 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person405">
                  James 
                  Norril 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person405" type="surname" value="Norril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person405" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The next Morning a Neighbour of Mr. Hill's and mine went to look for the Piece of the Jews-Harp, and found it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person406">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person406" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person406" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person407">
                  William 
                  Walter 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person407" type="surname" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person407" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say with respect to this Fact against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Walter. My Lord, I went along with the Constable, about Seven o'Clock, to the Compter, to hear if we could find my Neighbour's Plate. About Seven o'Clock the Prisoner at the Bar began to confess several Robberies ; at length he confess'd about the Tankard and Cup; he said he would not say any thing 'till the right Owner of the Goods was there; and I immediately sent for Mr. Hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, did Mr. Hill come?</p>
               <p>Walter. Yes, my Lord, he came presently. As soon as Mr. Hill came into the Room, the Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150033"></xptr> said, that's the Gentleman that we took the Cup and Tankard from; he was sitting behind the Compter with his Spectacles on, selling some Rings to a Gentlewoman .</p>
               <p>Q. What then ?</p>
               <p>Walter . I ask'd him, my Lord, what he broke the Wires of the Grate with; he told me with a Jews-Harp, and said, if you look under the Grate where I broke the Wires off, there you will find a Piece of the Jews-Harp .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at any Time go to look for it ?</p>
               <p>Walter. On the 16th in the Morning, about Six o'Clock, I got up and look'd under the Grate, and here's the Piece of the Jews-Harp which I found .</p>
               <p>[The Jews-Harp and Piece were produced in Court, and they exactly tallied .]</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he give the Jews-Harp to when he took it out of his Pocket?</p>
               <p>Walter. The Constable had it, I saw him take it out of his Pocket. I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17461015-22-person408">
                  Edward 
                  Bellamy 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person408" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person408" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and shew'd him this Jews-Harp, and he said it was a very material Thing, I should be careful of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-22-person409">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-22-person409" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-person409" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) What have you to say with respect to this Fact?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I will throw myself up to the Mercy of the Court.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Witness?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17461015-22-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17461015-22-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-22-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-22-defend391 t17461015-22-punish94"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
