<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400522-11">
               <interp inst="t17400522-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-11" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-11" type="date" value="17400522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-11-off69-c98" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-defend125 t17400522-11-off69 t17400522-11-verdict73"></join>
         
               <p>261. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-defend125" type="defendantName">
                     Rochford 
                     Fitzgerald 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-defend125" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-defend125" type="given" value="Rochford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-defend125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400522-11-defloc67">St Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-defloc67" type="placeName" value="St Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-defloc67" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-defend125 t17400522-11-defloc67"></join>, was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17400522-11-cd68" type="crimeDate">First of February, 1738</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-off69 t17400522-11-cd68"></join> 
                  <rs id="t17400522-11-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously made and forged, and caused to be made and forged, a certain false and counterfeit Order for the Payment of Money
            </rs>, in the Words and Figures following, viz.</p>
               <p>London 27 December 1738.</p>
               <p>Messieurs Knight and Shuttleworth.</p>
               <p>Pay Mr Rochford Fitzgerald, or Bearer, Fourteen Days after Date, Twelve Pounds Ten Shilings.</p>
               <p>L. 12 10 o</p>
               <p>For Richd. Lutterell and Comp'.</p>
               <p>Change Alley.</p>
               <p>With Intent to defraud 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-victim127" type="victimName">
                     Robinson 
                     Knight 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim127" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim127" type="given" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-victim129" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Shuttleworth 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim129" type="surname" value="Shuttleworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim129" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17400522-11-viclabel70" type="occupation">Bankers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-victim127 t17400522-11-viclabel70"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-victim129 t17400522-11-viclabel70"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-victim131 t17400522-11-viclabel70"></join>, in Exchange Alley, against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Indictment further charged him with uttering and publishing the said counterfeit Order (as above) he well knowing it to be false and counterfeit, with Intent to defraud Mess. Knight and Shuttleworth, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>He was farther charged, as in the first Count in the Indictment, with Intent to defraud 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-victim131" type="victimName">
                     Patrick 
                     Cannon 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim131" type="surname" value="Cannon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim131" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-victim131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of St Martin's in the Fields, <rs id="t17400522-11-viclabel71" type="occupation">Vintner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-victim131 t17400522-11-viclabel71"></join>, against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>He was likewise charged with uttering and publishing the same, with Intent to defraud Patrick Cannon, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution having opened the Indictment, and the Nature of the Offence, the Witnesses were call'd.</p>
               <p>Patrick Cannon. I know this Paper, 'tis a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220013"></xptr> Draught on Knight and Shuttleworth. I had it for a Security, and I was taken up last New-Year's Day was Twelvemonths, on Account of this Note, at Messieurs Knight and Shuttleworth's, in Change-Alley. I went thither to get the Note accepted, and tendered it to Mr Shuttleworth himself: He desired me to stay a little, and told me he thought Mr Lutterel was not then (a Trader) in Company, but he said he would send for him, and accordingly he did, and asked him if the Name Richard Lutterel and Company was his Hand? He told him it was not; upon which I was taken up, and carried before the Lord Mayor; but was discharged, because I only came with it for Acceptance. I had it from the Prisoner; he came to my House, the Sign of the Cannon in Suffolk-Street, with two Bailiffs, and desired me to Bail him in a Action for 6 Guineas. I told him I did not care to be bail for him, because I had suffered before, by being bail, and had paid the Money. He said, - because you shall not be under any Apprehensions of losing by me, here's a Note, (but the Money is not yet due,) take it for your Security, and I shall be obliged to you. So I took it as a Security, and had it 6 or 8 Days, in my Pocket. 'Tis now in the same Condition as it was when I received it from the Prisoner, and when I tendered it for Acceptance, excepting that my Name Pa. Cannon, is wrote upon the back. I have known the Prisoner 2 or 3 Years; and I know his Hand-writing: I have seen him write several Times. I take the Words Lutterel and Company, to be the Prisoner's Hand: All the Note I think is the Prisoner's Hand-writing, and I have seen him write several Times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. You speak of something on the Back of the Note; - What was wrote on the Back?</p>
               <p>Cannon. When I tendered the Note for Acceptance, Mr Lutterel was sent for, and he asked me my Name, and where I lived? I told him, and he wrote it on the Back of the Note. I did not examine the Note when I took it, but thought it a very good one, seeing it drawn on checqu'd Paper, and I read it, at the same Time; and thinking it was a good Note, I did not take much Notice of it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did you take it to be my Handwriting, when you received it from me?</p>
               <p>Cannon. No; I did not. I did not know but it might be Mr Lutterel's Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was not you acquainted with my Hand-writing before?</p>
               <p>Cannon. Yes; but I could not then tell whether 'twas his, or no: If I had taken it to have been the Prisoner's Hand-writing, to be sure I should not have carried it to the Bankers for Acceptance.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was not I arrested that Morning; and had not I some Discourse with you (before this Note was given you) about your being Bail for me?</p>
               <p>Cannon. Yes: He was arrested that Morning, and I did not chuse to be Bail for him. He had sent for me before this, to be Bail for him for 32 l. which I refus'd; but this he said was a Trifle, 'twas but for 6 Guineas.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you say, you did not care to be Bail, because you should disoblige your Wife?</p>
               <p>Cannon. I can't tell whether there was any Discourse at all, about my Wife. I never consult her about these Things.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. How long was it, after I came in, that you bail'd me?</p>
               <p>Cannon. In about 8 or 10 Minutes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was the Note given, before you bail'd me, or after?</p>
               <p>Cannon. I can't resolve that Question: I think it was given me, for a Security, if I would bail him. I told him, I did not care to be Bail for him, and he gave me this Note, as a Security, and said it would be the same as Money. He told me, it was not yet due, and therefore, he could not then command the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you say, you must have something to shew your Wife, before you could give Bail.</p>
               <p>Cannon. I never mentioned a Word about my Wife, when he talked about my being his Bail, as I know of. I think the Note was given me, after I had bail'd him. I was not willing to be bail for him, but when he offered me the Note for a Security, I agreed to be his Bail. The Note was read, as inserted in the Indictment, and on the Back thereof was wrote, - Pa. Cannon, in Suffolk-Street.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. You say, you was taken up, on New-Year's Day was a Twelvemonth; When did you see me after that?</p>
               <p>Cannon. The next Day; and several Times afterwards, but he was not taken up on this Account. The Prisoner came to me the next Day after I was taken up; and asked me, if I had not been in the City, with Mr Lutterel? I said, No, I have not. He reply'd, I thought I had seen you with him. And at that very Time, I sent for Mr 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person132">
                  Mark 
                  Lawn 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person132" type="surname" value="Lawn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person132" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and told him I would not let the Prisoner go, 'till I was satisfied for the Money I had bail'd him for. The Prisoner then said, he was sorry for what he had done, but Mr Lutterel<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220014"></xptr> (he said) had given him Liberty, to draw upon his Checques. He farther told me, he had been with Mr Lutterel, and had desired him not to give the Note out of his Hands.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Had not I surrendered myself, in Discharge of my Bail, at that Time?</p>
               <p>Cannon. No, for on Saturday after this, he came to my House, in the Afternoon, and said, he had paid the Debt, or made it easy; but on the Monday following I had Notice, that if I did not come and pay the Money, I should be sued; so I went and gave in Bail above; which cost me 8 s. After this he gave me his Sword, and two Guineas for my Security.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Have not I been often at your House for these 8 Months last past; and have not I been visible, and publick, in other Places?</p>
               <p>Cannon. Yes; I believe he hath.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Have you not declared, that at the Time the Note was given you, you knew it was my Hand Writing, and that it was deposited with you, only to make your Wife easy.</p>
               <p>Cannon. No; I swear I never did.</p>
               <p>Mr Lutterel was called, but the Prisoner's Counsel observing that the Indictment charged the Prisoner, with intending to defraud the said Mr Lutterel, the Court were of Opinion he could not be permitted to give Evidence, because he was concerned in Point of Interest.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner admitted the Note in Question, to be his own Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person133">
                  Edward 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person133" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person133" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot positively say I heard the Prisoner say he forged this Note, but I advised him to go abroad on Account of forging it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. After this Note was given, was not I visible, and to be seen?</p>
               <p>Mr Masters. Yes; I have seen him at Can non's House, after the Note was given, and after Cannon had been carried before the Lord Mayor: I cannot tell how often I have seen there; I have met him in the Streets, within these three or four Months, but have not seen him at Cannon's House, within these 8 Months last past. Formerly I have seen him in Mr. Lutterel's Company, but not since the Date of this Note.</p>
               <p>Couns. But when you advised him to go abroad did he not take your Advice?</p>
               <p>Mr Masters. He went abroad some time afterward, - 'twas some Time in the latter End of January; how long he staid abroad, I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth was called, and as it appeared that he refused to accept the Note, he could not be concerned in Point of Interest, therefore he was admitted to give Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth. Tho' the Note was brought to me, I was not liable to pay it, unless I had accepted it. I had Money of Mr Lutterel's in my Hands, and had the Note come from him, I should have paid it. This Note was brought to me, by Cannon, on the 1st of Feb. 1738, for Acceptance. I knew it was not Mr Lutterel's Hand, but if I had not happened to have seen it, I do not know but our Servants might have accepted it.</p>
               <p>Couns. When you saw it was not Mr Lutterel's Hand, did not you give him Notice?</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth. Yes, I sent for him.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you ever pay any Draught to the Prisoner, in Mr Lutterel's Name?</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth. No, never in my Life, as I know of. We had had several Draughts forged upon us; one in particular for 154 l. which made me the more careful at that Time.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not Mr Lutterel's Draughts used to be in the Name of Lutterel and Company?</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth. Yes, formerly they did, but not lately: not when this Note was made.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was not the Note shewn to Mr Lutterel, at the Time it came to be accepted?</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth. Yes, it was, in order to be carried to my Lord Mayor's; and it has been either in his Hands, or mine, or the Attorney's, ever since. We gave it to the Attorney, that he might take out a Warrant for the Prisoner; but he was not taken up, for he fled; as I was told by Mr Barnard the Attorney.</p>
               <p>Couns. [to Cannon ] Was you acquainted with Mr Lutterel's Hand-writing, as well as the Prisoner's?</p>
               <p>Cannon. I cannot say I am; I never saw him write in my Life.</p>
               <p>Defence. Cannon says I came to him with two Officers, - I had been with him to tell him that I had had the Officers with me, on Account of a Debt which was not my own; and not being willing to pay it, I desired him ( Cannon ) to pay it, and I appointed the Officers to come to his House, and I would meet them there. Accordingly I went thither and drank Frontiniac above Stairs, and told him I had been arrested, and by whom; and I desired him to be Bail for me, telling him I should have Money in a few Days. He made no Objection to it; but said, he had no kind of Doubt that he should suffer by me, I having often owed him more Money and paid him. Afterwards he told me, he apprehended it might occasion some Family Disturbance, and begged to be excused from bailing me, unless I could contrive to silence the Family Disturbance: upon which I took this Piece of chequed Paper<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220015"></xptr> out of my Pocket, which I had from Mr Fitzgerald, who is Mr Lutterel's Clerk, to make some Draughts upon Mr Lutterel, by Order of a Gentlewoman who had Cash in his Hands, and upon a Piece of this chequed Paper I wrote this Draught, desiring him not to use it; and telling him, I gave it him to silence the Disturbance in his Family, till I brought him the Money, or the Plaintiff's Discharge. And in this Confidence in him, that it should not be made Use of, I gave him this Draught, and made it payable not till 14 Days after Date. But the Day after, he being pressed for Money, goes into the City and offers the Note, telling me I was a good-natured Man, and he believed, that as I was intimate with Mr Lutterel, the Sanction of my Name would have influenced Mr Lutterel to pay it. What I have farther to offer, is, that I had at that time several accepted Notes of Mr Lutterel's in my Possession, and therefore it is not to be supposed that I should do this with an Intent to defraud him, and I put the Word Company to his Name, left it should be made an ill use of. Mr Lutterel told me, (being married to one of his Family, and being often at his House, and seeing his Letters, and being conversant in his Counting-house, and in his Business) that he was assured I did neither intend, or mean, to injure him or Mr Shuttleworth f, but that I had done an imprudent Thing; therefore (says he) go and discharge Cannon from any Demand he has upon you. Accordingly, though I never intended to have paid this Debt of 6 l. yet as I had done so imprudent a Thing. I went and paid it; and yet after all this, Cannon (being spirited up by some People who are pleased to have some little Jealousy of me,) goes before Colonel De Veil, and makes an Affidavit of all this, upon which there was a Warrant taken out against me, and I was advised to step out of the way: I refused to go, at first; because that would look like Guilt; but afterwards having 157 l. due to me at Dunkirk, I applied to Mr 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person134">
                  George 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person134" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person134" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in the City, and he gave me a Letter of Recommendation, that I might be assisted in the Recovery of the Debt; and having a Gentlewoman that lived with me, at that time there, I promised to come and see her at Dunkirk, for which End, I sent over some Money and Cloaths, and went to her, because some of her Friends and mine were disobliged at our living together; so I took that Opportunity to go thither; and an Affair about a Bankruptcy detain'd me there, longer than I intended to stay. But since my coming back, I have been several times at Mr Lutterel's, and fifty times at Cannon's House; and I have dined there often, I imputed this Transaction to his Ignorance rather than to any Design; but being there one Sunday Evening playing a Game at Cards, Cannon, who served the Wine, was pleased to make some Observations on the Game, which since has subjected me to another * Indictment: He alledging that I subjected the Gentleman (my Partner) to the Loss of the Game, that I might come in, for a Share of his Money which he was to lose. I intended to have prosecuted Cannon for this Aspersion, and so he brought this Prosecution against me.</p>
               <p>* See the Conclusion of last Sessions Paper.</p>
               <p>Mr Shuttleworth was asked if he gave this chequed Paper to People, that were to draw upon him? He answered yes, and that he believed the Cheque upon which this forged Note was drawn, was one of his.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person135">
                  Robert 
                  Gill 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person135" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person135" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I, and 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person136">
                  Matthias 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person136" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person136" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             arrested Fitzgerald, in St Martin's Street, near Liecester-Fields, some Time in December last was a Twelve month; he was carry'd to the Py'd Bull, in Grays Inn Lane, and afterwards to Cannon's House. There was nobody with us at Cannon's, but Powel and I, the Prisoner, and Powel's Man. We went up Stairs, and I was one of his Bail, with Cannon. I don't remember any Talk about the Note, nor did I see any Note given. Cannon had been applied to before, to bail the Prisoner, in an Action in the Sheriff's Court for 30 l; but his Bail was not thought sufficient at that Time. In this Action for 6 Guineas, 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person137">
                  Robert 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person137" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person137" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was Plaintiff, and the Suit was in the Marshalsea Court; and when the Prisoner proposed Cannon to be his Bail, he said, he did not want any Security at all; he said nothing about this Note; I did not see any thing of it; nor was there any thing said about Cannon's Wife.</p>
               <p>Couns. Where did you first see Cannon?</p>
               <p>Gill. At the Py'd Bull in Gray's Inn Lane. Fitzgerald and Cannon were together there, and I went with them from thence to Cannon's House.</p>
               <p>Couns. Might not the Prisoner and Cannon be together, when you was not present?</p>
               <p>Gill. I was not with them all the Time, for we staid at Fitzgerald's Lodgings, while he went to see for Bail.</p>
               <p>Couns. How soon was the Bail given, after you came to Cannon's House?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220016"></xptr>Gill. It was given directly, as soon as possibly it could be done.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. What did Cannon say, when I asked him to be Bail for me, for the Six Guineas?</p>
               <p>Gill. Fitzgerald put his Hand in his Pocket, and pulled out some Money; Cannon said, he did not want Money at all; his Honour was sufficient. This was just before he gave Bail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person138">
                  Mark 
                  Lawn 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person138" type="surname" value="Lawn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person138" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Cannon's House when the Prisoner was arrested: Cannon told me Fitzgerald was arrested for 6 Guineas, and was above Stairs with two Officers. Before I went away, Cannon went up Stairs, and when he came down again, he told me, he had bail'd him, and he had a Note in his Hand. I looked at it, and said 'twas a Draught on Messieurs Knight and Shuttleworth. No, says Cannon, 'tis his own Hand-writing. Why says I, do you think the Man would be such a Fool to do such a Thing? Cannon immediately put his Hand in his Pocket, and pulled out a Letter, which he said was his Hand-writing too. I laugh'd at him, and said it was a Joke. I told him, 'twas a good Note on Messrs. Knight and Shuttleworth: No, said he, 'tis his own Handwriting: I know it as well as I do my own. I insisted upon it, that no Man in his Senses would do such a Thing; upon which he put his Hand in his Pocket, and pulled out the Letter; I compared the Note and the Letter, and never saw two Things so much alike in my Life; and then I believed it. This was 5 or 10 Minutes, or a Quarter of an Hour before the Officers went out of the House. When he shew'd me the Note, he said to me, I would have bailed the Prisoner, had he given me nothing; but he gave me this, and I know 'tis his Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did he give you no Reason why he took the Note, when he said he would have bailed me for nothing?</p>
               <p>Lawn. No; he did not. I might think what I pleased, but he said nothing to me about his Wife. I never saw the Prisoner above once or twice, before he came to Cannon's to be bailed. I thought it was done to satisfy his Wife, as such Things are often done to make a Family easy; but he did not say any thing about his Wife.</p>
               <p>Couns. And would you see a false Note produced under a Gentleman's Hand, and not complain of the Fraud.</p>
               <p>Lawn. Am I to be busy, and complain, when the Man (Cannon) told me himself, that he knew it was Fitzgerald's own Writing? I think I should have done very ill, if I had told of it, in any Company. I was glad to see Fitzgerald out of Custody.</p>
               <p>Couns. Where did you learn such Principles? Of Wreatbock?</p>
               <p>Lawn. I knew Mr Wreatbock, but what's that to me! Since the Prisoner came from France, I have been in his Company; and have seen Cannon with him; and so I have after Cannon had been taken up about this Note. I was with, him when he left his Sword and 2 Guineas with him as a Security for the 6 Guineas, after the Note was discovered. 'Twas easy for him to have taken him up before he did; for after he came from France, he appeared as publickly as any Man in the World. I have seen him at Randall's Coffee-House, and at the Royal Exchange, Fleet-Street, and all Parts of the Town.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether Mrs Cannon did not come into the Room, at the Time he was shewing him this Draught? and telling him it was my Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Lawn. I think that was the Thing that stopped our Discourse. I can't remember particularly, whether she came into the Room; but when the Door was open, she might hear every Word we spoke. I think I saw her, and that that hush'd our Discourse. I am a Marshalsea-Court Officer, and have been so these thirteen or fourteen Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person139">
                  Constantine 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person139" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person139" type="given" value="Constantine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person140">
                  Mark 
                  Lawn 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person140" type="surname" value="Lawn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person140" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Cannon's House, the Day the Prisoner was bailed; when Cannon came down Stairs, he said, he had bailed the Prisoner, and he brought down the Note, and said it was his Hand-writing; and he took a Letter out of his Pocket, and compared it with the Note. I did not know the Prisoner's Hand-writing, nor did Cannon say on what Account the Note was given him. Mrs Cannon was passing to and fro, at the same Time; and she came into the Room, when he was comparing the Note with the Letter, upon which he put it aside, and when she was gone she compared them again. Mr Lawn compared them together likewise, and said he knew it was his Hand-writing, upon comparing the Names together.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he say the Names, or the Body of the Note was the Prisoner's Writing?</p>
               <p>Matthews. I do not know what a Note is; but he compared the Hand-writings together, and said they were the same. I am Lawn's Assistant, and have been at Cannon's many Times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person141">
                  John 
                  Cogland 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person141" type="surname" value="Cogland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person141" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I used to go to Cannon's House to drink a Glass of Wine, and about 18 Months ago, I heard him say there was a Draught of 12 l. 10 s. and he was sorry he had presented it, for fear it should hurt the Prisoner. There was an Intimacy between the Prisoner and Cannon after he had presented; and he said he believed it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220017"></xptr> was not the Prisoner's Intention to defraud any body by it; but I am not positive to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person142">
                  Robert 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person142" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person142" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner; and have seen Cannon once or twice: This Note was given him about 18 Months ago, but I have seen him and the Prisoner in Company together after that. Fitzgerald the Prisoner owing me 6 Guineas upon a Note, I got him arrested, and my Attorney told me, he had put in Bail. A fortnight afterwards the Attorney told me, that unless the Prisoner surrender'd, the Bail would be fix'd for the Money. About a fortnight after this, the Prisoner call'd at my House, and proposed to pay me 5 Guineas: I went with him to a Tavern, and there I saw Mr Masters, a Wine Merchant, and Mr Cannon, and I received 5 Guineas, 4 of which, Cannon gave to the Prisoner, and he (the Prisoner) adding one to it, gave it me, and he was to pay the Attorney; at the same Time, Cannon returned a Silver-hilted Sword to the Prisoner, and the Bail was discharged, upon the Prisoner's giving me a Note for the remaining Guinea. Mr Masters told me, the Prisoner had made a fine Jobb of it; for in order to get Bail to my Action, he had forg'd Mr Lutterel's Name to a Draught upon the Bankers. Why, says I, what was the four Guineas and the Sword for? The Prisoner said, he gave him them to induce him to be Bail for him; and Cannon was by, and seem'd to own it: But he made some Difficulty in giving back the 4 Guineas, because the Prisoner owed him 35 s. for Wine, and Reckonings unpaid. I asked the Prisoner, how he could do so imprudent an Act, as to sign a Man's Name to a Note? He told me he did it, to let Cannon see he did not want Money; for he intended to make up the 4 Guineas, which he had given Cannon, 6, and to have paid me. But Cannon's calling at the Bankers with the Note, had discovered it to be bad. I never saw the Prisoner from that Time to this, 'till the Affair at the late Masquerade, and then I happened to dine with Mr Lutterel, and heard he was about prosecuting him for this Draught.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did Cannon hear the Prisoner say he had deposited 4 Guineas with him, to induce him to be Bail?</p>
               <p>Mr Fitzgerald. Yes, and Cannon own'd it; and with Relation to the 30 s. which Cannon would have stopp'd, the Prisoner told him, he need not talk so much about 30 s, for his Reckonings, for he had made his Wife a Present of Something, of much greater Value. I thought it was an odd Way of reproaching Cannon with his own Gallantries, but I was very glad to get my 5 Guineas. I have heard the Prisoner's Defence, and that he says he gave Cannon this Note to pacify his Wife; but I heard nothing of such a Pretence then. I asked the Prisoner what need he had to give him a Note, when he had left 4 Guineas and his Sword with him? He told me, he did it because I would not have him think he was under any Obligation to him. I understood that the Prisoner drew this Note before Cannon's Face, and I told Cannon, he was a Fool to take a Note wrote before his Face. Mr Masters said something, that Cannon was a Blockhead, but I do not know whether Cannon was in the Room when this was said. I was there about 10 Minutes, or much about that Space of Time; and the Prisoner then insinuated as if Cannon had seen him draw the Note. I have seen Cannon once, since that Time, at Mr Lutterel's, and it was the Day after the Masquerade. He insisted upon it that the Prisoner took it out of his Pocket ready drawn, and if he has sworn so now, I do not doubt but it is true.</p>
               <p>Mr 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person143">
                  James 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person143" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person143" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he knew the Prisoner; and that at Mr 
               <persName id="t17400522-11-person144">
                  George 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person144" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person144" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Request, he gave him, in October, a Letter of Recommendation to a Friend of his at Dunkirk, that he might be assisted in the Recovery of a Debt; that a Month or two afterwards, he saw the Prisoner upon Change, and had frequently seen him since he returned from France, but the Witness had no Acquaintance with him. The Witness was asked if the Debts he went over to recover were not one Nelson a Jeweller's? He answered, - he could not tell.</p>
               <p>J - H - deposed, he had known the Prisoner 6 or 7, or 5 Years to be sure; that he lived a <rs id="t17400522-11-deflabel72" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-11-defend125 t17400522-11-deflabel72"></join> with a Neighbour of his, and his Master when he came away gave him a good Character. Since which, he had bought Goods of him; he had given him Credit, and the Prisoner had paid him. He was asked if he had not suspected his having taken some of his Goods, and he answered, there was a Person said something to him about a Piece of Cambrick, but the witness was convinced there was nothing in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person145">
                  James 
                  Leony 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person145" type="surname" value="Leony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person145" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known him about 4 or 5 Months, and had been in his Company several times, but knew nothing of his General Character.</p>
               <p>G - B - had known him 7 or 8 Years; he had had Transactions with him, and never met with any Fraud. The Witness had seen him at his House, but never had any Conversation with him at Taverns, or Publick Houses. He believed he had been a visible Man for 7 or 8 Months last past. He added, that he knew the Prisoner before he went to France; he knew not what Business called him there; but while he was there he transacted some Affairs for him relating to one Nelson, and the Witness sent him a Bill of 20 l. for his Trouble. He could not remember whether the Prisoner appeared publickly before he went to France.</p>
               <p>Hen. Bostock had know him some Years, and he was surprized the Prisoner should subpoena him in his Behalf, when he could speak nothing in his Praise. He deposed, that the Prisoner's General Character for 5 or 6 Years past, was such, that he should be ashamed to claim him for an Acquaintance. He understood him in general, to have an idle contemptible Character; he knew nothing wicked of him himself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person146">
                  James 
                  Cogland 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person146" type="surname" value="Cogland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person146" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known the Prisoner about 6 years, and never till now heard of his being dishonest.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person147">
                  Joseph 
                  Simmonds 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person147" type="surname" value="Simmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person147" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known him 8 Years, he never heard any thing ill of him, except that he was addicted to Gaming.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person148">
                  Alex 
                  Montgomery 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person148" type="surname" value="Montgomery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person148" type="given" value="Alex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had know him since 1728. He used the Witness's House, and they had had Dealings together. He never knew any thing amiss of him, but heard he was under Misfortunes, about the Year 1738, and that he then went abroad; after which he returned and was frequently at the Witness's House, and was visible within 8 or 10 Months last past.</p>
               <p>- Burges had known him about a Year, in which time he never heard any great Harm of him, till this time. His first Acquaintance with him was in France.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person149">
                  Edward 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person149" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person149" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr Lutterel's Book-keeper, deposed, that the Prisoner and his Master were acquainted, but had no Dealings together, as he knew of; except that sometimes Mr Lutterel used to give him a Draught on Messrs. Knight and Shuttleworth, for Money due to Mrs Rookes, who received an Annuity of 50 l. per Annum from Mr Lutterel. He added, that sometimes the Prisoner came for the Money; sometimes Mrs Rookes; and that Mrs Rookes and the Prisoner kept Company together, but he did not take them to be Man and Wife. He farther said, that he delivered 2 or 3 of Mr Lutterel's Checques to the Prisoner, because he told the Witness he wanted to go to the Play, and he gave him these, that he might write upon them, to the Box-keeper, in order to get Admission for himself, or his Friends.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-11-person150">
                  Rob 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17400522-11-person150" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person150" type="given" value="Rob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed that upon the Prisoner's Application to him to give him a Character, he sent him Word, that he could not do it. He swore his Character was very indifferent, and that ever since he had quitted Business for a Pleasureable Life, he had been a Gamester. He added, that he had heard of twenty bad Actions of the Prisoner's; such as he should have been ashamed of.</p>
               <p>Another Gentleman deposed that he never had had any Acquaintance with the Prisoner; but he had heard him called a Gamester and Sharper. The Jury <rs id="t17400522-11-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-11-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
