<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420115-25">
               <interp inst="t17420115-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-25" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-25" type="date" value="17420115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420115-25-off117-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-defend219 t17420115-25-off117 t17420115-25-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>30. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-defend219" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Jordan 
                  <interp inst="t17420115-25-defend219" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-defend219" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-defend219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17420115-25-defloc116">St. Luke's, Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-25-defloc116" type="placeName" value="St. Luke's, Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-25-defloc116" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-defend219 t17420115-25-defloc116"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420115-25-off117" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-off117" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-off117" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420115-25-victim221" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Colt 
                        <interp inst="t17420115-25-victim221" type="surname" value="Colt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420115-25-victim221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420115-25-victim221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-off117 t17420115-25-victim221"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in a certain Court call'd <placeName id="t17420115-25-crimeloc118">Hartshorn court</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-crimeloc118" type="placeName" value="Hartshorn court"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-crimeloc118" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-off117 t17420115-25-crimeloc118"></join>, near the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Hat, Value 7s. a Peruke, Value 8 s. a Guinea and 4 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420115-25-cd119" type="crimeDate">Jan. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-off117 t17420115-25-cd119"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person222">
                  Thomas 
                  Colt 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person222" type="surname" value="Colt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person222" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was sevennight, at almost Twelve at Night, I met the Prisoner in Long-lane. He was asking Charity, and begg'd for God's Sake that I would relieve him. I told him it was not in my Power to relieve him, but I was going to the Red-lion in Aldersgate street, and if he would accept of Part of a Tankard of Beer, he should be welcome. We went into the Golden-horse Alehouse, and called for Beer, and when we were coming out, I told him, I was as destitute of a Lodging as he; upon which he said, he could help me to one. He then took me up Barbican into Golden-Lane , and then into Hartshorn-Court, where he said, he had got a Sw eetheart, and he would make her get up, and I should go to Bed. I did not like the Looks of the House, therefore would not go in; and he then shewed me another Place, where there was a Light; but I did not care to go in there neither, and so I determined to go to my own Lodging; and just as I came back to the House where he would have had me gone in first, he knock'd me down; I can't tell whether it was with his Fist or a Weapon, but my Face was very black. When he had got me down, he took off my Hat and Wig, and a Guinea in Gold, 4 s. in Silver, and a silk Hankerchief out of my Pocket. As soon as I recovered myself, I ran down some Alleys and call'd Watch! and I told the Watchman I had been robb'd, and that I believed the Prisoner was gone down some of those Alleys, but not being able to find him , I went to the Watch-house, and shewed the Beadle the Place where I was robb'd. I afterwards went with one of the Watchmen to the Golden Horse to see if they knew the Prisoner, but they denied that they knew any Thing of him, upon which I went back to the Watch-house, and after I had got a Handkerchief to tie about my Head, I went Home. The next Morning about ten o'Clock, the Watchmen came to my Lodging, and inform'd me they had found a Wig, and when I saw it, I knew it to be mine. They said, they would go to a Place where they suspected the Prisoner was, and would help me to the sight of him. Accordingly they went into a House, and I follow'd them, but the Place was so dark, that I came out again; and one of the Watchmen told me, the Person whom they suspected was there, and he was going to a Cook's Shop, and if I would set down on the Bench, I might have a full View of him. Presently he came out, and as soon as I saw his Face, I knew him to be the Man that robbed me. We went back to the Watch-house, and three Men were dispatch'd to take him, and when he was brought into the Room, he immediately came up to me, fell on his Knees, and desired me not to prosecute him, for so sure as I did, he should be hang'd; and this he repeated several Times.</p>
               <p>Pris. Is he sure I am the Man?</p>
               <p>Colt. Yes, I am certain of it.</p>
               <p>Pris. Where did you light on me first?</p>
               <p>Colt. In Long-Lane.</p>
               <p>Pris. Where did you carry me to?</p>
               <p>Colt. To the Golden-Horse .</p>
               <p>Pris. What did you give me there?</p>
               <p>Colt. Some Drink.</p>
               <p>Pris. Who was in Company?</p>
               <p>Colt. A great many Hackney Coachmen and some other People.</p>
               <p>C. Was it light enough for you to see the Prisoner's Face?</p>
               <p>Colt. Yes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174201150013"></xptr>C. Was you Sober?</p>
               <p>Colt. Yes, as sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person223">
                  John 
                  Austen 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person223" type="surname" value="Austen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman in the Liberty of Golden-Lane. Last Tuesday Morning at Two o'Clock, I was beating my Rounds in Hartshorn-Court, and heard a Man call Watch! Just by the Pump I saw the Prosecutor; he had a Blow on the Right Side of his Face, and he told me he had been knock'd down and robb'd. I bid him come along with me and I'd see if I could find the Prisoner. We went down some Alleys to no Purpose and then the Prosecutor went to the Watch-house, and we parted. When the Prisoner was taken and brought to the Watch-house, he fell on his Knees once or twice, and begg'd of the Prosecutor not to send him to Goal, for if he did, he was sure to be hang'd. He likewise did the same when he was before Justice Poulson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person224">
                  Charles 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person224" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person224" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About 2 o'Clock last Tuesday Morning, this 
               <persName id="t17420115-25-person225">
                  Thomas 
                  Colt 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person225" type="surname" value="Colt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person225" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came down to the Watch-house, and desir'd to come in. I was standing at the Door, and seeing him without either Hat or Wig, imagin'd he had been in a Quarrel, therefore refus'd to let him come in. The Beadle order'd him in, and he then describ'd the Person that had robb'd him, and the Place where he was carry'd to. I told him I would shew him the Person in the Morning, and accordingly I went into a Gin-shop in Hartshorn-Court by myself, and called for a Quartern, and I immediately saw the Person whom I suspected: That was this Man, 
               <persName id="t17420115-25-person226">
                  Christopher 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person226" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person226" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I told Colt that the Prisoner was coming out, and as soon as he saw him, he said, that is the very Man that robb'd me, but he has not got the same Cloaths on. We went down to the Watch-House, and told the Beadle of this, upon which he desired the Prosecutor not to take the Man up if he was not sure he was the Person, but he still insisted that he was the Man, and he should know him from ten Thousand. We then went, and apprehended him, and brought him to the Watch-House, and he directly went up to the Prosecutor, and said, for God's Sake don't prosecute me, for I shall be hang'd.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person227">
                  Henry 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person227" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person227" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with 
               <persName id="t17420115-25-person228">
                  Charles 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person228" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person228" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to take this Man out of the Ginshop, and when we brought him to the Watch-house, he fell on his Knees before the Prosecutor, and said if he was sent to Goal, he should certainly be hang'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person229">
                  William 
                  Whistler 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person229" type="surname" value="Whistler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person229" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into the Watch-house at Dinner time with a Pint of Beer according to Custom, and the Prosecutor desir'd me to go with the Watchmen to take 
               <persName id="t17420115-25-person230">
                  Christopher 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person230" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person230" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and with some Persuasions I consented. Hunt went in first, and Thompson and I follow'd, and we brought the Prisoner to the Watch-house. As soon as came in, he went up to the Prosecutor who sat facing the Door; and the Beadle asked him whether he knew the Prisoner? He reply'd he did, and that he was the Man that robb'd him: The Prisoner then said, for God's Sake, don't send me to Newgate ; don't swear against me, for if you do, so sure shall I be hang'd; and this he repeated three or four Times.</p>
               <p>- Dyer I was charged to assist the Constable , and when the Prisoner was before Justice Poulson , he fell on his Knees and desired Colt not to prosecute him, for it he swore against him, he should be hang'd,</p>
               <p>Defence. I have 2 or 3 Coachmen here that were in the Box drinking with the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person231">
                  George 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person231" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person231" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next Door to the Prisoner: Last Monday was 7-night , at Night, my Mistress desired the Prisoner to let me lie with him, and as I was going to Bed the Prisoner desired me to stay and sup with him; accordingly I did, and before twelve o'Clock, the Prisoner and all of us were a-bed .</p>
               <p>Q. How do you remember that Day?</p>
               <p>Hodges. Because the Prisoner was taken up next Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business do you follow?</p>
               <p>Hodges. I am a Frame Maker by Trade, but now Business is dead, I run on Errands.</p>
               <p>Q. What House is this in Hartshorn-Court ?</p>
               <p>Hodges. It is a sort of a Brandy-shop kept by one Mrs. Bagley.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person232">
                  Timothy 
                  Beversley 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person232" type="surname" value="Beversley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person232" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nothing to say on Account of the Prisoner, only this, that he is not the Person that came into the Golden Horse Alehouse with the Prosecutor, last Monday 7-night at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Beversley. Because I let them in, and took particular Notice of them.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of Night was the Prosecutor there?</p>
               <p>Beversley. He came in about Twelve, and staid a Quarter of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there at that Time of Night.</p>
               <p>Beversley. I assisted the People of the House, because it was Club Night, and the Gentleman of the House was angry, because I let Strangers in.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you take on you to say the Prisoner is not the Man, that came in with the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174201150014"></xptr>Beversley . Because when I went on Saturday to see the Prisoner I found him quite otherwise ; the other Man was a little short siz'd Man , of a dark Complection, and pretty much pock-broken .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person233">
                  George 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person233" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person233" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the lower Room under the Prisoner: There was a Sort of a Bit of a Supper that Night, and the Prisoner went up to Bed between Twelve and One , and the Door was bolted. I sat by the Fire-side when the Scuffle of the Robbery was done, and I heard some-body cry, Aye Boy! I can't tell who it was; presently one ran up the Alley, and then the Watchman came almost Two. I heard a Man call Watch! and the Watchman cryed, Aye Boy! What's the matter now? My Wife went out at Three o'Clock to visit a Woman who was dying; and I went down and bolted the Door after her and no-body went out afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person234">
                  Thomas 
                  Bradford 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person234" type="surname" value="Bradford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person234" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Man at the Bar is not the Person that came into the Golden Horse with the Man that was robb'd; I know it very well because I was there when they came in at 12 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Bradford. I am a Coachman and live in the Neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a Man was the Person that you say came in with the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Bradford. A thin, squat Man, fresh-colour'd in his Face, with a brownish Coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink with them?</p>
               <p>Bradford. No, but I was in the Box fronting them, and they had a pint of Two-penny Purl .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person235">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodcrost 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person235" type="surname" value="Woodcrost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person235" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Dinner at the Black-Horse in Golden-Lane at the same Time that the Prisoner was taken up. The Prosecutor said the Prisoner had pick'd him up in Long-Lane, and took him to the Golden Horse in Aldersgate street and treated him with a Pint of Two-penny Purl, after which he knock'd him down and robb'd him under Pretence of getting him a Lodging: I hearing this went to the House, and asked them what Sort of a Man was there last Night: They told me he was a swarthy Man, thin visag'd, and with brown Cloaths on. I desired them to go down to New-Prison to see the Prisoner, and Mr. Bradford and some others went, and said he was not the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person236">
                  John 
                  Gearing 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person236" type="surname" value="Gearing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about 16 Years: We work'd together as Wheel-boys in the Gold and Silver Way, I never heard but that he was an honest Fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person237">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Morson 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person237" type="surname" value="Morson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person237" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a Child, and liv'd in the House with him 10 Years. He used to go on Errands, and cry Fish about the Streets, and I never knew him guilty of an ill Thing; but I have not seen him much these 6 Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person238">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person238" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person238" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lived in my House 6 Years, and about 12 Months ago he worked with my Husband at some Houses in Cold Bath Fields. I have entrusted him all over my House when I had more than I have now, and never knew that he wrong'd me of any Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-25-person239">
                  Rebecca 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17420115-25-person239" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person239" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten Years, and never heard any ill of him in my Life. I liv'd in the Neighbourhood where his Mother lives, in Featherstone-street by Moorfields; he used to cry Fish about the Streets, and I have seen him almost every Day. - I am out of Place at present; the last Place I lived at was Mr. Hinton's, Cashier to the Bank.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you any Relation to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Warner. No, only a very great Acquaintance. <rs id="t17420115-25-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420115-25-punish121" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-25-punish121" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-25-defend219 t17420115-25-punish121"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
