<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-7">
               <interp inst="t17470429-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-7" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-7" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-7-off26-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-7-defend72 t17470429-7-off26 t17470429-7-verdict29"></join>
         
               <p>182. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-7-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Turner 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-7-defend72" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-defend72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470429-7-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing half a Guinea
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-7-victim74" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Lyon 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-7-victim74" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-victim74" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-victim74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-7-off26 t17470429-7-victim74"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470429-7-cd27" type="crimeDate">April 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-7-off26 t17470429-7-cd27"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-7-person75">
                  Edward 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17470429-7-person75" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person75" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the the 23d of this Instant, I came down Stairs, about nine o'Clock, I live at <placeName id="t17470429-7-crimeloc28">Newington-green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-7-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Newington-green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-7-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-7-off26 t17470429-7-crimeloc28"></join> ; when I came down, I says to my Mother, Pray be so kind as to set the Bar to rights, and John will clean it. I keep the Sign of the Weaver's Arms.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Lyon. While he was sweeping of it, he picked up half a Guinea; here, Sir, says he, if I had not been very careful, I might have swept this away, and you might have laid it to my Charge; so I whipp'd up Stairs, and said to my Wife, how could you leave half a Guinea on the Ground; she told me she had left two, a crooked one and a strait one, in the little black Box in the Drawer. With that I whipp'd down again ; Come, says I, John, look sharp, and you will find the other by and by; here's no Cellar , it can't run through, in the little black Box she left it; he was the Space of an Hour and an half hunting about; Come, says I, look sharp, John, you will find it; he was fumbling about his Side; Come , says I, John, if you can't find it, you shall be searched for it, for it can't be gone without Hands; accordingly I took him into the back Room , and made him pull off his Coat , and then I bid him unbotton his Breeches ; while he was unbottoning his Breeches , this Bag he flipped out of his Pocket, and slid down on the Ground; I asked him what that was? he said nothing that belongs to you, 'tis something of my own; my Wife and Mother stood at the Door, as it was not proper for them to be in the Room when the young Fellow was stripping ; so I says to my Mother, come in, here's something he does not care that I should see it; so my Mother came in , and she took hold of both his Hands, and we took up the Bag; I asked him what was in it, he said nothing but his own things; when the things were turned out, there was this crooked half Guinea, that we had missed, it was among the Half-pence; when I asked him how he could serve me so, he had nothing to say to the Purpose in his own Defence, but the Dog had thrown the Drawers down, and the like.</p>

               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-7-person76">
                  Eleanor 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17470429-7-person76" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person76" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Lyon . I gave Silver for two half Guineas; I had a crooked one before Candle-lighting, and a smooth one after; when my Husband came up to me, he said I was very careless to leave half a Guinea on the Ground; I said I left them in the Box; when he came down, John was a good while in the Bar, in order to find it; he had him into the other Room, then we went into the Room, and my Mother had hold of his Hands, and the Bag was turned out, and there was half a Guinea .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290009"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-7-person77">
                  Alice 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17470429-7-person77" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person77" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-person77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When my Son called me in, he was in a Sort of Struggle with the Prisoner . I saw the Bag , I said, this is my Bag, and I will see what is in it, and I held his Hands; this is my Bag, I made it myself, in Lothbury, at the Cock and Bottle, when I kept it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-7-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[The Prosecutor said he had a great Opinion of his Honesty, and he could not but acknowledge he had a good Character of him ; and as judging it might be the first Fact, he was only ordered for corporal Punishment.]</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-7-punish30" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-punish30" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-7-punish30" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-7-defend72 t17470429-7-punish30"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
