<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420224-57">
               <interp inst="t17420224-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-57" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-57" type="date" value="17420224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420224-57-off243-c297" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-57-defend408 t17420224-57-off243 t17420224-57-verdict245"></join>
         
               <p>59. 
               <persName id="t17420224-57-defend408" type="defendantName">
                  Jane 
                  Hale 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-defend408" type="surname" value="Hale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-defend408" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-defend408" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , for <rs id="t17420224-57-off243" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-off243" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-off243" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               receiving and housing the said Peterson, knowing him to have committed the aforesaid Felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person409">
                  Jonas 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person409" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person409" type="given" value="Jonas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17420224-57-crimeloc244">Lemon street, Goodman's Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-57-crimeloc244" type="placeName" value="Lemon street, Goodman's Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-57-crimeloc244" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-57-off243 t17420224-57-crimeloc244"></join>. On Saturday Night last, I had been out, and when I returned, I found my Wife in a great Surprize, and some Neighbours informed me that they had seen three Men in my Shop. I missed the Goods mentioned in the Indictment, and therefore got a Warrant to search a House which I suspected, at Saltpeter-Bank. When we went in, we found the Prisoner Hale there, - it was her House, and the Gentlemen drew their Swords and Daggers, and threatened our Lives. There were three Thieves, and four Women there: Hale was one of them, and she gave the Men the Key to get the Weapons, in order to drive us out of the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person410">
                  Mary 
                  Wissingham 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person410" type="surname" value="Wissingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person410" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person410" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday Night about Dusk, I was going Home towards Whitechapple, and saw the Prisoner Peterson, at this Gentleman's Door; - he keeps a Shoemaker's Shop. There was another Man in the Entry, who seemed to be opening the Hatch. I keeping a stand in Rag-Fair, knew these People bore a very bad Character, and was frighted; and so I went to my Neighbour's House, and told her I believed the Gentleman would be robbed; upon which, she left her Shop and went to see them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person411">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pretty 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person411" type="surname" value="Pretty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person411" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The last Witness came to my Shop, and told me, my Neighbour was like to be robbed, and I went and saw the Prisoner and two more, who have made their Escapes. I met Peterson and another, as I was going to tell my Neighbour. The other Man had an Apron as full of something as it could hold. I had been threaten'd by these Men before, therefore dust not take any Notice of them; but I went to my Neighbour Mrs. Rogers, and told her that her House was beset by Thieves She started up as I was talking to her, and out started a Man from the same Side as my Neighbour sells his Shoes on. Mrs. Rogers got up immediately, and said, she was robb'd and undone, and fell into Fits presently.</p>
               <p>Pris Peterson. Did you ever know me to be a Thief?</p>
               <p>Pretty I detected him once in taking a whole dozen of Stockings from a Neighbour; there were three of them, and I am sure he was one of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person412">
                  Nicholas 
                  Abel 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person412" type="surname" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person412" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , The first Proceeding of coming into the Thing was, that I was robbed last Friday Night. I happened to be along with a Customer in my Way of Business, and my Wife came to me, and told me, my Shop had been robbed. On Saturday, about 7 at Night I was informed, that Mr. Rogers had been robbed much in the same Manner as myself, a little after Candle-light, and therefore went to his House, and thought by our going together, we might meet with the Thieves who had robb'd us. He happened not to be at Home then, but on the Monday following, we took out a Warrant to search Hale's House. When we came in, there were the Prisoner and two more, who were the three Thieves of whom we had Information One of them I knew by Sight, because he is the Captain of New Prisons Son, I told the Constable - there was his Prisoner, and then one of them said, - D - you have is a Search Warrant! Why don't you give me the Key? Upon that, the Prisoner Hale put her Hand into her Pocket, and he made Use of a great many vile Expressions, and took the Key from her, and said, he would shew us what we came to search for. He open'd a Closet, and took out a Sword and two Doggers, or other dangerous Weapons, and after they had each taken one, he cried, - Now clear the House, or else D - n you, I will pin you up, or cut you down directly! Upon that, we having nothing to defend ourselves, the Constable went out first, and we being in Danger, were very ready to follow: - My Wife was the last in the House. The Prisoner took the shortest Weapon of the three; - they were all ready drawn in the Closet, and he held it up as if he was making an Offer to push at us. We told them, we had a search Warrant when we went into the House; - that was the first Thing we mentioned: the Woman ( Hale) was there at the same Time. After they had turned<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240023"></xptr> us out of the House, they all made their Escape backwards, and in a turning by Grace's-Alley, I saw the three Men together. I caught hold of the Prisoner Peterson, and a Knife was taken from him, which is here to be produced, which is not a proper Thing for People to carry about them. This is the Knife, and I found it open in the Prisoner's Pocket. - It appeared to be a French Knife about a Foot long</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person413">
                  Wm 
                  Wiman 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person413" type="surname" value="Wiman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person413" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             We went with a Warrant to search the House, and a tall, thin Man, almost 6 foot high, asked me what I wanted: - It was the Prisoner Hale's House, she owned it was hers before the Justice I told them I had a Search Warrant, and they would not give us Time to shew it them, for the tall Man Cavanah, called the Woman B - n, for some such Thing, and ask'd her for the Key, and said, he would shew us something; after which, he pulled out a Sword, and swore he would stick me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Peterson any Weapon delivered to him?</p>
               <p>Wiman. I can't tell what Weapon he had, for when the other Man pushed at me, I turned my Head. The Prisoner Hale was there all the Time, for she gave them the Key to get the Arms.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-57-person414">
                  Ann 
                  Abel 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person414" type="surname" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person414" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person414" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Wife to 
               <persName id="t17420224-57-person415">
                  Nicholas 
                  Abel 
               <interp inst="t17420224-57-person415" type="surname" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person415" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and went with him and the others to Hale's House in Saltpetre Bank. The Constable was going to knock at the Door, but a Woman came out, and we got in without any Resistance. There were three Men sitting in the Kitchen, - Peterson was one, the Captain of New-Prison's Son another, and a Man in a grey Coat was the other. Cavannah, the tallest of the three, asked us what we wanted? Rogers and the Headborough told him, they had a Search Warrant. Upon that, he ran up Stairs, and left Peterson and the other in the Room. We heard a rustling above Stairs for 2 or 3 Minutes, and then Cavanah came down and damn'd the Prisoner Hale, and bid her give him the Key; upon which he said, - D - n them, I will shew them what they search for. He then opened the Closet, and took out three drawn Weapons, one of them was longer than the others, and that he kept for himself, and gave the others to the Prisoner Peterson and the other Man. He told us, if we did not quit the House that Moment, he would stick us against the Wall. The first Man that turn'd his Back was the Constable, and the others were very ready to follow him. I let my Husband go out first, because I thought they would not hurt me, and Cavannah swore if I did not go out, it should be the worse for me. When Peterson was apprehended, I saw my Husband take this Knife out of his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Peterson. This Woman (Hale) used to wash Shirts for me, and I went to her House to get one. I had ben at Sea, and thought these People were coming to press me, therefore I took this Knife to drive them out of Doors.</p>
               <p>Hale. I desired these People to search every Corner of the House a great many Times.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17420224-57-verdict245" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-57-verdict245" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
