<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480706-37">
               <interp inst="t17480706-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-37" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-37" type="date" value="17480706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480706-37-off169-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-37-defend286 t17480706-37-off169 t17480706-37-verdict173"></join>
         
               <p>358. + 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-defend286" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-defend286" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-defend286" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise <rs id="t17480706-37-alias-8" type="alias">Cullingham</rs>, late of <placeName id="t17480706-37-defloc168">Wingfield, in the county of Suffolk</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-37-defloc168" type="placeName" value="Wingfield, in the county of Suffolk"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-37-defloc168" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-37-defend286 t17480706-37-defloc168"></join>, was indicted upon a suggestion, that he, the said 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person287">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person287" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person287" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , after the 24th day of July, 1746, to wit, on the 19th day of August, 1747, at the parish of St. Paul, Covent-Garden, in the county of Middlesex, was in due manner charged, before 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person288">
                  Thomas 
                  Burdus 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person288" type="surname" value="Burdus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person288" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; one of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace for the said county, by 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person289">
                  Robert 
                  Chinnery 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person289" type="surname" value="Chinnery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person289" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a creditable person, upon oath, that <rs id="t17480706-37-off169" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-off169" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-off169" type="offenceSubcategory" value="taxOffences"></interp>
               he, the said 
                     <persName id="t17480706-37-person290">
                        Robert 
                        Cunningham 
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person290" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-37-person290" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-37-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , with divers other persons, to the number of three or more, after the said 24th day of July, 1746, to wit, on the <rs id="t17480706-37-cd170" type="crimeDate">5th day of September, 1746</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-37-off169 t17480706-37-cd170"></join>, were assembled at <placeName id="t17480706-37-crimeloc171">Tiberton, otherwise Tiverton, in the county of Suffolk</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-crimeloc171" type="placeName" value="Tiberton, otherwise Tiverton, in the county of Suffolk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-crimeloc171" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-37-off169 t17480706-37-crimeloc171"></join>, armed with fire arms, and other offensive weapons, in order to be aiding and assisting in running, landing, and carrying away uncustomed goods, &amp;c
            </rs>. And that he, the said 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person291">
                  Thomas 
                  Burdus 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person291" type="surname" value="Burdus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person291" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; did forthwith, to wit, on the said 19th day of August, 1747, certify, under his hand and seal, and did return the said information to the most noble 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person292">
                  Thomas 
                  Holles 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person292" type="surname" value="Holles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person292" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Duke of Newcastle, one of his Majesty's principal secretaries of slate, who did, as soon as conveniently could be, to wit, on the 8th day of September, 1747, lay the same before his Majesty, in his Privy-Council; and that his Majesty did, on the said 8th day of September, make an order in council, requiring, and commanding the said 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person293">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person293" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person293" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Cullingham, to surrender himself, within forty days after the first publication of the said order in the London Gazette, to the Lord Chief Justice, or to one other of the Justices of the Court of King's Bench, or to any of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace; and that this order was published in the two next succeeding London Gazettes. And that, on the said 8th day of September, this order was transmitted to the sheriff of the county of Suffolk; and that the said sheriff did, within fourteen days after the receipt thereof, cause the same to be publickly proclaimed on the two next marketdays, between the hours of ten in the morning and two in the afternoon, in the publick marketplaces of Dunwich and Saxmundham, being two market towns near to the place where the offence was committed; and that the said order was fixed up in the publick market-places of the said towns of Dunwich and Saxmundham; and that the said 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person294">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person294" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person294" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Cullingham, did not surrender himself according to the said order, and therefore the said 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person295">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person295" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person295" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is, and stands convicted, and attainted of felony; and this the attorney-general, for our said Lord the King, is willing to aver and testify, and therefore prays the Court to award execution against the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Clerk of the Ar. Gentlemen of the Jury, the several issues contained in this suggestion the Prisoner has denied, and thereupon issue is joined, and you are to try these issues between our sovereign Lord the King, and the Prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. May it please your Lordship, and Gentlemen of the Jury, the Prisoner comes before the Court in the manner I am going to mention to you.</p>
               <p>The Legislature considering the great progress the smugglers had made, the height they were got to, and the violences they had committed, thought it necessary to suppress this practice; and in order to do that, there was an Act of Parliament<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060023"></xptr> made, to make it felony, without benefit of clergy, for three or more persons to be assembled together with fire arms, in order to be aiding and assisting, in running, landing, and carrying away uncustomed goods; for it was difficult to bring them to justice in the common way, by reason of the outrages they committed, and the damages they did in the country, and therefore the Legislature made an Act, that if they did surrender themselves, according to due course of law, they should have mercy, but if they put their country at defiance, and did not surrender themselves according to that Act of Parliament, they are guilty of felony; and in order to this, there are several steps, which are by that Act directed to be taken.</p>
               <p>And gentlemen, the first step is to have the fact laid before a proper Magistrate upon oath, then that is to be laid before a secretary of state; then laid before his Majesty in council; an order made by his Majesty in council, and that order to be transmitted to the sheriff of the county where the offence was committed, and is to be proclaimed on the two next market-days, at two market towns near to the place where the fact was committed, and stuck up in the publick market-places of those towns, that the Prisoner might know what his offence was; then, by that Act of Parliament, he was to surrender himself, according to the directions of the Act; but if he did not surrender himself, he was to be convicted, as if he had been convicted of felony, in point of law; and this was done, upon account of that practice, which the Government thought so prejudicial to the publick.</p>
               <p>My Lord, the Prisoner at the bar has been charged according to the directions of that Act of Parliament; he has been charged with being armed with fire arms, and assembled together, with three or more, to be aiding and assisting in running and landing uncustomed goods; and this has been laid before a proper Magistrate; and has been laid before the Duke of Newcastle, one of his Majesty's principal secretaries of state; has been laid before his Majesty in council, and an order made, and every thing has been done according to the Act of Parliament; therefore he is now, if these facts are proved, guilty of felony, and if he cannot disprove these things, he is attainted and convicted of felony; therefore it is incumbent upon us to prove these facts, and as you are a Jury according to the laws of the land, you are to try whether these facts are true, and if you find these facts, the Prisoner will have execution awarded against him, as a person attainted of felony.</p>
               <p>Second Coun. for the Crown. My Lord, and gentlemen of the Jury, I will state to you what facts are to be proved, in order to have execution awarded against the Prisoner; and these facts are contained if the suggestion, which has been opened to you, by the gentleman who spoke before me.</p>
               <p>First, That he was, on the 19th of August, 1747, charged before 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person296">
                  Thomas 
                  Burdus 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person296" type="surname" value="Burdus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person296" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; one of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace, by a creditable person on oath, that he, with three or more, with fire arms, were, on the 5th of September, in the 20th year of his Majesty's reign, at Tiberton, in the county of Suffolk, concerned in running and landing uncustomed goods; this, which is the first fact, we shall prove to you by an information given before Mr. Burdus, on oath; and that Mr. Burdus did, on the nineteenth of August, 1747, certify, under his hand and seal, and returned the information to his Grace the Duke of Newcastle, one of his Majesty's principal secretaries of State; and that he did, on the 8th of September following, lay this before his Majesty in council; and upon this his Majesty made an order in council; for them to surrender themselves within forty days after the first publication of that order in the London Gazette; either to the Lord Chief Justice of the Court of King's Bench, or to one other of the Justices of the Court of King's Bench, or to one of his Majesty's Justices of the Peace.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, the next thing to be proved, is, that this order was published in the two next succeeding London Gazettes, and we shall prove to you, that this order was published in these two London Gazettes: Then we shall prove, that, on the 8th of September, this order was transferred to the sheriff of the county of Suffolk; and that he caused this to be proclaimed at Dunwich and Saxmundham, being two market towns near to the place where the fact was committed; and we shall prove, that these two market towns are near to the place, and that this order was placed up in the market-places of those towns; and then he is to prove, that he did surrender himself; but if he did not surrender himself, gentlemen, you will find the issues for the King.</p>
               <p>[Mr. 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person297">
                  Charles 
                  Chaworth 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person297" type="surname" value="Chaworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person297" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced the information of 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person298">
                  Robert 
                  Chinnery 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person298" type="surname" value="Chinnery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person298" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .]</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did he swear to this?</p>
               <p>Chaworth. Yes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060024"></xptr>Pris. Coun. Do you know this Chinnery?</p>

               <p>Chaworth. I should know him, if I was to see him again.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you think you have seen him?</p>
               <p>Chaworth. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Tell me whether you have, or have not?</p>
               <p>Chaworth. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. This will not bear a verdict in a civil action.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Did he inform by the name of 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person299">
                  Robert 
                  Chinnery 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person299" type="surname" value="Chinnery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person299" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Chaworth. Yes.</p>
               <p>The information of 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person300">
                  Robert 
                  Chinnery 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person300" type="surname" value="Chinnery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person300" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was read.</p>
               <p>'' 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person301">
                  Robert 
                  Chinnery 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person301" type="surname" value="Chinnery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person301" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             against 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person302">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person302" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person302" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             '' of Wingfield, in the county of Suffolk, <rs id="t17480706-37-deflabel172" type="occupation">labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-37-defend286 t17480706-37-deflabel172"></join>.</p>
               <p>'' This informant faith, that 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person303">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person303" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person303" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , '' Morley, Brook, and others, were assembled '' together, at Feberton, otherwise Feverton, '' armed with fire arms, on the 5th of September, '' 1746, and had landed twenty hundred '' weight of tea, and eight half anchors of brandy.</p>
               <p>'' Signed</p>
               <p>'' 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person304">
                  ROBERT 
                  CHINNERY 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person304" type="surname" value="CHINNERY"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person304" type="given" value="ROBERT"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Do you know any thing of Mr. Burdus's certifying this to the Duke of Newcastle?</p>
               <p>Choworth. Yes; I delivered it to Mr. Ward, the office-keeper at the Duke of Newcastle's office.</p>
               <p>[The certificate, under the hand and seal of Justice Burdus was read.]</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person305">
                  William 
                  Sharpe 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person305" type="surname" value="Sharpe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person305" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Do you know any thing of that information being laid before his Majesty in council?</p>

               <p>Sharpe. This information was laid before his Majesty in council, the 8th of September, 1747.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. And what was done upon that?</p>
               <p>Sharpe. I had orders to issue an order, for 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person306">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person306" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person306" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and several more, to surrender themselves, within forty days after the first publication of the said order in the London Gazette, and I sent it that very night to the sheriff of Suffolk, to have it proclaimed, and put up in two market towns, near the place where the fact was committed.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. And I suppose to the printer of the London Gazette?</p>
               <p>Sharpe. Yes; I sent it to Mr. Owen, the printer of the London Gazette.</p>
               <p>[The order of council was read.]</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person307">
                  Edward 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person307" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person307" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Do you publish the London Gazette?</p>
               <p>Owen. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you publish this order in the London Gazette?</p>
               <p>Owen. Yes; I published it in the two succeeding London Gazettes.</p>
               <p>Q. What days?</p>
               <p>Owen. On the 8th and 12th of September.</p>
               <p>[The order, printed in the Gazettes of the 8th and 12th of September, was read ]</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person308">
                  Charles 
                  Tisted 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person308" type="surname" value="Tisted"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person308" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Under-sheriff of the county of Suffolk ). On the 9th of September last this order came to me, directed to Mr. Robert Edger, high-sheriff of the county of Suffolk, and my clerk made two copies of it, and directed them to 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person309">
                  Henry 
                  Curtis 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person309" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person309" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a bailiff at Saxmundham.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. So you only give orders by hearsay; how did you come by them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharpe. I sent them by the post, and I have a letter, signed 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person310">
                  Charles 
                  Tisted 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person310" type="surname" value="Tisted"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person310" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , acknowledging the receipt of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-37-person311">
                  Henry 
                  Curtis 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person311" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person311" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Did you receive from Mr Tisted two copies of the order for Cunningham to surrender himself?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Did you proclaim them?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. In what towns?</p>
               <p>Curtis. The first was at Saxmundham.</p>
               <p>Q. At what hour?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Between the hours of ten and two, I believe it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What day?</p>
               <p>Curtis. On Thursday the seventeenth of September.</p>
               <p>Q. When you had proclaimed them, where did you place them?</p>
               <p>Curtis. At our whipping-post, as we call it; it is our pillory.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you proclaim them next?</p>
               <p>Curtis. At Dunwich.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Dunwich a market town?</p>
               <p>Curtis. There is no market kept there, the sea has got it almost all.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Curtis. On the nineteenth of September, between the hours of ten and two.</p>
               <p>Q. Are they both market towns?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes, they are, and the two nearest market towns.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060025"></xptr>Pris. Coun. Can you, of your own knowledge, say, that Dunwich is a market town?</p>
               <p>Curtis. I cannot, of my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you know whether it is a market town, or a market-place?</p>
               <p>Curtis. The Justice of Peace told me it is a market town; it has been a corporation and a city.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. So has Old Sarum.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Mr. Tisted, do you know Dunwich to be a market town?</p>
               <p>Tisted. I do not know it, of my own knowledge, for I never was there.</p>
               <p>Q. to Curtis. Do you know Dunwich to be a market town?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Only as I am told; the Justice told me it was a market town, and that the market was kept on a Saturday. There were several people there when I read the order.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Mr. Curtis, you are very well acquainted, I suppose, with this country?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Yes, pretty well. I live thereabout, and have about thirty years.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is the nearest town to Benacre?</p>
               <p>Curtis. Dunwich.</p>
               <p>Q. How near is Beccles to Benacre?</p>
               <p>Curtis. About fifteen miles.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. It does not appear, that this is the 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person312">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person312" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person312" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that is meant in the indictment; for there is another 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person313">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person313" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person313" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that is the Prisoner's father; and we do not know whether it is the father or the son that is meant in the indictment; besides, here is another 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person314">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person314" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person314" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Court.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. You are to prove, that the Prisoner is not that 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person315">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person315" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person315" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , mentioned in the order of council.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. I can prove, that there is another 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person316">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person316" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person316" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of that town, with the same addition to his name as the Prisoner, and I think the Council for the King are to prove, that he is the 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person317">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person317" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person317" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , mentioned in the order of council. I beg leave to call my witness.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Not in such a case as this. Mr. Tisted, how far is Dunwich from Feberton?</p>
               <p>Tisted. Three miles.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Saxmundham from Feberton?</p>
               <p>Tisted. Five miles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-37-person318">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person318" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person318" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. I live in the next parish to Wingfield.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived there?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. About twenty-three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Yes; he kept a little farm.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. A very honest fellow.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know another 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person319">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person319" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person319" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Of what place?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Of Wingfield.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. A labourer.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he living?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. Is the Prisoner a runner of goods?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. I never heard he was, in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the other 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person320">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person320" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person320" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a smuggler?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. I don't know that he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What place do you live at?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. At Stradford.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade are you?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. I do not come as an evidence, gentlemen, but if you have any thing to say, I have persons to my character. I came to Smithfield market.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Dunwich?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. No, I never was there.</p>
               <p>Q. You say there is another 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person321">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person321" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person321" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Wingfield; when did you see him?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Last Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he living then?</p>
               <p>Cunningham. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. You have not brought the other 
               <persName id="t17480706-37-person322">
                  Robert 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17480706-37-person322" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person322" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             here?</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. No, we have not.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. It would have been very proper for you to have done it.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. The Prisoner is so poor, he could not be at the charge of bringing him up.</p>
               <p>Clerk of the Arraigns. Gentlemen of the Jury, do you find the issues for the King, or for the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Jury. <rs id="t17480706-37-verdict173" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-37-verdict173" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               For the Prisoner
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Crown. I desire, as the Jury have acquitted the Prisoner, to inform the Court, that I have another Indictment against him, and desire he may be detained; and he was accordingly ordered to remain in custody.</p>
            </div1>
