<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420714-27">
               <interp inst="t17420714-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-27" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-27" type="date" value="17420714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-27-off130-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-defend240 t17420714-27-off130 t17420714-27-verdict133"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-27-off130-c189" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-defend242 t17420714-27-off130 t17420714-27-verdict133"></join>
         
               <p>30, 31. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend240" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend240" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend242" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend242" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for that they, <rs id="t17420714-27-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               not having God before their Eyes, &amp;c. on the 15th of April, feloniously, wilfully, and maliciously, one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420714-27-victim244" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Cooke 
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-victim244" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-victim244" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-victim244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-off130 t17420714-27-victim244"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did kill and murder. The Indictment farther sets forth, that the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person245">
                        Stephen 
                        Price 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person245" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person245" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , with both his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140014"></xptr> Hands, and with Malice aforethought, in a certain open Place near the King's Highway, cross a wooden Rail, the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person246">
                        Thomas 
                        Cooke 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person246" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person246" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did cast and throw, and upon the Head, Face, Breast, and Body of the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person247">
                        Thomas 
                        Cooke 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person247" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , several mortal Bruises did give, of which Bruises the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person248">
                        Thomas 
                        Cooke 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person248" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person248" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   languished from the <rs id="t17420714-27-cd131" type="crimeDate">15th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-off130 t17420714-27-cd131"></join> to the seventh of June, and then died. And that the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person249">
                        John 
                        Clark 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person249" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   was aiding, abetting, and assisting the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person250">
                        Stephen 
                        Price 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person250" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person250" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . the said Murder to commit, and that the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person251">
                        Stephen 
                        Price 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person251" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person251" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person252">
                        John 
                        Clark 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person252" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-27-person253">
                        Thomas 
                        Cooke 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person253" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person253" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-27-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , feloniously, wilfully, and maliciously did kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They were likewise indicted on the Coroner's Inquest, for feloniously staying the said 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person254">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person254" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person254" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>After the Counsel had opened the Nature of the Cause, the Witnesses for the Prosecutor were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person255">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Root 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person255" type="surname" value="Root"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person255" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Cooke the deceased, and I, were at work together, in <placeName id="t17420714-27-crimeloc132">Mourning-Lane , in Hackney Parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-27-crimeloc132" type="placeName" value="Mourning-Lane , in Hackney Parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-27-crimeloc132" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-off130 t17420714-27-crimeloc132"></join>: This Mr Clark, and this Mr Price, came riding along the Road by us full speed, and they had like to have rode over Cooke; he told them they ought to be knocked off their Horses for riding so fast. Clark comes up to Cooke first, and dismounted, upon that Cooke held his Spade against Mr Clark, over his own Head, and Clark had the Butt End of his Whip over Cooke's Head.</p>
               <p>- Cooke held his Spade up in his own Defence.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was up first, the Whip or the Space?</p>

               <p>Root. I cannot say whether the Spade was held up before Clark had his Whip up. - I cannot say which was up first. Upon that this Mr Price came up, and I catched him by the Arm, and bid him go about his Business, - he made no Answer whether he would or no, but after a few Words more, they both went away. -</p>
               <p>2. What Time of the Day was it? -</p>

               <p>Root. It was between two or three o'Clock in the Afternoon, I did not see them afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not you working in a Ditch?</p>
               <p>Root. No. It is level Ground, there is no Ditch at all, we were making up the Bank. Cooke was a little frightned, and if they had not turned back again, there would have been no Harm done: He did not call after them, he spoke as they were riding by. - I think, as near as I can say, the Horses were just over-against him. - There was never a Blow struck on either Side, as I saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person256">
                  Daniel 
                  Ferguson 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person256" type="surname" value="Ferguson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person256" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This was by Mr Rudge's Brew-House in Hackney-Parish. On the 15th of April, I was coming along Mourning-Lane, I had a Load of Soot upon my Back. The Prisoners came riding along very hard, - they rode a full Gallop; my Fellow-Apprentice was before me, and bid me get out of the Way; and if I had not I should have been rode over. So I threw myself against the Bank. Mr Clark's Horse came pretty near the Bank, then Cooke said, you ought to be knocked off your Horses for riding so hard: Whereupon Clark, he, the tall one, lifted up his Whip against Cooke. I was about thirty Yards off, and saw Cooke lift, up his Spade, so, which was up first, the Whip or the Spade, I cannot say: I saw no Blows pass, nor any thing after this, for I was in the Shed, shooting my Soot out of my Sack.</p>
               <p>Root called again. What Day of the Month was this?</p>
               <p>Root. It was the 15th Day of April.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person257">
                  John 
                  Flatman 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person257" type="surname" value="Flatman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoners at the Bar in Mourning-Lane, the 15th of April last. I was going Home after my Boys, this and another; these two Gentlemen were riding at a great Rate, and passed by me: I could not see quite up the Lane, for there is a winding in the Lane, and then they were out of my Sight till I came up to the turn of the Lane, then I saw Mr Clarke and Mr Cooke have hold of each other by the Collar, - it was between two and three o'Clock in the Afternoon, Clark dismounted, and held up his Whip with the butt End upwards against Cooke. - I do not know whether he held the Whip up against Cooke with a Design to strike him. - I stepped up, and said, do not be afraid of the Man that has got hold of you, for the other shall not meddle with you. Mr Price came and laid hold of me by the Collar, I asked him what he laid hold of me for: he said, because you should not hurt my Friend, I said I am not going to hurt you, nor your Friend neither; let me go or I will give you a knock on the Face, then they soon mounted their Horses and away they went.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them afterwards on that Day?</p>
               <p>Flatman. Yes. I saw them about four Hours afterwards in Mourning-Lane. I live just by the Place where this happened. People had done Work. They passed by, came back and rode into my Yard, I was smoaking a Pipe over the Pales; they asked me for a Pot of Beer, I answered them I sold none; is there no Publick House near, says they, let us drink together; thinks I, if I do not go, they will think I am afraid of them, and so I went with them to the Plough Alehouse at Hammerton ; when I came to the Alehouse, Mr Clark, I think it was, called for a Pot of Beer, and there was a full Pot of Beer brought, then, while<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140015"></xptr> the Beer was fetching, Mr Price would have quarrelled with me, I told him I did not care for fighting. Mr Clark brought the Beer to me, and I drank out of the Pot. Mr Clark asked me which was the House Cooke lived at; one Man pointed at the House, and said, that is the House. Mr Clark said he would go and see for him, and he did go, I did not go with Mr Clark. - Cooke lives about sixty Yards from the Plough; he was not at Home, and Clarke said, if he had been within, and would not have come along with him, he would have whipped him before him. - A little after, - as soon as the Words were well out of his Mouth, he saw Cooke coming towards his own House. Says one, there is Cooke coming along. Clark hailed him, and Cooke made a short stand, then he beckoned him, and Cooke came up to the Plough Door. Says Clark, Now if you are a Man fight me. Cooke said, I will not fight, I am not obliged to fight every Fellow, or Words to that Effect, and he would not fight: Then both the Prisoners said, if he would not fight they would Horse-whip him. Said Cooke, you may use your Pleasure, but you had better let it alone than horse-whip me. Then Mr Price went and talked to him, what the Words were, I cannot tell, but they were spoke in an angry Way. Mr Price laid hold of his Arm in order to get him into the House to fight. Cooke had pitched his Load, and sat down at the Door with a Pipe in his Mouth. Price took the butt End of his Whip, and broke the Pipe in Cooke's Mouth, and the Piece which Cooke had in his Hand, which was the Bowl End, he took and irted at Price, but I do not know whether it hit him. Price then fell upon Cooke, and flung him over or cross the Rail, with the blows that he gave him, and fell upon him and beat him; there were several Blows about the Face, for his Face was as bloody as a Slaughter-House. - You could not see his Face for Blood. - Clark was by, but Clark did not meddle with him. -</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Clark lay hold of the deceased?</p>
               <p>Flatman. I did not. Then Cooke went away and went Home. - I saw Cooke come by my Door three or four Times afterwards. - I saw him two or three Days after this Quarrel, and he was in a miserable black Condition. -</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any Complaints?</p>
               <p>Flatman. He said he had got some inward and never should be his own Man again, and he said he believed the Man that beat him was the occasion of it - I believe he did not know his Name then. - I never spoke to him after that Time, but every Time I saw him, I thought he grew worse and worse. He could walk as upright as any Man before, but could not do so afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear that he complained of his Lungs.</p>
               <p>Flatman. No. He was pretty healthy, but he had not a ruddy Complexion.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw this, why did not you take him off.</p>
               <p>Flatman. I have had too much of that already, but if I had done it, this Person, Mr Clark, would have fell upon me, and then we should have been all in a bad Condition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this Transaction appear to you as any thing more than a common Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Flatman. It did not appear as a common Quarrel to me, for Men to come three or four Hours afterwards, and kill another Man, I do not think that can be called a common Quarrel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person258">
                  Joseph 
                  Rollo 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person258" type="surname" value="Rollo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person258" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Cooke very well, I saw him the Thursday before Easter, I cannot remember the Day of the Month, (on looking into an Almanack, it appeared to be the 15th of April). I saw Mr Clarke at the Plough at Hammerton, either on Horse-back or Mare-back, I cannot tell which, I saw him go from the Plough to Cooke's House, with his Whip in his Hand, and I saw him return again, and heard him say, he was not at Home; and I believe in a Minute, or two Minutes afterwards, as Cooke was coming by the Marsh-Gate, in his Way Home, I saw Mr Clark beckon with his Hand to call him to come up, and then Mr Clark offered him five Shillings to box him, then there were Words arose between all three of them, then I saw Mr Price take the butt End of his Whip, and as Cooke was rising, upon the half Bend, knocked the Pipe out of Cooke's Mouth, then he laid hold of him, overpowered him, and threw him upon the top of the Rail, - then he lay upon him, and beat him over the Face with his Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it with his Hand or Fist, for there is some Difference between them.</p>
               <p>Rollo. With his Fist to be sure, for Men do not go to fight like Women with their Hands open. - Clark did not do any thing. - Cooke was afterwards in a drooping, wasting Condition. I do not know that he did any Work after this; it was a dismal Aspect to see him afterwards, for he grew worse and worse Day after Day, and Time after Time. - He was very well before, I do not know that in two Years that I have known him, he has had a Day's Illness.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140016"></xptr>Q. Do you know the Occasion of his Illness afterwards?</p>
               <p>Rollo. No; I cannot tell the Occasion of a Man's Disorder, for I am not a Surgeon. I have often asked him how he did? he said, he was worse and worse, and that he was sadly used.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to part them, when you saw him so abused?</p>
               <p>Rollo. It cost me once, at Hick's-Hall 10 l. for parting a Man and his Wife, and I did not care to part two Men.</p>
               <p>- Green. I knew 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person259">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person259" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person259" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw him and the Prisoners at the Bar, the Thursday before Easter, at the Plough Door, they were enquiring (I can't tell which of them it was) where Cook lived, Mr Clark went and enquired if he was at home, and they said he was not; then Clark said, if he had been at home, and would not have come, he would have whipp'd him all the way up to the House. In a very little while afterwards, Cooke was going homeward, and Clark called to him, and he came; and I believe Clark said, was you not a Rogue to serve me as you did, to threaten to knock me me off my Horse, and then to go to strike me with your Shovel? said Cooke, My Partner said, if he had been in my Place he would have knock'd you off the Horse. I believe Cooke sat down, and Price insisted on his going into a Room to fight him; I believe he took him by the Collar, and said, he would either swear the Peace against him, or he should fight him; Cooke said, he might do as he pleased, for he would not fight: The little Gentleman, Price, up with his Whip, and made an offer to hit 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person260" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but he did not. Then, presently, he broke Cooke's Pipe, which was in his Mouth, with his Whip, Cooke tossed the other Piece at him; with that Price fell a beating him. - He was very much beat, and very bloody. The next Morning he looked very bad, and said, he was sadly hurt; but he could not tell who it was that beat him. - I saw him about three Weeks before he died; then he was very bad. - He was very well before that beating.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person261">
                  Samuel 
                  Pamplin 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person261" type="surname" value="Pamplin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person261" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw some Persons at the Plough Door, - it was the 15th of April; I heard Mr Price, say to Cooke, Will you fight me? says he, Gentlemen, I do not want to fight with you, if I should be hurt, how shall I maintain my Family? Sirrah, says he, I will give you a Crown, or half a Crown, or a Crown Bowl of Punch to fight me; but he would not: With that, this Mr Price walked up and down, and now and then took the Man by the Collar, and shook him, as he was smoaking; that he came up to him and said, you old Rogue will you fight, and then with a sort of a slanting Stroke, he hit the Pipe out of his Mouth, with his Whip; and Cooke tossed the Bit of the Pipe that was left in his Hand at him, with that Price closed in upon him, and after a short Scuffle, threw him down cross the Plate of the Sign-post, and there he held him, that the Man could not turn his Body one way or another; he gave him several Blows about his Breast and Arms, and held him by the Handkerchief, which he had about his Neck. - I saw a little Blood come out of his Mouth, but that might be caused by the Pipe; then they mounted their Horses and went away, Cooke walked away as well as he could; but he walk'd but sadly. He went to get an Officer to take them up. When I saw him afterwards, he always looked sadly. He said, he was very bad, and should never be his right Man again. - Before that he appear'd to be in good Health. - He was always a Pale looking Man. - I believe he never did a Day's Work afterwards. - I said, it is a sad Thing that so many People should be standing by, and not take him off, but let the Man be murdered. Sirrah, says Clark, if you do any thing, I will give you as much; let them have it out. The Man at the Plough, I think, parted them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person262">
                  Jane 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person262" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person262" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Plough Door, Mr Clark and Mr Price came up, and called for a Tankard of Beer, Cooke came up, with his Pipe in his Mouth, and Clark jangled with him, and called him Rogue, and asked him to fight. This little Man struck Cooke, and slung him cross the Sign Post; he dropp'd his Whip, and took hold of his Handkerchief so, and beat him till the Blood came wretchedly; he laid with his Back cross the Sign Post. I came and laid hold of Price by the Waist-band of his Breeches, to pull him off, and Clark got up his Whip, and said, You old Bitch, I'll knock your Brains out, if you do not begone. I said, that is more than you dare do. - My Master at the Plough came out and unclosed them; Cooke said after this, he believed he had given him his Death, and should never be his own Man again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person263">
                  Mary 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person263" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person263" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 15th of April I was looking out of Window, and Mr Clark stopped to water his Horse, Mr Price rode on a little faster; then Price turned back again, and said to Mr Clark come along Johnny, for I have done his Business, or I have done it for him. Clark said, do not ride so fast, for I am not afraid of him. He was very much bruised. He appeared to be in a good State of Health before, but declined ever afterwards. I have known him 11 Years all but one Month.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person264">
                  Sarah 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person264" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person264" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Widow of the Deceased. What I have to say, is with to respect Clark, I never saw Price till Yesterday. The 15th of April Clark comes and asks, if this was Cooke's House? Yes, Sir, said I, what would you please to have with him? he said, I want to speak with him, tell him my Name is Clark, and send him to the Plough, to drink a Pot of Beer with me; about two or three Minutes, after Clark was at my House, my Husband was coming along, all in his Blood; when he came home, he was in a very bad Condition; he said, the worst of all was his Back; he said, he has hurt my Back so, I am afraid I shall never recover it; my Face may be well again, I do not mind that; he grew worse ever after, and by way of Complaint, has often said, This Man has been the Death of me. He said, the little Man has done my Business; Clark never hit him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person265">
                  John 
                  Dunckley 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person265" type="surname" value="Dunckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He was in a good State of Health before this. He has often told me, he believed he should never get over it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person266">
                  Samuel 
                  Summer 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person266" type="surname" value="Summer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person266" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd good part of the preceding Evidence. On the 15th of April I saw there was a little Man just rode by, and I think I met that tall Gentleman on Horseback; he said, you old Rogue, you have it now, remember the Spade in the Lane. I saw Cooke the next Day, and his Face was almost as black as my Hat. I think, before this, he was in a good State of Health. About three Weeks after this Accident, I saw him drooping very much; I asked him, where his Complaint was? he said, in my Stomach, and the Small of my Back: Said I, do you think it came by the Quarrel? Yes, said he, I believe it did, and nothing else.</p>
               <p>Mr Norris sworn. This Deposition was taken by me. I knew the Deceas'd very well, it was read before him in my Presence, and I signed it; I gave him a great Caution to take care of what he said, that he was going to appear before God Almighty, and he must be exceeding careful of what he said in his Deposition; he said, he would say nothing but what was true, he died in eight or nine Days.</p>
               <p>[The Deposition read to the following Effect.]</p>
               <p>Dated the 30th of May, signed 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person267">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person267" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person267" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his Mark.</p>
               <p>Midd 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person268">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooke 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person268" type="surname" value="Cooke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person268" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the Parish of St. John Hackney, in the County of Middlesex, Labourer, maketh Oath, That on the 15th of April, as he was working with one Root, in Mourning-lane, two Persons, (one he was was informed, keeps a Livery-Stable, near the City of London) rode by very hard, he spoke to them, and one of them said, he would lick him, upon which he held up his Spade to keep him off, but did not touch him with it. In two or three Hours they returned again, and hearing that two Persons wanted to speak with him, at the House of 
               <persName id="t17420714-27-person269">
                  Richard 
                  Herbert 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person269" type="surname" value="Herbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person269" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he went there, and that Clark said, Damn you, you old Rogue, you shall fight me. The other Person, who to the Deponent is unknown, broke his Pipe and beat and bruised him in a very dangerous Manner; that he is now in a low and weak Condition, and verily believes, that this beating and bruising was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Mr Fisher, Apothecary. Cooke came to my Shop, I do not remember the Time, it was in April, or May. I saw him pretty near his Death, he opened his Waistcoat, and I could not see any Marks of Violence upon his Breast or Back. I saw him about 10 Days before he died, he spit soetid, corrupted Matter, and was in an emaciated Condition; - I choose to leave it to the Surgeons to account for his Disorder.</p>
               <p>Mr Girle, Surgeon. Upon opening the Body there was an Adhesion of the Lungs on the Right-side, and there was corrupted Matter on the Lungs. I cannot tell what was the Occasion of his Death. - A Man may live a great while under such Habit of Body; but such an Accident may hasten his Death. They have Pains, and Coughs in the Beginning of all Adhesions. A violent Blow may affect the Lungs. I cannot say how long this Adhesion may be coming in a natural way, it may come suddenly upon a violent Inflammation; and supposing this Adhesion to be an old Disorder, this Usage might hasten his Death.</p>
               <p>Mr Nourse, Surgeon. I was desired to be at the opening of the Body, I saw no Marks of Violence on the Outside, in the Inside I found a Quantity of Matter in the Thorax, and the Lungs had contracted a Quantity of Matter, and there was a general Adhesion of the Lungs, which in diseased Bodies are very common. This Adhesion was, I believe, before this Scuffle, for if this Inflammation had been so great, as to occasion this Adhesion, his Complaint would have been much worse when the Inflammation was so violent, than afterwards; and his Complaint was not so great at first as afterwards; I believe that this Violence might hasten his Death. On the Right-side there was a Quantity of Matter, of a reddish Hue, I took more particular Notice of the Colour of the Matter, because I designed to make an Experiment. When I asked the Apothecary, whether he thought he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140018"></xptr> had ever spit Blood? he said, He believed he had. I asked him, Whether he was so curious, as to examine into the Matter, he called Blood? he said, He had not made Enquiry enough to satisfy himself. I do not think he spit any Blood at all; this Matter which is of a reddish Hue, is so much like Blood, that a Person may be deceived, and take it for Blood. I made an Inspection into all the other Bowels, and found them as they usually are, except the Liver, which had some Appearance of a Decay; which must have been coming some Time before. - Such a Blow as would have occasioned an Inflammation, must have been visible at first.</p>
               <p>Mr Polock, Surgeon. I examined this Body, I saw him about three or four Days before his Death, he complained of a Purging, there was no Appearance of any Violence, but there was an Inflammation in his Bowels.</p>

               <p>Q. Is that a Distemper that People have naturally without any external Blow?</p>
               <p>Polock. Yes, undoubtedly. If it was occasioned by a Blow, it must make a visible Appearance. - I was sent thither by Mr Clark; he said he did not know that he was hit in any other Place but the Face. He complained of being thrown over a Rail. He said he was not struck on the Breast, but only complained of a Soreness in his Back. - He did not say to me, that it was the Occasion of his Death, or that he should not be his own Man again.</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard how this Man was used. Might not this occasion his Death?</p>
               <p>Polock. I cannot say that it would.</p>
               <p>Q. But might not this hasten his Death?</p>
               <p>Polock. I cannot say but it might.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person270">
                  Joseph 
                  Sumpter 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person270" type="surname" value="Sumpter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person270" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Cooke riding in the Marsh in May, when they were going to gather Stones for Mr Rudge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person271">
                  Richard 
                  Herbert 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person271" type="surname" value="Herbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person271" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Master of the Plough Alehouse. I saw Mr Clark and this Gentleman come into the Town, and ask where they could get a Pot of Beer, they called for a Pot of Beer, and my Servant got it for them; they were sometimes in the House and sometimes at the Door. - The Gentlemen were talking about a Quarrel they had before; I saw no Blows at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Who parted them?</p>
               <p>Herbert. I parted them. This Gentleman, Mr Price, and Cooke, had hold of each other by the Collar, when I parted them. - I did not see any Motion of the Hand to strike. - He was upon the Rail, but not the Rail of the Sign-Post.</p>
               <p>Couns. You look upon this only as a common Quarrel, don't you?</p>
               <p>Herbert. It was only a Quarrel: They were a little drunkish. - It looked to me as if they had been quarrelling. Price was uppermost, he was bloody, and must have had a Blow.</p>
               <p>[The Witnesses to the Prisoners Characters, called.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-27-person272">
                  James 
                  Waldon 
               <interp inst="t17420714-27-person272" type="surname" value="Waldon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person272" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Price five or six Years. He always behaved as civilly as any Lad in the Kingdom, and is as peaceable, quiet a Man, as ever I knew in my Life.</p>
               <p>- Vaughan. I have known Price a Matter of Twenty Years, he has the Character of a peaceable, quiet, honest, sober, careful, civil Lad, as ever I knew in my Life, and is beloved by all the Company that know him.</p>
               <p>Walker. I have known Price between five and six Years, and am intimate with both his Masters that he lived withal, and they give him a very good Character. I never heard any Thing, but that he was a quiet peaceable Man.</p>
               <p>Stephens. I have known Price ever since he was a Child, was born in the same Parish. The first three Years he lived with my Brother, who always gave him the best of Characters.</p>
               <p>Morris. I have known Price three or four Years, and been out with him often on Foot, on Horseback, and by Water, and never heard but that he was a quiet peaceable Man.</p>
               <p>Meredith. I have known Price three Years, we lived together as Fellow-Servants, with Mr Stephens in Thames street. He bears as good a Character in the Family as ever I heard any one in my Life, an honest, just, peaceable, and good-natured Man.</p>
               <p>Pitches. I have known Price ever since he came to London, which is five or six Years. He lived just by me. He was always a quiet, peaceable young man.</p>
               <p>- Randall. I have known Clark six or seven Years. I have a Stable I hired of him, he is a careful Man, and always obliging. He is seen a sober Man, that when my Coachman went away, I would have had him, rather than any other.</p>
               <p>Brace. Clark has lived with me three or four Years, and is a very honest, quiet, sober Man, and might have lived with me to this Day, if he had not married.</p>
               <p>Cleave. I have known Clark seven Years, he is a good-natured, quiet, honest Man, far from being quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>Fellows. I have known Clark three Years, he always appeared to me to be a civil, quiet, modest Man, and always used me well.</p>
               <p>Dyson. I have known Clark about six Years, I never was in Company with a better nature civiller Man in my Life, he always behaved himself in a good-natured Way.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140019"></xptr>John Brown gave him the Character of a quiet inoffensive Man.</p>
               <p>Morgan. I have known Clark ever since he was seven Years of Age. He lived with my Father-in-Law, and became Servant to an Uncle of mine. He has the best of Characters, for a sober, diligent, careful Man, and never quarrelsome upon any Occasion. Both <rs id="t17420714-27-verdict133" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-verdict133" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-verdict133" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of  Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420714-27-punish134" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-punish134" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-27-punish134" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-defend240 t17420714-27-punish134"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-27-defend242 t17420714-27-punish134"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
