<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-10">
               <interp inst="t17400903-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-10" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-10" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-10-off65-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-defend107 t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030010"></xptr>374. + 
               <persName id="t17400903-10-defend107" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17400903-10-defend107" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-defend107" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-defend107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-10-defloc64">St. Sepulchre's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-defloc64" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-defloc64" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-defend107 t17400903-10-defloc64"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-10-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17400903-10-victim108" type="victimName">
                        Elizabeth
                         the 
                        <rs id="t17400903-10-viclabel66" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-victim108 t17400903-10-viclabel66"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-person109 t17400903-10-viclabel66"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17400903-10-person109" type="victimName">
                              Abraham 
                              Brodier 
                           <interp inst="t17400903-10-person109" type="surname" value="Brodier"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17400903-10-person109" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17400903-10-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-person109"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17400903-10-victim108" type="surname" value="the"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-10-victim108" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-10-victim108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-victim108"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her 18 Pence in Money, and a Pair of Steel Scissars, value 12 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400903-10-cd67" type="crimeDate">July 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-cd67"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-10-person110">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brodier 
               <interp inst="t17400903-10-person110" type="surname" value="Brodier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person110" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bear-Alley, near the <placeName id="t17400903-10-crimeloc68">Fleet-Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="Fleet-Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-crimeloc68"></join> ; on the 14th of July, I came home about 11 o'Clock, having been out a little later than ordinary, and this Prisoner (whom I have known some Years , by passing up and down, tho' I never spoke to her in my Life) as I was passing along, was sitting at the <placeName id="t17400903-10-crimeloc69">Crown and Anchor</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-crimeloc69" type="placeName" value="Crown and Anchor"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-10-crimeloc69" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-10-off65 t17400903-10-crimeloc69"></join> Door, next the Market, and another Woman was sitting with her . I was going home quietly, and thinking nothing, the Prisoner rose from the Alehouse-Door, and came up to me, and called out Kate, and swore a great Oath, that I should go and lie with her that Night ; I made answer again, and said, - Hussy , I have no Business to go Home with you; I have a Husband and Children to go Home to. With that she knock'd me down with her Fist, and took out of my Pocket what I had. I had but 18 d. in Money, a Pair of Steel Scissars, and some odd Trifles. She left me there for dead, and ran away; and I was bad enough for a Month after it. She did nothing to me, but strike me with her Fist, yet I was so sore, that I was bad a Month after it. It was Eleven o'Clock at Night, when this was done; but it was just under a Lamp, not three Yards from the Crown and Anchor Alehouse-Door. When I was a little recovered, I got up, but she was gone; so I went after her next Morning, being an ill Creature in the Place, and always robbing every Body she came nigh; for she robb'd me on the 14th of July, and on the Friday following I took her my own self, in the Fleet-Market. She was sitting in the Fleet-Market, so I went to her, and took her, and she beat me sore that Time; but I took her to an Alehouse, and a Gentleman went for a Constable to help me, and we took her before my Lord-Mayor. 'Twas on the Monday Night she robb'd me, and the next Morning I heard where she liv'd; People told me she liv'd in an ill Place, in Love's-Court. When she was before my Lord-Mayor, she confess'd that it was the other Woman (who was with her) that robbed me, and that she had then on the same Gown, which the Prisoner has on now . She said the other Woman had the Gown on, when she robbed me, that the Prisoner her self had on when I took her. When I went into Love's-Court, I went to an ill House which the Prisoner resorted to, and which is kept by one Rachael , - but I don't know her other Name, and there I saw some trifling Things of mine, - a Tea-spoon, and my Scissars, but I could not have them, because as the Prisoner had pawned them for Gin, the People refused to deliver them to me. I was advised to take my Husband and another with me, and go and demand the Things, but they having robb'd a Gentleman of 6 Guineas, and his Watch, and stripp'd him of his Cloaths, are all run away. I formerly kept a Publick-House myself, of 45 l. a Year, and knew the Prisoner by coming up and down the Market.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw her in my Life: Pray ask her why she did not cry out Stop Thief.</p>
               <p>Brodier . As soon as I recovered myself, I cry'd out Stop Thief, and ran towards Holburn-Bridge , and call'd the Watch; but they were all gone to beat their Rounds.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-10-person111">
                  Judith 
                  Wilmot 
               <interp inst="t17400903-10-person111" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person111" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know nothing of this Fact, but the Prisoner has brought People to rob me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-10-person112">
                  Abraham 
                  Brodier 
               <interp inst="t17400903-10-person112" type="surname" value="Brodier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person112" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know my Wife came home on the 14th of July, the Day before St. Swithin's Day, about 11 o'clock at Night, very much puddered and frighted . Her right Cheek Bone was bloody, and she was muddy, and dirty. I asked her what was the matter? she said she had been robbed and beat, by Betty Green . Her Knees were black and blue; and she had a Bruise upon her Head. I was not with her when she was robbed , so I can say nothing to that. But she came home in a Pucker , and in such a manner .</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I work hard for my Bread; and had just finish'd a Sieve of Currants , when she took me up. I never saw him in my Life, before he came to me, in our Brideswell , and told me, he would hang me if it was in his Power. <rs id="t17400903-10-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-10-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.* </p>
               <p>* Of the Persons try'd this Sessions, this is the only one, committed by any Magistrate of the City of London, who has not been adjudged to be a Felon by the Verdict of their Country.</p>
            </div1>
