<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-7">
               <interp inst="t17400416-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-7" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-7" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-7-off41-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-defend74 t17400416-7-off41 t17400416-7-verdict45"></join>
         
               <p>197. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Newel 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-7-defend74" type="surname" value="Newel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-defend74" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-defend74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400416-7-defloc40">St Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-7-defloc40" type="placeName" value="St Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-7-defloc40" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-defend74 t17400416-7-defloc40"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-7-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Gold Watch, and a Gold Chain and Seal, val. 15 l. from the Person of the Chevalier 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-7-victim76" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Rusca 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-7-victim76" type="surname" value="Rusca"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-7-victim76" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-7-victim76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-off41 t17400416-7-victim76"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17400416-7-cd42" type="crimeDate">March 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-off41 t17400416-7-cd42"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Prosecutor being a Foreigner, a Gentleman was sworn his Interpreter.</p>
               <p>The <rs id="t17400416-7-viclabel43" type="occupation">Chevalier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-victim76 t17400416-7-viclabel43"></join> Charles Rusca . On the ninth of March last, as I was going into the <placeName id="t17400416-7-crimeloc44">Sardinian Ambassador's Chapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-7-crimeloc44" type="placeName" value="Sardinian Ambassador's Chapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-7-crimeloc44" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-off41 t17400416-7-crimeloc44"></join>, the Prisoner plucked my Watch out of my Pocket. I seized hold of her Hand, and cry'd, Where's my Watch! Upon this, she threw up both her Hands, and opened<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160006"></xptr> her Breast, and said, she had it not, she had none of the Watch. The Reason of my mistrusting she had got it, was not from my feeling her take it, but from seeing the Motion of her Hand; and this made me imagine my Watch was gone, though I did not see it in her Hand. When I taxed the Prisoner with having taken it, she deny'd it; but a person informing me she had dropped it behind her, I looked for it, and found it on the Ground, just behind where the Prisoner had been standing. When I had got my Watch again, I troubled myself no more about the Prisoner, but went into the Chapel.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you take hold of another Woman at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Chevalier Rusca . After I had seen that she had nothing in her Hand, I did lay hold of another Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-person77">
                  James 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person77" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person77" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Thing was done on Sunday the ninth of March; I was going into the Chapel at the same Time, and was within a Yard and a half of the Gentleman when it happened. I saw him catch hold of the Prisoner's Hand, and he cry'd out, Ma Montre! Ma Montre ! A Gentlewoman coming up, asked what was the Matter? I told her the Gentleman cry'd, Ma Mon-tre ! Ma Montre ! Why (says she) that is, His Watch! His Watch! Upon which I caught hold of the Prisoner on one Side, while the Gentleman held her on the other, and while I called out, - The Gentleman has lost his Watch! she shifted her Hand behind her, and dropped it upon the Ground, just within the Chapel. I am positive she is the Woman, and that I saw the Watch drop behind her, but by the crouding of the People she was pushed a little beyond it, and then we saw it. When we took it up, we saw a little Tin Box on the Ground, in which was three Shillings ; the Prisoner cry'd , - that Box is mine; but I did not see her drop that , though I saw her drop the Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I lift up my Hands directly, to shew I had none of the Watch?</p>
               <p>Smith. As soon as ever she had dropped the Watch, she lifted up her Hands, and then cry'd out, - Search me! Search me! I am sure she dropped it before she lifted up her Hands, for I saw the bottom Part of the Watch, and the Chain, slipping through her Hand. This is the same Watch, I am almost sure of it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask the Chevalier whether the Watch had a Chain to it at that Time?</p>
               <p>Chevalier Rusca . It had the same Chain to it then. The Watch was in the same Condition as it is in now.</p>
               <p>Smith . I saw the Thing from beginning to ending. When the Gentleman had got his Watch again, he went into the Chapel; but the Mob saying he had given Orders to his Footman to have the Woman secured, we took her, and carried her to a publick House, the Sign of the John of Gaunt , and from thence to a publick House in Holhourn , where we kept her till we got more Constables.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if the Gentleman did not seize another Woman?</p>
               <p>Smith. Not just then; - it was afterwards. The Gentleman had hold of the Breast of her Gown, when she threw up her Hands; and I informed him she had dropped the Watch, in half a Quarter of a Minute, - I told him of it as soon as I could, for there was a Croud of People in the Chapel, and then he laid hold of another Woman. I was giving him Notice that the Prisoner had dropped it behind her, while she was holding up her Hands, and just after he had picked it up, he took hold of another Woman, and pushed her and the Prisoner about, as much as to say, - Get out of the Chapel, The second Woman that he lay'd hold of, was one who came up to him after the Watch was found; and desired him not to hurt the Girl (meaning the Prisoner) now he had got it again, I can't say what he took hold of the second Woman for, because I could not understand what he said.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing of the Watch, nor of that Woman; but the Gentleman held my Hands till the Watch was found; and then he bid us both go about our Business. Besides, - I had then a long scarlet Cloak on, and how could he see me drop the Watch?</p>
               <p>Chevalier Rusca . She had then the same Cloak, which she has on now. (She had a light-coloured short Cloth cloak on at the Bar.)</p>
               <p>Smith. I think she had a red short Cloak on, at that Time; and had a Velvet Hood, and a Hat over it.</p>
               <p>Chevalier Rusca . I am sure it was the same she has on now.</p>
               <p>Smith . To the best of my Remembrance, she was then in a red Cloak.</p>
               <p>Chevalier . I don't remember how her Head was dress'd; but she had a Cloak of the very same Colour with that she has on now.</p>
               <p>Smith . When the Gentleman had got his Watch again, he went into the Chapel, and staid till the Ceremony was over; after which a Man told him the Woman was in Custody, and he must go to Colonel De Veil's. He went accordingly,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160007"></xptr> but did not see the Prisoner; for she was rescued from the Constables, as they were carrying her thither.</p>
               <p>Jury . We desire Smith may be asked what Trade he is, and what brought him to that Place?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am 'Prentice to Mr Richards, a Tin-Man, at the Black Horse and Star in Fleet-street, near Fleet-Ditch; and am of the same Perswasion, - a 
               <persName id="t17400416-7-person78">
                  Roman 
                  Catbolick 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person78" type="surname" value="Catbolick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person78" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>A Gentleman upon the Bench deposed, that the Chevalier was with him, waiting for the Prisoner, in order to have this Affair examined into, but that after they had waited some Time, three Constables and a Beadle came and inform'd them, that the Prisoner had been rescued out of their Custody. He added, that he knew her to be a most notorious Pickpocket, and that both she and her Husband had been several Times committed for Felony, which they afterwards had compounded.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, - not for Felony, it was for keeping a disorderly House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-person79">
                  Gilbert 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person79" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person79" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. My Beadle being charged with the Prisoner for robbing the Chevalier Rusca, on Sunday, March 9, he brought her to my House. She then had a red short Cloak on; but it is possible she might have changed her Cloak, between the Chapel and my House. She was brought to me between 12 and 1 at Noon, and we kept her two Hours, because the Gentleman did not care to give himself the Trouble to appear against her, and I did not know how to discharge her. At last I found him out, and desired him to go to the Justice's, and told him, I would bring the Prisoner to him there: but as we were carrying her along, three Fellows with Fire-Arms stopped the Coach, over-against Windsor-Court in Drury-Lane, broke the Door open, and rescued her from us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-person80">
                  Thomas 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person80" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person80" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We took Coach at Mr Ward's Door, and were going before the Justice, with the Prisoner, but when we came against Windsor-Court , one Man came up, and clapp'd a Pistol in at the Coach-Door, and swore he would blow our Brains out. Another bid the Coachman stop: I bid him drive on; but he refused, and said he would not venture his Life. Upon this our Beadle jumped out of the Coach, but another Fellow ran up to him with a great Sniggersnee Thing, and swore he was a dead Man, if he stirred farther. Upon this the Prisoner jumped out of the Coach, and they all ran away together. The Chevalier's Footman gave the Beadle charge of the Prisoner, on the Outside of the Chapel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-person81">
                  Eleanor 
                  Byant 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person81" type="surname" value="Byant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person81" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Mantua-maker, and Habit-maker. I have worked three Years for the Prisoner, and between 7 and 8 for her Mother. I know they are honest People; what I have done for them, they have paid me for. Her Mother liv'd at St. James's, and the Prisoner liv'd first in the Hay-market, and now in Windsor-Court, in Drury-Lane. The old Woman was a green Grocer, and as to the Prisoner's Business, I had no Occasion to enquire about that, - for if she employed me, she paid me. She kept a House, but I don't know what Sort of a House it was, nor do I know her Husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-7-person82">
                  Eleanor 
                  Puzzle 
               <interp inst="t17400416-7-person82" type="surname" value="Puzzle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person82" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-person82" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know the Prisoner kept House in Drury-Lane; I can't say what Sort of a House, - it might be a House of Lodgers for any Thing I know: I never was in the Inside of it. I never knew any Harm of her in my Life. - I have known her about half a Year, - I have spoke to her, but never in the Way of dealing with her, for I never had any Dealings with her, but I can say she is an honest Woman, - as far as I know; and I never heard otherwise of her.</p>
               <p>Jury. We desire to know what Business this Witness follows?</p>
               <p>Puzzle. I am a Shoemaker's Wife.</p>
               <p>A Gentleman. This Witness is a common Bawdy-house Keeper she has been committed herself: she kept a Bawdy-house in Jackson's Alley, but I believe she is broke now. <rs id="t17400416-7-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-7-punish46" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-punish46" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-7-punish46" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-7-defend74 t17400416-7-punish46"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
