<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-22">
               <interp inst="t17470225-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-22" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-22" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-22-off96-c253" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-defend300 t17470225-22-off96 t17470225-22-verdict100"></join>
         
               <p>153. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-22-defend300" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Barker 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-22-defend300" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-defend300" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-defend300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-22-off96" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-off96" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-off96" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Clock, value 30 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17470225-22-victim301" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-victim301" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-off96 t17470225-22-victim301"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17470225-22-cd97" type="crimeDate">February 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-off96 t17470225-22-cd97"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to De Barker. What have you to alledge against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Barker. I am a <rs id="t17470225-22-viclabel98" type="occupation">Clock-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-victim301 t17470225-22-viclabel98"></join>; I missed the Clock the 2d of February. I live in <placeName id="t17470225-22-crimeloc99">Leather lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-22-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="Leather lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-22-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-off96 t17470225-22-crimeloc99"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Barker. I missed it in the Afternoon; it was the Property of one Mr. Harrison in the Temple; I had it to clean.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found the Clock again?</p>
               <p>Barker. I found the Clock again in this Gentlewoman's House.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who took it away?</p>
               <p>Barker. I believe the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you find it?</p>
               <p>Barker I found it last Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-22-person302">
                  Mary 
                  Billings 
               <interp inst="t17470225-22-person302" type="surname" value="Billings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person302" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Billings. I live at the Turn stile in Drury lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>

               <p>Billings. Nothing at all, I bought it of this young Gentleman here; the Clock was brought to me about a Fortnight ago, it was brought by 
               <persName id="t17470225-22-person303">
                  Andrew
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250033"></xptr> Franket<interp inst="t17470225-22-person303" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger, this Mr Horn came with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Billings He said his Father had fetched it out of Pawn, for five and twenty Shillings; I gave him a Guinea and a half for it, and he cheated the Prisoner out of a Crown of it, for he gave him a Crown less than I gave him; when the Constable came to me, I delivered the Clock last Tuesday.</p>
               <p>[The Clock was produced in Court]</p>
               <p>Franket the younger. The Prisoner brought this Clock to my Father, and he lent him Money upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come to your Father to lend him Money upon this Clock?</p>
               <p>Franket About three Weeks ago the Prisoner came to my Father, and told him he had a Clock in Pawn for 16 s. which was his Mother's; my Father went with the Prisoner to get it out of Pawn, and they brought the Clock back with them.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Clock was brought back, what then?</p>
               <p>Franket. When the Clock was brought back, my Father made the 16 s. up a Guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Father give the Remainder in your Presence?</p>
               <p>Franket. I did not see him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they do afterwards?</p>
               <p>Franket. The Prisoner at the Bar came several Times to my Father, and wanted more Money upon it, but my Father said he would have no more to do with it; so the Prisoner came afterwards to fetch the Clock; he said he would let him have what Money he advanced for it; and my Father sent me as a Security along with him; to bring his Money back again.</p>
               <p>Court. You went with him, where did you go?</p>
               <p>Franket. As we were going along the Street, he (the Prisoner) said he would not carry it to a Pawnbroker's, they would not let him have so much Money upon it, so he would sell it out right.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go then?</p>
               <p>Franket. So Mr Horn made Answer, and said he could carry him to an honest Person's House, that would give him as much as any Body; so we went to 
               <persName id="t17470225-22-person304">
                  Mary 
                  Billings 
               <interp inst="t17470225-22-person304" type="surname" value="Billings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person304" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's House; he said if I could get three or four Shillings to buy him some Victuals, besides what would pay my Father, I might have the rest; he did not go with me to sell the Clock, because he had never a Hat, but stood over the Way; while we were dealing about the Clock, 
               <persName id="t17470225-22-person305">
                  Mary 
                  Billings 
               <interp inst="t17470225-22-person305" type="surname" value="Billings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person305" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked whose Clock it was, she asked me who it belonged to, and I showed her the young Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-22-person306">
                  Mary 
                  Billings 
               <interp inst="t17470225-22-person306" type="surname" value="Billings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person306" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person306" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I would not have gave a Shilling for it had I seen the young Man.</p>
               <p>Franket. She gave me a Guinea and a Half, and I gave him 26 s and kept 5 s for myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him what you sold it for?</p>
               <p>Franket. No. he asked me no Questions, but was very well satisfied</p>
               <p>Court. This is a bad way of dealing, you make yourself a Party.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He told me he sold it for no more than five and twenty Shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Franket. He was an Apprentice by us in Red-lyon-Square.</p>
               <p>Horn. About a Fortnight or three Weeks ago, I went into Franket's for a Pint of Beer; when I came in, young Franket and the Prisoner were going to pawn this Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Horn. Very slightly; I never was in his Company.</p>
               <p>Q. What Discourse had you with the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Horn. None at all, my Lord; Mr. Franket desired. I would go with them; the Prisoner said he believed he could not pawn it for so much as would pay Mr. Franket, and he said he would sell it; so I told him of a Person that I had known a great while, that would give as much as any Body; so accordingly I went to this Gentlewoman's Husband, but he was not at Home, but the Gentlewoman was, so I went and shewed him the House; so Mrs Billings gave him a Guinea and an Half for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing else going along?</p>
               <p>Horn. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Question asked by Mrs Billings, when she bought it?</p>
               <p>Horn. While she was giving him the Money, says she, whose Clock is it, is it your own? is it that young Man's that stands over the Way? then she made Answer again, he is a Clock-maker; says Franket the younger, he is, for he has a green Apron on.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came back again, what did he do with the Money?</p>
               <p>Horn. Whether he gave it his Father, or what, I can't tell; when we all came back, he (the Prisoner) was very free, and offered to treat me at Mr. Franket's House, with Half a Crown's worth of Punch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-22-person307">
                  Andrew 
                  Franket 
               <interp inst="t17470225-22-person307" type="surname" value="Franket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person307" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sen. The Prisoner came to my House along with a Neighbour, about three Weeks ago, with a Shoemaker.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250034"></xptr>Q. Did he bring any thing with him?</p>
               <p>Franket. He had a Pint of Beer, and said he was almost starved, and had not a Shoe upon his Feet, and he wanted Money to fetch a Clock out of pawn, that he had made almost all himself; he said if I would do it for him, he should be bound to pray for me as long as he lived.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say the Clock was pawned?</p>
               <p>Franket. At one Singleton's a Pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prisoner say of his Mother?</p>
               <p>Franket. That his Mother was dead; I went along with him to Singleton's, whereof they would not let me see it, before I paid the Money down, so I paid 16 s. and one Shilling for the use of it; it was pawned in his own Name, and he said it was his own Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the Clock?</p>
               <p>Franket. I brought it Home; he says I shall be pretty well when I have Shoes and Stockings; I made it up a Guinea to buy him some Shoes and Stockings; I drawed him but one Pint of Beer; I told him to go and lay it out for himself; I brought the Clock Home, about three or four Days after he comes to me himself, and he said, Mr Franket, I do not know why you should be afraid to trust him, you have three or four times the Worth in your Hands than what I owe you: he would have sold it for four or five Shillings more, but I would not have it; I said he might take it, and do what he would with it.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoner. What have you to say in your Defence, in Answer to this Charge?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Witnesses ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have not seen any one Soul that I know.</p>
               <p>Dr Barker. The Prisoner worked with me at the Time I lost the Clock; and for seven or eight Months; I never found him deficient before.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you take him again if you wanted a Servant?</p>
               <p>Dr. Barker. Yes.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-22-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-verdict100" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>[On the Account of the general good Character one Master had given the Prisoner, and believing it might be the first Fact, he was only ordered to be <rs id="t17470225-22-punish101" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-punish101" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-22-punish101" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-22-defend300 t17470225-22-punish101"></join>
               burnt in the Hand
            </rs>.]</p>
            </div1>
