<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450530-24">
               <interp inst="t17450530-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-24" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450530-24" type="date" value="17450530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450530-24-off150-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-defend317 t17450530-24-off150 t17450530-24-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>288. + 
               <persName id="t17450530-24-defend317" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah 
                  Moore , otherwise <rs id="t17450530-24-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-defend317 t17450530-24-alias-7"></join>Phillis Cox</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17450530-24-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-defend317 t17450530-24-alias-8"></join>Phillis Booker</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-defend317" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-defend317" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-defend317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of <placeName id="t17450530-24-defloc149">St. Mary Le Bow</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-24-defloc149" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Le Bow"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-24-defloc149" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-defend317 t17450530-24-defloc149"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450530-24-off150" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-off150" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-off150" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silk handkerchief, value 12 d. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450530-24-victim319" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Barnes 
                        <interp inst="t17450530-24-victim319" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-24-victim319" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450530-24-victim319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-off150 t17450530-24-victim319"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450530-24-cd151" type="crimeDate">May 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-off150 t17450530-24-cd151"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-24-person320">
                  Henry 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17450530-24-person320" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person320" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of this month, about twelve o'clock at night, I was going from Black Friars to St. Catherine's, and passing along <placeName id="t17450530-24-crimeloc152">Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-24-crimeloc152" type="placeName" value="Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450530-24-crimeloc152" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450530-24-off150 t17450530-24-crimeloc152"></join>, the Prisoner and another young woman followed me; my coat was open, and my handkerchief was in my coat pocket, for I had it but just before: I said to the Prisoner you have got my handkerchief, and the Prisoner gave it me, and said, there's your handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of the women took it out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner the woman?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I believe she is the woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she is the woman?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I think it was her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she taken up directly?</p>
               <p>Barnes. She was taken up presently.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner the woman who was presently taken up upon that occasion ?</p>
               <p>Barnes. She is the person.</p>
               <p>Q. What become of the other woman?</p>
               <p>Barnes. She was committed to the workhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put your hand into your pocket to feel whether your handkerchief was there? or did you only put your hand into your pocket occasionally?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I put it in to feel for my handkerchief to wipe my face.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I had been drinking pretty plentifully of Yorkshire ale.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think you had your senses so as to know what you did?</p>
               <p>Barnes. Yes; I knew very well what I did</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Barnes. I was pretty merryish, I went home very well that night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You did not charge me in the watch-house with taking it.</p>
               <p>Barnes. I did charge you with it in the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether he was not so much in liquor that he fell down in the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Barnes. I did not fall down at all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Constable desired me to give him the handkerchief, and said he must prosecute me; and one talked of a reward of 10 l. and another talked of 10 l. it is only for the sake of the reward.</p>
               <p>Barnes. When I took her up, the Constable said there was a reward of 10 l. for every one that was taken in the city.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said in the watch-house he would not charge either of the women with the handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Barnes. I did not say any such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-24-person321">
                  Thomas 
                  Rybright 
               <interp inst="t17450530-24-person321" type="surname" value="Rybright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person321" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 16th of this month at midnight the watchmen came to the watch-house about twelve o'clock at night with the Prosecutor, the Prisoner and another woman; the Prosecutor appeared to me to be as sober as he is now, and talked as reasonably as he does now, but the women appeared to be almost fuddled. The Prosecutor said, Mr. Constable, I have had my handkerchief picked out of my pocket, and I desire you would take charge of these women. I asked the Prisoner how she came by the handkerchief; she said the Prosecutor desired her to take it out of his pocket, and he said, he did not say any such thing. When we came before the sitting Alderman, she said she took it out of the right side waistcoat pocket; but when it came to be examined, it was so bad it would not hold a handkerchief; then she said she took it out of the left side pocket, and that was as bad.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they talk any thing of the reward?</p>
               <p>Barnes. The watchmen I believe did talk of the reward, but I did not much mind what they said; I believe nobody here does it for the sake of the reward.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174505300028"></xptr>Prisoner. The Constable persuaded him to call upon him again in the morning, and told him, if he let me go he would not have the 10 l. it is only for the sake of the 10 l. that they do this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you order him to prosecute her for the sake of the reward?</p>
               <p>Rybright. I told him I understood the Prisoner was a common nusance, and that prosecuting her would be doing his country justice.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Prosecutor said he did this for the sake of the 10 l.</p>
               <p>Barnes. I never said such a thing; I can call a great many people to my reputation, for I always behaved well.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They drank two shillings in beer, which I gave to the watchmen, and they wanted me to give them a crown, but I would not; I said I have no business to give you a crown when I never did any body any harm.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did the Prisoner give the watchmen?</p>
               <p>Rybright. I did see one of the women put something into a watchman's hand, but what it was I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Barnes. There was no beer while I was there.</p>
               <p>Rybright. There was a man before the sitting Alderman, who I believe is one of the thieftakers, and he said the Prisoner was one of the Black Boy Alley crew.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I live in Goswell Street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-24-person322">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wilks 
               <interp inst="t17450530-24-person322" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person322" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner several years, I never heard any thing of misbehaviour of her in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does she follow?</p>
               <p>Wilks. She buys and sells old clothes.</p>
               <p>Q. What business are you?</p>
               <p>Wilks. I keep a shop at Aldersgate, I have lived there 17 or 18 years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450530-24-person323">
                  Ann 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17450530-24-person323" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person323" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-person323" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Prisoner, she is an entire stranger to me. I happened to be coming that way by accident, and they were pulling and hawling the poor woman about. I asked what was the matter; I said it was a shame they should do so, and she said they had charged her wrongfully; and she desired to know where I lived: and a man said, I don't know what they pull the woman for, for I don't know that I have lost any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that said so? was it the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Martin. I don't know who it was, it was a man's voice.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Martin. It is about a fortnight ago as near as I can remember the time.</p>
               <p>Q. How many men were there?</p>
               <p>Martin. I believe there were two or three men.</p>
               <p>Barnes. There was not above a minute's distance between my losing my handkerchief and her being in custody. There were no more than two women there; I am sure you was not there.</p>
               <p>Martin. I did not stay long. <rs id="t17450530-24-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450530-24-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
