<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17461015-23">
               <interp inst="t17461015-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-23" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17461015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461015-23" type="date" value="17461015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17461015-23-off96-c366" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-23-defend411 t17461015-23-off96 t17461015-23-verdict99"></join>
         
               <p>357. 
               
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-defend411" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Hope 
                  <interp inst="t17461015-23-defend411" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-defend411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-defend411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of Milk-Street, the <rs id="t17461015-23-cd95" type="crimeDate">5th of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-23-off96 t17461015-23-cd95"></join>, <rs id="t17461015-23-off96" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-off96" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-off96" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               being big with a certain Male Bastard Child, the said Male Child from her Body was brought forth alive, and the said 
                     <persName id="t17461015-23-person412">
                        Mary 
                        Hope 
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person412" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-23-person412" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461015-23-person412" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not having the Fear of God before her Eyes, but being moved by the Instigation of the Devil, the aforesaid Bastard so alive, feloniously, willfully, and aforethought, did make an Assault upon, and with a certain Linnen Apron, into a certain Wooden Box, feloniously and willfully, by wrapping and solding the said Linnen Apron, the said Bastard Child did put, by which it was so suffocated that it died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-person413">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person413" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person413" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-23-person414">
                  William 
                  Aget 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person414" type="surname" value="Aget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person414" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Sir, what do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Aget. The Prisoner at the Bar was my <rs id="t17461015-23-deflabel97" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-23-defend411 t17461015-23-deflabel97"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Aget. In <placeName id="t17461015-23-crimeloc98">Milk-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-23-crimeloc98" type="placeName" value="Milk-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461015-23-crimeloc98" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461015-23-off96 t17461015-23-crimeloc98"></join>. The Prisoner at the Bar was my Servant; she had lived with me about four or five Months; and on Sunday the 5th of this Instant October she came down Stairs with her Fellow Servant in the Morning, but finding herself indisposed, went up again .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by when she came down ?</p>
               <p>Aget. No, my Lord, I was not up. When I came down, this was the Relation her Fellow Servant gave me .</p>
               <p>Court. What her Fellow Servant told you is nothing; did you see her ?</p>
               <p>Aget. I did not see her 'till the Afternoon; but about Nine o'Clock in the Morning; I heard her cry out; so I sent her Fellow Servant up to see what ail'd her ; she brought me Word she was not well, and desir'd to be indulged to lie abed . She would not sufler her Fellow Servant to stay in the Room as little Time as possible; she bid her go about her Business, that she was better. This was what her Fellow Servant told me. My Duty call'd me to Church; when I came from that, I enquired how she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no Suspicion ?</p>
               <p>Aget. Yes, Sir, that Cry gave me a Suspicion. My Servant told me she was much better, and intended to come down in the Afternoon. In the Afternoon she did come down, about Five o'Clock; I saw her do her Business, light a Fire, &amp;c. I then desired my Wife and the Witness, the other Servant, to go up into her Room; there they saw what they thought was sufficient to convince them that there had been a Labour or something like it.</p>
               <p>Court. You did not go up into her Room?</p>
               <p>Agit . I did not then. When they came to me, they said they were very sure there was a Labour, or something like it had been in that Room. She strongly denied it. When nothing could be found in the Room they look'd in every Place where any Thing might be conceal'd: My Wife insisted upon opening her Box; she made some Difficulty and could not find the Key; upon which I told her, her Mistress should have Satisfaction , and if the Key was not be found I would break the Box open; accordingly I took her fellow Servant up with me and did break it open, and there, to my great Surprize, was a dead Child.</p>
               <p>Court. You saw it?</p>
               <p>Aget. I saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon the Child, was there any Marks of Violence ?</p>
               <p>Aget. I saw none. I sent for the Constable and charg'd him with her .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-person415">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person415" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person415" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Would you ask Mr. Aget any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174610150034"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-person416">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person416" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person416" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-23-person417">
                  Dorothy 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person417" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person417" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Was you fellow Servant with the Prisoner ? Do you live at Mr. Aget's?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an Account of what you know of the Matter. Do you remember when she cry'd out?</p>
               <p>Robinson. It was about Nine o'Clock; and I went up.</p>
               <p>Q. What Condition was she in ?</p>
               <p>Robinson. She complain'd of being very ill, but did not tell me her Distemper.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Suspicion of her being in Labour?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes, we thought so by her Screeking out, but she deny'd it, and it went over.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she desire you to go down ?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes Sir, she desired me to go down , and I told my Mistress, and my Mistress went up and examin'd her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with your Mistress then?</p>
               <p>Robinson. No Sir, I was below.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you up any more?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes, I went up several Times in the Day, and I ask'd her how she did; and she said she was better.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she always tell you that she was better?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes, 'till she came down; she said she would come down in the Afternoon .</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say when she came down ?</p>
               <p>Robinson. She said she was much better.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go up Stairs with your Master and Mistress when the Child was found in the Box?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes. My Mistress told her she was sure she had a Child, and she would examine; so they broke open the Box and found the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Child, Male or Female?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Male.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Child seem to have any Marks of Violence?</p>
               <p>Robinson. No Sir, we could not perceive any Marks of Violence about the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any Childbed Linnen ready?</p>
               <p>Robinson. We examin'd her Clothes and there was none to be found.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you skilful enough to know whether she went her full Time?</p>
               <p>Robinson. My Lord here is the Midwife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-person418">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person418" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person418" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17461015-23-person419">
                  Mary 
                  Jeyne 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person419" type="surname" value="Jeyne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person419" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person419" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) Are you a Midwife?</p>
               <p>Jeyne . Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Jeyne . I was sent for on Monday was se'nnight. She was deliver'd the Sunday before; I was sent for to know if she was safely deliver'd. I did not examine her, I examin'd other Matters, and found she was safely deliver'd .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Child ?</p>
               <p>Jeyne. Yes my Lord .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Marks of Violence on the Child? Was it of its full Time .</p>
               <p>Jeyne. I believe it was, or very nigh, my Lord .</p>
               <p>Court. You that are a skilful Woman, do you think the Child was born dead , or came to any violent Death afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Jeyne. I saw no Marks of Violence: 'Tis impossible for any Body to say it was born alive; for want of Help in Time it might be suffocated, or another Way, thro' the Naval String, or otherwise, &amp;c. I turn'd it before them all, and there were no Marks of Violence found .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any Thing else.</p>
               <p>Jeyne. The Child look'd just like another Child that should die a natural Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461015-23-person420">
                  Richard 
                  Wheatland 
               <interp inst="t17461015-23-person420" type="surname" value="Wheatland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person420" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About Eight o'Clock on Sunday Evening, the 5th Instant, Mr. Aget came to me, seemingly in a very great Fright, he said I must go along with him .</p>
               <p>Q. What are you, a Constable?</p>
               <p>Wheatland. Yes. As we were going down the Street together, he said his Maid was deliver'd of a Child, and he believ'd it was murder'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Wheatland. I went up with Mr. Aget and his Wife into the Garret , where I saw the Woman sitting on the Bed, crying prodigiously; I said to her, good Woman are you married? she said yes she was. I says, what Provision have you made for the Birth of this Child? none at all said she; upon which I said to her, it was surprising to me that a married Woman should suffer herself to bring a Child into the World and have nothing to put it in; tell me the Truth I says, are you married or not? she crying still, said at last she was not; I then ask'd her again, have you nothing at all made for this Child, no Linnen whatsoever? none at all she said: I ask'd her who was the Father of the Child; she said a Sailor. I ask'd her what was become of him, she said he was gone to Sea: I afterwards saw the Child, my Lord, in this check'd Linnen Apron. Mr. Aget gave me charge to take her in a Coach to the Compter, which I did, and went with her myself, my Lord, in the Coach, which Mr. Aget paid for; I told the Deputy Keeper of the Compter to put her up warm, for she was deliver'd that Morning: She declared that the Child was born dead, that is all that I know, <rs id="t17461015-23-verdict99" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461015-23-verdict99" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
