<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-31">
               <interp inst="t17400903-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-31" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-31" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-31-off198-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-defend261 t17400903-31-off198 t17400903-31-verdict201"></join>
         
               <p>399. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-defend261" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-31-defend261" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-defend261" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-defend261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-31-defloc197">St Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-31-defloc197" type="placeName" value="St Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-31-defloc197" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-defend261 t17400903-31-defloc197"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-31-off198" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-off198" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-off198" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17400903-31-victim262" type="victimName">
                        William 
                        Swinney 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-victim262" type="surname" value="Swinney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-31-victim262" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-31-victim262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-off198 t17400903-31-victim262"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , and throwing him upon a Stone-Pavement, and giving him (so lying upon the Stone-Pavement) with both his Hands and Feet, several mortal Bruises, in and upon his Head, Neck, Stomach, and Belly, <rs id="t17400903-31-cd199" type="crimeDate">July 2</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-off198 t17400903-31-cd199"></join>. Of which mortal Bruises he languished from the 2d to the 10th of July, and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time charged by Virtue of the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person263">
                  William 
                  Bourn 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person263" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . That is the Man, Gentlemen, I will tell you what I know about it. It happened about 2 months ago, as near as I can think, (for I am no Scholar). - It happened that this William Swinney was murder'd; I am sure he was. He was going into <placeName id="t17400903-31-crimeloc200">Bowl-Yard, Broad St Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-31-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="Bowl-Yard, Broad St Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-31-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-off198 t17400903-31-crimeloc200"></join>, between 4 and 5 in the Morning, and this Prisoner came up to him, and tapp'd him on the Shoulder, and said, - You Blood of a Whore, will you fight. I did not know the Prisoner before, but I know it is him, because I am positive by the Marks and Tokens that he is the Man. The Deceased said he would not fight; I am no fighting Man, moreover, I am drunk. The Prisoner said, You Blood of a Whore, if you will not fight, I will make you fight. They had not been in Company together, for the Deceased and I had had 2 Pots of Beer together, at the Cannon and Crown in Broad St Giles's. So when the Deceased refused to fight, the Prisoner knock'd him down to the Ground with his Fist; for I believe he had no Stick, nor any other Weapon. When he had knock'd him down, he gave him 3 or 4 Kicks on the Sides, and at every Kick he cry'd, - You Blood of a Whore, there's Dublin for you. For he that is dead, was an Irishman; what the Prisoner is I know not. The Deceased got up, and the Prisoner knock'd him down 3 or 4 Times, and gave him the same Usage, and at every Kick he cry'd out, - there's Dublin for you. The Deceased, to the best of my Remembrance, made no Resistance in Life; he was not able to stand, and he told the Prisoner so before he struck him. The last Kick he gave him was about the Throat, after which he lay a Quarter of an Hour senseless, and stirred neither Hand nor Foot. With that, I knowing the Man that was kill'd, and seeing 3 or 4 Men stand at the Corner, for Fear they were Confederates, I dare not come near to assist my Acquaintance, - for Fear my Life should be lost as well as his. - I am an Irishman, - I never will deny my Country. So with this, the Man lay for the Space of a Quarter of an Hour, and did not stir Hand nor Feet, and I stood all the while leaning against a Bulk. Then the Prisoner came up to me, and said, - You Blood of a Whore, do you belong to that Man? No, really, says I, I don't, - I don't know him; I never saw him to my Knowledge. Says the Prisoner, You Blood of a Whore, you lie, you are one of his Confederates, and so he gave me a Knock on the Side of the Head, as I leaned against the Bulk, and I staggered 6 or 7 Yards, before I fell to the Ground, and then, I believe, he did not give me another Knock. Then here is the Women who stood by and said, O you cruel Man, are not you ashamed to use the poor old Man so barbarous as you do? Meaning me, by the poor old Man. This is one of the Women who cry'd out so, and one Tisdale, who refuses to come, is the other. What is that to you, you B - ch - s, (says the Prisoner) what I do, so they ran in and shut their Doors, for Fear he should do them some bodily Harm. I have no more to say, but a Word or two. The Prisoner, when he left me and the Deceased knocked down, he went with these 3 Men, who stood on the other Side, to a Night-house (one Mr Allen's that was) in St Giles's, but who keeps the House now, I don't know; and whether there was 3 or 4 of them I don't know, but thither they went. The Deceased got up some Time after, and with that he went Home, I believe, to his Bed. His Home was not above 2 or 3 Stones-throw from the Place where this happened: he lives in Vine-Street, Broad St Giles's. I did not go home with him, for I was afraid I was as bad as he, so he went home himself, but I saw him the next Morning in his Bed, about 6 o'clock, and he said he was in a bad Condition. I saw him 4 or 5 Times before he died, in a very weak Condition, as he told me, for I am no Physician. The<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030030"></xptr> Night before he died, he sent for me, and said, - 
               <persName id="t17400903-31-person264">
                  William 
                  Bourn 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person264" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person264" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I send for you to let you know a little of my Mind, by Reason you was a Witness to my Mis-usage , and my being murdered; and I leave it as an Obligation on you, if you can find him, at any Time, to bring him to Justice, for he has actually killed me; and he dy'd on Wednesday, the very Day after he told me this Expression. Says I to him, No, William, my Dear, God is able to bring you from it. No, says he, I never will recover; and my Wife is out of Town, so I leave it as an Obligation on you to bring him to Justice. He dy'd 8 or 9 Days after he received the Hurt; he received the Hurt on Wednesday, and he dy'd on the Wednesday after; I don't know how long it was after he was hurt, for I am no Scholar; I don't know a B from a Bird's Foot. He shew'd me a great many of his Hurts, and he had every Bit of him all over hurt, and I did not see him out of his House after he was hurt. He had no Doctor, for I believe he had no Money. He used to go about with Hard-ware.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person265">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Howel 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person265" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person265" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person265" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was out in the Street selling Rice-milk between 4 and 5 in the Morning, and saw the Prisoner meet the Deceased in Bowl Yard. The Prisoner tapp'd the Deceased on the Shoulder, and asked him if he would fight? The Deceased said no, and told the Prisoner he [the Deceased] was drunk. The Prisoner asked him what Countryman he was? The Deceased said he was an Irishman; upon which the Prisoner gave him a Blow, and said, if he would not fight he would make him fight. After some Blows had passed, the Deceased took hold of the Prisoner's Shirt, and tore it. The Prisoner then beat him in a very barbarous Manner, and knock'd him down several Times. I afterwards saw a Street-walking Woman take the Deceased to a Pump, and wash him. The Prisoner gave the Deceased some Kicks after he was knock'd down, and the last Kick was in the Throat. The Deceased made no more Resistance, than only to take hold of the Prisoner's Shirt, and tear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person266">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tyler 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person266" type="surname" value="Tyler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person266" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Last Wednesday Morning, about nine Weeks ago, I call'd at my Landlady's about 4 o'clock in the Morning, to take her Daughter with me to Paddington : as I waited at the Door for her, I saw something of a Fight, in the Bowl-Yard. One Man knocked the other down several Times. My Landlady and I called out, - You Rogue! You Villain! How can you use your Fellow-creature so. I never saw either of the Men before, nor have I ever seen the Prisoner since, till to Day, but I know him again. And all he said, when I spoke to him, was, - What did he tear my Shirt for. After this my Landlady and I shut ourselves in, for Fear of bringing ourselves into Trouble; and one, whom we took to be a Woman of the Town, took him to the Pump, and washed him, and seemed very careful of him. There was 3 or 4 People stood by during the Fray. One was a Ballad-singing-Boy, and the other a Person who had been 'Prentice to a Neighbour of ours.</p>
               <p>Defence. 
               <persName id="t17400903-31-person267">
                  Walter 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person267" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person267" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Dealer in Coals. In the Beginning of July, between 3 and 4 in the Morning, I heard an Outcry and a Noise, so I jump'd out of Bed, flung up the Sash, and saw two Men fighting in the Broad-Way: and, to the best of my Remembrance, the Prisoner was one of them. I saw some Blows struck, but from what I could perceive, they were not Blows that could occasion the Death of any one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person268">
                  Edward 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person268" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person268" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That he was going with News that Morning to Kensington , between 3 and 4 in the Morning, and saw the Deceased push against the Prisoner, and heard him say, he did it for Fun. Upon which they fell to fighting, and fought a long Time. When they had done, one went one Way, and the other another. The Witness observed a Man with the Deceased, but he did not know who he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person269">
                  William 
                  Hampton 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person269" type="surname" value="Hampton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             saw the Prisoner and the Deceased fighting a long time together that Morning; after which the Prisoner gave out; and then the Deceased said, - You English Bug, you have lost one Eye, and I will drive the other out. And upon the Deceased's striking him again, the Prisoner said, - You Irish, Bog-trotting Dog, I will not give out. They then fell to fighting again, and the Witness went away, and left them engaged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-31-person270">
                  Mary 
                  Hampton 
               <interp inst="t17400903-31-person270" type="surname" value="Hampton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person270" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-person270" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, That she saw the Squabble, and that the Prisoner having done fighting, was about to put on his Cloaths ; but the Deceased jumped upon him again, knocked him down, and calling him Bug , said he would beat his other Eye out.</p>
               <p>Three Persons gave the Prisoner the Character of a peaceable Man. <rs id="t17400903-31-verdict201" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-verdict201" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-verdict201" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400903-31-punish202" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-punish202" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-31-punish202" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-31-defend261 t17400903-31-punish202"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
