<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440912-25">
               <interp inst="t17440912-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-25" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-25" type="date" value="17440912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440912-25-off127-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-defend223 t17440912-25-off127 t17440912-25-verdict131"></join>
         
               <p>376. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-25-defend223" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Howard 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-25-defend223" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-defend223" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-defend223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17440912-25-defloc126">Hamstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-25-defloc126" type="placeName" value="Hamstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-25-defloc126" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-defend223 t17440912-25-defloc126"></join> , was indicted for the <rs id="t17440912-25-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440912-25-victim225" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Paulet 
                        <interp inst="t17440912-25-victim225" type="surname" value="Paulet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-25-victim225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-25-victim225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-off127 t17440912-25-victim225"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by throwing him down upon the ground with both his hands, and as he was lying on the ground striking him with both his hands upon his head, neck, back, belly, and stomach; by which blows he received upon those parts several mortal bruises, of which he instantly died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440912-25-cd128" type="crimeDate">August 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-off127 t17440912-25-cd128"></join>.</p>
               <p>He was likewise charged on the Coroner's Inquest for feloniously slaying the said 
               <persName id="t17440912-25-person226">
                  William 
                  Pawlet 
               <interp inst="t17440912-25-person226" type="surname" value="Pawlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-25-person227">
                  Richard 
                  Hind 
               <interp inst="t17440912-25-person227" type="surname" value="Hind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person227" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of August in the evening, the deceased, after he had done work, sat at the door of a publick-house at <placeName id="t17440912-25-crimeloc129">West-End</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-25-crimeloc129" type="placeName" value="West-End"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-25-crimeloc129" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-off127 t17440912-25-crimeloc129"></join> : the Prisoner came with a piece of victuals in his hand to the house where the deceased was, and complained that he was tired with his work: whereupon the deceased said, it was not possible he could be tired, for his work was nothing but play.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his work?</p>
               <p>Hind. A <rs id="t17440912-25-deflabel130" type="occupation">Bricklayer's labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-25-defend223 t17440912-25-deflabel130"></join> - After the deceased had said that, they disputed it some time, and I believe the Prisoner gave him the lie; then the deceased said if he gave him the lie again he would give him a slap on the face. Upon which the Prisoner made answer and said, he would return it if he did; then the deceased said he would lay the Prisoner five shillings that he beat him in three minutes time, and the Prisoner offered to lay him he did not, but I saw no money pulled out: however, they agreed to fight, and they both stripped very fairly and fought; the Prisoner received the first two falls, and the third fall they both fell together, and the Prisoner had rather the worst of it. Then the deceased said he would fight no more; I told the Prisoner that he would fight no more, then the Prisoner said I will go and shake hands with him, and he said, that he might and welcome - The deceased was sick and vomited: - He was carried home, and I did not see him afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-25-person228">
                  Daniel 
                  Slann 
               <interp inst="t17440912-25-person228" type="surname" value="Slann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person228" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner came with a bit of victuals in his hand, pretty near to the place where the deceased was sitting, and said, he was very much tired. The deceased made answer and said, how could he be tired, for his work was but play; and the Prisoner said it was hard work, for he had carried a thousand and a half of bricks two story high that day. They contradicted one another, and the Prisoner gave the deceased the lie, and the deceased said if he gave him the lie again, he would hit him a slap on the face: and the other said if he did, he would return it. After that they talked of laying a wager about fighting, and then they went to fighting by consent: they had three falls, and the third fall they both fell down together sideways, and the Prisoner had rather the worst of it - I don't know any thing of any wound he received - He went home and died in about an hour afterwards. The Churchwarden said the Coroner obliged him to prosecute, and I appear for the parish.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-25-person229">
                  Edmund 
                  Kelleck 
               <interp inst="t17440912-25-person229" type="surname" value="Kelleck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person229" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I live in Great Russel-Street; I was sent for to the deceased three days after he was dead to open the body, and found a vast quantity of blood in the cavity of the abdomen, which I believe proceeded from an eruption of one of the blood vessels, for there were no wounds upon him; and this must from the shock of the fall: there was one of the capital vessels in the cavity of the abdomen, and the body was quite in a diseased state before this accident. I opened the skull in order to see if there was any contusion upon the brain, but found it clear and safe. One lobe of the lungs was quite adhered to the pleura and was quite emaciated (but that was not occasioned by this fall) and there was a little adhesion of the other lobe, but not like that. <rs id="t17440912-25-verdict131" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-25-verdict131" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> of the murder, and also on the Coroner's inquest.</p>
            </div1>
