<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-39">
               <interp inst="t17400416-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-39" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-39" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-39-off233-c267" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-39-defend347 t17400416-39-off233 t17400416-39-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>232. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-defend347" type="defendantName">
                     Alexander 
                     Lambley 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-39-defend347" type="surname" value="Lambley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-defend347" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-defend347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400416-39-defloc232">St James's Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-39-defloc232" type="placeName" value="St James's Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-39-defloc232" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-39-defend347 t17400416-39-defloc232"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-39-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously and traiterously forging, counterfeiting and coining, 4 Pieces of false and feigned Money, to the likeness of the good and lawful Coin, called Shillings
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17400416-39-cd234" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-39-off233 t17400416-39-cd234"></join>, against the Form of the Statute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person348">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person348" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person348" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the Prisoner above two Years. My Aunt (Ursuld Harris) kept a Chandler's-shop, in Tooley-Street, and he used to come to her House. The first Time he came was with one 
               <persName id="t17400416-39-person349">
                  William 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person349" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person349" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Butcher, but both he and my Aunt are dead. We then sold Drams, and they had a Dram a-piece, and paid 3 d. in Copper. After this he came several Times, and I being a single Woman, and he a single Man, he frequently came to the House, to see me.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you ever see him at Wood's-Close.</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes; after he had been at our House, we grew intimate, and he fetched me there. I have been there several Times within this Year and a half. But after I had been there once or twice, I saw he had a Wife, and then I went to visit his Wife, and have seen him sell this false Money.</p>
               <p>Couns. Have you ever seen him do any thing to it?</p>
               <p>Harris. I saw him put a Shilling between a Piece of Paper into a Hand-vice, at Wood's-Close, and rub round the Edges, with a three-square-file; but I don't know what condition it was in, before he rubbed it with the File, nor what he did to it afterwards. The second Shilling I saw was one which he offered to my Aunt; but she looked at it, and gave it him again, telling him it was not a good one. He made a Laugh of it, and after he had rubbed it with some Powder, between his Finger and Thumb, he tossed it down on the counter and said, who would dispute that Shilling was not a good one. It looked like Lead before he had rubbed it, but afterwards it appeared like Silver. He afterwards told me, I might get a good Living, if I would dispose of such Shillings, and that he would give me 3 or 4 of them for a Shilling; but I never had any from him to dispose of. He said, if he could not get 100 £. a Year he could not live, and I might get a good Livelihood too if I would dispose of such Shillings. I never saw him rub or file them except once: but several Times when he has been at our House, he has appeared in a Hurry, and has said, he must go and put off his Tom Tits, and has thrown down a Piece of the Money on the counter, and said, - 'tis as good a King William and Queen Mary as ever was coined. He pretended to be Hog-Butcher, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160040"></xptr>when I went to his House, I found very good Entertainment for Trades-people. He lodged up one Pair of Stairs, at a Widow's House, in Wood's-Close, but I don't know her Name.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you ever see him put off this Money to any Body?</p>
               <p>Harris. I have seen him give People three or four of these Pieces, as I have thought, and they have given him a Shilling for them. I have seen him three several Times give three for a Shilling: but I cannot tell who the Persons were that took them, nor did I mind what the Prisoner said, when he sold them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When you was taken up you did not know your own Mother. Pray what House do I live in?</p>
               <p>Harris. Between the Alehouse and the Barber's Shop, in Wood's-Close.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Tell me whereabouts in the Room is the Fire-place: where my Bed stands, and what Sort of a Woman my Wife is?</p>
               <p>Harris. The Fire-place is on the farther Side of the Room; the Bed may have been moved since I saw it, but his Wife is a little Woman, shorter than I am, and has a young Child.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How come you to be perswaded to come and give Evidence now, when last sessions you would not appear?</p>
               <p>Harris. I did not know the Consequence. - I have had no Perswasions, nor any Money?</p>
               <p>Couns. He would have it understood, that you don't know where he lodg'd: Did not you carry the Persons who have the Charge of the Prosecution to the House?</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes; and I knocked at the Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw her in my Life, before this Morning.</p>
               <p>Harris. I know him, and have been at his House several Times.</p>
               <p>Couns. Can you recollect what Time it was, when you saw the Prisoner put the Shilling into the Hand-vice?</p>
               <p>Harris. No; - it was about a Twelvemonth ago, at Wood's-Close: and it was about a Quarter of a Year before that Time, when I saw him rub the Shilling at my Aunt's in Tooley-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person350">
                  Christopher 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person350" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person350" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner between two and three Years, -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am informed that Man has been in the Pillory for Perjury, and a Conspiracy against Drinkwater. He was convicted here two or three Years ago.</p>
               <p>Brown. I became acquainted with the Prisoner, by drinking with him at a Publick-house in Wood's-Close. I once saw him sell three or four of those Pieces for a Shilling, and have heard him say, if he could not get a Hundred a Year, he could not maintain his Family. And when some of the Shillings have looked like Lead, I have seen him rub them over with something white, and make them look like Silver. I can't take on me to say they were such Pieces (before they were rubb'd) as are here in Court, but I have seen him rub them between his Finger and Thumb; after which he has shewn them upon the Table, and said they look'd like Silver. And they have looked like King William and Queen Mary's Shillings. Those which I have seen upon the Prisoner, have not been so rough as these I see now.</p>
               <p>Couns. What Business did he say he followed?</p>
               <p>Brown. He told me he was a Horse-Jockey; and afterwards he said he was a Dealer in Hogs, and another Time he was a Polisher of Glass. I have seen him have Horses in Ward's Rents, near Hockley in the Hole, where he had a House of his own, since Michaelmas last; after he removed from Wood's-Close. I can't say what Business he did in that House, but he said, - provided there were Molds, or Money found there, it could not be proved that he put them there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17400416-39-person351">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person351" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Brown. I don't know any such Man. - O! I believe he is a Clogmaker; but I never saw him with the Prisoner in my Life; nor have I ever had any Talk with Clark, about the Prisoner, nor about this Prosecution: but Clark's Character is very dull, if Clark comes to that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Have not I told the Truth about your having stood in the Pillory?</p>
               <p>Brown. I have nothing to say to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person352">
                  John 
                  Cart 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person352" type="surname" value="Cart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Wood's-Close, and am a Carpenter. On the 21st of June, as I was pulling down the House of Office, where the Prisoner lodged, I found this Bag of counterfeit Money, under the Seat. There were fourscore and four Shillings concealed upon a Board; where they could not be seen, though searched for with a candle; and could only be found, by putting a Hand thro' the Hole, and turning it under the Seat. I know the Prisoner lodged in that House, and continued there a Quarter of a Year after this Thing was rumoured about, and talked of.</p>
               <p>Harris. The Piece I saw him rub with a File in the Hand-vice, was like these, but I can't swear to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person353">
                  Jane 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person353" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person353" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lodged in my House in Wood's-Close, about a Year and three Quarters: and I know there was a Parcel of bad Money found<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160041"></xptr>in the Vault, but I don't know who put it there. When he lived with me, he behaved civilly, and paid me my Rent, in good Money. When he came first to my House, he dealt in Horses; I don't know what Business he followed afterwards. I know there was bad Money found in the Vault that he used to go to, as well as the rest of the Lodgers. - I never saw any bad Money upon him, but I never go into my Lodgers Rooms; I was not fix Times in the Room while he was in it, so I can't tell what he did there. He lodged in my House when the Money was found; I suspected him, and gave him warning two or three Days after it was discovered, and I think he went away a Month before Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>Couns. Had you any other Lodgers in the House at that Time?</p>
               <p>Watson. No; none but the Prisoner and his Wife, and an old Gentlewoman who boards with me. There had no other Person lodged in the House, for a quarter of a Year before the Money was found. - The Vault only belongs to our House, and none but our own People can go to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person354">
                  John 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person354" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person354" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I keep a Coffee-House in Well-Court, in Queen-Street. I have seen the Prisoner before; and believe he is the same Person who came twice to our House, and changed a Shilling each Time, to pay for what he had, and we found a bad Shilling both Times in the Drawer after he was gone. The third Time he came was last December was 12 Months, and he then changed a good Six-pence to pay for a Dish of Coffee, and went out! In half an Hour he returned again, and called for a Glass of Ale, and some Tobacco, after which he offered my Wife a bad Shilling; she told him, it was not a good one; but before I could get to the Bar, he had snatched it up, and had laid down a good one. I told him, he was a vile Fellow, and that this was the third Time he had served me so. The Gentlemen in the House said, I ought to secure him; upon which he fled for it, and got 100 Yards from the House, but I pursued him, and tho' he resisted, I took him, and asked him, what need had he to change a Shilling, when he had changed Six-pence but ++ of an Hour before? He said he had no Half-pence, but when the Constable came we searched him, and found fifteen or 16 good Shillings upon him; one bad one; and about three Shillings in Half-pence, more than he had received from us in change. He then offered to spend a Crown in the House, if I would let him go; I refused to discharge him, and carried him before Mr Alderman Perry, and produced the bad Shilling we found upon him, but not being able to swear it was the same identical Shilling, which he had offered in Payment, he was discharged.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did the bad Shilling which you found upon him, tally with the other two you had taken before?</p>
               <p>Mr Blackwell. Yes; so very exactly and minutely, that several Gentlemen in the Room were of Opinion, they were all made in the same Mold. That which I found upon him was broke, that it might go no farther, - it was a King William's, and the Date was 1696.</p>
               <p>Couns. These now produced are King William's, 1696.</p>
               <p>Harris. I can't tell what Impression was on the Piece which I saw him put into the Hand-vice: nor can I tell whether the Edges were smooth before he filed them. He did not let me see that Piece. That which I saw him rub between his Fingers, he tossed down, and said, there's as good a King William's and Queen Mary's, as ever was coined: and I saw something of a Head upon that, I am certain: but it did not found like good Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person355">
                  Samuel 
                  Etheridge 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person355" type="surname" value="Etheridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person355" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Mr Blackwell's Evidence, and added, that he went to the Prisoner in Gaol, and asked him, if he had ever been at Blackwell's Coffee-House? To which the Prisoner answered, No; nor did he know where it was.</p>
               <p>Mr North deposed, That he having secured one 
               <persName id="t17400416-39-person356">
                  Thomas 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person356" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person356" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . for uttering counterfeit Money. Brown, (a former Witness) sent for him to a Tavern, and told him, that the Prisoner (who had married Wood's Daughter) was one who counterfeited the Coin, and put it off. That he took the Prisoner upon this Information, and searched his House in Ward's Rout's, but found nothing, except some Powder in some little Holes and Corners of the House, which answered the Description of that which Brown said he had seen him rub the Shillings with. That the Prisoner had prevaricated in all the Answers to the Questions he put to him, and denied that he had ever been at Blackwell's Coffee-House in his Life.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner desired Mr North might be becaked, if he had not given Christopher Brown, otherwise Bawes, Money to appear against him? Mr North answered, that Brown was poor, and as he offered himself voluntarily, he had given a Shilling, now and then, - and sometimes 2 s. or half a Crown, once in a Week, or a Fortnight: and that he once gave Harris three Shillings.</p>
               <p>Harris deposed, that that Money was not given her to swear against the 
Prisoner.</p>


               <p>Mr North added, that before last sessions, sBrown went away from his Lodgings, and he knew not where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160042"></xptr>to find either him, or Harris, when he wanted their Testimony. But that one Serjeant came afterwards to him, and told him, if he would make it worth his while, he (Serjeant) would help him to Brown and Harris. That to induce Serjeant to discover where these People might be found, he offered him a Guinea, and upon Serjeant's telling him they were afraid to see him, because they had had some Money from him, he gave him a Note, in which he promised not to give them any Trouble on that Account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person357">
                  Robert 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person357" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person357" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he went with Harris to the Prisoner's House, and had Orders to take particular Notice, whether she knew it. That he walked before her, and went past the House, but she called him back, and shewed it him.</p>
               <p>Jury to Watson the Landlady. Have you seen Harris come to your House after the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Watson. I don't remember her: but I did not mind who came after him.</p>
               <p>Jury to Brown. Is Brown your true Name?</p>
               <p>Brown. Yes; my Name is 
               <persName id="t17400416-39-person358">
                  Christopher 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person358" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person358" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I have not gone by any other Name for some Years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you charged with a Conspiracy by the Name of Bews?</p>
               <p>Brown. I was charged with a Conspiracy against Drinkwater, by a Person whom I never saw in my Life. I was indicted by the Name of Baws, and not Bews.</p>
               <p>* See January Sessions, 1737.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-39-person359">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17400416-39-person359" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person359" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Bews, he lived in the same House with me, and went by that Name, as well as by Brown. About Christmas last he came to me, and said, there is a Man in the Counter for counterfeiting the Coin, and you may do a Thing which won't hurt you, and you may get 40 £. in your Pocket. If you'll go along with me, I'll shew you the Man, and the House where he lived, that you may be the more positive: and if you'll do this you may be relieved, till his Trial comes on. - I was to swear I saw him counterfeit the King's Coin. I never saw the Prisoner, till about two Hours ago, I was going to buy two Shilling's worth of Velvet to make Cloggs, and Mr Serjeant told me, the Prisoner was to be tried to Day, and that it would be of Service to him to come here; so I came voluntarily.</p>
               <p>Brown. This Fellow sends his Wife out a-whoring for Six-pence a Night, and it is the only Way of living he has.</p>
               <p>Mr Pankerman gave an Account that the Prisoner worked with him as a <rs id="t17400416-39-deflabel235" type="occupation">Distiller</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-39-defend347 t17400416-39-deflabel235"></join> about the Time of the Date of the Prosecution, and had lived with him half a Year before. That he had worked with him at Times, for seven Years past, but had left him in July last. That he found him honest while he lived with him, but knew nothing of him since July. He added, that he believed the Prisoner had kept Hogs and Horses too, and that the Prisoner's Father was an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Mrs Vanderesh, Mrs Triam, Mrs Weaver, and Mrs Barker, gave the Prisoner a good Character. <rs id="t17400416-39-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-39-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
