<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-62">
               <interp inst="t17441205-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-62" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-62" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-62-off399-c673" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-defend819 t17441205-62-off399 t17441205-62-verdict402"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-62-off403-c673" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-defend819 t17441205-62-off403 t17441205-62-verdict402"></join>
         
               <p>107. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-62-defend819" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Hedley 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-62-defend819" type="surname" value="Hedley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-defend819" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-defend819" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17441205-62-defloc398">St. Mary, Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-62-defloc398" type="placeName" value="St. Mary, Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-62-defloc398" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-defend819 t17441205-62-defloc398"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17441205-62-off399" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-off399" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-off399" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441205-62-victim821" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Cliff 
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim821" type="surname" value="Cliff"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim821" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim821" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain alley, or open place, near the King's highway, putting her in fear, and taking from her a pair of stays, value 6 s. a cambrick cap, value 6 d. a cambrick handkerchief, value 12 d. and an apron, value 6 d. the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17441205-62-person822">
                        Mary 
                        Cliff 
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person822" type="surname" value="Cliff"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-person822" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-person822" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-62-cd400" type="crimeDate">Nov. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off399 t17441205-62-cd400"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off403 t17441205-62-cd400"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-62-person823">
                  Mary 
                  Cliff 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person823" type="surname" value="Cliff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person823" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person823" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am almost sixteen years of age; I live with Mr. Lud, a bricklayer, by Oxford Market; the Prisoner is a chairwoman's daughter just by, [she is about seventeen years old] I went to see her, and she said, Polly, will you go with me to see my cousins; there are three young misses, and they want three young girls to wait upon them; and you shall ride in a coach every day, and have every thing you want? So Betty Brotherton and I went with her. She took us into Rag-fair. I asked where her cousins lived. She said, they are gone to h - ll, to cry brooms. She took me up an alley, and said, D - n you, you b - h, pull your stays off. I won't want while there's any thing to make money of. And because they did not come off easily, she broke the lace. She said, if I cried out, she would run her fist down my throat. And she sold my stays for three shillings and six-pence - I had not a farthing of the money. The other girl [Brotherton] had five shillings of what she sold her things for. The Prisoner took me to a two-penny lodging in <placeName id="t17441205-62-crimeloc401">Church-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-62-crimeloc401" type="placeName" value="Church-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-62-crimeloc401" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off399 t17441205-62-crimeloc401"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off403 t17441205-62-crimeloc401"></join> by Ragfair; we had bread and butter and strong beer for supper, and I staid with her all night, and sat upon the bed crying, and she said, D - n you, you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050058"></xptr> sniveling b - h, come to bed. The next day we went to Oxford Market, and I was afraid of going home for fear of being beat. She wanted us to go to Mary-le-bon bason, and said, if she had got us there, we should not have told who hurt us. - She sold the stays and things in Rag-fair, and she would not let us go into the shop. She said, D - n you, stay out - We were afraid to cry out, that she had robbed us - I never went out with her. before. We met Mr. Ankers as we were going home; and when she saw him, she said, G - d d - n you, we are all caught. I said, Mr. Ankers what shall I do. And he said, I should go to Mrs. Brotherton's, and she should beg for me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We had tea and bread and butter for breakfast, and she came to me in the morning when I was in bed, and said she would go to the Buoy in the Nore to see her brother. 
               <persName id="t17441205-62-person824">
                  Betty 
                  Brotherton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person824" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person824" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person824" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said she was sick, and must pull her stays off. I said I would not pull mine off, but she pulled hers off, and sold them, and we had wine and strong beer at supper.</p>
               <p>Cliff. I had no wine, nor 
               <persName id="t17441205-62-person825">
                  Betty 
                  Brotherton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person825" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person825" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person825" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             neither.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We had two bottles of wine. What made you sick?</p>
               <p>Cliff. I was not sick at all. The Prisoner said to 
               <persName id="t17441205-62-person826">
                  Betty 
                  Brotherton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person826" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person826" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person826" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , D - n you, if you don't sell your ear-rings, I will get a Constable, and send you home to your mother, and have you well slogged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-62-person827">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brotherton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person827" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person827" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person827" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am coming into my 13th year; Cliff and I were going out, and the Prisoner would have us go with her to her cousins, who, she said, kept their coach: and she said, D - n you, it does not signify talking, for you shall go. When she went she could not find her cousins. I asked her where they were. She said, Oh d - n them, they are gone to h - ll to sell brooms. She took me up a passage, and said, I must strip; and before I could get my stays off, she tore them open. - I was not sick then, I was sick afterwards at a house she carried me to. Then she took my gold bobs - she had the money for them: she said, she had sold my stays for a shilling. What, in the name of G - d, said I, did you sell my stays? She said, I must have more than your stays; I must have your ear-rings. She hit me a blow on the stomach, and said, she would send me to h - ll: and she said, If you don't let me have them, I'll get a porter, and send you where you shall never be heard of - I had no wine; the Prisoner had wine, and a rabbit, a French cook frigafeed it - I did not taste it, I had nothing but a bit of bread and butter. I sat crying, and she called me, Snivelling b - h. There was a long bottle brought with white wine, and another with red; she sat by herself, and we sat behind the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she tell you, if you sold your things, she would acquaint your mother with it?</p>
               <p>Brotherton. No, indeed; she was going to kill us once, and there came a hog along, she thought it was a man coming, and she run away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you the money the things were sold for?</p>
               <p>Brotherton. She gave me a crown, and said, here d - n you, take this, and put it into your pocket, and don't look like a fool; said I, what shall I do for my stays? She took 3 s. from me again, then I had a groat left and she took that away from me at last - we took the prisoner the next day but one at her mother's.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ankers. I live in the house with 
               <persName id="t17441205-62-person828">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brotherton 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person828" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person828" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person828" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (the friends of the two girls had been under some uneasiness about them.) Just by Great Marlborough-street there did I meet these three creatures draggled in mud. and in a miserable condition; the prisoner made off, and said, by G - d the fault shall not all lye upon me, they shall have part as well as myself; she had her cloaths on as she had when she went out, but the others were stripped - they had their caps on.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That man knows nothing of it, there's nobody knows any thing of it but the two girls and I.</p>
               <p>A person who happened accidentally to be in court, said he saw the two girls [Cliff and Brotherton] without Aldgate as drunk as they could be, rolling and tumbling in the channel. <rs id="t17441205-62-verdict402" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-verdict402" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>+ 
               <persName id="t17441205-62-person829">
                  Ann 
                  Hedley 
               <interp inst="t17441205-62-person829" type="surname" value="Hedley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person829" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-person829" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was also indicted for <rs id="t17441205-62-off403" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-off403" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-off403" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441205-62-victim831" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Brotherton 
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim831" type="surname" value="Brotherton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim831" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-62-victim831" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , of a pair of stays, value 2 s. an apron, value 18 d. and a pair of gold ear-rings, value 5 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17441205-62-cd404" type="crimeDate">November 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off399 t17441205-62-cd404"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-62-off403 t17441205-62-cd404"></join>. <rs id="t17441205-62-verdict405" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-62-verdict405" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
