<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-28">
               <interp inst="t17470429-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-28" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-28" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-28-off114-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-28-defend246 t17470429-28-off114 t17470429-28-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>208. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-28-defend246" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     HUNTER 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-28-defend246" type="surname" value="HUNTER"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-defend246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-defend246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17470429-28-off114" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-off114" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-off114" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               that he, not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, but being moved by the Instigation of the Devil, on the <rs id="t17470429-28-cd115" type="crimeDate">20th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-28-off114 t17470429-28-cd115"></join>, in and upon the Body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470429-28-victim248" type="victimName">
                           Grace 
                           Pitts 
                        <interp inst="t17470429-28-victim248" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-28-victim248" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-28-victim248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-28-off114 t17470429-28-victim248"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , feloniously did make an Assault, wickedly ravish, and carnally know and abuse, against the Form of the Statute in that Case made and provided
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Please your Lordship, and you, Gentlemen of the Jury , I am of Council in this Cause for the Crown, and you will see the strongest Reasons to support this Prosecution; it is for a wicked Fact charged upon the Prisoner, a Rape upon the Body of 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person249">
                  Grace 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person249" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person249" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17470429-28-viclabel116" type="occupation">Child</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-28-victim248 t17470429-28-viclabel116"></join> of ten Years of Age. As I am Council for the Crown, perhaps you will expect from me a particular Detail of these Facts, from the Circumstances of the Evidence, we shall infer to you the Heinousness of the Offence, and the Necessity , for the Sake of Justice, to find him guilty.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, in the first Place, the Evidence that must be laid before you, is of such a Nature (in order to enable you to give your Verdict) that it is absolutely necessary it should be publickly given, but Decency requires it should not be publickly repeated no oftner than is necessary; you must hear it from the Mouth of the Witnesses. In capital Cases of this Kind, as the Law now stands, Prisoner have no Right to the Assistance of Council in making their Defence, which indeed I have thought something hard .</p>
               <p>But, Gentleman, if any Matter of Law should arise, the Prisoner will be indulged to defend himself by Council.</p>
               <p>I am sorry to say to you, that the Prisoner at the Bar, and the poor miserable little Wretch, the Subject of his Abuse, this Fact, wicked as it is, will not only be proved to you with all the blackest Circumstances, but we shall prove that the Prisoner was guilty in Point of Law as well as Conscience . To the Witnesses I shall leave the whole Matter; by his own Actions, let the Prisoner stand or fall. Gentlemen, I trust you will do all that the Prosecutors desire, that is, Justice.</p>
               <p>Council to 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person250">
                  Hannah 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person250" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person250" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . You know 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person251">
                  Grace 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person251" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person251" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , she lives with you, don't she?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. Give an Account how you came to suspect something ill had been done to her?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. By her Linen.</p>
               <p>Council. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Last Thursday, her Linen led me to enquire how it came.</p>
               <p>Council. You examined her?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you find the Girl greatly disordered.</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir, she did not know how to walk.</p>
               <p>Council. You say there was something upon her Linen, what did you apprehend?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I thought the Child had a Running.</p>
               <p>Council. Does that Disorder continue upon the Child still?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. Was you present when the Prisoner was taken up?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir, and he said she often use to be asking for Half-pence , and he did not think there was any Hurt in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a Child is it in it's Behaviour?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. A decent well behaved Child.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the Child?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. The Child was ten Years old last St Thomas's Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure this Child was in a good State of Health? Was there no natural Disorder ?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290023"></xptr>Council for the Prisoner. You must prove Force and Violence in this Case in a Person above ten Years of Age. I beg Leave to ask a few Questions in relation to this Child. I think this young Man lived at the Three Tuns in Bow-street , which leads to the Sanctuary , and your House joined next Door to the Passage. I think you said this Child had lived with you almost three Years. How long had this young Man lived at this House?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson I don't know.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you before suspect this Man's doing any thing to the Child? Has not this Child frequently gone with Messages? Has not this Child frequently gone on Errands for you to this a Man and to the Maid-servants?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson . She went to this House, where the Man lived, now and then, as a Neighbour might for any thing.</p>
               <p>Council. Now, Mistress, I would beg Leave to ask you (the first Time that you had any Intimation of this thing, was from the Linen of the Girl) did you ever, at any Time before that, find any thing ail her Linen?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I did not suspect it to arise from a Strain.</p>
               <p>Council. Have you never seen Linen coloured in the same Way, happen from a Strain?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, never in my Life.</p>
               <p>Council. But have you seen Linen of that Colour before?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I never did.</p>
               <p>Council . I would adventure to ask you, Mistress, upon this, when you was with the Girl ; I believe on Friday last; I think you went before the Justice. When you went before the Justice of Peace, was there a Complaint that the Girl actually was ravished, or only an Assault, with an Attempt to commit a Rape?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. A Rape, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the Surgeon examined the Child?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir, and he said the Child was very bad, and the Fellow had used her very ill; he said he ought to be hanged.</p>
               <p>Council. So the Justice committed this young Man?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this Fact committed?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. About a Fortnight or three Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any Complaint to you before you found it out by her Linen?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. I object to this Child being admitted an Evidence; there was a Man indicted for robbing the Mail in the County of Surrey, and a Boy was produced of 12 Years of Age, and he was rejected entirely as an Evidence. As this is a Case of such a Nature, as will affect Life, a Person indicted therefore, is liable to so high a Punishment, that your Lordship will hardly, in a Case of this Nature, admit this Child to be an Evidence. There was a Case about eight or nine Years ago that happened in the County of Surrey; a Person was produced there of eleven Years of Age, to prove a Rape on her Body, and the Judge refused her.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. If Mr. Dawson can set aside such an Evidence, his Client, and all such, will be highly obliged to him; Without their Evidence being admitted. how is such a Crime to be proved? Can it be expected when a Man goes about such an Act, he calls Witnesses? With Regard to what Mr Dawson mentions, what may occasion that, may be that, when Persons are under Examination, with Regard to the Nature of an Oath, and have been totally ignorant; but not only in this Place, but Children every Day are admitted; this Child was ten Years old last St. Thomas's Day.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Mr. Potter has given no direct Answer to what I mentioned; that is, the Case of Miller, indicted for robbing the Mail, that a Boy was the only Witness in that Case, and not admitted. Mr. Potter says, if the Child is not admitted, how can such Facts be proved? In the Three Tun Tavern , if the Child had cried out, from the Alarm of a thing of that Kind, there might have been twenty other Persons to have been Witness of this Kind.</p>
               <p>Court to 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person252">
                  Grace 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person252" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person252" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know what taking an Oath is? Do you know what swearing is? Do you know what will be done to you, if you swear false?</p>
               <p>Pitts. God Almighty will hate me if I give a false Oath.</p>
               <p>[The Child was admitted an Evidence .]</p>
               <p>Council to 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person253">
                  Grace 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person253" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person253" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Give an Account of what he did to you; What did he do to you, Child?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I went to speak with one of the Maids, but none of them were at Home; and he said if I would go into the Back Room, he would give me an Orange, I did not think he would hurt me; when I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290024"></xptr> went in, he shut the Door and used me ill; he set himself down in the Chair, and pulled something out of his Breeches , and pulled me to him.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you feel any thing particular?</p>
               <p>Pitts . It felt st - ff .</p>
               <p>Council. Did it hurt you?</p>
               <p>Pitts . I said it hurt me sadly; he would not let me alone; I said if he did not let me alone, I would cry Murder.</p>
               <p>Council. How came you not to cry out?</p>
               <p>Pitts . Because he threatened me, and I was afraid.</p>
               <p>Council. Upon your Oath, as you desire that God should love or hate you, did it hurt you?</p>
               <p>Pitts . Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel any thing particular about the Time that it was there?</p>
               <p>Pitts. There was wet just as he was about to take it out; there was something wet, I felt it, and some of it went into me, and some of it I saw afterwards upon the Ground; it was in me a little way, but a very little way.</p>
               <p>Council. Was, or was you not, hurt by it?</p>
               <p>Pitts. It hurt me all the Time.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. What Day of the Week was that?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Council. Can't you tell what Day of Week, or Day of the Month it was?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I cannot tell, but I believe it was about the latter End of the Week.</p>
               <p>Council. How long ago was this?</p>
               <p>Pitts. About a Fortnight or three Weeks.</p>
               <p>Council. When you went into the Three Tuns , where was it that you saw this Man?</p>
               <p>Pitts. In one of the Fore Rooms.</p>
               <p>Council. Where was you at that Time?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I went into the House.</p>
               <p>Council. Was you in another Room when you first saw him? you say he called you to come to him.</p>
               <p>Pitts . He bid me come along with him, and he would give me an Orange; upon that I did go to him.</p>
               <p>Council . Did he give you the Orange?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes, he gave me the Orange, and bid me not tell that he gave me an Orange .</p>
               <p>Council . Did he say that he would do any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Pitts. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. You said he sat down upon the Chair?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes, Sir, and pulled me upon his Lap.</p>
               <p>Council. When he pulled you that to him, did not you cry out?</p>
               <p>Pitts. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. Did he not pull up your Coats?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes, Sir, and then I was frightened.</p>
               <p>Council. When he put something to you, did you not then cry out?</p>
               <p>Pitts. He said if I did he would do something else to me.</p>
               <p>Council. What was that he said he would do to you?</p>
               <p>Pitts. He did not say what.</p>
               <p>Council. So upon that you did not cry out?</p>
               <p>Pitts. No, Sir, I was afraid.</p>
               <p>Council. When he put it to you, did it hurt you a great deal, or only a little?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I told him it hurt me sadly; I told him I would get away from him, and he said I should not.</p>
               <p>Council. You say it hurt you a great deal; Was you sensible all this Time what he did to you? if you was not sensible, how could you tell that it hurt you?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I was sensible it hurt me, but was not sensible what it was .</p>
               <p>Council. When this thing was over, Child, where did you go to directly?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I went into the other Room till some Body knocked for me; I stayed some Time in the other Room.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you offer to cry out in the other Room?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I would have cried out, i f he had not threatened me so.</p>
               <p>Q. Now who was the Person that knocked for you?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Our House joined to this, and I could hear them; the knocking was from my Mistress's House that joined; I walked away home.</p>
               <p>Council. Who was the first that saw you when you came home?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Mrs. Wilkinson.</p>
               <p>Council. So you made no Complaint?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I told no Body, for I was afraid.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first Time you did tell it?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I never told.</p>
               <p>Council. She never said any thing till her Mistress taxed her with it .</p>
               <p>Mr. Dove, Surgeon.</p>
               <p>Council. Sir, have you examined this Child?</p>
               <p>Dove. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. What Condition did you find her in?</p>
               <p>Dove. She is in a bad Condition ; I find her Parts very much distended, much enlarged and soul .</p>
               <p>Council. Do you know any thing of the Prisoner's being disordered?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290025"></xptr>Dove. I don't know any thing of him.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. When did you examine this Child?</p>
               <p>Dove. Yesterday, about two o'Clock, but there is another Surgeon that did examine her before.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. I ask you whether you saw these Parts tore or lacerated?</p>
               <p>Dove. Not tore, but extended.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. May not the Extension of these Parts arise from other Accidents ? the Extension may be done by many things.</p>
               <p>Dove. She is not only extended, but prodigiously clapped too.</p>
               <p>Council. May not the Extension of these Parts arise from other Accidents, than to come by the use of Men.</p>
               <p>Dove. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council to - Holland. Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17470429-28-person254">
                  John 
                  Hunter 
               <interp inst="t17470429-28-person254" type="surname" value="Hunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , What Character does he bear, how long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Holland. I am a Brewer and Victualler; I have known the Prisoner four Years, ever since he came out of the Country, and he bears a very honest Character.</p>
               <p>Council. Is he a licentious lewd Sort of a Person?</p>
               <p>Holland. Not as I know of; he bears a very good Character as far as ever I heard of him; he lived a Servant with me almost a Year.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known him about two Years.</p>
               <p>Council. Does he bear the Character of a modest sober young Man?</p>
               <p>A Witness . I never heard a bad Word of him before this; he has gone to Church with my Children.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. To the Church or Mass ?</p>
               <p>A Witness. To Church.</p>
               <p>- Reynolds. I have known the Prisoner about three Years, he has the Character of a sober Man, I never heard any thing to the contrary .</p>
               <p>Q. to - Tull. How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tull. I have know the Prisoner for about three Years, his Character was good when he came to us, I was his Fellow Servant for two Years, during that Time he behaved soberly .</p>
               <p>[It was represented by the Court to the Jury, that the Child was but a very few Months out of the Statute of that Clause, in that Text which construes every Fact committed upon the Body of a Child, under ten Years old, whether by Force or Delusion, and Deceit, she is drawn in to have such a Fact committed upon her, 'tis all one; this Infant being a little above that Age, takes her out of that Clause of the Statute, which makes her Consent not necessary; consequently he is indicted now in the same Manner as he would have been in a Fact committed on a Woman of mature Age. There were these things hinted which constitute a Rape; in the first Place, a carnal Knowledge of the Body of a Person; and the next Place it must be by Force, and altogether without the Consent of the Person. Now Delusion and Deceit that is not Force, there is in some Measure the Consent of the Will. It was represented by the Court, what a wicked thing it was to be the Author of such a Delusion and Deceit, but yet that does not constitute a Rape. There were these two things that caused this Person guilty of such a stagitious Crime to escape; viz. her exceeding in Age by a few Months the limited Time specified in the Act of Parliament , and not being able to prove a direct Force upon the Child.]</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-28-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-28-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
