<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460117-42">
               <interp inst="t17460117-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-42" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-42" type="date" value="17460117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460117-42-off164-c542" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-42-defend615 t17460117-42-off164 t17460117-42-verdict168"></join>
         
               <p>82. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-defend615" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Dixon 
                  <interp inst="t17460117-42-defend615" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-defend615" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-defend615" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460117-42-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               shooting and wounding with a Gun
            </rs>, 
               
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-victim617" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Carter 
                  <interp inst="t17460117-42-victim617" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-victim617" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-victim617" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-42-off164 t17460117-42-victim617"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , a <rs id="t17460117-42-viclabel165" type="occupation">Child</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-42-victim617 t17460117-42-viclabel165"></join> of 13 Years of Age, <rs id="t17460117-42-cd166" type="crimeDate">December 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-42-off164 t17460117-42-cd166"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person618">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person618" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person618" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person619">
                  Susannah 
                  Eastland 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person619" type="surname" value="Eastland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person619" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person619" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know in relation to the Death of 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person620">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person620" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person620" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person620" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Eastland. I was coming down St. Martin's-Lane. The Prisoner at the Bar, my Lord, was coming before me. The deceas'd, 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person621">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person621" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person621" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person621" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , stood upon a pair of Cellar Steps, two Steps down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that near you?</p>
               <p>Eastland. Yes, my Lord. And the Child stood between him and me. The Child was about 13 Years of Age.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was it from you? And how far from the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Eastland. About half a Rod. The Prisoner turn'd round all of a sudden, and pointed his Gun, as I thought, to shoot at me. But whether or no, I cannot say. He went to discharge his Gun and it would not go off.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether he try'd to let it go off?</p>
               <p>Eastland. He levell'd it, and it would not go off. He pull'd Powder out of his Pocket and discharg'd the Gun immediately. I clapp'd up at the End of the Tavern, the Child was nearest, about half a Rod, as near as I can guess.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Child and you in the same Position?</p>
               <p>Eastland. I was in the Street, and the Child on the Cellar-Steps. The Cellar-Steps come into the Street. He discharg'd his Gun and the Child fell off the Steps direct ly. I saw him level his Piece, pointing it, as I thought, towards me.</p>
               <p>Q. So you thought the Gun was pointed at you?</p>
               <p>Eastland. He discharg'd the Gun and hit the Child, and the Deceas'd fell down the Cellar-Steps.</p>
               <p>Q. What follow'd after this?</p>
               <p>Eastland. I heard a great Outcry in the Cellar, and there were several there, and a great deal of Blood issued out of the Child's Breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he die directly?</p>
               <p>Eastland. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prisoner do after he had done the Mischief?</p>
               <p>Eastland. He put the Gun upon his Shoulder, and went up the Street as fast as he could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person622">
                  Peter 
                  Venderkee 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person622" type="surname" value="Venderkee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person622" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person622" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Foreigner.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174601170033"></xptr>The Court not understanding his broken English, he therefore spoke by an Interpreter.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when the Gun was discharged?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. He was at a Publick House. The <rs id="t17460117-42-deflabel167" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-42-defend615 t17460117-42-deflabel167"></join> standing in the Street, he saw him discharge his Gun.</p>
               <p>Q. Ask him how near he was to the Soldier when he saw him discharge his Gun?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. As near as that Door, ( pointing to the Door of the Court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Ask him whether he saw the Soldier when he was coming along ?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. He, the Prisoner, was just going to discharge his Gun, when this Man, the Witness, came, he was behind the Soldier.</p>
               <p>Q. Ask him whether he saw the Soldier before he did discharge his Gun?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. No. But it went off immediately as he saw him. He was firing into the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. Ask him if he saw the Boy?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. He did not see the Boy before the Gun went off.</p>
               <p>Q. How far behind the Soldier when the Gun went off ?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. Not quite so far as the Door of the Court. After the Gun was fired, he went to the Cellar and heard the Outcries.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the Soldier?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. After One o'Clock they brought the Soldier to the Publick House. And the People that brought him advised him, the Prisoner, to tell the Justice that the Affair happen'd by Accident.</p>
               <p>Q. Ask him whether he saw any Woman standing with her Back to the Tavern?</p>
               <p>Interpreter. No. But he saw the Man pointing his Gun to the Cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person623">
                  Thomas 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person623" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person623" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person623" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the Bar I follow'd from the End of New-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you any Relation to the Deceas'd?</p>
               <p>Carter. Yes. I am his Brother.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this Soldier before?</p>
               <p>Carter. Yes, he lodg'd in my Mother's House. He laid his Hand upon my Head, and said, he loved me, but hated my Brother, that he was a sulky old Dog, and he would shoot him directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was a sulky old Dog?</p>
               <p>Carter. My Brother. They us'd to call him the old Man. Then he put his Hand in his Pouch and took a Cartridge of Powder out and prim'd his Piece and fir'd it directly.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from your Mother's House?</p>
               <p>Carter. My Mother lives the next door to the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw him load his Gun and prime it, did you see your Brother?</p>
               <p>Carter. Yes, my Lord. He was two Steps down the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with his Gun, after he had prim'd it?</p>
               <p>Carter. After he had done, he levell'd it at my Brother and then put it upon his Shoulder and went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say nothing to him, when he talk'd so about your Brother?</p>
               <p>Carter. No. My Lord, not a Word.</p>
               <p>Q. And what happen'd after this ?</p>
               <p>Carter. Then, my Lord, I run to the Cellar and my Brother was full of Blood, and I dragg'd him to the middle of the Cellar.</p>

               <p>Q. What became of your Brother?</p>
               <p>Carter. He was carry'd to the Infirmary. And beliv'd 10 Days.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had this Soldier lodg'd at your Mother's?</p>
               <p>Carter. He lodg'd about a twelve Month, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you not surpris'd to hear him talk thus about your Brother?</p>
               <p>Carter. No, my Lord. I thought he had been about to flash his Gun, I did not think he was about to shoot.</p>
               <p>Council. While he lodg'd at your House, was he not frequently familiar with your Brother, playing with him. Do you remember at any Time, he made him a Present of a little Ivory-headed walking Stick.</p>
               <p>Carter. He gave it between us both, said, we were to toss up for it.</p>
               <p>Council. Pray did you not that Day beg some Powder yourself.</p>
               <p>Carter. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask the Boy, whether he did not ask me for a Cartridge of Powder as I was going in at the Door the same Day. The Question was put to the Boy, but he deny'd it.</p>
               <p>Susanah Hatton. My Lord, the Child stood up on my Cellar-Stairs. I had his little Sister in my Lap below. He, the Deceas'd, came down for his Sister, to come up to Dinner, and the Child would not come up with him, but the Deceas'd said, Day Day, upon the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Could any Body in the Street see the Child? Did you see the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hatton. No. I never saw him. When the Gun went off, the Child was frighten'd, and said, Dixon had done it; I fell into, that is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person624">
                  Mary 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person624" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person624" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person624" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot say that I saw it done. But my Child was kill'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174601170034"></xptr>Council. Did he not shew a great Regard to the Child?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person625">
                  Mary 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person625" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person625" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person625" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know that he, the Prisoner, had once an Antipathy to the Child about a Pail of Water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person626">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person626" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person626" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person627">
                  John 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person627" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person627" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person627" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon) Did you see this Boy in the Infirmary ?</p>
               <p>Barker. I saw him the 30th of December. I examin'd the Wound as soon as he came in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what had occasion'd the Wound?</p>
               <p>Barker. The Ball was not lodg'd in the Side, but went quite thro'. I put my Finger into the Wound, and found several Pieces of shatter'd Bone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Boy live or die?</p>
               <p>Barker. He languish'd about ten Days.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you believe was the Cause of his Death?</p>
               <p>Barker. The Wound that he receiv'd by the Ball, in his Side, was the Cause of his Death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person628">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person628" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person628" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person629">
                  Amelia 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person629" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person629" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person629" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Did you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ford. I know that he lov'd the Deceas'd entirely well. Last Quarter Day he paid the People 15 s. and gave the Deceas'd an Ivory-headed Cane, and mended their Shoes &amp;c.</p>
               <p>- Levet. Please you, my Lord. I saw the Lad, the Deceas'd, come to the Prisoner on the Parade, where we are paid, as near as I can remember, the Friday before Christmas-Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take Notice of the Boy, in regard to any Friendship he had for him?</p>
               <p>Levet. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you remember sending any Thing to him on Christmas-Day?</p>
               <p>Levet. The Prisoner's Wife sent them some Plum-Pudding. And I believe he would be far from doing any such Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person630">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person630" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person630" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-42-person631">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tyler 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person631" type="surname" value="Tyler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person631" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person631" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Tyler. All that I have to say is this. About a Fortnight before the Thing was done, the Prisoner brought the Deceas'd up Stairs, and bringing the Child up, his Shoes were unripp'd, Says he, George, the Man that mends your Shoes has not done you Justice, and when you want them mended, I will mend them for you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person632">
                  Alexander 
                  Cartridge 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person632" type="surname" value="Cartridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person632" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Said, he was a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person633">
                  John 
                  Blydon 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person633" type="surname" value="Blydon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person633" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner four or five Years. He is as good a natur'd Man as can be, and would go any where to serve his Friend. I do not believe that he intended the Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-42-person634">
                  Richard 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17460117-42-person634" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person634" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-person634" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to the Prisoner, he was always a quiet, harmless Man. <rs id="t17460117-42-verdict168" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-verdict168" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-42-verdict168" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
