<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450911-21">
               <interp inst="t17450911-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-21" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-21" type="date" value="17450911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-21-off103-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-21-defend203 t17450911-21-off103 t17450911-21-verdict105"></join>
         
               <p>321. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-defend203" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Locker 
                  <interp inst="t17450911-21-defend203" type="surname" value="Locker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-defend203" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-defend203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17450911-21-defloc102">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-21-defloc102" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-21-defloc102" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-21-defend203 t17450911-21-defloc102"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17450911-21-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               for assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450911-21-victim205" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Thompson 
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim205" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim205" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting her in fear, &amp;c. and taking from her two cambrick caps laced, val. 2 s. a cambrick handkerchief, val. 2 s. and a linen handkerchief, val. 3 d. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450911-21-victim207" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Buchannan 
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim207" type="surname" value="Buchannan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim207" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-21-victim207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17450911-21-cd104" type="crimeDate">Aug. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-21-off103 t17450911-21-cd104"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person208">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person208" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person208" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Saturday was seven-night, about ten o'clock at night. I was passing a little below Charing Cross; the Prisoner met me, and gave me a slap on the face, so that I could not see, and took my bundle from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose goods are they?</p>
               <p>Thompson. They are the goods of 
               <persName id="t17450911-21-person209">
                  Alexander 
                  Buchannan 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person209" type="surname" value="Buchannan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person209" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Charles Street, Westminster , my husband works with him. After the Prisoner had taken my bundle, I took hold of the Prisoner and called watch, and he would not come; then I called out murder, and he would not come, but in a little while he did come, and the Prisoner was secured.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these things in that bundle?</p>
               <p>Thompson. They were all in that bundle.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Pray Madam, did not I immediately charge you with the watch, for taking my hat off my head?</p>
               <p>Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person210">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person210" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person210" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Thompson) What are you?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I am a taylor's wife, and I take in washing, I live in Bedford Bury.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person211">
                  Lydia 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person211" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person211" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Thompson asked me to go with her to her husband who was at Westminster, as Mrs. Thompson was going along with the bundle under her arm, a parcel of young fellows came up, and the Prisoner came up to Mrs. Thompson.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in company with the rest?</p>
               <p>Blackwell. He was in company with them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do?</p>
               <p>Blackwell. Just below Charing Cross, he came up from those fellows, and gave Mrs. Thompson a slap on the face.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it pretty hard?</p>
               <p>Blackwell. I did not feel it; but it was hard to be sure, for she seemed to reel against me, and cried out watch, watch, Blackwell I am robbed; and she took hold of the Prisoner and held him fast, then the watch came, and he was secured.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the person?</p>
               <p>Blackwell. I am positive of it, and that he gave her the blow.</p>
               <p>Q. What light was there?</p>
               <p>Blackwell. It was quite moon light.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I do not know any thing of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person212">
                  Emanuel 
                  Prior 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person212" type="surname" value="Prior"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person212" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman of St. Martin's in the Fields; on Saturday was seven-night, there happened a little quarrel against my stand,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110014"></xptr> at last there was watch called; I went, there was the Prisoner and this gentlewoman [Thompson] he had hold of her hand I think, and she had hold of him, and I think she had his wig in her hand: she was for charging him, for assaulting her, and putting his hand against her belly: and he charged me with her for taking his ht. I strove to get him into the watch-house, but he was very resolute, and they did not to go into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. What he or she ?</p>
               <p>Prior. He was very willing to go, but she was not; and madam Thompson delivered the Prisoner's hat into my hand, but the wig was thrown into the street, and they wanted to make their escapes.</p>
               <p>Q. What the women?</p>
               <p>Prior. Yes , the women. The young lad finding they were gone, run after them again, and overtook them, and laid hold of them again, and called for my assistance to lay hold of them again, and I carried them back to the watch *. They never talked of losing these things at first, but when they were retaken, then they talked of this robbery and losing these things; then we carried them to the Round-house.</p>
               <p> * It is very strange that the constable nor any other of the Watchmen would appear; and it is to be hoped the character of this Watchman will be enquired into by the Gentlemen of the parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Who ordered you to carry them to the Round house?</p>
               <p>Prior. They had liberty to go home to their beds, and the boy was confined.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to be set at liberty, and the boy confined?</p>
               <p>Prior. Because they brought friends.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the boy to be committed?</p>
               <p>Prior. Why they swore very hard and very positive, and the boy had nothing to say for himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Prior. Yes, and I have known his father and mother there twenty years .</p>
               <p>Q. What does the boy do for his living?</p>
               <p>Prior. I do not know what he does.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person213">
                  Samuel 
                  Stafford 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person213" type="surname" value="Stafford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person213" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to the fact the Prisoner is charged with I know nothing of, but I have known his parents these sixteen years , they lodged at my house when the prisoner was about twelve years of age. His father is a very good taylor ; I never heard any thing of the boy that was unhandsome, but I never heard much of him since that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person214">
                  William 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person214" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person214" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about five years, and he is a very sober honest boy, I I never heard any thing amiss of him, he lives with his father [the boy is about eighteen years of age .]</p>
               <p>Q. What business is he ?</p>
               <p>Ford. He is a holder to a painter - his character is that of an honest industrious youth .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-21-person215">
                  Nicholas 
                  Hudson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-21-person215" type="surname" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person215" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner twelve or thirteen years; I never knew or heard but he was a very honest lad, and bore no other then a good character; I never knew he was inned to cheat or defraud any body. He lives with his father, and used to be employed by a pa.</p>
               <p>Jury. (to Mrs. Blackwell) After the boy had charged Mrs. Thompson, I desire to know whether she did go away or no, and he run after her ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Thompson made answer; Gentlemen, I was frightened with the slap that was given me on my face, and the woman that was with me said , I had better lose the thing than go to the Round-house , for I never was in trouble in my life ; and when I came to the Watch-house, the mob said , knock the Scotch bitch down; I was frightened, as I was with child; and Mrs. Blackwell said, you had better come back than lose your own life and the child's , if you lose your things.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go out of the Round-house?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I never was in the Round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the women make their escapes from the watch?</p>
               <p>Prior. Going to the Watch-house. <rs id="t17450911-21-verdict105" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-verdict105" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17450911-21-punish106" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-21-punish106" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-21-defend203 t17450911-21-punish106"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
