<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480526-22">
               <interp inst="t17480526-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-22" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-22" type="date" value="17480526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480526-22-off126-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-22-defend242 t17480526-22-off126 t17480526-22-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>286. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480526-22-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Alcomb 
                  <interp inst="t17480526-22-defend242" type="surname" value="Alcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-defend242" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-defend242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17480526-22-defloc125">St. Mary, White-chapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-22-defloc125" type="placeName" value="St. Mary, White-chapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-22-defloc125" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-22-defend242 t17480526-22-defloc125"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480526-22-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 7 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480526-22-victim244" type="victimName">
                           Joshua 
                           White 
                        <interp inst="t17480526-22-victim244" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-22-victim244" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-22-victim244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-22-off126 t17480526-22-victim244"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480526-22-cd127" type="crimeDate">May 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-22-off126 t17480526-22-cd127"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-22-person245">
                  Joshua 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17480526-22-person245" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person245" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17480526-22-person246">
                  Sarah 
                  Alcomb 
               <interp inst="t17480526-22-person246" type="surname" value="Alcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person246" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>White. No. But on Wednesday, the 18th of this instant I was coming from Westham, and this woman picked me up.</p>
               <p>Q. At what time?</p>
               <p>White. Between two and three in the morning, by Whitechapel Church.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by picking you up?</p>
               <p>White. That she said I must go home along with her.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you go home with her?</p>
               <p>White. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that?</p>
               <p>White. At the <placeName id="t17480526-22-crimeloc128">Green Dragon Inn Yard, by Whitechapel Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-22-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="Green Dragon Inn Yard, by Whitechapel Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-22-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-22-off126 t17480526-22-crimeloc128"></join>, and there was a person with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by a person, a man, or a woman?</p>
               <p>White. A woman; and the Prisoner said she wanted some beer, and the other woman went for it; in the mean time she got hold of my watch, as I was next her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sitting by her?</p>
               <p>White. No, we were standing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the other woman there then?</p>
               <p>White. No; she went for some beer, and she came back again, and said she could not get any, and in about five or six minutes, the Prisoner got hold of my watch again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she put her hand into your breeches?</p>
               <p>White. No, she put it into my coat pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your watch in your coat pocket when you went into the room?</p>
               <p>White. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174805260019"></xptr>Q. So when you was there, you pulled it out of your breeches and put it into your coat pocket?</p>
               <p>White. Yes, it was in my fob before, and she had almost got it out, so I put it into my coat pocket, and in about five minutes more she got it out; I got hold of her hand, and she called to the other woman to aid and assist her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she want the other woman to aid and assist her for?</p>
               <p>White. To take the watch out of her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not stand passive all the while, did you?</p>
               <p>White. No, we were talking all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What were you talking about?</p>
               <p>White. She asked me several questions, how I lived, &amp;c. I said she had got my watch, and desired to have it again; and she said she had it not. Presently her husband came into the room, and then I did not make any more disturbance about it.</p>
               <p>Q I don't find you made any disturbance before.</p>
               <p>White. None at all. I went two or three times afterwards the same day, and I enquired for her in the neighbourhood, and she was not to be found. I went the next day to the room where she lodged, and her husband was in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that in the room you was in before?</p>
               <p>White. They had moved their lodging, I got a warrant, and took the Prisoner's husband up, and asked, whether he knew where the watch was? he said he knew nothing at all about it, and desired me to be easy and favourable. I desired he would send for his wife, which he did; and before she came, I asked him whether he could give me any information about it? and if he did, it would be the better for him; and as I was going along, I met the Prisoner, and we all went to a publick house, and there I asked the Prisoner what she had done with the watch? she said she had borrowed 45 s. upon it. Then we went before a justice, and she declared, to him, that her husband was innocent of the fact, and swore so, and she said she was the person that took it, and borrowed the money upon it.</p>

               <p>Q. to White. You knew before that, that she had no hand in it?</p>
               <p>White. No, I did not, for it was in the dark.</p>
               <p>Q. So as to what you have said concerning her taking the watch out of your pocket, and bidding the other woman take it out of your hand; all this time you were in the dark?</p>
               <p>White. Yes.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bird. I am constable.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this matter?</p>
               <p>Bird. Mr. White brought me a warrant to take up 
               <persName id="t17480526-22-person247">
                  John 
                  Alcomb 
               <interp inst="t17480526-22-person247" type="surname" value="Alcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his wife, and I took him up, and we went to a publick-house , and the Prisoner came to clear her husband; and she said he was innocent of the affair, and owned herself to be guilty, and Mr. White said, that is your Prisoner; so I took her into custody, and waited an hour and a half before we went before a magistrate; she owned it at the publick-house , and before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she own before the justice?</p>
               <p>White. She owned she took the watch from me, and not her husband.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you in liquor?</p>
               <p>White. I was a little in liquor to be sure.</p>
               <p>Mr. Glegg. I went with 
               <persName id="t17480526-22-person248">
                  Joshua 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17480526-22-person248" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person248" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to Westham , and we staid there till one o'clock in the morning, and I kept him company till we came to Whitechapel Church, and then it wanted a quarter of an hour of three. This was on the Wednesday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Glegg . He was a little cherry-merry ; he came to me the next morning, and said he had lost his watch: we went to the house, and they were moved, and he offered the gentleman a crown if he would let him know where they were moved to; and we got the man, and he told us where his wife was at work; but telling her that her husband was in hold, she presently followed him, and told us that she took the watch, and that her husband was innocent.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I might say what I did not do, for I did not take it, and know nothing of its being gone; but in my fright I might say that I took it, because my husband was in trouble; but I don't know what I said in the fright, for I know myself to be innocent; it was the other woman that took it, and not I.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480526-22-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-22-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
