<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-4">
               <interp inst="t17420909-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-4" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-4" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-4-off17-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-defend55 t17420909-4-off17 t17420909-4-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>58. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Matth.ew 
                     Booney 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-4-defend55" type="surname" value="Booney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-defend55" type="given" value="Matth.ew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420909-4-defloc16">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-4-defloc16" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-4-defloc16" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-defend55 t17420909-4-defloc16"></join>, was <rs id="t17420909-4-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               indicted for that he, on the <rs id="t17420909-4-cd18" type="crimeDate">29th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-off17 t17420909-4-cd18"></join> last, on the King's Highway, in and upon one 
                     <persName id="t17420909-4-person56">
                        Abraham 
                        Goodwin 
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person56" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-4-person56" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did make an Assault, and put the said 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420909-4-victim58" type="victimName">
                           Abraham 
                           Goodwin 
                        <interp inst="t17420909-4-victim58" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-4-victim58" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-4-victim58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-off17 t17420909-4-victim58"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in Fear and Danger of his Life, and took from him a Watch, val. 5 l. 5 s. a Seal, val. 2 s. a Snuff-Box, val. 20 s. and 18 d. in Silver
            </rs>, the Property of the said 
               <persName id="t17420909-4-person59">
                  Abraham 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person59" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person59" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-person60">
                  Abraham 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person60" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person60" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday the 29th of April, between Ten and Eleven at Night, between Bow and the Alms-Houses at <placeName id="t17420909-4-crimeloc19">Mile Edd</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-4-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="Mile Edd"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-4-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-off17 t17420909-4-crimeloc19"></join> , (it was a fine Moon-shiney Night) I saw two Fellows standing upon the Causeway, on the Right-Hand Side of the Road, each of them had a Pistol in his Hand: They demanded what I had, I told them I would deliver all if they would use me well; the first thing I delivered was a Seal with a Coat of Arms, with a String, and this Case of a Watch; he said, Damn your Blood, what is become of the Guts? I said, Gentlemen, I had forgot it, and gave them that; then they took from me a Snuff-Box, 18 d. (and a Handkerchief, and some Half-pence, which is not in the Indictment) and they made off towards Bow, in the Middle of the Road. I being apprehensive of meeting with some Body else, said, Gentlemen, let me speak a Word to you, you have robbed me, give me a Word by which I may save myself, if I should meet with any Body else; said one of them, say I have spoke with the Captain , or the Carman, but I think it was the Carman. The Prisoner answers to the Heighth of the Person, and I believe him to be the Person, because I observed a Scar on the Right Side of his Cheek. Cavenagh was dressed in a 
               <persName id="t17420909-4-person61">
                  Brown 
                  Coat 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person61" type="surname" value="Coat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person61" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I verily believe Cavenagh to be one of them. As to Mooney. I could see the Scar better then than I can now, for his Beard was long and black.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Gentlemen, pray observe what he says, he says I had a black Beard, and I have no black Beard.</p>
               <p>Goodwin. His Beard was rather blacker than it is now.</p>
               <p>[
               <persName id="t17420909-4-person62">
                  William 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person62" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.]</p>
               <p>Court. Consider now you are admitted as a Witness , and take Care to speak nothing but what is strictly true.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-person63">
                  William 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person63" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person63" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I will, my Lord. - On the 29th of April last, the Prisoner at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17420909-4-person64">
                  John 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person64" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person64" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and myself, went towards Bow between Ten and Eleven at Night, when we came by the Sign of Why not beat Dragon, the Prisoner at the Bar and I went on, Martin said behind, and this Gentleman was walking in the Road Way; each of us had a Pistol in his Hand, and we demanded his Money: He delivered first the Out-side case of his Watch into Mooney's Hand, and Mooney gave it to me; I found it was not compleat, but only a Case, and I asked him for the Guts of it, he said, Gentlemen, I forgot it; I think he put his Hand into his Breeches and pulled it out: I took a Snuff-Box from him, and a Shilling and a Six-pence in Silver, and 1 d. and when he asked what he should say if he met any Body else, I bid him say he had met the Carman.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him how long he has been acquainted with me?</p>
               <p>Cavenagh. I came acquainted with him about April, by a Woman that bought stolen Goods. - The Watch was sold to a Man that kept an Alehouse.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Ask him why he did not swear against me in his first Information ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-person65">
                  William 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person65" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person65" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did mention him in my first Information; if you please to look into it you will find it, (the Information was read and it was found to be so). - *Lot Cavenagh is no Relation of mine.</p>
               <p>* The Person on whose Information the Prisoner was committed . See the Trials in Mr Alderman Perry's Mayoralty, No. 147, 148.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said his Father would spend a great deal of Money to take away my Life, and for the great Reward that is depending upon my Life. I came to London the Eleventh of May, and I was in a Fever, he passed for a Surgeon, and came to bleed me.</p>
               <p>Goodwin . I had the Watch from William Cavenagh's Father.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-person66">
                  Thomas 
                  Moone 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person66" type="surname" value="Moone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person66" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Joiner, the Prisoner wrought for me in Dublin , the 2d and 3d of May last; the 1st of May is a Day of Diversion among the Tradesmen, there is piping and dancing; I am positive to his working for me the 1st, 2d, and 3d of M ay.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-4-person67">
                  William 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person67" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person67" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Ask him if the Prisoner at the Bar is not his own Son?</p>
               <p>Moone . No: he is not my Son, I never knew his Mother in my Life, - he never passed for my Son.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090005"></xptr>Court. It is not customary to work on a Sunday, now the 2d of May proves by the Almanack to be on a Sunday .</p>
               <p>Moone. Yes sometimes it is , in making Coffins, and he did work for me in making Coffins . - I cannot tell which Day the Coffin was made. - I cannot tell who the Coffin was for, it was an Oak Coffin . - There was no Undertaker, I was Undertaker.</p>
               <p>Court. Did you supply the whole Funeral? -</p>
               <p>Moone. There was no other Funeral than making of a Coffin. - I found out he was in Goal, by some of his Countrymen; he did not write to me to come.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This 
               <persName id="t17420909-4-person68">
                  William 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17420909-4-person68" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person68" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said he had nothing against me, that there was nothing but what Lot Cavenagh had against me.</p>
               <p>Moone . I live at St Giles's, in one Gerrard Cavenagh's House. - I have been in London since Sunday was se'nnight. - I came from Dublin a Fortnight ago, for Debt. - a Debt about 10 or 11 l. - I am an Irishman.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That young Man said he was robbed by a Man in a light coloured Coat, and I have no such Coat.</p>
               <p>The Jury asked what Mr Goodwin was, because there is a Reward in this Case.</p>
               <p>Goodwin. I am Clerk to Mr Penny , an Attorney in New Broad street, my Father is a Woolstapler in Broad-street. <rs id="t17420909-4-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420909-4-punish21" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-4-punish21" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-4-defend55 t17420909-4-punish21"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
