<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440728-21">
               <interp inst="t17440728-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-21" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-21" type="date" value="17440728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440728-21-off124-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-defend301 t17440728-21-off124 t17440728-21-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>324. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-defend301" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17440728-21-defend301" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-defend301" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-defend301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17440728-21-off124" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-off124" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-off124" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two gowns, value 32 s. a velvet hood and pilgrim, value 10 s. three ells of silk, value 12 s. two tablecloths, value 6 s. a handkerchief, value 3 s. two ells of silk, value 18 d. one yard of holland, value 3 l. 6 d. a yard of cambrick, value 4 l. thirteen ells of linen, value 10 s. four ells of dowlas, five pair of sheets, &amp;c
            </rs>. the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-victim303" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Nicholls 
                  <interp inst="t17440728-21-victim303" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-victim303" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-victim303" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-off124 t17440728-21-victim303"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person304">
                  Mary 
                  Nicholls 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person304" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person304" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In April last I was sent to the Counter, and was there two days and two nights out of the spite of the clerk and the footman in the family where I was <rs id="t17440728-21-viclabel125" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-victim303 t17440728-21-viclabel125"></join>; there was a woman in the Counter which the Prisoner kept, and she asked me if I wanted a man to go of my errands. I asked him if he would go round among my friends for me, and he said he would (he said he was an attorney at law: ) I was sent from the Counter to Bridewell; he went along with me, and asked me 5 s. for going to my friends, and he did not go to any of them but two; then he said he was acquainted with the Sheriffs and Aldermen, and Mr. Lord Mayor, and under pretence of doing me great services he wanted money to treat them: he desired I would let him have the keys of my room (I have a room in <placeName id="t17440728-21-crimeloc126">Houndsditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-21-crimeloc126" type="placeName" value="Houndsditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440728-21-crimeloc126" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-off124 t17440728-21-crimeloc126"></join> ) to get some money. I had but 14 s. 6 d. in my box, and I let him have the key, and bid him bring the money, a cap, a handkerchief, and an apron, and he brought me but 2 s. a cap, a handkerchief, and an apron; he said he could find but 4 s. and he kept 2 s. for himself, for he said he wanted money. The matron of Bridewell asked me how I came to employ such a man , for he had not a good look, and bid me ask him (when he came again ) for the keys. I asked him for the keys, and what he had done with a half guinea I had there; he said he had not found the half guinea, but would bring me the keys. When I came to enquire after him, I found he was a runner at the Counter; when I was discharged I went to my lodging, and missing my things, I was surprized. I went to the Counter to enquire after him, and they said they did not know any thing of him, but one of the debtors said he was a rogue and a villain. He absconded about six weeks, and I could not hear any thing of him but by the help of the matron and my friends coming to me I was discharged; and one day as Mrs. Moyett and I were together, I saw Parker going up the Fleet Market, I took him by the shoulder, and said, Parker, how could you rob me (there was one Mrs. Stevens who lives with him ) he trembled very much, and said, I know I have robbed you - he said he had robbed me; we went into a publick house, and I got a constable, and had him before my Lord Mayor, and he owned then that he had wronged me, that he had pawned the things, and would make me easy in three or four days, but he had a fortnight's time given<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280018"></xptr> him, and did not do it then. He sent Mr. Goodall to me, and he gave me a note on the behalf of Parker , that he would get my things in a week's time, or he would produce two guineas; but I was informed the note was good for nothing. I got a search warrant, and found all the goods mentioned in the indictment at four pawnbrokers, one in Clare Market, one in Shoe Lane, one in Barbican, and the other in Houndsditch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person305">
                  Frances 
                  Moyett 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person305" type="surname" value="Moyett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person305" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mrs. Nicholls at the Ditch Side when she met with Parker (he gave himself the title of a Solicitor, but I found he was only a <rs id="t17440728-21-deflabel127" type="occupation">runner at the Counter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-defend301 t17440728-21-deflabel127"></join>) I took hold of him myself: and she took hold of him, and saw him sence in this manner - he wanted to hold her hands down, he trembled very much, and said, I have wronged her it is true, but I will make her any satisfaction whatsoever for her things. I kept hold of his arm, and would not let him go till I got into a house. We went into a house the corner of Fleet Lane, and he sat very quietly; Mrs. Nicholls said she would have me go and fetch a constable, I told her she had better go herself : while she was gone, I said to him, I wonder how you could use this woman so barbarously when she was in prison I told him there were five pair of sheets, and a great many other things; he said, I am sorry for it, I will make her any satisfaction; where is she gone? I believe she is gone to fetch a constable: I said at first I did not know, and afterwards I said, I did not know but she might. I asked him how much he thought they might be worth; he said he believed he had pawned them for about 40 s.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I said if I had injured her I would make her satisfaction.</p>
               <p>Moyett. He said he had wronged her, and that he would make her satisfaction for her things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person306">
                  Lawrence 
                  Ambrose 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person306" type="surname" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person306" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Nicholls was under my care at Bridewell, I saw her deliver the keys to the Prisoner, and she desired him to fetch her a cap, a handkerchief, and some money - I cannot tell how much money she ordered him to bring, but afterwards she told me it was fifteen shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver these keys to the Prisoner for any other purpose than to fetch these things and the money?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. For no other use.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person307">
                  John 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person307" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live at Mrs. Harvey's in Houndsditch , the Prisoner came to our shop about the 19th of April, and brought a gown, a napkin, and a tablecloth; he said he came from Mrs. Hickman over the way, and wanted 20 s. upon them: he said, I believe you may know the things, for Mrs. Hickman has brought them before, as she had done. I told him I would not lend so much upon them, I would lend him but 16 s. he went and brought another gown, and then I lent him 20 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him any orders or leave to pawn them?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. I never did indeed, he pretended he had a note from me to do it, but it was not my note.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person308">
                  Francis 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person308" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person308" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Barbican, the Prisoner pledged three ells of silk, a napkin, and a piece of new cloth at my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person309">
                  Abraham 
                  Bibby 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person309" type="surname" value="Bibby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person309" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Stanhope Street, Clare Market, I took in these from the Prisoner, the mob and velvet hood were pawned by the Prisoner and another, the pilgrim and cap were pawned by the Prisoner himself the next day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person310">
                  Judith 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person310" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person310" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person310" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner said before my Lord Mayor that he had wronged Mrs. Nicholls , and would make her all the satisfaction he could.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. In April last I went accidentally, or rather unfortunately into the Poultry Counter , the Prisoner was committed there on suspicion of robbing her master. I had some business with relation to the clearing some insolvent debtors, which was the reason of my going there. I was recommended to her to assist her, and went about her business (she acknowledged she had been guilty of a great many errors.) When she was removed from the Poultry Counter, I went and attended her in Bridewell: she desired I would take her keys, but I sent another man for them; she delivered the keys to him, and he delivered them to me. She ordered me to pawn some things for her, and bid me say I came from Mrs. Hickman: and I do say, I do allow, I said I came from Mrs. Hickman, for I had her order so to do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person311">
                  John 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person311" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person311" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . You did say so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She said do this for me, but do not tell Mrs. Hickman, for she is this, and that, and t'other. She asked me for money several times, and I gave it her: I asked her for money several times, and she had none; whatever she asked me for she had.</p>
               <p>Jury. What sum did you give her?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Whenever she asked me I gave her; I have two witnesses in the Poultry Counter, one of them can come, and has been here; the other is in upon a writ de Capias Excommunicando .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person312">
                  Thomas 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person312" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person312" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner upwards of ten years, he has been concerned for some eminent brewers as a clerk, about four or five years ago, one in Holborn, another at Knightsbridge , &amp;c. and in all those places I never heard any<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280019"></xptr> thing of this kind laid to his charge - he has since that done business for attornies as a writer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person313">
                  William 
                  Goodall 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person313" type="surname" value="Goodall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person313" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner these five or six years, for I am concerned as an agent for his brother, who is a reputable attorney in the country; and since the Prisoner has been out of business, I have employed him as a scribe, he writes a good hand, though he was not bred an attorney. I heard he was sent to the Counter on suspicion of a robbery; I enquired into it, and went to the Prosecutrix, and said, if he has robbed you, I will not be concerned in it, but I do expect his brother in town and then he will make you satisfaction . She said she was in upon suspicion of a robbery herself, and while she was there nobody would come to her; she said she had entrusted him with her keys to go to her lodging and take some things out: says I, you must have a very good opinion of a man to suffer him to do that; she said he owned he had taken her things, and pawned them to the value of 40 s. or upwards. I asked whether it was without her privity (because he said she had given him power to go and take such things in order to raise money) and she said she had given him the keys to take some things to pledge to raise money, but I cannot say what particular things she mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she gave him directions to take particular things, or was it a general order?</p>
               <p>Goodall. I understood it was a general order to take what he thought proper, but I cannot say positively it was. The Prosecutrix came to me a second time at King's coffee-house in Fleet Street, and said , I do not want to hurt the man, but unless you will give me two guineas I am advised to prosecute him for Felony : there was a Jew along with her at that time.</p>
               <p>Edwards . I was with her before my Lord Mayor, and she never pretended it was a Felony.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you upon your oath whether you ever said to Mr. Goodall , that you gave the Prisoner your keys to take such things as he thought proper to pawn? Is that true, or not?</p>
               <p>Nicholls . I never had any such thought, nor never said any thing like it.</p>
               <p>Q. He says you owned you gave the Prisoner your keys to pawn either some particular goods, or else in general to pawn goods for your use?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. I never said any such word, or any thing like it, as I am in the presence of God.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say it was all one to you, if he would give you two guineas or your goods, or else you would prosecute the man?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. I said I was very much imposed upon, and I would go by my Lord Mayor's directions.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he offer any note to you?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. He did offer me a note, and I was told that the person who offered me the note wanted to impose upon me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person314">
                  Thomas 
                  Lamley 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person314" type="surname" value="Lamley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person314" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I having some knowledge of Parker , went with him to Grocer's Hall, he had three or four hearings before he was committed, because the Prosecutrix did only desire security for her goods, or to have her goods again. She offered to take that gentleman's note [Mr. Goodall's ] and said she did not desire to prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she say he had robbed her?</p>
               <p>Lamley . No, she did not say any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she say something to this effect?</p>
               <p>Lamley . She said, if I can get security for my money or goods, I will not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she acknowledge she gave him the key to take the goods to raise money?</p>
               <p>Lamley . She said she gave him the key to take the goods to raise money as he thought proper, - She said this as we were walking backwards and forwards in the hall.</p>
               <p>Nicholls. I never spoke to the man in my life.</p>
               <p>Lamley. She talked with me an hour together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person315">
                  Sarah 
                  Hickman 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person315" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person315" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Houndsditch, Nicholls had a room in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say about Nicholls goods?</p>
               <p>Hickman. What would you please to have me say? I don't know what I came for.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Speak the truth.</p>
               <p>Hickman. I am to speak the truth between. Parker and Nicholls; she had a lodger one John Brown who was a fellow servant with her in Bishopsgate-street, and when he left his master he came there, and came with all her keys.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Parker ever come alone?</p>
               <p>Hickman. The first time he came with her keys he came alone, and John Brown saw him, he was in the room when he brought them. - I can't say how many times he came, I believe it was 4 times, it might be 5 times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you say to me, Take care what you do, or you will bring yourself into a secret?</p>
               <p>Hickman. I bid you be very careful what you did. You brought the keys, and came for things, and said you had her order for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he carry them out publickly before your face?</p>
               <p>Hickman. He carried out 2 gowns, a napkin and a table cloth publickly at noon day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-21-person316">
                  Judith 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17440728-21-person316" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person316" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-person316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present with Mr. Goodall ,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280020"></xptr> and Mrs. Nicholls at the Feathers-Tavern in Cheapside , and at King's coffee-house in Fleet-street, I was there all the time, and heard every word that passed between them.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you whether she said she gave him the keys to raise money by any particular goods, or by the things in general?</p>
               <p>Fletcher. She gave him no such orders, she said she gave him the keys to fetch a cap, an apron, and a handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention any money that he was to bring?</p>
               <p>Fletcher. She said there were four shillings and half a guinea in her box; I don't know that she bid him bring any money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she was indifferent about prosecuting the man, or if he did not make it up, she would make a felony of it?</p>
               <p>Fletcher. No indeed she did not, indeed she is very much wronged I must own. <rs id="t17440728-21-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17440728-21-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-21-punish129" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-21-defend301 t17440728-21-punish129"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
