<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-55">
               <interp inst="t17420428-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-55" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-55" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-55-off243-c357" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-55-defend471 t17420428-55-off243 t17420428-55-verdict244"></join>
         
               <p>63. *
               <persName id="t17420428-55-defend471" type="defendantName">
                  Prior 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-defend471" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-defend471" type="given" value="Prior"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-defend471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17420428-55-off243" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-off243" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-off243" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               willful and corrupt Perjury
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>* See Sessions Book, No. 3. for 1742.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution having open'd the Indictment, proceeded to call the following Witnesses to support the Charge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-55-person472">
                  John 
                  Cardel 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person472" type="surname" value="Cardel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person472" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Defendant very well. He was a Brasier by Trade; I have known him follow that Business 8 or 10 Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Did you know him follow it at the Time of the Commission of Bankrupt?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17420428-55-person473">
                  Jean 
                  Brifant 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person473" type="surname" value="Brifant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person473" type="given" value="Jean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Yes, he was what we call a French-Plate-Worker, and I know of above an hundred Pounds worth of his Goods, which I myself have taken in, and enter'd into Mr. Green's Book.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Was there no Payment made by Green?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Not one single Payment of 20 s. to my Knowledge. Here is the Book where I set it down. I was Green's Servant, and he often sent me to Brifant's House to look out Goods for Sale.</p>
               <p>Here the Commission of Bankrupt was read.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Why you talk of a little Brass ting'd over with a Silver Colour! an hundred Pounds is a great deal of Money!</p>
               <p>Cardel. I understand the Business a little better than you: there were Goods to that Value according to the Market Price.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Will you venture to say there were 5 l. worth of Silver on all that you took in?</p>
               <p>Cardel. That is not material, if it was the Market Price. I took Care not to pay more than the common Price, because I understood them better than Mr. Green.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. I don't impeach your Understanding: was there the whole Value of fourscore Pounds brought into your Shop?</p>
               <p>Cardel. I dare say there were upwards of 100 l in Brass, Silver and Workmanship.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280036"></xptr>Counc. Def. How long did you leave Green before he fail'd?</p>
               <p>Cardel. I believe 3 or 4 Months.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. So then you can't say there were 100 l. due when Green fail'd?</p>
               <p>Cardel. No, but when I left him there was so much due.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before you left the Defendant, were the last Goods sent in on Brifant's Account?</p>
               <p>Cardel. That I can't say, for we had Trifles often coming in: we receiv'd a great Quantity that were pack'd up as if they were going abroad. I receiv'd with my own Hands to the Value of 113 l. and to my Knowledge none of them were paid for.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Did you never hear Brifant say he had received Money?</p>
               <p>Cardel. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever deny Green to any Body?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Yes, to Mr. Rudge's Clerk: He desired me not to let him be troubled with such People, in April 1740.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you know that these People were Creditors?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Yes, Rudges Clerk asked me for Money: we took our Beer of Mr. Rudge. I have likewise denied him to Mr. Hopkins a Glazier.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Green when you denied him to Mr. Rudge's Clerk?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Sometimes he has been out, but I have denied him when he has been above Stairs in the House.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Had not your Master a Lodging at Hackney?</p>
               <p>Cardel. Yes, but Mr. Rudge served us with Beer in Town: I can't tell whether he did the same in the Country.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Then you don't know but that Mr. Rudge and your Master might have settled Accounts?</p>
               <p>Cardel. I don't know that they did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Hopkins the Glazier do any Business for your Master?</p>
               <p>Cardel. I can't say that; I have heard that he glaz'd the House.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. I was one of the Commissioners named in this Commission, and it was on the 15th of Nov. 1740. Mr. Malmot, Mr. Salkeld, and my self took the Oath as the Act directs. The Purport of it was, '' 
               <persName id="t17420428-55-person474">
                  I
                   Roger Coningsby
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person474" type="surname" value="Roger Coningsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person474" type="given" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person474" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do swear, I '' will faithfully and impartially execute the Trust '' reposed in me; so help me God.'' We that Day declared the Defendant a Bankrupt. Mr. Malmot, Mr. Salkeld, Mr. Whitorne, and myself were Commissioners, and this is the original Declaration made by us as Commissioners.</p>
               <p>Here the Declaration was read, together with the Notice in the Gazette, for Prior Green to surrender himself for Examination, the 24th of Nov. and the 1st and 30th of Dec.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. The Defendant did surrender himself on the 24th of Nov. but for the Particulars of the Examination, I must refer myself to the Proceedings which I have sign'd.</p>
               <p>They were read, and it appear'd by them that the Defendant did surrender himself to Mr. Coninsby, Mr. Melmot, Mr. Conway, and Mr. Whitorne, and that being on Oath, he said he was not prepar'd to make a Discovery of his Effects, therefore desired farther Time, which accordingly was granted.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did Mr. Whitorne qualifie himself when he fate?</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. I must beg Leave to refresh my Memory; if you will cast your Eye upon that Place, you will find he was sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Now as to the Defendants signing his Surrender; - is that his Hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. I believe it to be so by my signing it, and I am very sure it was read to him, for I never allow these Things to be sign'd till they are read carefully over.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Is it not common to take these Things away from the Table, and not sign them before you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. No, they are always sign'd before me. The next meeting we had was on the 15th of December, at the Crown-Tavern, but I beg to be guided by the Proceedings all along, though I very well remember I was there. 
               <persName id="t17420428-55-person475">
                  Thomas 
                  Malcher 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person475" type="surname" value="Malcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person475" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Green's Apprentice was there, but he had received great Threats from his Master, and it was sometime before we could give him Spirits, but at last he was examin'd, and I believe this might be his Examination. Mr. Green bid us Defiance very much, and behav'd quite unbecoming his Condition.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was he sworn then?</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. I verily believe he was, but I can't tell who swore him, for sometimes one does it, and sometimes another. I am sure one of the Commissioners gave him the Oath. I can't remember the particular Questions and Answers at that Time, but it appear'd to us, that he had paid 
               <persName id="t17420428-55-person476">
                  Wm 
                  Warden 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person476" type="surname" value="Warden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person476" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             his Book-keeper, at his Shop in Moorfields, 20 l. which he represented to us a fair Debt, whereas no such Money was due.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goulder. I was Clerk to this Commission. and when the Defendant appear'd on the 15th of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280037"></xptr> December, 1740, I was present all the Time: Three was an Enquiry made with regard to 20 l. that he had paid to one Warden, and which Warden returned him again: He said it was all due to Warden for Wages and Board: He was contradicted in that by a Receipt in full but the Midsummer before, for Wages and Board He was then asked, if Warden did not return him that 20 l again, and he said he did not. This was at the Crown Tavern, and I believe he was an Hour on his Examination. There is another Examination of the 17th of February, and for Particulars, I must refer to that.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Did not you fetch the Defendant from an Alehouse the 15th of December, for Examination?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goulder. No, I never was at an Alehouse with him in my Life: He might be fetched from thence for ought I know.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Was he not disguised in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goulder. He might for ought I know, for he behaved very badly, and I believe he had been drinking pretty freely; but he was pretty sober when he attended the Commissioners afterwards, and then he accounted for the 20 lbs.</p>
               <p>Counc. Def. Was he ever offered his Certificate?</p>
               <p>Mr. Goulder. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Council to Mr. Coningsby. Do you think that the Defendant was on the 15th of December so disguised as not to be examined?</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. To be sure if I had thought him so, I would not have examin'd him; but what with Passion or Liquor, he seemed always to be outragious: I never saw him otherwise.</p>
               <p>Mr. Goulder. I believe he generally was in Liquor, except the last Day, which was the Time that he explained himself; then he was tolerably sober.</p>
               <p>The Lord Chancellor's Order, for enlarging the Time for the Defendant, was read, being first proved by Mr. Goulder.</p>
               <p>Mr. Coningsby. This Examination was taken in February, 1740, and I saw the Defendant sign it.</p>
               <p>It was read, and the Purport of it was, That Prior Green surrendered himself the 17th of February, 1740, to the major Part of the Commissioners, and upon Oath said, That the Writing mark'd D, the several Books mark'd A B C, and the Writings mark'd E and F, did contain a full Disclosure of all his Effects.</p>
               <p>Then several Interrogatories, which were sent to the Defendant, were read to the following Effect.</p>
               <p>Did you, or did you not go from your late Dwelling-house in Cheapside, to the Crown Tavern in or near Bloomsbury?</p>
               <p>The Answer was, - That the Defendant did some Time before the Commission, go to the Crown Tavern in Bloomsbury.</p>
               <p>Did you, or did you not carry with you, an Iron Chest?</p>
               <p>The Defendant said, - He did get a Porter to carry an Iron Chest to the Crown Tavern.</p>
               <p>What was contained in it? What Money, &amp;c.?</p>
               <p>- There were a Silver Tankard, six large Spoons, six small Tea-spoons, and a small Sum of Money, not exceeding 20 l. and no other Effects whatsoever, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The last Question, contained in the Writing mark'd F, was, Did you not, on or about the 13th of November, 1740, pay 
               <persName id="t17420428-55-person477">
                  William
                   Warden Twenty
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person477" type="surname" value="Warden Twenty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person477" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Pounds, and whether he did not return it again?</p>
               <p>The Answer was, - That he did pay 20 l. and that Warden did return it again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-55-person478">
                  Thomas 
                  Malcher 
               <interp inst="t17420428-55-person478" type="surname" value="Malcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person478" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Defendant's Apprentice, deposed, That Warden was first his Master's Journeyman in Cheapside, and afterwards at his Shop at Moorfields, and that Cardel lived with him at the same Time: That on the 13th of November, before the Commission came out the Defendant told Warden, he had received a Sum of Money from Mr. Waters, a Baker, and desired him (Warden) to give him a Receipt for 20 l. for fear he should he called to an Account for the Money, at the same Time telling Warden, he might receive the Money, and give it him again: That a great many Persuasions were made use of, and at last Warden did give him a Receipt, and paid the Money back again to the Defendant, in the Space of five Minutes: That he (this Witness ) was in the Room at the same Time, and that one Edmund Eyles, who is dead, was a Witness to the Receipt: That after the issuing of the Commission, he moved two Stove Grates to his Mother's House; that one of them was by the Defendant's Orders taken away by a Porter, and the other was put into a Coach in Cheapside and carried off. This Witness added, That he was sent by Warden to fetch a Shop-Book which was concealed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280038"></xptr> in an Alley in Moorfields, Being asked, Whether there were not some Iron Bars put up at the Defendant's House, to prevent his throwing himself out of the Window, he answered, He believed there were some put up, but he believed they were to prevent him from doing himself any Mischief when in Liquor.</p>
               <p>We can only say in general, that several Witnesses was called by the Prisoner's Council, to prove, that the Property of the Goods in Dispute, was not the Prisoner's, but other Peoples; and others, to prove, that he had for some time past committed Acts tending to Lunney; and it being allowed by the Attorney for the Prosecutor's that the Debts proved, amounted to 1300 l. and that they had received in Money and Effects 1100 l. upon the whole the Jury <rs id="t17420428-55-verdict244" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-55-verdict244" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
               <p>N. B. The further PARTICULARS of the TRIAL of PRIOR GREEN, by the unavoidable Indisposition of Mr. BROOKER the Compiler, the Proprietors of this PAPER cannot oblige the PUBLIC with at present, and humbly hopes their DELAY, in publishing this SECOND PART so many Days after the former, (to their very great Loss) will be interpreted as it really is, 2 Willingness to have obliged the PUBLIC had it been in their Power, and promise to give it genuine in the next Paper, in Case Mr. BROOKER recovers.</p>
            </div1>
