<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490222-37">
               <interp inst="t17490222-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-37" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-37" type="date" value="17490222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-37-off173-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-defend241 t17490222-37-off173 t17490222-37-verdict176"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-37-off173-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-defend243 t17490222-37-off173 t17490222-37-verdict177"></join>
         
               <p>201, 202. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-defend241" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Haydon 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend241" type="surname" value="Haydon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend241" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-defend243" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Anthony 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend243" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend243" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-defend243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted for <rs id="t17490222-37-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 2 l. 10 s. one pair of silver shoe buckles, value 25 s. one pair of silver knee buckles, value 19 s. one pair of silver sleeve buttons, value 2 s. one pair of shoes, a pair of stockings, and 28 guineas in gold
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-victim245" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Wilkinson 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-37-victim245" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-victim245" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-victim245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-off173 t17490222-37-victim245"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-person246">
                  John 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person246" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by the water-side, and saw two women very well dressed. I asked them where I could have a lodging? they took me to a house, then they wanted something to eat: I gave them a shilling to go and get something; they were gone when I was robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. Besides the things mentioned in the indictment, I lost two silk handkerchiefs and two linnen handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. What reasons have you to accuse the prisoners at the bar?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. The man was in the room when I awoke; he, and others that were then in the room, bid me make the best of my way out or I should lose my life: I went out into the yard and saw an out-house, so I crept in there and lay till morning; then I saw Haydon, the prisoner, with my buckles in his hand through the window; I went into the street bare-footed as they had left me, and ran after him, but could not catch him: I secured the woman; then after some time, I saw the man go past again; I pursued him and the constable took him with the buckles upon him; but he gave the woman the buckles to convey away; and going before the Justice she dropped the buckles; the constable being behind her took them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account how, or when you lost these things.</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I was a little in liquor, and just come home from Virginia; and having but little rest for four or five days and nights, I fell asleep, and was robbed while I was sleeping.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to bed?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, my Lord, I was sitting by the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know you had your things when you went to sleep?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I felt my money in my pocket while I was sitting, before I fell asleep; I had told the money just before ; I had been paid it that afternoon, about four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17490222-37-person247">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person247" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person247" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person247" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one of the women that took you into that house?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, my Lord, but she and two more came into the room where I was; there was only two women when I went to sleep, and they were gone when I awoke.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you awake?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the two women again that went out with your shilling?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, my Lord, I never saw the two fine damsels since.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any men in the room with you?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. There was a tall thin man; I never saw him since. My shoe-buckles were found upon Haydon next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the room when you awoke?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. There were three men, and they threaten'd me very much; I was afraid of being murder'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-person248">
                  Samuel 
                  Ellise 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person248" type="surname" value="Ellise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person248" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough of White-Chapel parish; between seven and eight in this morning, there were two boys came to my house, and told me there was a <rs id="t17490222-37-viclabel174" type="occupation">sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-victim245 t17490222-37-viclabel174"></join> had been stripp'd in <placeName id="t17490222-37-crimeloc175">Bakers-Arms Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-37-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Bakers-Arms Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-37-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-off173 t17490222-37-crimeloc175"></join> ; I went there, this sailor, 
               <persName id="t17490222-37-person249">
                  John 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person249" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was in the room bare-footed: says he, I have been robb'd. It is a noted place for thieves. He said, a man with a blue jacket has got my buckles, adding, they were wrapp'd up in white paper. There was the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17490222-37-person250">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person250" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person250" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and two more girls, in a sad dishabil , ragged, and bare-footed; they tightened themselves up to go along with us, as I insisted on taking them before the Justice. The Prosecutor having his eye towards the street, seeing the Prisoner, said, that is the man that has my shoe-buckles ; he run after him, without shoe or stocking, and I run, got sight of him, and took him.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220012"></xptr> I brought him back to the three girls; we took them all four, and put them all close in a box together at an alehouse, it being too soon to go to the Justice; then afterwards we went before the Justice, Heydon confessed there, he gave the buckles to 
               <persName id="t17490222-37-person251">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person251" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person251" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other Prisoner. Going along she dropp'd them down; I happen'd to be just behind her, saw them fall, and took them up; they were in the paper he bought them with, as he before described; he had, as he said, bought them about two hours before, with the rest of the things.</p>
               <p>Court . You must deliver the buckles to the Prosecutor .</p>
               <p>Ellise. I shall, my Lord, according to contract. I found him in much distress, so I then lent him a shilling, and since that I lent him more, to carry on this prosecution , and he has agreed to let me keep the buckles till he pays me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-person252">
                  Charles 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person252" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person252" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be coming by in the morning, and saw the sailor walking about the streets in a dismal manner; he said he was robbed, mentioning the things in the indictment, saying, he saw the man running along the street that had his buckles in his hand, but he could not get him; says I, I'll go along with you back, which I did, and the house was shut up; said he, the man went in here, so we went in, and there were three women laid down: says I, do you know any of them? he said he knew one or two . We sent for a constable, and gave him charge of this woman at the bar; he turned himself about, and saw the man, and the constable pursuing , who took him. We did not search him, designing that before the Justice. He owned giving them to the woman there , and that he had had them . I saw them when the constable took them up.</p>
               <p>Haydon <rs id="t17490222-37-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of felony.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-37-person253">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17490222-37-person253" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person253" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17490222-37-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490222-37-punish178" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-37-punish178" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-37-defend241 t17490222-37-punish178"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
