<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-60">
               <interp inst="t17431207-60" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-60" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-60" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-60" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-60-off311-c351" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-60-defend472 t17431207-60-off311 t17431207-60-verdict314"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-60-off311-c352" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-60-defend474 t17431207-60-off311 t17431207-60-verdict314"></join>
         
               <p>+ 70, 71. 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-defend472" type="defendantName">
                  Charles 
                  Flood 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend472" type="surname" value="Flood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend472" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-defend474" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Bargame 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend474" type="surname" value="Bargame"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend474" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-defend474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , were indicted, for <rs id="t17431207-60-off311" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-off311" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-off311" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               that they not having the Fear of God, nor weighing the Duty of their Allegiance, &amp;c. but devising and intending our Lord the King, and his people, craftily, falsely, unlawfully, deceitfully, feloniously, and traiterously , to deceive and defraud, after the 29th Day of September, 1742. to wit, on the <rs id="t17431207-60-cd312" type="crimeDate">1st Day of December, in the 6th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-60-off311 t17431207-60-cd312"></join> , with Force and Arms, at the parish of <placeName id="t17431207-60-crimeloc313">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-crimeloc313" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-crimeloc313" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-60-off311 t17431207-60-crimeloc313"></join>, in the County of Middlesex, craftily, falsely, unlawfully, deceitfully, feloniously, and traiterously, did fill, and with certain Materials, producing the Colour of Silver, did wash and colour two pieces of Brass Money of this Realm, called Farthings, with Intent to make each of the said pieces resemble, look like, and pass for, a lawful piece of Silver Coin of this Realm, called a Six-pence: The Indictment farther charged them, that they on the 1st Day of December, &amp;c. did alter the Impression on each Side of two Farthings, with the like Intent; and the Indictment did likewise set forth, that they on the said first Day of December, &amp;c. did wash and colour the said two Farthings, with the Intent as before; and this was laid to be against the Duty of their Allegiance, against the peace of the King, and against the Form of the Statute
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>At the Desire of the Prisoners the Witnesses were examined apart; upon that the King's Council moved, that the Witnesses for the Prisoners should not be in Court while the King's Witnesses were examined, and they were ordered to withdraw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-person475">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person475" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person475" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Flood about three Years, and Bargaine about two Years; I have seen them file Farthings, and make them into Six-pences, and Half-pence into Shillings - I was concerned with them in the doing it; first we file the Britannia off, and take the Ribbon off, which hangs by the Side of the Neck on the Head Side, and alter the Head to make it look like a Six-pence, and then file them to the Size and Thickness of a Six-pence; after that we polish them with a piece of Leather to take off the Scratches and Roughness of the File; then we put them into a little Hand-vice, and put a bit of Leather between them and the Vice, to prevent it from marking them, and then bend them and whiten them over, so as to make them look like Silver, by rubbing them with Aqua Fortis, Cream of Tartar, and burnt Silver, made into a Sort of a paste. [This Witness proved the Experiment.] Then we used to put them off at Chandlers Shops, Bakers Shop, or where we could. I have put off five or six in a Day; we always went single - Sometimes we took out twenty or thirty at a Time, sometimes but two or three; if two of us went out together, only one went into the Shop, the other was placed at a Distance with a Quantity of this Money: He that went into the Shop had but one, and when he had parted with that he came to the person that had the Bag for another. [There were two of the altered Farthings showed to the Witness.] These are like them, they are King George the Second's Farthings. I am positive to both the Prisoners, they used to work at this Business at 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person476">
                  Garret 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person476" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person476" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's * and 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person477">
                  Patrick 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person477" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person477" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. - I made my first Information last Christmas Day past.</p>

               <p>* Garret Cavenagh, and his Wife, and 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person478">
                  Patrick 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person478" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person478" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and his Wife, were tried last January Sessions, and convicted of High Treason, upon the Evidence of this 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person479">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person479" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person479" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and others. See Trial 116, 117, 118, 119. Page 70.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them alter more than one, to make them resemble and pass for Sixpences?</p>
               <p>Graham . Yes; I have seen them do a hundred - I have seen both the Prisoners go through all the parts of this Business, altering the Impression, filing them to a Thickness, bringing them to the Breadth, polishing them, bending them, and silvering them over, and I have seen them pass them off.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you never informed against for this practice?</p>
               <p>Graham. I was in Custody in the Year 1738, and since that Cavenagh and Kelly laid an Information against me for counterfeiting the same.</p>
               <p>Q. And you were an Evidence against them, and now you have the good Fortune to be an Evidence against these persons?</p>
               <p>Graham. Yes; I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you been so kind as to desire a little Money of Flood?</p>
               <p>Graham. Yes; perhaps I have; ask me what you will, and I will answer you.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070028"></xptr>Q. Have not you sent to Flood to demand Money of him, and to tell him, if he did not give it you, you would turn Evidence against him?</p>
               <p>Graham. I had had some Difference with Flood, and in August last I met him and Bargaine , and four or five more by Camberwell , with Hoes and Sticks , and I was afraid they would do for me, because they knew what I had done; they came up to me, and said, are not you afraid to do so and so? I said, you threatened to lay an Information against me, and I do not know for what, for I never endeavoured to hurt you; Says Bargaine, I am going to Portsmouth to Morrow, I will give you a couple of Guineas if you will not be Evidence against me; so he gave me a couple of Guineas; I thought I would give them good Words till I got away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go away with the two Guineas?</p>
               <p>Graham. Yes; they gave them me in a Day or two; I went to Labouring Work, and there was a Constable on the other Side of the Water, that said Bargaine was taken up for a Robbery in Surrey; [he is brought here by a Habeas Corpus ;] I went to Mr. North that Night with a Constable to prove he was the Man - I cannot fix the Day I made the Information.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person480">
                  Dennis 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person480" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person480" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and Rose Kennedy ?</p>
               <p>Graham. Yes; I know them to be Affidavit people; they are vile wicked people; there is such a parcel of this Irish Gang about, that if this place was Diamonds they would swear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-person481">
                  Sarah 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person481" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person481" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person481" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the Evidence of 
               <persName id="t17431207-60-person482">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person482" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person482" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with Respect to the Prisoners performing every Branch of that Business, and that they have done this till their Fingers have been blistered, and that sometimes they were so hot they would stick to their Fingers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-person483">
                  Sarah 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person483" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person483" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person483" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Flood's Wife has put off twenty six in an Evening, and Bargaine's Wife twenty four or twenty five many an Evening - The least we put off was twenty four or twenty five of a Night; when we went out we used to say to one another, Good Luck to you; we used to lay them out for some small Matter or other, and get good Money in the room of them - I have seen the Prisoners fell the Filings of the Half-pence and Farthings for 7 d. per pound. [There was a Box of paste produced.] Mr. Bargaine had such an one, and Mr. Flood had such an one - I believe it is the same Stuff [smells at it] it is the same Sort of Stuff; sometimes they have cut them cross the Face, and then they would pass better than another; and they said they would serve the K. so if they could: There are several people here to swear against me, Flood's Sister, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Mr. North produced two pieces of Money resembling Six-pences, which had been altered, and which he had of Mr. Matthews , and which he said were both Copper Farthings of the present King's.</p>
               <p>Mr. Matthews . I keep a Publick House, the Swan near St. George's Church, Southwark, Charles Flood and two more came for a full pot of Beer, and Flood gave me this Farthing for a Six-pence; I rubbed it upon the Floor, and delivered it to him again; said I. honest Man, what makes you use me so, it is but a Farthing; then they gave me this, I returned it again, and afterwards desired them to let me see them again, and they gave them me; said I again innocently, Methinks you are full of this Sort of Money (I cannot say that ever I saw Bargaine) Flood took an Apple out of his pocket, and flung this Box [the paste for colouring] out of Doors, and there was the print of one of these pieces in the Apple; this was the 18th of November, 1741.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect yourself how long this was ago?</p>
               <p>Matthews . It was two Years ago the 18th of last Month.</p>
               <p>Q. to Graham. Were you ever concerned with them since Cavenagh and Kelly were tried?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-person484">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person484" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person484" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, not in this Way - I was taken up this Month was twelve Months - I saw Bargaine and Flood making Farthings into Six-pences, and Half pence into Shillings, the Week before I was taken into Custody; I was taken up for an Assault, and made myself a voluntary Evidence in this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-60-person485">
                  Sarah 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17431207-60-person485" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person485" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-person485" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - I cannot justly remember how long it was before my Husband went into Confinement ; I saw them making some about a Fortnight before Christmas, I believe it was about the eighth or tenth of December; the last I put off for Mr. Flood and Mr. Bargaine was for a Quarter of a pound of Sassasras .</p>
               <p>- Boyle . I took Bargaine up some Time in February last upon the Information of Graham, and by Clerkenwell Watch-house he made his Escape; the next Time I saw him was in the New Goal in Southwark; a little before last Sessions Graham and his Wife charged me with him.</p>
               <p>It appearing that the Farthings, which were produced, had been altered and uttered before the Commencement of the Act of Parliament, which did not take place till the 29th of September , 1742, and there being no working Tools or Materials for that purpose found in the possession of the Prisoners, they were <rs id="t17431207-60-verdict314" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-60-verdict314" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
