<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411014-25">
               <interp inst="t17411014-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-25" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-25" type="date" value="17411014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411014-25-off133-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-defend215 t17411014-25-off133 t17411014-25-verdict136"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411014-25-off133-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-defend217 t17411014-25-off133 t17411014-25-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>30. 31. 
               
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-defend215" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Westwood 
                  <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend215" type="surname" value="Westwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend215" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-defend217" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Bellinger 
                  <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend217" type="surname" value="Bellinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend217" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-defend217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17411014-25-defloc132">St. Mary White chappel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-25-defloc132" type="placeName" value="St. Mary White chappel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-25-defloc132" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-defend215 t17411014-25-defloc132"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-defend217 t17411014-25-defloc132"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17411014-25-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411014-25-victim219" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Butler 
                        <interp inst="t17411014-25-victim219" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-25-victim219" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-25-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-off133 t17411014-25-victim219"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain alley, called <placeName id="t17411014-25-crimeloc134">Rosemary-branch-alley</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-crimeloc134" type="placeName" value="Rosemary-branch-alley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-crimeloc134" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-off133 t17411014-25-crimeloc134"></join>, near the King's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him 7 s. in money
            </rs>; <rs id="t17411014-25-cd135" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-25-off133 t17411014-25-cd135"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person220">
                  Charles 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person220" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person220" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 1st of June last I met the prisoner Westwood and five others at the Hampshire Hog in Rosemary-lane: he was buying some fish, and I followed him into the house, to ask him for 40s. which he owed me. I call'd for a pint of beer, and while the landlord was gone to draw it, Westwood told me, if I asked him for the money, he would swear me into a robbery, and he ran his cane into my mouth. I told him I would get a writ for him, and he said, I had no money, and could not; upon which I shew'd him a letter, wherein I had orders to go to Spithead to receive 22 l. 10s. I then left the house, and four of them followed me into the city, and after having arrested me, they dragg'd me into Rosemary-branch-alley. They followed me into Rosemary-lane, and then the prisoner Bellinger came up with a piece of parchment in his hand, and said, I have got it. I took hold of 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person221">
                  Daniel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person221" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person221" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's collar, to keep me from falling, and then they cut me on the head, and one of them ran his tipstaff into my eye. After this, Bellinger put his hand into my pocket, and pulled out six shillings and two sixpences. I cried out Murder! and said I was robb'd, and went to put my foot on some of my money that had dropp'd on the ground, but Westwood came up and shoved my foot aside, and took it up. Then they used me so that blood came out of my nose and eyes. I was carried to the Infirmary, where I lay speechless and out of my senses for some time. My bleeding can't be stopp'd, and I have been these 20 weeks, next Monday, under this calamity.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Westwood indebted to you for?</p>
               <p>Butler . I am a bricklayer and fitted up his house inside and outside.</p>
               <p>Westwood's Q. Have you not been in company with me several times since? and have you ever charged me with this robbery?</p>
               <p>Butler . I have seen him but once since: I did not charge him with the robbery because justice Phillips took bail for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not attempt to get a warrant for him?</p>
               <p>Butler. No; I knew where he lived, but he absconded (from) his house.</p>
               <p>Westwood's Q. Did not you charge me with assaulting you after the commission of the robbery?</p>
               <p>Butler. No, I charged him with aiding and abetting in the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of you went first into the Hampshire Hog?</p>
               <p>Butler. I went in first: Westwood was buying some fish at the door, and followed me in. They had no writ against me, and I owed no man any money.</p>
               <p>Westwood. How came you to put off the trial last sessions by an affidavit that yourself and another man were material Witnesses, and now no body appears but yourself?</p>
               <p>Butler. The other man was a Bricklayer, but I had not timely notice that the Trial would come on.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Westwood . I am an officer belonging to the sheriff of Middlesex, and having obtained a writ against Butler, I desired these officers to arrest him for me. Accordingly they did arrest him, and he being obstropulous and not willing to go with them, they beat him and pulled and haled him about. He says I aided in beating and robbing him. I shall call 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person222">
                  William 
                  Walmsley 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person222" type="surname" value="Walmsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to shew that I was not there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person223">
                  William 
                  Walmsley 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person223" type="surname" value="Walmsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was standing over against the Rosemary-Branch ale house, and as soon as this tumult was raised, he went backwards into the house and I saw no more of him.</p>
               <p>Westwood's Q. Can you take upon you to say whether I was along with them when the man was arrested?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. I am sure he was not near them.</p>
               <p>Westwood . How long might they continue in the street?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. About a quarter of an hour or half an hour the very most.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of them afterwards?</p>
               <p>Walmsley . They were charged with the officers . I took 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person224" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             myself .</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was there any talk of a robbery at this time?</p>
               <p>Walmsley . No, I heard no complaint of any robbery at all. Butler fell down in the court on his back, and beat his head against the stones, which caused blood to come out of the back part of his head, and soon afterwards a doctor came and bled him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140015"></xptr>Q. Did you see what was done when Butler was dragg'd up the alley?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. Yes: there were 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person225">
                  Thomas 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person225" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person225" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person226">
                  Daniel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person226" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person226" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Bellinger. Jones had hold of one of Butler's legs, Roberts another, and Bellinger had hold of his collar and his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stay there any Time after Bellinger had him by the collar?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. No, I did not stay a minute because I had a shop to mind and was afraid of losing my goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go after that?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. To my shop door, about ten or fifteen yards off.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see there what was done at the back of the Rosemary-Branch alehouse?</p>
               <p>Walmsley. No, I was not able to do that to be sure.</p>
               <p>- Wood. I keep the 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person227">
                  Rosemary 
                  Branch 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person227" type="surname" value="Branch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person227" type="given" value="Rosemary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             alehouse, and remember this dispute. Westwood was in my house when the mob came past. He said they had arrested a man, and it was strange they could not arrest a man without beating him. The bailiffs then had Butler hold by the arm and dragg'd him through the alley. Westwood never came out of my house for the space of half an hour. There were not two of the mob then left, and Butler was gone to the Infirmary. As to the robbery, Westwood robb'd him no more than I did I believe, for I heard nothing at all said of a robbery.</p>
               <p>Isabella Seers. I live in Cock alley, and was waiting on Mr. Wood's children, and remember the day that Butler was arrested. Mr. Westwood came in about 2 minutes before the mob came past the door, and called for a pint of beer. When the mob came round to the back door they said there was a man arrested, and the man fell down in the court. Mr. Wood then put Westwood into a back parlour, and locked him in, and he staid there 'till the man was gone to the Infirmary.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did Wood lock the prisoner in?</p>

               <p>Seers . Because the mob said they would knock his brains out. I was binding a silk petticoat and he sat best part of the time that I was doing it. I never heard a word of a robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Seers. Between 1 and 2, we were just going to dinner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person228">
                  Matthew 
                  Crawley 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person228" type="surname" value="Crawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person228" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I serve Mr. Wood with bread. I brought him a loaf, and saw the mob coming just by the door. I got as fast as I could into the house, and saw Wood and Westwood talking together in the room, and I staid there two hours 'till all was dispersed.</p>
               <p>Westwood Q. Did I go out 'till all was over?</p>
               <p>Crawley. No, he did not indeed.</p>
               <p>Westwood's Q. Had I any opportunity to go out to rob a man?</p>
               <p>Crawley. No, he was in presence of me all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go into the room where he was lock'd in?</p>
               <p>Crawley. No, but I had the command of the Door in my eye that he could not go out. After I had been in the house some time, I had a fancy to see the mob, and I went as far as the pump and came back again, and saw Westwood where I left him.</p>
               <p>Westwood's Q. Could, I when you was out of the room, rob a man without your seeing me?</p>
               <p>Crawley . No, he could not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person229">
                  Mary 
                  Battersey 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person229" type="surname" value="Battersey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person229" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live in Rosemary Lane, and hearing a tumult that the officers had hurt the man, I desired them to raise him up against the wall: they did so, and a gentlewoman gave me some wine to give him, and I put my finger in his mouth to see if he could drink, but he could not. After this his wife came, and took a handkerchief off her neck and put it about his cut head: she took money out of his pocket several times, and put it into her bosom, and I myself lent her a great pin to pin her gown to prevent her losing the money. I never saw either of the prisoners there, nor ever heard the least syllable of a robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person230">
                  Clifford William 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person230" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person230" type="given" value="Clifford William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Esq. Colonel 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person231">
                  Deacon
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person231" type="given" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had the 4 bailiffs before him after this assault was committed, and he sent them to the Tower goal for farther examination. The next day he sent for me to join with him in taking the examination: The assault appeared to be a very violent one, and we committed the 4 bailiffs to Newgate. Butler being in the Infirmary in the parish where I live, and being told he was like to die, I went thither to take his examination. The doctors reported to me that he had been speechless all night, but that he was now come to his senses, so I took my clerk into the room and bid him take the examination exactly as he spoke it, and I would come in when he had done, for I did not like the stench of the place. When it was done, I came in, and found that he had charged Westwood with thrusting his cane into his mouth at the alehouse. (which was some time before the arrest) and likewise that he had charged Bellinger with robing him. Seeing Westwood charged only in this manner, I asked Butler whether he was concern'd in this cruel usage? he told me he was not. Upon this I granted a warrant against Bellinger, but Westwood came voluntarily, and I took bail for the assault. This is the examination and this is Butler's hand: it was read over to him very distinctly and he was very sensible when he sign'd it.</p>

               <p>The examination was read, the substance of which was, that between the hours of 11 and 12 he (Butler) met with 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person232">
                  William 
                  Westwood 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person232" type="surname" value="Westwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person232" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 4 others at the Hampshire Hog in Rosemary Lane; that he asked Westwood for the money that he ow'd him: that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140016"></xptr> Westwood replied he would pay this deponent when he was going to Tyburn: that this deponent saying those were not expressions fit for a married man as he was, Westwood ran his cane against his mouth; and then this deponent paid three half pence for a pint of beer which he had call'd for and said he would get a writ for him. That he (this deponent) then went away, and going past the Merchant Taylors alms houses, some persons came up to him and said, your journey is stopped ; that a person said hold of this deponent , and they saying they had no action to produce , he (this deponent) knock'd his head in his face. That one of the 4 persons struck this deponent in the eye with a tipstaff, and another gave him a blow on his head. That one of them said, d - n your limbs, where have you been this great while? and pulling out a yellow piece of parchment with a red seal to it, all the 5 persons pull'd and haled this deponent into a narrow alley, and that 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person233">
                  Daniel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person233" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person233" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             tripp'd him up. That this deponent got up again, and laid hold of 
               <persName id="t17411014-25-person234">
                  Daniel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person234" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person234" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's collar: upon which Bellinger said, undo his hands. That then Bellinger came up, and put one hand to this deponent's collar, and the other into his pocket, and took out his money. That one of the 5 persons knock'd this deponent down; that another said d - n him he is resty, he will not go: that they haled him so far that he was deprived of his senses, and that Westwood said, bale him away, dead or alive, for go he shall: &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Mr. Philips . He said that Westwood came out of Wood's house while he was in this condition, and said he should be taken away, but he had no concern in the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person235">
                  Edward 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person235" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person235" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the room when Butler gave the information to justice Philips, and he never mention'd any robbery against Westwood. I had 2 warrants to serve upon the prisoners. I was 3 days and 3 nights looking after Bellinger, but Westwood I took presently. I went to see Butler several times in the Infirmary, and once while I was there his wife was sitting on the side of the bed by him. She call'd him forsworn son of a b - h, and said she took the money out of his pocket herself, he d - d her and bid her hold her tongue, and hearing this I surrender'd up the warrants into another officer's hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-25-person236">
                  Mary 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17411014-25-person236" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person236" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . When this hurley-burley was, I like a great many more fools must go and see it, and I saw Butler's wife put her handkerchief about his neck, and take the money out of his pocket. Mrs. Battersey held one arm and I held the other while he was blooded, and he never complained of a robbery.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deacon gave an account that he committed the 4 bailiss to Newgate for this abuse; and that afterwards by a certificate from the doctor and apothecary of the Infirmary that Butler was out of danger, he took bail for them. That Westwood was one of their bail, and that Butler was present and made no mention of any robbery committed by him. Both <rs id="t17411014-25-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-25-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
