<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-66">
               <interp inst="t17401015-66" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-66" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-66" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-66" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-66-off356-c378" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-66-defend466 t17401015-66-off356 t17401015-66-verdict357"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150036"></xptr>504. 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-defend466" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Loppenburg 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-defend466" type="surname" value="Loppenburg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-defend466" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-defend466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401015-66-defloc354">Paddington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-defloc354" type="placeName" value="Paddington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-defloc354" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-66-defend466 t17401015-66-defloc354"></join>, was indicted for that he, after the 24th Day of June, 1731, viz . on the <rs id="t17401015-66-cd355" type="crimeDate">26th of April</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-66-off356 t17401015-66-cd355"></join>, <rs id="t17401015-66-off356" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-off356" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-off356" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               150 lb. of Lead, val. 15 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17401015-66-victim468" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Frapwell 
                        <interp inst="t17401015-66-victim468" type="surname" value="Frapwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-66-victim468" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-66-victim468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-66-off356 t17401015-66-victim468"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , fixed to a certain Messuage, he did rip, steal, and carry away
            </rs>.</p>
         
               <p>The Prisoner, being a Foreigner, demanded a Party Jury, and the following Persons were sworn.</p>
               <p>English</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person469" type="jurorName">
                     Samuel 
                     Adderson 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person469" type="surname" value="Adderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person469" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person470" type="jurorName">
                     Robert 
                     Tonstal 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person470" type="surname" value="Tonstal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person470" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person471" type="jurorName">
                     Richard 
                     Spire 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person471" type="surname" value="Spire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person471" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person472" type="jurorName">
                     Thomas 
                     Wilkin 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person472" type="surname" value="Wilkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person472" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person473" type="jurorName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Eager 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person473" type="surname" value="Eager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person473" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person474" type="jurorName">
                     John 
                     Brice 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person474" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person474" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               .</p>
               <p>Foreign</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person475" type="jurorName">
                     Charles 
                     Delahaye 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person475" type="surname" value="Delahaye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person475" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person476" type="jurorName">
                     John 
                     Payne 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person476" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person476" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person477" type="jurorName">
                     Robert 
                     Wanmer 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person477" type="surname" value="Wanmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person477" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person478" type="jurorName">
                     James 
                     Grelliere 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person478" type="surname" value="Grelliere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person478" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person479" type="jurorName">
                     Peter 
                     Lemaistre 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person479" type="surname" value="Lemaistre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person479" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person480" type="jurorName">
                     Francis 
                     Roasiere 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-66-person480" type="surname" value="Roasiere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person480" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               .</p>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person481">
                  Walter 
                  Dobener 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person481" type="surname" value="Dobener"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person481" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of April, I was informed that a Leaden Gutter, and several Pipes, were stolen from Mr Frapwell's House. I thought fit to get a Warrant to search proper Places, and just as we were got to Marybon Turnpike , a shower of Rain came upon us, and we stood up in the Turnpike House. While we were there the People were talking, that a Man was taken in a Brick-Field with Leaden Pipe upon him, and that he was carried to the Bell at Paddington . We went to the Bell, and found the Prisoner with some People, who had secured him, in a little Room in the House, and a Bag of Lead on the Table. I took Dimensions of the Lead, and went to the House from whence it was taken, and it fitted exactly. I then charged a Constable with the Prisoner, and carried him before a Justice, where he said, that he found it in a Pond. When he was taken he was asked where he found the Bag, and he said in the other Field, behind the Bush; and that there was a Lock of Straw on it. I was not at the first taking of the Prisoner; I was going to the Gravel-Pits, but hearing at the Turnpike that a Man was taken with Lead, I turned back again. When I charged him with stealing it, he behaved very cooly, and said, that he found it in a Pond, and the Bag behind the Bush. There was a wet Shirt in the Bag beside the Lead, and before the Justice he said, that he went to the Pond to wash his Shirt, and then found the Lead. There was about a Quarter of a hundred in the Bag, and the wet Shirt. The Shirt was produced before the Justice, and was very dirty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person482">
                  John 
                  Gays 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person482" type="surname" value="Gays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person482" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of April, I was informed that some Lead was found in Spruce and Baker's Pond at Paddington . I went with them to see it, and a Storm of Hail occasioned us to go to a Hedge 40 Yards from the Pond for Shelter. In the Interim the Prisoner came into the Field, and went towards Bay's-Water, I did not suspect him by his Dress; he came between us and the Pond, and I took particular Notice to see if he looked towards the Pond, but could not perceive that he did. We set a Man to watch, imagining that the Lead would be fetched out of the Pond in small Quantities. I put the Lead, which had been taken out of the Pond, in again, after the Prisoner was gone out of the Field towards Bay's-Water . I then went away, and sent a Man to watch; he came running back to me, and said, he saw a Man come to the Pond with something in a Bag; I went after the Prisoner, and when I came near him, I saw that he had a Bag in his Hand; he went over a Ditch into another Field, put the Bag into the Ditch, and then retreated from it 3 or 4 Yards. I ran up to him, imagining it to be the Lead, and asked him how he came by it; he said, he found it in the Pond. We then carried him to Paddington, and he answered all the Questions that were put to him, in English, very distinctly; he had the same Coat on then as now, his Shirt was not so clean, and he looked a little rough. There was a Shirt found by the Bag, and he said he went to the Pond to wash it; but there were many other Places more private where he might have done it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person483">
                  Richard 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person483" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person483" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr Frampton's Gardiner, and lie in the House. On the 26th of April last, I heard a Noise between 1 and 2 o'clock in the Morning; I got up and looked out at the Window, and saw a Ladder against the House. I did not go to Bed again, but looked about the House, and found that a great deal of Lead had been taken from the West End; there were leaden Pipes, and part of the Gutter gone. The Lead was pretty substantial, and required some Work to take it down, and the Noise waked me, but I heard no Voices. The Ladder belonged to a Carpenter at Kensington, and he lent it to a Bricklayer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person484">
                  John 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person484" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person484" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of April, between 8 and 9 in the Morning, I was sent for to watch at the Pond, and while I was there, I saw the Prisoner go from the Pond with the Lead in a Bag; he did not take the Foot-path, but crossed the Road, and seemed to run with it. I then called Gays, and he ran after the Prisoner and overtook him, and when I came up he had hold of him; the Bag and a dirty Shirt lay by him; I asked him what he designed to do with the Lead, he said it was to make Shot, to go a shooting with, and that he was going to wash his Shirt, and found the Lead in the Pond.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150037"></xptr>Defence. I went out that Morning in order to wash a coarse dirty Shirt; I was ashamed to be seen doing it by any body, because it was torn and ragged. I went to one Pond, and saw People there, so I went to another, and as I was washing it, I saw Lead in the Pond. I hung my Shirt up to dry, and walked to and fro while it was drying, and saw two Men walking about; I threw the Shirt from me least they should laugh at me, and imagining they would come and find the Lead, I thought I might take some of it too to make Shot, and finding the Bag, I took a little out and put it into the Bag.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person485">
                  Erasmus 
                  Preia 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person485" type="surname" value="Preia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person485" type="given" value="Erasmus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner came into England with Esquire Burrard, who had serv'd as a Voluntier in the Russian Army, against the Turks. When the Prisoner first lodged with me, I liv'd in King-Street, St. James's, but now I live in Leicester-fields. On the 25th of April, the Prisoner went to Bed at a little after 10, and I lock'd up the Doors and took the Key with me. I deliver'd the Key to my Maid a little after 6, that my Lodgers might go out to Work, and I did not see the Prisoner afterwards. I take him to be very honest; he always kept the best Company; but never gam'd at Cards, or any thing like it. He had washed his Linnen often himself, and used to wash his Master's, when in the Russian Camp .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person486">
                  John Christopher 
                  Mendel 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person486" type="surname" value="Mendel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person486" type="given" value="John Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner; ed with him in that Gentleman's House all the Winter. On the 25th of April he lay with me all Night . I awak'd several Times in the Night and found him abed, and we 'rose together at half an Hour after 5 in the Morning, but I went out and left him at Home. I don't know any thing about his going out that Morning in particular , but I know he frequently used to go into the Fields to wash his Shirts, because he did not care that any Body should see them.</p>
               <p>Jury to Prtia. How far is it from your House to Paddington .</p>
               <p>Prtia. About half a Mile.</p>
               <p>Mendel. He never lay out all Night, but behaved very civilly, and frequented no bad company.</p>
               <p>Mr. Burrard . I have known the Prisoner since last June was Twelve-months, I had leave from his Majesty to make a Campaign under Count Munich, in 1738, and he came from abroad with me. He lived in my House, and behaved himself as a diligent Servant, and I always thought him as honest a Fellow as ever I knew in my Life. My Brother gave me a Character of him, and he had 'trusted him by himself through Poland with his Baggage, where he did not meet with a House, or an Inhabitant for 100 miles. I really believe the man to be as innoceent of this as myself. He propos'd to go into the India Service, if this had not happened.</p>
               <p>Mr Bromfield. I have known the Prisoner about 12 months; I have been frequently in this Gentleman's House, and never heard a better Character of any one in my Life.</p>
               <p>Mr Burrard again. When he has been with me, he has not had his Cloaths off for 3 Weeks together, and if he had had a mind to have wrong'd me and gone off, I could not have enquired after him, because I could not speak the Language of the Country. He has had frequent Opportunities in my House, to wrong me, if he had been so inclined. He has the best of Characters, I never saw him drunk in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person487">
                  Earnest 
                  Cibber 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person487" type="surname" value="Cibber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person487" type="given" value="Earnest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew him at Petersburgh , in Muscovy, he lived with an Ambassador at that Place. I am a Goldsmith, and have entrusted him, and he always behaved very honestly. I took him to be a very sober man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-66-person488">
                  Christian 
                  Lisener 
               <interp inst="t17401015-66-person488" type="surname" value="Lisener"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person488" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-person488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a Year, he always behaved well, and I never heard any Harm of him in my Life. I have been at his Master's House, and was always desirous of his Company. <rs id="t17401015-66-verdict357" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-66-verdict357" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.* </p>
               <p>*This Trial came on in a former Sessions, but was then omitted merely for want of Room.</p>
            </div1>
