<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450911-20">
               <interp inst="t17450911-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-20" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-20" type="date" value="17450911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-20-off98-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-20-defend192 t17450911-20-off98 t17450911-20-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>320. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-defend192" type="defendantName">
                     Monica 
                     Branning 
                  <interp inst="t17450911-20-defend192" type="surname" value="Branning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-defend192" type="given" value="Monica"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-defend192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17450911-20-defloc97">Christ Church, Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-20-defloc97" type="placeName" value="Christ Church, Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-20-defloc97" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-20-defend192 t17450911-20-defloc97"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450911-20-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450911-20-victim194" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Grayley 
                        <interp inst="t17450911-20-victim194" type="surname" value="Grayley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-20-victim194" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-20-victim194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-20-off98 t17450911-20-victim194"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain alley or open place, near the King's highway, putting him in fear, &amp;c. and taken from him a watch, with an inside and an outside case made of silver, value 5 l. a silver chain, val. 10 s. and a silver seal, val. 1 s.
            </rs> his property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person195">
                  Nicholas 
                  Grayley 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person195" type="surname" value="Grayley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person195" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a <rs id="t17450911-20-viclabel99" type="occupation">bricklayer and plaistrer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-20-victim194 t17450911-20-viclabel99"></join>. Some time in January last, I had been at Mr. Sparks's house in Phoenix Street, Spittle Fields , with a neighbourly club; I pulled out my watch to see what it was o'clock, and it was past eleven, and I went away, and at the corner of <placeName id="t17450911-20-crimeloc100">Buttermilk Alley, cross Phoenix Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-20-crimeloc100" type="placeName" value="Buttermilk Alley, cross Phoenix Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-20-crimeloc100" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-20-off98 t17450911-20-crimeloc100"></join> I wanted to make water, and this woman [the Prisoner] wanted to have a buss of me, and she put one of her hands round my neck, and the other to my fob, and pulled my watch out, I felt it going, and missed it immediately, I put my hand upon her gown, and took hold of it (she had a printed linen gown on at that time) she turned round, and gave me a blow upon my hand, and made me leave my prize; the place was a little slippery, and with that and the blow she gave me, I fell down upon my two hands; upon which she run away, and I do not know which way she took. The next morning I went to the Justice's clerk to get a warrant for her, but I could not find her, she kept out of the way and I have not seen her since till about three weeks ago, when I was watching some goods for the landlord, I saw her go by, and took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner at the house that you was in?</p>
               <p>Grayley. Yes, I found out who she was, and I went to her mother's, and her mother told me she had not been at home all night, and said, she was a sad creature.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When did you miss your watch?</p>
               <p>Grayley. I missed it immediately, and took hold of your gown directly .</p>
               <p>Q. How can you be sure she is the person?</p>
               <p>Grayley. I saw her face very plain in Buttermilk Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Grayley. It was between dark and light.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you return back to the house afterwards?</p>
               <p>Grayley. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you complain that you had lost your watch?</p>
               <p>Grayley. When I went into the house, the woman of the house said, Mr. Grayley, I suppose you have lost your watch, and I said, yes madam, I have.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person196">
                  William 
                  Sparks 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person196" type="surname" value="Sparks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person196" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep that house; the Prosecutor and the Prisoner were in my house that evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in company together?</p>
               <p>Sparks. Only in publick company, in the publick room. The Prosecutor went out first, and in eight or ten minutes, as near as I can guess, the Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110013"></xptr> soner went out after him: I wondered that he was gone, so went to look for him in the yard, but he was not there: as I was going to shut up the windows, he came and gave me a blow cross the back with his cane; said I, what is that for, Mr. Grayley! and then I heard a noise about the watch, and that he had lost it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he declare when he came back that he had lost his watch?</p>
               <p>Sparks. When he struck me cross the back he did not say any thing about the watch, but pushed into the house directly, and then the company were all gone except his wife and another.</p>
               <p>Grayley . Did not I ask you what the woman's name was?</p>
               <p>Sparks. Yes, and I told you her name.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in liquor or not?</p>
               <p>Sparks. Indeed, to my belief, neither the Prosecutor nor the Prisoner were sober.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. His wife was drunk and lay cross two or three chairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person197">
                  Ann 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person197" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person197" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner a great while, she takes in dubbling, and goes out frequently with heavy loads, and if she was a bad creature she would hardly work so hard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person198">
                  Ann 
                  Rot 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person198" type="surname" value="Rot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person198" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner three quarters of a year, and I never knew any harm of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person199">
                  Mary 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person199" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person199" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She lived with me two years and an half, and I had things of great value, and she never wronged me of any thing; and when work was slack, I know she and her child have lived a day upon a pennyworth of Leg of Beef.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person200">
                  Mary 
                  Lynch 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person200" type="surname" value="Lynch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person200" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her these eight years, I have sent her many a time with my husband's watch, and she was always very honest; but I have heard there is money for taking her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-20-person201">
                  John 
                  Marioge 
               <interp inst="t17450911-20-person201" type="surname" value="Marioge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person201" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the Headborough's of the parish of Christ Church, where this fact was committed; and very often we are disturbed by people in that passage, and I do say it is impossible to swear to the face of a person in that place, for there is never a lamp in it. I would do the fair thing by every body, and that is the reason of my speaking in this affair.</p>
               <p>Sparks. It is a dark ugly place, and it is difficult to distinguish a person's face there; and if there is a lamp in the day, it is knocked down in the night. <rs id="t17450911-20-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-20-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
