<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490405-19">
               <interp inst="t17490405-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-19" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-19" type="date" value="17490405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490405-19-off91-c107" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-defend141 t17490405-19-off91 t17490405-19-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050009"></xptr>260. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490405-19-defend141" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17490405-19-defend141" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-defend141" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-defend141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17490405-19-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490405-19-victim143" type="victimName">
                           Bartholomew 
                           Fleming 
                        <interp inst="t17490405-19-victim143" type="surname" value="Fleming"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-19-victim143" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-19-victim143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-off91 t17490405-19-victim143"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's high-way of a silver watch, val. 4 l. one pair of shoe buckles, val. 5 s. and 5 d. in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490405-19-cd92" type="crimeDate">Mar. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-off91 t17490405-19-cd92"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-19-person144">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Fleming 
               <interp inst="t17490405-19-person144" type="surname" value="Fleming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person144" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Golden-key in Drury-lane, I am a <rs id="t17490405-19-viclabel93" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-victim143 t17490405-19-viclabel93"></join>, and had some business to do at the Swan-Tavern opposite Somerset-house in the Strand; I stayed there pretty late March the 2 d 'till about two o'clock in the Morning of the 3 d. I had just parted from Mr. Ives , I went by the prisoner at the bar with another person with him, who is not yet taken; this was betwixt <placeName id="t17490405-19-crimeloc94">Catherine-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-19-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="Catherine-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-19-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-off91 t17490405-19-crimeloc94"></join> end, and the <placeName id="t17490405-19-crimeloc95">New Church in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-19-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="New Church in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-19-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-off91 t17490405-19-crimeloc95"></join>, they demanded my money, the Prisoner took my watch out of my fob , while the other held me by the collar; the prisoner had then a loose coat on, I believe the same he has now; he took 5 s. out of my pocket, he stooped down and took the buckle out of my left shoe, and then out of the right; with the last he took the strap of my shoe. Mr. Turberfile was going by at the same time, he seemed not to understand what they were upon; he turned about and after observing them said, Are you at that Sport; then have at you. I believe he did not strike them; they took to their heels, the prisoner ran towards the New Church, there he stumbled and fell, Mr. Turberfile was foremost, and I close behind him; so by that means we secured him. We had more assistance come by my calling out Watch! Watch! the watch was drop'd down betwixt the prisoner's legs. Mr. Hussey took it up; the buckles and strap were brought to me by two different hands who picked them up the next day.</p>
               <p>Mr. Turberfile . I know the prosecutor from that night ; I was passing by at the time I saw three men up against the wall together, I suspecting they were at no good went up and asked them what they were about, the prisoner and one other ran and left the prosecutor; one ran up Eagle-court, and the prisoner ran towards the New-church. I cannot swear this is the man I took, I was not at the Justice's the next day; the watch was found on the ground between his feet where I took hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the man that was robbing the prosecutor is the man that stumbled and fell, and him that you took?</p>
               <p>Turberfile . That I am sure of?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-19-person145">
                  Henry 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17490405-19-person145" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person145" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am the constable; the prisoner at the bar is the man that Mr. Turberfile delivered into my custody about two o'clock that morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-19-person146">
                  Thomas 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17490405-19-person146" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person146" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I heard the cry Watch! Watch! I ran and saw Mr. Flemming had hold of the prisoner : I ask'd what was the matter ; he told me he had been robb'd of his watch, &amp;c. I saw between the prisoner's feet the watch lie, I did not see it drop, I took it up, and deliver'd it to Mr. Smith a brewer.</p>
               <p>Harper Smith. I was coming by in the morning about two o'clock, Mr. Hussey call'd to me, knowing me, and said there was a gentleman had been robb'd ; I went and saw the watch on the Ground, and saw Mr. Hussey take it up, and he gave it to me, and I deliver'd it to the constable .</p>

               <p>Thomas Green . I am a watchman, I heard the cry Watch, at little Drury-lane end, I ran down the lane with my lanthorn and staff, and saw these four gentlemen and the prisoner; he had a bloody nose: Mr. Fleming gave me charge of the prisoner, I charg'd four of them to assist me; the prisoner much oppos'd going with me, I was obliged to give him some blows to quell his obstinacy ; so we took him to the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490405-19-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490405-19-punish97" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-19-punish97" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-19-defend141 t17490405-19-punish97"></join>
               Death
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
