<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430413-31">
               <interp inst="t17430413-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-31" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-31" type="date" value="17430413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430413-31-off191-c313" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-31-defend382 t17430413-31-off191 t17430413-31-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>216. 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-defend382" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-31-defend382" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-defend382" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-defend382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17430413-31-defloc190">St Mary le Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430413-31-defloc190" type="placeName" value="St Mary le Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430413-31-defloc190" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-31-defend382 t17430413-31-defloc190"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17430413-31-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Silver Coral, val. 5 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-victim384" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-31-victim384" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-victim384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-victim384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-31-off191 t17430413-31-victim384"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17430413-31-cd192" type="crimeDate">April 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-31-off191 t17430413-31-cd192"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-person385">
                  John 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17430413-31-person385" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person385" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Wife missed the Coral on Wednesday the 6th of April; I had been out, and when I came home, my Wife was crying about it; said I, Do not make yourself uneasy we shall find it presently; but not finding it, I advertised it; and on Thursday I was sent for by a Silversmith, who keeps a Shop by Clare-Market; says he, there is one Morris brought such a Coral to my House to know the Value of it, and I told him I would give no more than six Shillings for the Silver; I went to Col. De Veil to get a Warrant for this Morris, and went with Mr Trent the next Morning, to the House were he lived; his Wife said he was out, but would be at home about 10 o'Clock; Trent called out, Morris, and one said, he was in Bed; said Morris, So I am: He desired Morris to come to him to Clare-Market, which he did: Says he, Mr Parker says you or I have got a Coral of his, and Morris confessed he took it away: I asked him how he could take it away without being seen? said he, There was no Body in the Kitchen where the Coral was, but the Maid belonging to the House, and when she went out of the Kitchen to do something, I happened to knock my Elbow against a Basket, and hearing the Bells ring, I took and put it into my Pocket; he said, he had pulled the blue String out and gave it to his Wife; the Prisoner sent to his Wife to let her know the Coral was in such a Drawer, and sent Orders for her to deliver it, which she did: he desired not to go before Justice De Veil, so I carried him before Justice Frasier. The Prisoner did not deny it, he said, he was a little in Liquor, or he would not have done it - Morris has sometimes been a Bailiff's Follower.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever think that I could be a Thief?</p>
               <p>Parker. I never thought you to be so; you were the last Man I should have suspected - I take this to be my Coral, it is the Coral that was fetched from the Prisoner's House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-person386">
                  Henry 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17430413-31-person386" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person386" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner said, the Coral was in such a Drawer, in his Room, at the farther Corner, and this Man (Pritchard) went and fetched the Coral - the Prisoner said, he took the Coral out of the Cradle, in the Kitchen, at Parker's House.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174304130026"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-person387">
                  William 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17430413-31-person387" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person387" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Morning that Mr Parker had Intelligence of his Coral, he got a Warrant, and desired me to go and find Morris; I went to Mr Trent's and told the Story, and Mr Trent said, I will go to his Room, I am sure he will answer me; that he went and called Morris, and his Wife said, he was not at home; said he, I am sure he is in Bed; says Morris, That's true, so I am; and Mr Trent went with him to an Alehouse in Clare-Market; after they had been there a little while, says Trent, There is something I have to say to you about Parker's Coral; they went to another House, and Morris owned that he was sitting in the Kitchen, and the Maid desired him to rock the Cradle while she went for a Pint of Beer, or something, and that his Arm hit against the Basket and shook it, and he heard the Bells ring, and that he took the Coral and put it into his Pocket; says he, Here is the String of the Coral, and took it out of his Pocket and delivered it up, and said, The Coral is in my Drawer, at the further Corner; I went for it, and the Drawer was opened and there it was, it was rolled up just in the same Manner it is now.</p>
               <p>Parker. He said he was in Necessity and wanted a little Money to get into his Place of a Bailiff, and he said, when he had got this Coral he thought he should not be beholden to any Body, and that was the Reason of his taking it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr Trent had sent me to wait for a Man in Craven's-Buildings, and I found the Coral as I was coming out at a Door, and the next Day when I came to Mrs Parker's she talked of losing a Coral, and said, it was worth a Guinea and an half, and I went to this Goldsmith's to enquire the Value of it, that I might know whether it was her Coral or no; (I put the String into my Pocket) and I advised her to advertise it on Wednesday.</p>
               <p>- Shudall. I have known the Prisoner 20 Years; he was born in the Neighbourhood, and I think it probable that if he had been guilty of any such Thing before, I might have heard of it, which I never did.</p>
               <p>- Coombs. I have known the Prisoner 19 Years, and have been Security for him many Years; I have trusted him in a great many Affairs and never found him faulty; I was surprised when I heard this. - I am a Taylor and Salesman in narrow-high Holbourn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-person388">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430413-31-person388" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person388" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 24 or 25 Years, he has been frequently with me in Appraisements and Sales, and I never knew him to wrong any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-31-person389">
                  John 
                  Caesar 
               <interp inst="t17430413-31-person389" type="surname" value="Caesar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner twelve Years; some time ago there was a Fire happened in the Neighbourhood where he lived, and he desired me to let him bring his Goods to my House; he lived with me about three Quarters of a Year; I have employed him as an Officer eight or nine Years, and he has always done his Business very honestly, and was always so charitable, that if he arrested a poor Prisoner, he would give them Victuals and Drink for nothing, as far as was in his Power, and has very often gone and made Matters up with the Plaintiff.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I waited for the Person who saw me pick up the Coral, but he is not come, though he is the most material Evidence. <rs id="t17430413-31-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430413-31-punish194" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-punish194" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-31-punish194" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-31-defend382 t17430413-31-punish194"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
