<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-17">
               <interp inst="t17400227-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-17" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-17" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-17-off104-c143" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-defend190 t17400227-17-off104 t17400227-17-verdict109"></join>
         
               <p>171. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ogden 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-17-defend190" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-defend190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400227-17-defloc103">Harrow on the Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-17-defloc103" type="placeName" value="Harrow on the Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-17-defloc103" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-defend190 t17400227-17-defloc103"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-17-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-17-victim192" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Vincent 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-17-victim192" type="surname" value="Vincent"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-17-victim192" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-17-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-off104 t17400227-17-victim192"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , between the Hours of 1 and 2 in the Night, and stealing a Moidore, 8 Guineas, 6 half Guineas, and 5 l. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400227-17-cd105" type="crimeDate">January 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-off104 t17400227-17-cd105"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Vincent. I am a <rs id="t17400227-17-viclabel106" type="occupation">Baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-victim192 t17400227-17-viclabel106"></join>; I live at <placeName id="t17400227-17-crimeloc107">Harrow on the Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-17-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="Harrow on the Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-17-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-off104 t17400227-17-crimeloc107"></join> : the Prisoner had been my <rs id="t17400227-17-deflabel108" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-17-defend190 t17400227-17-deflabel108"></join>, and left me a Fortnight before last Michaelmas. On the 18th of January, as I was coming from my Bed, to come down into the Bakehouse, my Apprentice called, and told me he fear'd the House was broke open. I immediately went up a Ladder into the Kitchen, to the Place where my Money lay, and saw the Corner Cupboard broke open, and the Money gone. There was 18 l. 17 s. in it, but it was all taken away. One Piece was a Moidore, the rest were Guineas, half Guineas, and Silver, and among the Gold were 6 half Guineas. I went down immediately to the Boy in the Bakehouse, and told him I had lost my Money; and seeing a Faggot mov'd, and set in the Place where the Prisoner used to set them when he lived with me, I suspected him to have done it. When I came to look farther, I saw a Hole broke in the Wall in the Bakehouse, big enough for a Man to creep through. There is a Pair of flat Doors which lean against the House, and under these Doors there is Brickwork of 18 Inches or 2 Feet high: the Frame of the Doors is laid upon this Brick-work, and these Doors open into the Bakehouse. The Hole was made through this Brick-work; therefore I thought it must be somebody that knew the House as well as I; and I told my Boy, that I believ'd it was the Prisoner who had done it; and upon making Enquiry in the Country after him, a Countryman of his told me, he saw him the very Day before I was robb'd in a very mean Capacity, and that the Shoes on his Feet were not worth 3 Pence. After this I had a Messenger came from Watford to tell me, he was seen there the Monday following, with a great deal of Gold and Silver in his Pockets, by 
               <persName id="t17400227-17-person193">
                  John 
                  Runnington 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person193" type="surname" value="Runnington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person193" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and from several other Circumstances I was confirmed in my Suspicion of the Prisoner, and at last I took him at the Running-Horse in David-Street , and carried him before Colonel 
               <persName id="t17400227-17-person194">
                  De 
                  Veil 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person194" type="surname" value="Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person194" type="given" value="De"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person194" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and there he said, he got this Money by a Bank Note of 15 Guineas, and deny'd his being concerned in this Robbery. Colonel De Veil told him, there was no such Thing as a Bank Note for 15 Guineas; and upon his second Examination he said, he had it from a young Woman who is now in Court, (
               <persName id="t17400227-17-person195">
                  Anne 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person195" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person195" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) and that he was drunk, when he was first examined; but he was as sober then, as I am now. One principal Reason of my suspecting the Prisoner, was the placing the Faggots: for they lay upon the Stairs at Night when I went to Bed: but when I got up they were moved, and set against the Wall, on the Right-hand of the Stairs, where the Prisoner always placed them, when he lived with me: besides, he had been lurking about the Country, and never had been in any Business, since he left my Service. I am sure the Faggots were moved, and that the Hole in the Wall was not there when I went to Bed, over Night at 9 or 10 o'Clock. I got up the next Morning between 5 and 6; 'twas the 17th of January, and I believe it was not Day-light when I 'rose: but I can't be particular, whether it was Day-light, or Moon-light: 5 o'Clock is our usual Time of rising, and I believe it was about that Time. The Boy lies in the Bakehouse, and called to me before I came down Stairs, to tell me he was afraid the House was broke: and I saw the Hole the Minute I came down Stairs. If I was to die, I can't be sure, whether I had a Candle</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270016"></xptr>When I came down, but I believe I had one. The Money was in a white earthen Decanter , which holds two Quarts, and is large enough for me to put my Hand in, and the Silver was in one Bag and the Gold in another. I was so much surprized at the Loss of my Money, that though the Hole in the Wall was made quite through into the Street, yet I can't say whether I saw Day-light thro' the Hole, or not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you always get up at an Hour when I lived with you?</p>
               <p>Vinsent . Much about the same Hour. It was certain, as near as could be. Sometimes when we have been up a Night or two at Work, I may lie a little longer than ordinary, - but it is very rare I do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person196">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person196" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person196" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am above 15 Years old, and am Apprentice to Mr Vincent, and saw the Faggots removed and the Hole that was made in the Brickwork, that Night my Master was robbed, but I can't tell what day Day of the Month it was. I only know it was Thursday Night. The Faggots were removed from the Place where they were set over Night, and were put where the Prisoner always used to set them. While he liv'd with my Master, I have often seen him loosening the Bricks where the Hole was made, but I cannot say at what particular Time he loosened them, nor how near to the Time of his going away. I lie in the Bakehouse, and remember I saw Light come thro' the Hole; I thought it was Daylight, for I saw a Woman (thro' the Hole) lighting her Fire on the other side of the Way. I think it was quite Light.</p>
               <p>Jury. Can you tell what Month it was, when this was done?</p>
               <p>Clark. No; but I believe it was 5 or 6 Weeks ago: and I believe it was between 5 and 6 in the Morning when I saw the Hole, so I was 'frighted, and lay till I heard my Master come down; then I told him I was afraid he had been robbed. 'Twas about 6 o'Clock when he came down. He uses to get up between 6 and 7, that is his usual Time. When I told him the House was broke, he ran up into the Kitchen, and returned and told me he had lost 18 l. 17 s. and looked at the hole in the Wall. I am sure it was not there when we went to Bed. I heard a Noise twice in the Night, but I was not thoroughly awake, nor did I imagine any body was in the House, nor did I see the Hole at either of those Times when I heard the Noise. The first of my seeing the Hole was when the Light came in from the Woman's Fire in an opposite House. When the Prisoner was taken up, he said, he had a Bank-Note from his Father for 15 Guineas, and he had changed the Note at a Banker's, but he would not tell the Banker's Name, he said he would take another Opportunity for that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mention one Time when you saw me loosening the Bricks.</p>
               <p>Clark. I can't say what Day, or Month it was, but I have seen him doing it several Times.</p>
               <p>Jury. What did he loosen the Bricks with?</p>
               <p>Clark . With nothing but his Hand; and I observed they were loosened by his pushing them. I did not tell my Master of this, for he saw him as well as I.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person197">
                  George 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person197" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person197" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Shoemaker's Shop, at Pinner, two Miles from Harrow. One Thursday in January, (but I can't tell the Day of the Month, to the best of my Knowledge, 'twas the 17th) the Prisoner came to my Shop, and asked for his Countryman, who had lived with me. I told him, he had been gone from me 3 Weeks before Christmas.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That's the Man that told Mr Vincent, I was in such a mean Condition.</p>
               <p>Howard . He was then in the same Cloaths, that he's in now; only he had Boots on then; and when he was before the Justice he was in his Shoes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Time did I leave you at Pinner?</p>
               <p>Howard. Between 11 and 12 at Noon: He staid with me about half an Hour, and whither he went, when he left me, I know not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Discourse passed between us?</p>
               <p>Howard. That which I have mentioned. He likewise asked me when I saw Nan Wood, because (said he) I was to have been married to her last Monday, and instead of that, I came to London, and left her waiting at Watford , to be married.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person198">
                  John 
                  Runnington 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person198" type="surname" value="Runnington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person198" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was drinking with the Prisoner at Haddington , about 5 or 6 Weeks ago, and he pulled out some Gold, and offered to lend me a Guinea. I thanked him for his Love, and told him, I did not chuse his Money. Then he pulled out some Silver, and offer'd me a Crown, a Half-crown, or a Shilling. I thanked him, and refused his Silver likewise. To the best of my Knowledge, he had about 8 or 10 Guineas in a Paper, and about 30 Shillings in Silver. He wanted me to come to London with him, but I told him my Money proved short, and I would go Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person199">
                  William 
                  Dawes 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person199" type="surname" value="Dawes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In January last, (but I can't tell what Day) I came to London with the Prisoner, from Watford in Hertfordshire . He lodged<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270017"></xptr> with me a Night or two at the Coach and Running Horses in David-street. Then I missed him 1 or 2 Nights (I can't tell which) out of my Company. I can't tell what Nights they were, but when he returned, I saw a pretty deal of Money, 9 or 10 Guineas, and a Watch in his Pocket, and he had none when he left me, for I had paid 16 d. for him. He told me he had the Money from a Friend in Town; and the Watch he said he had had these 7 Years; but I never saw it before. I believe it was the 17th or 18th of Jan. when I miss'd him, but I cannot be sure.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not the young Man, that came to Town with us, agree with me, to go again into the Country on Friday.</p>
               <p>Runnington. 
               <persName id="t17400227-17-person200">
                  John 
                  Snoxon 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person200" type="surname" value="Snoxon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to Town with us, and I heard such a Question asked, but I can't tell whether Snoxon agreed to go down again with the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if I was not in his Company all Thursday Evening, and if I did not lie with him that Night?</p>
               <p>Runnington. I can't be positive. On my Word I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person201">
                  Peter 
                  Merchant 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person201" type="surname" value="Merchant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person201" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner produce a Watch before the Justice, and it was a Watch I had sold about 6 or 7 Weeks before, for 3 l. 10 s. but I can't take on me to say, the Prisoner is the Man who bought it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-17-person202">
                  Anne 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17400227-17-person202" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person202" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I thought the Prisoner had been an honest Man: He has borrow'd Money of me several times; he has had different Sums of me, from 10 s. to 20 s. never so much as 14 or 16 l. nor any at all in Jan. last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was to have been married to her; but I came to Town with some young Fellows, instead of going to be married. She knows I went to my Father's in the Country, and brought up Money to be marry'd to her.</p>
               <p>Wood. He went down into Northamptonshire about Michaelmas, and came up again after Christmas, with some Money; but I know not how much. The Sums I lent him, were some before he went to see his Father, and some after, but none in January.</p>
               <p>Prisoner to Dawes. Did not I bear Snoxon's Charges as we came to Town?</p>
               <p>Dawes . He paid something for him, but I can't tell what. <rs id="t17400227-17-verdict109" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-17-verdict109" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
