<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440912-55">
               <interp inst="t17440912-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-55" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440912-55" type="date" value="17440912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440912-55-off312-c494" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-defend605 t17440912-55-off312 t17440912-55-verdict316"></join>
         
               <p>413. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-defend605" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Lodge 
                  <interp inst="t17440912-55-defend605" type="surname" value="Lodge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-defend605" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-defend605" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440912-55-defloc311">St. Botolph Aldersgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-55-defloc311" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph Aldersgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440912-55-defloc311" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-defend605 t17440912-55-defloc311"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17440912-55-off312" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-off312" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-off312" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for the murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440912-55-victim607" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Diggle 
                        <interp inst="t17440912-55-victim607" type="surname" value="Diggle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-55-victim607" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440912-55-victim607" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-off312 t17440912-55-victim607"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by striking him with his right fist upon his left eye, and thereby giving him a mortal bruise on the <rs id="t17440912-55-cd313" type="crimeDate">2d day of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-off312 t17440912-55-cd313"></join> last, of which he languished till the 8th day of the same month and then died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person608">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Diggle 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person608" type="surname" value="Diggle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person608" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person608" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband was a <rs id="t17440912-55-viclabel314" type="occupation">Constable, and kept a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-victim607 t17440912-55-viclabel314"></join> in Little-Britain. Mr. Newman and the Prisoner who is his <rs id="t17440912-55-deflabel315" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440912-55-defend605 t17440912-55-deflabel315"></join>, came in pretty much in liquor, about 10 o'clock the 2d of July; my husband went home with them, and in about a quarter of an hour returned with the jelly of his eye hanging upon his face; my husband went home with Mr. Newman, who being fuddled , was put to bed, and Mrs. Newman desired my husband (as being Constable) to stay with her for fear the Prisoner should murder her; he stayed, and desired the Prisoner to go to bed, upon which he abused my husband: Said Mrs. Newman, are not you ashamed to abuse Mr. Diggle, he is Constable? And he said, Let him be Constable or Churchwarden I'll do for him, (he was then lying upon the ground) and immediately got up, and my husband observed him to put his hand into his pocket, and pull out a little instrument they use in coral making, and jobbed it into his eye, and when he had done he hit him twice with his double fist over it, and said, G - d d - n you I have done for you. - My husband said he did not give him any affront, and continued in the same story till his death, he was sensible almost to the last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person609">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Doo 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person609" type="surname" value="Doo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person609" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person609" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Diggle, I saw the Prisoner strike my master three blows, only because he interposed between him and his mistress: the Prisoner abused his mistress, and offered to strike Mr. Diggle, and Mrs. Newman said don't strike Mr. Diggle for he is Constable, and he said, Let him be Constable or Churchwarden, or what he will, I'll do for him; he forced in between my master and his mistress, and struck him several blows. Mrs. Newman bid me call my mistress, and said he would murder my master. My master called him rogue; the Prisoner said, what do you call me rogue for? D - n you I'll have your eyes for it, and run at him immediately and knocked him down: I went out to call for help, and in a minute's time the accident happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person610">
                  Thomas 
                  Buckmaster 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person610" type="surname" value="Buckmaster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person610" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person610" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, that he heard a quarreling for a good while together, and heard the Prisoner say he would not be served so by a Constable; that he saw the Prisoner's and the Deceased's hands both up together, but who struck first he could not tell, but he presently saw that the Deceased's eye was hanging quite over his face. I did not see any thing in the Prisoner's hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person611">
                  Richard 
                  Foot 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person611" type="surname" value="Foot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person611" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person611" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 2d of July Mr. Newman and the Prisoner were at Mr. Diggle's, and the Prisoner being very much in liquor was supported home by Mr. Diggle on one side, and Mr. Newman his master on the other side; I followed them and heard the Prisoner's mistress was angry with him for being in liquor, and he said, D - n your bl - d you B - b if it had not been for my master, I had gone from you to day. I heard some words, and the Prisoner and the Deceased were standing at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174409120038"></xptr> a considerable distance one from the other in a posture of fighting: and I heard the Prisoner say, Let him be Constable or Churchwarden, by G - d I will do for him. I went back to the Deceased's house, and said for God's sake, gentlemen, let us prevent mischief: and in about a minute's time the unhappy blow was given; the left side of his face was very bloody, and he seemingly not sensible of the damage he had received, sat down in a chair and declined his head upon his left hand, and the Prisoner said, D - n his blood let him be Constable or Churchwarden, I know I have done for him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hett the Surgeon deposed, that the Deceased received a violent bruise upon the sight of the eye, which brought a great inflammation upon the whole eye, and was the occasion of his death. He said it was a lacerated wound, and made by a blunt, and not by a punctured or sharp instrument: the globe of the eye hung over the Deceased's face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person612">
                  Sarah 
                  Bignall 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person612" type="surname" value="Bignall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person612" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person612" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Newman, my master, the Prisoner and the Deceased came home together. My master went to bed at my mistress's desire, to prevent him and the Prisoner from quarrelling: the Prisoner was lying upon the ground, and the Deceased kicked the Prisoner on the foot as he lay upon the ground, and said, get up you dog; the Prisoner said he was in his master's house, and would lie where he pleased, and that his father was as good a man as he. The Deceased said the Prisoner's father might be a thief and a rogue as well as another man; then the Prisoner said to me, mind, he calls my father thief: then the Prisoner got up, and the Deceased said, an't you a deceitful dog, you told your master you could not get up; then the Deceased hit the Prisoner a slap on the face, struck him twice, and called him thief, and then they both fell to fighting - The Deceased struck the Prisoner before he gave him any blow - I can't say the Deceased kicked the Prisoner in anger, it might be to make him get up.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Newman. Mr. Diggle came home with my husband and the Prisoner, and brought some silver home, and laid it upon the table. The Prisoner made a motion to throw the silver at me, with that my husband took him in his arms and they fell down upon the ground, then I persuaded my husband to go up to bed and went up with him, he bid the deceased good night, and bid the Prisoner go to bed; he said, he would not, he would lie there. When I came down the maid said the deceased had called the Prisoner's father old rogue, the Prisoner jumpt up and the deceased called him a deceitful rogue, &amp;c. As in the maid's Evidence. The deceased hit the Prisoner a slap on the face and called him thief, the Prisoner said, call me thief again, and he called him thief again, and then they went to fighting and fell down between a table and a chair, when the deceased got up I saw his eye was bloody - I did not see the Prisoner strike the Deceased till they fell a fighting - the Prisoner did not quarrel with me, he only made a motion to throw the silver at me because he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you desire Mr. Diggle to stay to prevent mischief?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Newman. I was frightened, if I did, I don't know that I said so.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kidney. I went next morning to see the deceased and asked him how the affair happened, he said, he did not know how or in what manner; but that there was something came plunging into his eye at once, after which he seemed to be lost and confused, and could tell no farther about the matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440912-55-person613">
                  Joseph 
                  Gould 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person613" type="surname" value="Gould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person613" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person613" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17440912-55-person614">
                  Thomas 
                  Hind 
               <interp inst="t17440912-55-person614" type="surname" value="Hind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person614" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-person614" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , have known the Prisoner from his birth, never knew him engaged in any quarrel; and did not think he would designedly do any person any harm, and that he is of a mild quiet disposition. <rs id="t17440912-55-verdict316" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-verdict316" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440912-55-verdict316" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
