<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-46">
               <interp inst="t17400709-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-46" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-46" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-46-off234-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-46-defend392 t17400709-46-off234 t17400709-46-verdict237"></join>
         
               <p>337.+ 
               <persName id="t17400709-46-defend392" type="defendantName">
                  Joseph 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17400709-46-defend392" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-defend392" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-defend392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17400709-46-defloc233">St Butolph Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-46-defloc233" type="placeName" value="St Butolph Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-46-defloc233" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-46-defend392 t17400709-46-defloc233"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17400709-46-off234" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-off234" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-off234" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 73 Thirty-six-Shilling-Pieces,13 Guineas,3 Moidores,2 Three Pound Twelve Shilling Pieces, and 4 l.19 s. the Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-46-victim394" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Stephens 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-46-victim394" type="surname" value="Stephens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-46-victim394" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-46-victim394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-46-off234 t17400709-46-victim394"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400709-46-cd235" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-46-off234 t17400709-46-cd235"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution having opened the Charge, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>Mr Stevens . The Prisoner (Joseph Baxter ) is my <rs id="t17400709-46-deflabel236" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-46-defend392 t17400709-46-deflabel236"></join>, and had lived with me about 4 Years. On the 21st of June (Saturday) about 8 o'Clock in the Morning, my Wife and I being in the Chamber, where the Bureau was in which I kept my Money, I counted over my Cash, and settled it; it amounted to 176 l.- After I had so done, I locked my Bureau and came down into my Shop. About 12 at Noon, a Woman having bought a Gold Ring, asked me to give her Gold for 6 Guineas-worth of Silver. I told it over, and finding it all good, I swept it into my Apron; carried it up, and put it into my Bureau, and took out 6 Guineas for it. My Cash was all safe then, and I locked up the Bureau and came down Stairs. About 5 in the Evening a Gentleman in the Neighbourhood sent me a Moidore to change; I went up Stairs and changed it and found my Money still safe: and having locked it up in the Bureau, and put the Key in my Pocket, I came down again into my Shop. About 8 that same Evening, I carried home a Clock to Mile-end; had my Wife been at home, I should have gone sooner. My Son Philip went with me, and carried the Clock, and we returned from thence at a quarter after 9: it was a little before 10 when I got home, and I found my Wife was come home. I went to Supper with my Family, and went out no more that Night. I went to Bed at 11 o'Clock, and the Prisoner was not then come home. My Wife sat up for him till 12, then every Body went to Bed. The Prisoner came home a little while afterwards, and I called up my Son Joseph to let him in. As he went up Stairs, I called to him; and asked him, if he was not ashamed to keep such Hours? He made no Answer, but went up Stairs to Bed. In the Morning my Wife got up between 7 and 8, and about 8 I got up, and went to my Bureau, to empty my Pockets of the Cash I had taken the Day before. But coming to my Bureau, I found it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090036"></xptr> slack and open; and taking hold of the Lid, I found the Lock had been drawn back. I I remember I lock'd it at 5 o'Clock over Night, and finding it thus, I was surpriz'd ; and immediately clapp'd my Hand to the Drawer where I had put my Cash, and found myself stripp'd of all, and not one Farthing of my 176 l. left. Upon this I ran to my Wife,- What shall I do! My dear, what shall I do! I have lost 176 L . Since 5 o'Clock last Night. She went up Stairs with me, and I shew'd her my empty Drawers, at which she was in as great a Surprize as myself. This was on Sunday Morning, and the Prisoner was then in the Shop, cleaning his Buckles, and I being in so great a Surprize, to be sure did not speak softly; yet he took no manner of notice, but while I went up to shew my Wife the Bureau, he went out of Doors. I sent after him, and found him at the Barber's ; and carried him to Gillispy's Lodgings, who is a Person that worked in my House. We found Gillispy in Bed with his Wife; for he works with me, and lodges in my House all the Week, and I give him Leave to go home to his Wife on Saturday Nights. I made Gillispy get up. and I carried them both home to my House; told them of my Loss, and begged of them, if they had any Regard for me or themselves, to make a Discovery of the Money, for I was positive 'twas all safe at 5 o'Clock over Night. I argu'd with them two Hours, and told them the Danger of exposing themselves to the Publick; but I could get nothing out of them. About 12 o'Clock, I charged a Constable with them both, and searched Gillispy's Lodgings, but found nothing. The next Morning they were carried before the sitting Alderman at Guildhall, who after he had examined them both, discharged Gillispy, and committed Baxter the Prisoner. My Family consists of my Wife and 3 Children, one of which went out with me, the other 2 I left at home with the Prisoner: We have no Maid Servant, nor any other Men Servants but the Prisoner and Gillispy: and he (Gillispy) when I went out, followed me at my Heels, for when I was got to Whitechappel Mount , there's a little Field goes round by the Gun, and there we met one another; so he must have come out of my House but a Minute or 2 after me. I live but a little on this side Whitechappel Bars, and it cannot be half a Mile to the Place where I met him. I asked him where he was going? He told me he was going to one Mr Wade's, to see if he could get a Crown which he ow'd him. I told him he might come next Day and take a Dinner with me, and so we parted.[Mr Stevens mentioned the particular Pieces of Money, and the Quantity he had lost, as charged in the Indictment ]. The Prisoner is about 19 Years old. He was about 15 or 16 when I took him, and he had served me about 4 Years. I had but 2 Servants, the Prisoner and Gillispy; and Gillispy has less Time to serve than the Prisoner. For he married a Wife, and left my Service, intending to get into other Business; but that failing, and he being sick, his Wife came to me, and begged I would have some Compassion upon him. Accordingly, I reliev'd him, and ordered an Apothecary to asist him; upon which he promised to serve me out the rest of his Time. Once a Week he begs Leave to lie at his Wife's Lodgings,- on Saturday Night; and he generally comes home on Sunday Night, or Monday Morning. The Witness was asked if he had found the Prisoner honest.- As to that I can't say,- I can't positively prove any thing; but this Question obliges me to say, I have had a strong Suspicion to the contrary; for about 2 Years ago, I missed 20 Guineas out of my Cash out of my Bureau, and my wife and I were very uneasy about it, and the Prisoner at that Time absconded for a Month.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you charge me with it?</p>
               <p>Mr Stevens . I did not directly charge him with the Fact; but I said I had lost Cash, and a little before that I lost a Watch; I did not know what my Loss was; and I told him it looked Suspicious, and I thought it was an imprudent Thing for him to leave his Service after I had had that Loss. When he came again, he made me a great many Promises, that he would be a good Boy, and mind his Business, and that induced me to take him again; as I could not prove any thing upon him. Indeed while he absconded he sent me a Threatning Letter, intimating, that if I did not hold my Tongue, he'd make me.</p>
               <p>Mrs Stevens . I came home about half an Hour after 8, after my Husband was gone out, and I asked my Son Joseph (one of the Children who were left at Home) where his Father was gone?- He said,- to Stepney Green, to put up a Clock, and that he had been gone out about half an Hour. Joe, says I, where are the Keys of the Chamber? for I had lock'd the Chamber Door where the Bureau was, before I went out, and had laid the Keys upon Mr Stevens's Work-board in the Shop. Upon my asking my Son for the Keys, 
               <persName id="t17400709-46-person395">
                  Joe 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17400709-46-person395" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person395" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Prisoner said,- They are o'top of the Board, give them your Mother; and accordingly the child gave them me. I did not ask any one in particular for the Keys, but in general said - Where are the Keys of the chamber? I am sure the Door was fast locked when I went out. After my Son had given me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090037"></xptr> the Keys, I went up Stairs, and bid the Prisoner bring up the Shew-Glass from the Door; and as I put the Key in the Door, the Door went open without unlocking. This surprized me at first, but I thought,- perhaps Mr Stephens might have been up, since I went out, so after he had brought up the Shew-Glass, I locked the Door and put the Keys in my Pocket, and they were never cut of my Pocket,'till I went to bed. When the Prisoner had set down the Shew Glass, I followed him down Stairs, and he desired he might shut up the Shop, because he wanted to go out to buy a new Hat. He went out about 9 o'Clock, and from that Time, to my Husband's coming home, no one had been in the House. He came home about 12 o'Clock, and one of the Children let him in.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he use to keep such Hours?</p>
               <p>Mrs Stevens. Yes; Eleven was a very good Hour,- many Nights he has not come home at all. My Husband and I lay in the Room where the Bureau stood, and no Soul could come into it,- No Creature came into the House the next Morning, for I unchained the Street-Door myself, to take in some Milk.</p>
               <p>Couns. You laid the Keys upon the Board yourself,- before you went out.</p>
               <p>Mrs Stevens. Yes; and there were 3 or 4 Keys together: for my Husband having lost Money before, and People having said,- when a Man and his Wife has Access to it, nothing (with certainty) can be made out, and that I might take it, as well as another, I resolved never to go to the Bureau again.</p>
               <p>Couns. Upon the Oath you have taken, had you been at the Bureau, from the Time your Husband locked it, to the Time he missed the Money?</p>
               <p>Mrs Stevens. No, as God knows my Heart.</p>
               <p>Couns. You left the Keys,(you say) upon the Boards; is that the Place you usually leave them in?</p>
               <p>Mrs Stevens. Yes; when I am going out, my Husband desires me to leave them, else he can't get at his Cash, if he should want it. I went out about 6, and threw them down upon his Board. I returned home about half an Hour after 8, and found my 2 little Boys at home. My Son Philip was gone with his Father.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-46-person396">
                  Joseph 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17400709-46-person396" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person396" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am almost 15 years and a half old.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know the Nature of an Oath?</p>
               <p>Stevens. It is in my Catechism that I must not bear false Witness against my Neighbour,- I was at home that Saturday Night, when my Father went out; Gillispy went out about 3 Minutes after my Father, and only the Prisoner, I and my Brother Samuel, were left at Home.</p>
               <p>Mr Stevens. Samuel is about 11 Years old.</p>
               <p>Stevens. My Mother came home about half an Hour after my Father was gone.</p>
               <p>Couns . Between the Time of your Father's going out, and your Mother's coming home, who came into the House?</p>
               <p>Stevens . Only a Workwoman who brought a Dozen of Spoons, which my Father had bespoke. She gave her Goods into the Shop, and did not stay 3 Minutes. She never went up Stairs; but the Prisoner did: For after my Father was gone out, he cleared away his Work board, and told me he was going up Stairs to black the Shoes. He was above Stairs half an Hour, and I staid in the Shop to look after it. He was above Stairs half an Hour before my Mother came home.</p>
               <p>Couns. When your Father went out, where were the Keys left?</p>
               <p>Stevens . Upon my Father's Work board. The Prisoner was come down Stairs before my Mother came in; as soon as she came in, she asked for the Keys of the Chamber, and the Prisoner said,- they are upon the Board.- Joe , Give them your Mother. I am sure no body went up Stairs while my Father and Mother were out, but he.</p>
               <p>Couns. What Time of the Night did the Prisoner come in?</p>
               <p>Stevens. The Clock had struck 12; my Father called me up, to let him in, and I heard him speak to the Prisoner as he went up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Couns. During the Time that your Father and Mother were out, had you or your Brother been up Stairs?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No; nor near the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you take Notice of the Keys lying on the Board when your Mother went out?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I did not take Notice of that: but my Mother whenever she went out laid the Keys there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-46-person397">
                  Charles 
                  Gillispy 
               <interp inst="t17400709-46-person397" type="surname" value="Gillispy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person397" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr Steven's Apprentice. I remember the Saturday Night when he went to put up the Clock; but I did not see him go out; for I work above Stairs in the Garret, and was there when he went out, but I overtook him at Whitechappel Mount . He was gone out before I came down from Work, which was about 8 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was you in your Master's Room that Saturday?</p>
               <p>Gillispy. No; I was not. My Master came to me on Sunday Morning, and I went home with him: He did not tell me what his Business was,'till I came to his House.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know what Time your Master went out?</p>
               <p>Gillispy. No: I had been at work in the Garret, and nobody had been with me all Day, but the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090038"></xptr> children backwards and forwards, and the Prisoner. I was from 6 in the Morning to 8 at Night in the Garret; then I came down and went out?</p>
               <p>Couns. What Place does the Prisoner clean his Shoes in?</p>
               <p>Gillispy. In one of the Garrets, just by the Place where I work: I can't tell whether he came up to clean his Shoes before I went out,- I believe I should have seen him if he had. His usual Time of cleaning them is after 8 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Couns. As you come down from the Garret, do you pass by your Master's chamber?</p>
               <p>Gillispy. Yes; and if it had been open, I should have seen it; but I did not take any particular Notice of it.</p>
               <p>Couns. to Mr Stevens. When you went up the last Time, about 5 o'clock, did you lock your chamber door?</p>
               <p>Mr Stevens. When I went up at that Time, I found my Wife, and a Gentlewoman reading the Exposition of a chapter in the Romans, out of Barkit. Gillispy was then in the Garret, and the Prisoner and my 2 children were below. <rs id="t17400709-46-verdict237" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-46-verdict237" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
