<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-45">
               <interp inst="t17400116-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-45" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-45" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-45-off211-c236" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-45-defend337 t17400116-45-off211 t17400116-45-verdict215"></join>
         
               <p>132. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-defend337" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hurnell 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-45-defend337" type="surname" value="Hurnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-defend337" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-defend337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he on the 5th of October, in the 10th Year of His Majesty's Reign, in the Parish of St. Bride's, <rs id="t17400116-45-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               took to Wife 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-45-victim339" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Gardiner 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim339" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim339" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim339" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, and to her was then and there married: and afterwards, viz. on the <rs id="t17400116-45-cd212" type="crimeDate">4th of November in the 13th Year of His Majesty</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-45-off211 t17400116-45-cd212"></join>, at the Parish of <placeName id="t17400116-45-crimeloc213">St. Bartholomew, behind the Exchange</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-crimeloc213" type="placeName" value="St. Bartholomew, behind the Exchange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-crimeloc213" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-45-off211 t17400116-45-crimeloc213"></join>, he feloniously took to Wife 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-45-victim341" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Keep 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim341" type="surname" value="Keep"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim341" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-victim341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , Spinster, his former Wife (
                     <persName id="t17400116-45-person342">
                        Mary 
                        Gardiner 
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person342" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-person342" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-45-person342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ) being still living
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution having open'd the Indictment, the Nature of the Evidence, to be offered in Support thereof, was mention'd: and it was urged, that the Defendant (who is a <rs id="t17400116-45-deflabel214" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-45-defend337 t17400116-45-deflabel214"></join> to a Blackwell-Hall Factor) in the Year 1736, having marry'd Mary Gardiner, they lived for some Time at the House of one Watts a Peruke-Maker, and afterwards, at one Carrol's a Barber, at Fleet Ditch, near Holborn Bridge; and that at these 2 Places they lived together as Man and Wife, and had several Children, and were understood by all their Acquaintance to be Man and Wife. That the first Marriage was at the Fleet, but both Shelburn, (the Parson) and the Clerk being dead, they were under some Difficulty in procuring Shelburn's Register-Books. That the Defendant afterwards, getting acquainted with Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17400116-45-person343">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Keep 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person343" type="surname" value="Keep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person343" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person343" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a young Gentlewoman of between 3 and 4000 l. Fortune, (who was an Orphan, and under the Care of the City) he took a Lodging at the House of one Mrs. Immin's, in Winchester-street, where this young Gentlewoman lived with her Grand-mother, Mrs. Graves. When he had lodged here some Time, he took a Lodging in Throckmorton-Street, that when he had accomplished his Ends, he might have a Place to carry her to. That the Defendant in a little Time, by the Assistance of a Servant in the House, got the Lady away, marry'd her, and then carry'd her to Throckmorton Street, and has had the Custody of her ever since, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Couns. Pris. The Expression - [a second Marriage] is not so very proper, but we admit the Marriage with this young Lady, [ Mrs Keep]. It was likewise insisted upon, by the Counsel, in Behalf of the Defendant, that if they should produce a Fleet-Register, [with Relation to the first Woman] it would not be a legal Register, and so would be no Register at all. That Cohabitation was no Proof of a Marriage, not would a Fleet-Register, (if it should be brought) be sufficient to convict a Man of Felony, since even in a Civil Action it would not be allow'd without other Proof. And that, in case of a Felony, it has always been insisted upon, that positive Proof be given of the first Marriage.</p>
               <p>It was farther observed, that giving Evidence of a Cohabitation, before they had prov'd a first Marriage, is like felling a Tree at the Top. And tho' a Man's cohabiting with a Woman in an odd way, is a Crime not to be encouraged, yet it won't prove him guilty of Felony under this Act of Parliament. It was likewise urged, that the Register of a Parish is by Law an Authentick Register, and might be produced as legal Evidence, but where a Clergyman, un-authorized by Law, shall please to set up, in the Fleet, for himself, and who for Half-a-Crown will put any one's Name in his Register, it would be hard if such a Person or his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160024"></xptr> Register, should have the Sanction of a Court of justice.</p>
               <p>Mrs Barret. I knew 
               <persName id="t17400116-45-person344">
                  Anthony 
                  Shelburn 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person344" type="surname" value="Shelburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person344" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Clergyman. He has been dead some Years.</p>
               <p>Couns. Produce the Register-Book he kept.</p>
               <p>Barret. I can produce some of the Books, but not all. The Book I am called here to produce, is not in my keeping, - 'tis not my Book, but another Person's; I never had it in my keeping. I live in Fleet-Lane, but the Book this Marriage is in, belongs to Mr Cox, at the Hand and Pen at the Ditch side. I saw this Book at his House about 2 Months ago, and never have seen it since.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know what's become of this Book ?</p>
               <p>Barret. No: I was at Mr Cox's (he is Clerk) at the Hand and Pen about 2 Months ago, and he told me he was going out, and expected some People to come to search that Book, so he left it upon the Table, and ordered me not to let them search, unless they paid me first. Accordingly 2 Gentlemen came to search, and after they had done, I put the Book into the Beauset, and have never seen at since.</p>
               <p>Couns. Don't you know where the Book is?</p>
               <p>Barret. No, I don't, upon my Word, - upon my Oath I do not.</p>
               <p>Couns. Has no Body apply'd to you about this Book?</p>
               <p>Barret. No.</p>
               <p>Couns. Recollect yourself, - has no Body apply'd to you, to have this Book from you?</p>
               <p>Barret. No, Sir, indeed: nor can I tell where the Book is.</p>
               <p>Couns. What Books are they which you have got with you?</p>
               <p>Barret. They are the Registers of my Husband's Marriages: I can't give any Account of the other Book.</p>
               <p>Couns. Who were the Gentlemen that came to search the Book which we want?</p>
               <p>Barret. I can't tell; but there was two Gentlemen came to me to enquire about the Book, in which was the Marriage with Mary Gardiner.</p>
               <p>Couns. You mention a particular Book; what Entry was it they came to see?</p>
               <p>Barret. They came to search for an Entry, on such a Day, and they were scrupulous about paying; at last one of them said he would pay; after which they search'd, and said they had found it.</p>
               <p>Couns. What did he say he had found?</p>
               <p>Barret. He said he had found the Name he wanted; but he did not mention what the Name was.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not you tell the Gentlemen who came to search, that the Book was your's, and that you had bought it?</p>
               <p>Barret. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Couns. So, you say, you don't know what's become of that Book?</p>
               <p>Barret. No: I put it where I found it, and have never seen it since that Time. It was Mr Cox's Book at that Time; but he is dead, and it went to his Widow: She has since sold it to other Persons, and I know not who they are. When those Gentlemen came to look at it, it was left upon the Table at the Hand and Pen, and I was desired to stay by the Book, till the Gentlemen came. They came and search'd it, after which I put it into the Beaufet; since which it has never been seen at all.</p>
               <p>Dr. Morley was call'd, but did not appear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person345">
                  John 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person345" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person345" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a House-keeper in St. Andrew's Parish: I live by the Fleet-Market now, but for two Years last past, I kept a House in St. Sepulchre's Parish.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know the Prisoner, Hurnell?</p>
               <p>Carrol. Yes. - About two Months before last Christmas was twelve Months, he came and looked at a Room, and said he would send a Gentlewoman, in a Day or two, to see it, and agree for it. The Gentlewoman came, and took the Room, and gave me Earnest for it.</p>
               <p>Couns. How long did he and she remain at your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. 'Till about a Week before last Christmas.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did the Gentlewoman and he lie together at your House, during that Time; and did you imagine they were Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I gave Receipts for the Rent in his Name.</p>
               <p>Couns. Mind what you are ask'd. I ask you whether you have heard him call her his Wife, or make Use of such Expressions, as made you ima gine she was his Wife.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You are upon your Oath.</p>
               <p>Carrol. He used her in a very handsome Manner.</p>
               <p>Couns. But when he has been speaking of her to you, or in your Family, in what Manner has it been? How has he spoke of her?</p>
               <p>Carrol. He and I never changed five Words together, all the Time he was in the House. He went up Stairs, and came down, that's all.</p>
               <p>Couns. Though you might not have exchanged many Words, yet I ask you, if you have not heard him declare any Thing about this Gentlewoman?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160025"></xptr>Carrol. I never heard any Body come to ask for him; but People have ask'd for her.</p>
               <p>Couns. We are a little unfortunate, that we have not the most ready, willing Witnesses in the World. -</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They are your own Witnesses.</p>
               <p>Couns. But I wish some others have not had Dealings with them. I ask you whether they lay at your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. It was backward and forward, - I can't be positive about it.</p>
               <p>Couns. Consider you are upon your Oath, and you must give fair Answers.</p>
               <p>Carrol. Why they pass'd for Man and Wife, and went in one another's Name. I know no otherwise.</p>
               <p>Couns. I ask you whether or no, during the Time they were at your House, you never heard him own her to be his Wife?</p>
               <p>Carrol. He has ask'd for her by the Name of Mrs Arnol.</p>
               <p>Couns. Speak distinctly.</p>
               <p>Carrol. He said Arnol, to the best of my Knowledge. I can say no more.</p>
               <p>Couns. But you can speak distinctly if you will.</p>
               <p>Carrol. He ask'd for her by the Way of Arnol.</p>
               <p>Couns. Why what's the Prisoner's Name.</p>
               <p>Carrol. Arnol.</p>
               <p>Couns. Well, I see here's a bad Pronunciation, as well as a bad Witness. - Has he ask'd for her by the same Name he himself went by?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I say he has not ask'd for her above once, to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Couns. But I ask you, whether he has not ask'd for her by the same Name he went by?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Consider you're upon your Oath.</p>
               <p>Carrol. Why I have receiv'd Letters for Mr Arnol, I never had any Body to ask after him.</p>
               <p>Couns. You have heard him ask for her by the Name of Arnol, and you pronounce his Name in the same Manner. Was that the Name he went by?</p>
               <p>Carrol. She went by the same Name which he went by.</p>
               <p>Couns. And you say they lived at your House, 'till within two Months before last Christmas was Twelve-Months; now I ask you, whether she had not one or more Children at your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. She had one: but I don't know whether it was a Boy or a Girl.</p>
               <p>Couns. I hope this Child was Christen'd.</p>
               <p>Carrol. But I did not see it christen'd, so I am not a Judge.</p>
               <p>Couns. I ask you upon your Oath, if you did not know the Child was christen'd?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I did not see it christened; I don't know any Thing of it.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did it die at your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. Yes; to my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Couns. Perhaps you might be at the I uner' tho' not at the Christening.</p>
               <p>Carrol. No, I was at neither.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you see the Coffin?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I saw the Child.</p>
               <p>Couns. But I ask you if you saw the Coffin?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>Couns. Can you say, you did not?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I don't know, to the best of my Knowledge that I did.</p>
               <p>Couns. How long did it live?</p>
               <p>Carrol. Upon my Word I can't tell. I was not in the Room above half a dozen Times during their living at my House.</p>
               <p>Couns. Why Man, can't you tell whether it lived two or three Months, or but two or three Days?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't tell indeed.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did any Persons attend it, in its Illness, as an Apothecary, or a Physician?</p>
               <p>Carrol. Yes; there was an Apothecary, and a Physician came in his Chariot: but I don't know his Name.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know it if you hear it? Was the Apothecary's Name Avery?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't tell indeed; I did not hear it mentioned, nor the Doctor's Name neither. The Doctor came to Mrs Arnol, I see him come four or five Times.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know the Midwife's Name?</p>
               <p>Carrol. No, nor the Nurse's neither. I never asked them their Names, and how should I know their Names, when I never asked them.</p>

               <p>Couns. When they went from your House, do you know whether they went?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't tell. I know nothing at all of it, 'till the Day she paid me, and then she said, she was going to the other End of the Town, to live nearer at Hand with her Spouse: but he was not present at that Time.</p>
               <p>Couns. Had you no Conversation with him about leaving your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. Not till afterwards. Mr Arnol came to our House afterwards, and we had two or three Words together; I told him Mrs Arnol had not given me proper Warning, and that I expected a Quarter's Rent, if I should not let the Room - I am very ingenuous, - he said, he had given her Money to pay for the Quarter that was passed. -</p>
               <p>Couns. Who did he say he had given the Money to?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160026"></xptr>Carrol. ToMrs Arnol. He did not mention a Word more, but only that he had given her Money for the Quarter which was due, and which was to come. - Her Name was not then mentioned.</p>
               <p>Couns. Why who did you talk of?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I mentioned the Name [Mrs. Arnol] to him, and said I had given Mrs Arnol a Receipt for 1 l. 2 s. and 6 d. due at Christmas I gave the Receipts in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17400116-45-person346">
                  Thomas 
                  Arnol 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person346" type="surname" value="Arnol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person346" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Couns. Did any Friends or Acquaintance come to her at your House?</p>
               <p>Carrol. When People came, they enquired for Mrs. Arnol.</p>
               <p>Couns. I ask you, whether during the whole Time they were at your House, she did not go by the Name of Hurnell?</p>
               <p>Carrol. She always went by that Name, and Letters were directed to her in that Name. I took them to be Man and Wife all the Time they were at our House. They had a two Pair of Stairs Floor: there was a Closet for a Bed, and a little Parlour: there was every Thing very handsome. There was but one Bed, and she used to lie there constantly.</p>
               <p>Couns. And did not the Prisoner lie there?</p>
               <p>Carrol. He came backward and forward; I can't say he lay there constantly; but I have seen him go out in the Morning, and come home o'Nights.</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. I am an Apothecary, and knew the Woman that lived at this Carrol's House, when she went by the Name of Gardiner. I have known her seven Years. While she lived at Carrol's I visited her. She was ill, and had an Inflammation of the Bowels, and lay-in, in the Interim.</p>
               <p>Couns. Have you frequently visited her there?</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. Never as an Apothecary before that Time. I have visited her since, and my Wife has likewise. I was Godfather to the last Child she had at Carrol's House, - it was a Girl.</p>
               <p>Couns. I ask you what Name the Prisoner at the Bar called her by? And what Declarations you have heard him make?</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. I can say nothing to that. Mrs Hurnell requested of me to stand Godfather.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was not the Prisoner present?</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. No; but he was there a little before.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was he present at the Christening?</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. No; he was not; but it was with his Privity that I stood Godfather, because the Question was put to me, and she told him, I was to stand Godfather to the Child. I knew her when she went by the Name of Gardiner, and ever since I have known her, she has born the Character of a very vertuous, good Woman.</p>
               <p>Couns. Were there any Prescriptions wrote for her in her Illness.</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. Yes, and Dr. Morley was the Physician: his Prescriptions were for her, in the Name of Mrs. Hurnell, with this only Difference, her Name with an E, instead of an U.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was you paid for these Prescriptions?</p>
               <p>Avery. Yes; Mrs. Hurnell paid me, and I gave a Receipt in his Name, to her.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you and your Wife visit her?</p>
               <p>Avery. Yes, and she visited us; and since this Affair he has been at out House.</p>
               <p>Couns. On what Errand did he come?</p>
               <p>Avery. It was last Saturday was a Fortnight; he came and put the Question to me as thus. To ask me if I knew any Thing of Mrs. Gardiner? I told him, I did not. He said he had been at Mr. Elliot's, who is a Relation of Mrs Hurnell's, and had enquired after her, but could not hear any Thing of her; so he asked me, if I could tell any Thing of her? I said I could not.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not the Prisoner, when you visited her, ask you how she did? By what Name did he mention her?</p>
               <p>Avery. He has asked me in what Manner I found her, - or how she was ill, but never by any Name: tho' I always took it, that he meaned his Wife. I have called her by the Name of Mrs. Hurnell, to him, and he has never contradicted it.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. I know the Prisoner, Thomas Hurnell, and have visited Mrs. Hurnell, his Wife (as I took her to be) when she lodged at Carrol's House.</p>
               <p>Couns. Give your Reasons why you took them to be Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. Because they always seemed to live together as Man and Wife, and she said, he was her Husband.</p>

               <p>Couns. Have you ever heard him say any Thing like that?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. I never heard him say any Thing at all. I never saw him in his Room, but twice in my Life.</p>
               <p>Couns. Was you at the Christening of any of their Children?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. No: nor at any of her Children's Funerals.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did they ever visit you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. Mrs. Hurnell often did.</p>
               <p>Couns. How was their Way of Living understood in the Neighbourhood?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. I never heard that any one took them for any other, but Man and Wife: and I knew a pretty many of their Acquaintance too.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160027"></xptr>Couns. Has not the Prisoner applied to you lately? On what Occasion?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. About a Fortnight or three Weeks ago, he came to our House, and asked if Mrs. Gardiner was there? I told him, I did not know who he meant: is she not your Wife? He said, No, and asked me if she had paid my Husband. I told him, I believed she had. Because, said he, if she has, I desire your Husband not to trust her any more, in my Name, but on her own Account, for she is not my Wife. I was but very little acquainted with him before this, but I was acquainted with Mrs. Hurnell some Years before, and since she was married. She went by the Name of Gardiner before, and was a very modest Woman, as any one would say that was to see her. She was a sober, modest, fedate Woman, and I never heard otherwise:</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know of any Children being born?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. Yes, two: and I took them to be Mr. Hurnell's, they are both dead. One of them I saw, and as sine a Boy it was, as ever I saw in my Life.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you see the Coffin?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. No, neither of them. It was the first Child which I saw; it was brought to my House by 2 Nurses and the Mother to shew me.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you know any Thing of her after she left Carrol's House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Avery. Yes, for in her deplorable Trouble, she came to give me an Account of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person347">
                  Sarah 
                  Newbury 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person347" type="surname" value="Newbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person347" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I prosess Midwifry; and Mrs. Hurnell being taken ill, at Carrol's House, I was sent for, and she had the Advice of a Physician, ( Dr. Morley) she was with Child, and had a Fever.</p>
               <p>Couns. You call her Mrs. Hurnell, how came you to call her by that Name?</p>
               <p>Newbury. She came to me by that Name, when she was with Child, and directed me to enquire for her by that Name.</p>
               <p>Couns. Have you ever seen the Prisoner at these Lodgings?</p>
               <p>Newbury. Yes, several Times during her Indisposition, and he always treated her, in a very handsome, tender Manner, - as Gentlemen treat their Wives.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he call her by any particular Name?</p>
               <p>Newbury. No, he did not call her by any Name, but he used her in a tender Manner, and desired me to take Care of her.</p>
               <p>Couns. By what Name was the Child christened?</p>
               <p>Newbury. I was not at the Christening, nor at the Funeral.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person348">
                  Jane 
                  Ayres 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person348" type="surname" value="Ayres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person348" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Person whom they formerly called Mary Gardiner, but I did not know her by that Name. I kept her when she lay-in by the Prisoner, at Carrol's House. I know the Prisoner (Hurnell) very well: he used to come sometimes three Times a Day to visit her.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he call her by any particular Name?</p>
               <p>Ayres. I can't say that: but he would come and say, - how does she do now? He never called her by any Name, nor do I remember he ever called her his Wife; but he gave me a great Charge to take care of her, and one Night, he gave me a particular Charge about her. I know she went by his Name.</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you remember the Funeral of the Child?</p>
               <p>Ayres. Yes; I ordered the Coffin myself. It was a Girl, and I went to the Undertaker's and ordered the Name Anne Hurnell to be put upon it. This was the second Child: the first I know nothing of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person349">
                  Rachel 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person349" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person349" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person349" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the Wife of 
               <persName id="t17400116-45-person350">
                  John 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person350" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I know the Prisoner: he came himself to see a Room at our House: I had not Opportunity to shew him the Room he afterwards had, but my Husband shewed him a lower Room of the same fort. About three Days afterwards, Mrs Hurnell and a Relation of her's came and took it, I think it was the 3d of November. last was 12 Months. It was one Apartment, only there was a Place for a Bed in it.</p>
               <p>Couns. Who lay in it?</p>
               <p>Carrol. It was for two Persons, to be sure.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you ever see the Prisoner a-bed?</p>
               <p>Carrol. No: but he used to come in almost every Night, between 7 and 8.</p>
               <p>Couns. Have you seen him go away again o' Nights.</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't say I ever saw him go away again o'Nights; but I think I saw him once go away in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Couns. By what Name did he call her? Or how did he address himself to her?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I can't say he ever asked for her as he went up, or down, our Apartment lies so, that we seldom saw one another.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he come Home, and ask for her when she was abroad?</p>
               <p>Carrol No. The Morning she was brought to Bed, I met him coming up Stairs, and he said, - pray how does my Wife do! I told him, she was more likely to die than to live. This was when she lay in of the last Child, which was a Girl. I never heard him call her Wife, but that Time. Visitors indeed have asked for her by the Name<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160028"></xptr> of Hurnell. and Letters out of the Country have been cirected to her, in that Name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person351">
                  Silisia 
                  Pitts 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person351" type="surname" value="Pitts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person351" type="given" value="Silisia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner; Mrs. Hurnell his Wife, is a Neice of mine: her Maiden Name was Mary Gardiner. Before the Prisoner and she were marry'd she lodged with me, and Mr. Hurnell visited her, every Night, with a great deal of Respect. Soon after they were marry'd, I was taken ill, so I sent for her to come and be with me. -</p>
               <p>Couns. Do you know that they were marry'd?</p>
               <p>Pitts. She declar'd they were marry'd, and I saw him soon after I understood they were marry'd, and I wish'd him Joy of his Wife; he accepted it, and bowed and thanked me. This was about last Michaelmas was 3 Years. I was telling you, she was with me, while I was ill, and the Nights she did not stay with me, he always came and fetch'd her Home.</p>
               <p>Couns. Well, pray what did he use to call her?</p>
               <p>Pitts. I can't say I ever heard him call her any Thing, but Polly and my Dear.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you use to visit them?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes; I visited them as Man and Wife; they cohabited together, and I believed them to be Man and Wife. I judged so from his Behaviour, for he seemed to be very tender of her.</p>
               <p>Couns. You are related to her, pray has she any Sisters?</p>
               <p>Pitts. Yes, 2 or 3, but I never saw any of them in the Prisoner's Company: She has a Mother likewise, but she lives at Birmingham.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Powel. I know the Prisoner, and likewise Mrs. Hurnell. I have known Him, ever since he was marry'd to Mrs. Hurnell, or Mrs. Gardiner. I always thought they were marry'd, and they always appeared as Man and Wife.</p>
               <p>Couns. Have you ever heard him call her his Wife?</p>
               <p>Powel. I never heard him call her Wife; he used to call her Polly, and My Dear. They always behaved well, and he always used her like a Gentleman. I visited them very often after the Marriage, and always took her to be his Wife.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution were about to prove, that this Mrs. Hurnell [or Gardiner] was now living, but the Counsel for the Prisoner admitted it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am innocent of the Fact they charge me with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person352">
                  William 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person352" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person352" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Greville-Street, Hatton-Garden, and am a Peruke-Maker, I know both the Prisoner, and Mary Gardiner; she lodg'd near two Years in my House, and during that Time, I did not take her to be any Man's Wife. She came to live at my House about October or November, in the Year 1736, and continued there about two Years; in all which Time I had no Reason to believe she was marry'd to the Prisoner, nor did he ever call her any Thing but Gardiner, nor did I ever hear any one in the House call her any Thing else. The Prisoner used to come after her, and ask for her by the Name of Gardiner, and by that Name he had Admittance to her. She never pretended to me, nor to any one in my Hearing, that she was marry'd.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did you never see any Letters, which were directed to her at your House, by the Name of Hurnell?</p>
               <p>Watts. I never saw any.</p>
               <p>Couns. And was she never call'd by the Name of Hurnell at your House?</p>
               <p>Watts. There was some few People came after her, and ask'd for one Mrs. Hurnell, who lodged up two Pair of Stairs, and I told them I knew no such Person, - but there was one Mrs. Gardiner, I told them. I afterward told the Prisoner of this, and he seemed surpriz'd, and charged me, if any People came to ask for her by that Name, to tell them there was no such Person liv'd there. He was surpriz'd when I told him People ask'd for her by the Name of Hurnell.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did none of their Relations come to visit them, as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Watts. Never as Man and Wife: they never kept a Table together as Man and Wife, nor did they ever talk of going to visit Relations.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did not the Prisoner lodge there too?</p>
               <p>Watts. No.</p>
               <p>Couns. Did he never lodge there?</p>
               <p>Watts. I don't know that he did. - I believe he may have lodg'd there all Night, but upon my Oath I never saw them together.</p>
               <p>Couns. Why did she not lie-in at your House?</p>
               <p>Watts. I believe she did; but I don't know who visited her: Mr. Hurnell visited her then, as he did at other Times, and ask'd for her by the Name of Gardiner.</p>
               <p>Couns. So tho' you did not take her for a marry'd Woman, yet you permitted her to stay at your House, and Hurnell to visit her.</p>
               <p>Watts. Why, indeed, I did not take her to be a marry'd Woman, for Mr Hurnell told me he had Lodgings at an Apothecary's behind the Change. He was my Customer, and I have sent my Man there for his Wig. 'Twas at one Mr Maddox's in Throgmorton-Street. I am far from<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160029"></xptr> thinking she was his Wife; if she had been so, I believe I should have known it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person353">
                  John 
                  Wynne 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person353" type="surname" value="Wynne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person353" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Mr Watt's Journeyman; and remember Mary Gardiner's lodging at our House. I liv'd with Watts above twenty Months; I came to him in April, - I can't tell the Year; and it is about a Twelve-month ago since I left his Service, in December. She had liv'd there before I came, and was in the House while I continued with Watts; but she went away about a Fortnight or three Weeks before me. During this Time, she went by the Name of Gardiner, and no other, as I know of. Mr Hurnell is a Customer of my Master's; I never took her to be his Wife; it was never suspected she was so, but always to the contrary. If she had been his Wife, I should have known it. - She was always enquired for by the Name of Gardiner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person354">
                  Mary 
                  Wynne 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person354" type="surname" value="Wynne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person354" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't remember the particular Time when Mrs. Gardiner lodged at Watt's; but his Servant, and one Mrs Scriven's (who likewise lodged in the House) being both my Acquaintance, I visited them while Mrs. Gardiner liv'd there, and I have heard them call her Mrs. Gardiner. If she had gone by any other Name, I should have known it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-45-person355">
                  Margaret 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17400116-45-person355" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person355" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Mrs. Gardiner while she lodged at Watts's: She was there about 2 Years, and went by the Name of Gardiner; if she had gone by any other Name, I should have known it, for I lodged 3 Years in the House. I knew her when she lived at Carrol's, and she there went by the Name of Gardiner: I have asked for her at that House, by that Name, and a Boy has told me, she was above Stairs. I never knew she was marry'd in my Life.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cooper. I had a Child to nurse, from Mrs Gardiner, in the Name of Mary Gardiner. I had it 8 Months, and it has been dead a Year, and as much as since last Hay-time. It was christened by the Name of William Gardiner.</p>
               <p>Mr Cooper. I knew Mrs. Gardiner when we took the Child to nurse. My Wife received it by the Name of William Gardiner. I was at the Christening, and stood Godfather; it was baptized by the Name of William Gardiner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ingram. This is the Register-Book of Aldersgate Parish. I believe there is an Entry made of the Christening of a Child of Mary Gardiner, on the 4th of January 1737. The Child was baptized at our Church, on Sunday after Afternoon Sermon. I could not tell whether the Name was Garner, or Gardiner, so I entered it into the Book by the Name of William Garner. The Entry was read. '' Register of all the Marriages, Christen. '' ings and Burials, in St Butolph Aldersgate. '' Christenings, January 1737. Jan. 4. William, '' Son of William and Mary Garner.</p>
               <p>Mr Cooper. The Child was brought from our House at Walthamslow, to their Lodging in Greville-street, and was christened in Aldersgate Church, by the Name of William. It's Sirname was Gardiner. The Mother was there at the same Time, and I don't remember any Dispute about the Name.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's Counsel offer'd to call Mary Gardiner in his Behalf, but it was not permitted them. <rs id="t17400116-45-verdict215" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-45-verdict215" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
