<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480706-21">
               <interp inst="t17480706-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-21" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-21" type="date" value="17480706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480706-21-off106-c154" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-21-defend193 t17480706-21-off106 t17480706-21-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>338. 
               
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-defend193" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Clarenbolt 
                  <interp inst="t17480706-21-defend193" type="surname" value="Clarenbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-defend193" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-defend193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17480706-21-defloc105">St. George, in Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-21-defloc105" type="placeName" value="St. George, in Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-21-defloc105" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-21-defend193 t17480706-21-defloc105"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480706-21-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17480706-21-person194">
                        Thomas 
                        Milward 
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person194" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-21-person194" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-21-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and feloniously demanding the money of the said Thomas, with an intent to rob him
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480706-21-cd107" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-21-off106 t17480706-21-cd107"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-person195">
                  Tho 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17480706-21-person195" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person195" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been taking leave of some captains at the Hermitage, and as I was walking by the two sugar houses, by <placeName id="t17480706-21-crimeloc108">Well-Close-Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-21-crimeloc108" type="placeName" value="Well-Close-Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-21-crimeloc108" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-21-off106 t17480706-21-crimeloc108"></join>, about twelve o'clock at night, I was suspicious of a man that was going along in the highway; the Prisoner did not know me, and I did not know him at first, though I have drank with him many a time. I took my watch out of my fob, and put it into my coat pocket, and I was not afraid to see any body, for I had not much money in my pocket: He came up to me, and said, D - n you, Sir, your money. I struck him on the hand, run after him, and called out watch; and at the end of Neptune-Street there were two watchmen;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060016"></xptr> and he said, D - n you, Sir, I am not afraid of you, if you want me, I will come up to you; and just by a warehouse, which I rent of Alderman Parsons, we seized him, and took him to the watch-house in Well Close-Square.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Milward. Twenty years.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Has he been evidence in any cause in which you was concerned?</p>
               <p>Milward. I owe no body any ill will.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. I ask you whether he has, or has not?</p>
               <p>Milward. I don't know but he may.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. When you called out stop thief, did not he run back towards you?</p>
               <p>Milward. I did not call out stop thief, I called out watch.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What did you charge him with, when you carried him to the watch-house?</p>
               <p>Milward. I will tell you, Sir; I never knew a <rs id="t17480706-21-deflabel109" type="occupation">ropemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-21-defend193 t17480706-21-deflabel109"></join> hanged, and I was not willing to hang him, and I only charged him wit h an assault.</p>
               <p>Pros. Coun. Had he any weapon with him?</p>
               <p>Milward. I don't say that he had.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he demand your money of you?</p>
               <p>Milward. Yes; he said, D - n you, Sir, your money, and I struck him; he then run away, and I run after him like lightening.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was going along with two women, and one of them stopped to tie her garter; I said, my dear, shall I tie it for you? then I was in the highway, and Mr. Milward called after me, and said, you rogue, have I got you? and charged the watch with me; I said, Gentlemen, shall I go along with you? and I did go along with them; but he only said, that I had abused him, and assaulted him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-person196">
                  Robert 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17480706-21-person196" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person196" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a watchman). There was watch called in Neptune-Street, and Mr. Milward came up, and said, What is the matter? and he desired the women to charge us with the Prisoner, but they would not, and then Mr. Milward charged us to take him to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What did he say he had done to him?</p>
               <p>Harrison. He charged him with an assault.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did the Prisoner call him by his name?</p>
               <p>Harrison. He said, What do you want with me, Mr. Milward?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-person197">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17480706-21-person197" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a watchman). Mr. Milward would have had the two women have charged us with the Prisoner, but they would not; Mr. Milward was running after the Prisoner, and called out, Watch! Watch! and the Prisoner said, You need not call watch, for I will come to you directly.</p>
               <p>Mr. Spencer (the constable). At the watch-house, Mr. Milward charged the Prisoner with an assault, and threatening to blow out his brains.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did you see any pistol about him?</p>
               <p>Milward. He had none with him.</p>
               <p>Court. Did you see any women with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Milward. I did not see any women with him, as I am here standing, before God and man; he came up by himself, though these two rogues of watchmen swear so.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. And did not you desire any women to charge the watch with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Milward. No.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Was you sober, or not?</p>
               <p>Milward. I was as sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Mr. Milward's spite will appear.</p>
               <p>Mr. Touchfield call'd.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you know Mr. Milward?</p>
               <p>Touchfield. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him say any thing about the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Touchfield. Nothing.</p>
               <p>Pris Coun. What is the character of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Touchfield. Nothing bad.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Does he bear the character of a sober and industrious man?</p>
               <p>Touchfield. I know nothing tricking in him; I know him to be a man that follows his business, and does as other men do, and I believe he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eyres (a ropemaker). The Prisoner is a ropemaker, and a very honest man, and I hope I shall employ him again. There is a spleen in the case; he was an evidence against his son. The Prosecutor has drove him away from his work by a press-gang, and the Prisoner said he was afraid to come to work, for fear he should send him on board a man of war. I take this, upon my life, to be only spite.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-person198">
                  Thomas 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17480706-21-person198" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person198" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner served me seven years honestly and truly, and I take him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-21-person199">
                  George 
                  Stannard 
               <interp inst="t17480706-21-person199" type="surname" value="Stannard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person199" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner twenty-seven years, and he has the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you think he would do a bad thing?</p>
               <p>Stannard. No more than I think you would, or any body else.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-21-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-21-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
