<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-3">
               <interp inst="t17420428-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-3" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-3" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-3-off23-c66" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-defend74 t17420428-3-off23 t17420428-3-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     Edmund 
                     Larrat 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-defend74" type="surname" value="Larrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-defend74" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-defend74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420428-3-defloc22">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-defloc22" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-defloc22" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-defend74 t17420428-3-defloc22"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420428-3-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a weather Sheep, val. 40 s.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-victim76" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Wigans 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-victim76" type="surname" value="Wigans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-victim76" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-victim76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-off23 t17420428-3-victim76"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17420428-3-cd24" type="crimeDate">April 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-off23 t17420428-3-cd24"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-person77">
                  Thomas 
                  Wigans 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person77" type="surname" value="Wigans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person77" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a Weather Sheep out of <placeName id="t17420428-3-crimeloc25">Poplar Marsh</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-crimeloc25" type="placeName" value="Poplar Marsh"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-3-crimeloc25" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-off23 t17420428-3-crimeloc25"></join>, and Mr. Grainger a Carpenter, informing me that he had found some Wooll in 
               <persName id="t17420428-3-person78">
                  John 
                  Poor 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person78" type="surname" value="Poor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Lodgings, I had him taken up, and carried before a Justice, who admitted him an Evidence against the Prisoner. As to the Prisoner, I can't say any thing against him, only that we found two Skins in his Vault, but I can't swear them to be mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-person79">
                  Arthur 
                  Grainger 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person79" type="surname" value="Grainger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person79" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is a Tenant to me at Limehouse. I sent a Man to clean out a House of my Brother's which was empty, and he informed me that the Boards were pull'd down between that House and the next, so that a Man could go out of one House into the other. He told me there was some Wooll, and part of a Hide, but he could neither make one thing or t'other of it. I ask'd him how long he thought it might have been taken off the Sheep ? He said he could not tell. Upon this I acquainted the the Butchers in the Butcher row of this, and we appointed to meet hard by Limehouse Church. The Prisoner generally was out in the Day Time, so Mr. Wigans and I went into the empty House to view the Skin, but we could not make any thing of it by the Marks. We then got a Candle and look'd down the Vault of the empty House, and saw a Sheep-skin at the Bottom of it. After this we got a Warrant from Justice Jones, and went to the Prisoner's Lodgings, designing to search there, and accordingly I endeavour'd to go into one Room, but a Woman who was there refus'd to let me come in. I then went up Stairs, but finding nothing, I came down again, and pull'd back the Spring Lock of the Room Door, into which I had been refus'd Admittance, and went in: there I saw three Parts of five Sheep cut out; this was in the Room on the Ground Floor. I likewise search'd a Cup-board on the Stairs, and found a parcel of Fat, which I suppose belong'd to the Sheep that were cut out as I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-person80">
                  John 
                  Poor 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person80" type="surname" value="Poor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person80" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of April, the Prisoner desired me to go down with him into the Marsh at Poplar. It was between 9 and 10 at Night, as near as I can guess. He laid a Plank over the Ditches, and we by that means got into the Field. He then caught a Sheep and kill'd it, after which he took out the Guts and ridded the Fat and put it into a Bag. After that he cut the Sheep in halves, and put one half in one Bag, and the other half in another. Then we went over the Plank again and brought it Home.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with the Skin?</p>
               <p>Poor. I can't tell, I did not see him skin it. He carry'd the Sheep Home and put it down on the Floor in the lower Room. He then try'd the Fat in an iron Pot, and went out with 
               <persName id="t17420428-3-person81">
                  Ann 
                  Macdonnald 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person81" type="surname" value="Macdonnald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to sell it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to take you with him to steal this Sheep?</p>
               <p>Poor. I help'd him to carry it Home: I was a little in Liquor, and he persuaded me to go down into the Marsh with him to take a Sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that the Prisoner went to sell the Fat?</p>
               <p>Poor. He told me he would. I know this was Mr. Wigan's Sheep because he miss'd it out of an enclosed Place where he puts his Sheep.</p>
               <p>Jury. I think he says he went over the Ditch into the Marsh, where was he when the Sheep was skin'd that he did not see it?</p>
               <p>Poor. It was not skin'd there, but carried home in the Skin; he cut it in two without skinning.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280006"></xptr>Pris. Ask him if he had any Part of the Money?</p>
               <p>Poor. I had no part of any Money except what the Fat sold for</p>
               <p>Pris. I never ask'd him to go with me; it was his own Proposal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-3-person82">
                  William 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17420428-3-person82" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person82" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Marsh-man, and I look after the Marshes for a great many Butchers. I saw the Meat in the Prisoner's House, but the Skin was so bad, that we could not make any Thing of it. There was a good Shoulder, and there was a Leg and a Loin that lay in the Hole and stunk; this was about 3 Weeks ago, and the Day after we miss'd the Sheep.</p>
               <p>Pris. This Thing that he charges me with, I did not steal it, I found it by the Shipwright's Yard, just by Limehouse Causeway.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-3-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420428-3-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-3-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-3-defend74 t17420428-3-punish27"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
