<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410828-42">
               <interp inst="t17410828-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-42" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410828"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-42" type="date" value="17410828"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410828-42-off209-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-42-defend300 t17410828-42-off209 t17410828-42-verdict211"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410828-42-off209-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-42-defend302 t17410828-42-off209 t17410828-42-verdict211"></join>
         
               <p>50, 51. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-defend300" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Ross 
                  <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend300" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend300" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-defend302" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend302" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend302" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-defend302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17410828-42-off209" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-off209" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-off209" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a half guinea, and 4 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-victim304" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Alcock 
                  <interp inst="t17410828-42-victim304" type="surname" value="Alcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-victim304" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-victim304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-42-off209 t17410828-42-victim304"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17410828-42-cd210" type="crimeDate">August the 22d</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-42-off209 t17410828-42-cd210"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-person305">
                  Thomas 
                  Alcock 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person305" type="surname" value="Alcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person305" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This day sevennight, about 12 or one at night, I was got a little in liquor, and hearing some musick in a house as I pass'd along, I went in and call'd for some beer. They inform'd me that they sold nothing but China ale; however I went up stairs, and had 2 or 3 quarterns of liquor. There were some women follow'd me up stairs; Davis the Prisoner was one of them, and after we had drank our liquor, I agreed to go to bed with her, and one 
               <persName id="t17410828-42-person306">
                  Martin 
                  Heath 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person306" type="surname" value="Heath"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person306" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who was with me made a bargain with another creature, and we paid 6 d. a piece for our beds. I fasten'd the door of my room and we had not been in bed 6 minutes before the Prisoner Ross came up, and a man like a Chimney-sweeper or coal-heaver with him. He beat against the door in a strange manner, and swore he would kill me if I did not get up. I thought it very hard as I had paid for a bed not to be suffer'd to sleep in it, so I put the bed stead against the door to keep them out. I had a sword by me and I drew it, thinking to kill two or three of them, but then considering with myself that I was in a strange place, I thought it best to let them alone; so I put my sword up,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174108280014"></xptr> and they broke in upon me. Then the Prisoner Davis took my breeches from under the bolster, and carried them out of the room, but whether she carried them down stairs or not, I can't tell. I then was in care for my breeches, not knowing how to get home, and presently Davis came in and said the creature that was in bed with me had taken my breeches and rifled them; and if I would search about the bed-clothes I should find them. Then she pretended to tumble the clothes about, and I saw her put them down on the bed, and when I search'd my pockets I found only 2 d. in them, for my gold and silver was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner Ross do any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Alcock. Yes, he stood over me with a stick as thick as my wrist while she took the breeches.</p>
               <p>Davis. Did not you bring in 
               <persName id="t17410828-42-person307">
                  Frances 
                  Provert 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person307" type="surname" value="Provert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person307" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person307" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with you, and did you not say you had been married to her 4 years and an half?</p>
               <p>Alcock. I don't know but I might say so.</p>
               <p>Ross. When I came up stairs to bed, did I offer to strike you in any shape?</p>
               <p>Alcock. They came up swearing, and said they would kill me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-person308">
                  Frances 
                  Provert 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person308" type="surname" value="Provert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person308" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person308" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the Prosecutor by chance, and went with him to this house, and when we were a-bed, Ross came up, and a woman took the breeches from the bolster, but I can't say that it was the Prisoner Davis.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Ross when the woman took the breeches away?</p>
               <p>Provert. He was standing over the Prosecutor with a stick. The Prosecutor had his breeches again, for they were laid at the feet of the bed by the same woman that took them away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-42-person309">
                  Winifred 
                  Rawlins 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person309" type="surname" value="Rawlins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person309" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with 
               <persName id="t17410828-42-person310">
                  Martin 
                  Heath 
               <interp inst="t17410828-42-person310" type="surname" value="Heath"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person310" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at this house, and heard the Prosecutor cry out he should be murder'd. His breeches were brought down stairs, and I took the money out of them, and it was disbursted, for Ross had it all. There was a guinea, a half crown, and two shillings, and Ross had it all but one crown which he gave me. I can't tell who brought the breeches down stairs, for when I and Heath were with Alcock in the room up stairs, Davis was not there. Both <rs id="t17410828-42-verdict211" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-42-verdict211" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
