<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450116-6">
               <interp inst="t17450116-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-6" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-6" type="date" value="17450116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450116-6-off29-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-defend79 t17450116-6-off29 t17450116-6-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>131. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-defend79" type="defendantName">
                     Martha 
                     Stracey 
                  <interp inst="t17450116-6-defend79" type="surname" value="Stracey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-defend79" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-defend79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17450116-6-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450116-6-victim81" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Humphreys 
                        <interp inst="t17450116-6-victim81" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-6-victim81" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-6-victim81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-off29 t17450116-6-victim81"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the highway, puting him in fear, and taking from him one guinea
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450116-6-cd30" type="crimeDate">December 23d</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-off29 t17450116-6-cd30"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-person82">
                  William 
                  Humphreys 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person82" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person82" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About 20 minutes after 12 o' clock, between the 22d and 23d of December as I was going along the <placeName id="t17450116-6-crimeloc31">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-off29 t17450116-6-crimeloc31"></join>, by <placeName id="t17450116-6-crimeloc32">Northumberland house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-6-crimeloc32" type="placeName" value="Northumberland house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-6-crimeloc32" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-off29 t17450116-6-crimeloc32"></join>, the prisoner met me, and said, where are you going, my dear; I said, what is that to you, you bitch. Then a man came either behind me or on one side of me, and laid hold of my collar; as soon as I found that, I struck at him, then another man came up and they pulled me down backward upon a step, held me by the throat, and asked me what business I had to call the woman bitch. Then the prisoner unbuttoned my breeches, and turned every pocket the wrong side out, and took a guinea out of my right fob. But there was one six-pence left, which happened to stick in the corner of one of my pockets. As she was unbuttoning my breeches, I took hold of her by the coat with my right hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the men offer to hold your hands?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. No, they left my hands at liberty.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do after you got hold of her coat?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. Then I rose up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she doing this?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I believe she was about a minute, she was very dextrous. Then the men went off, and one of them struck at me with a stick about two foot and a half long. When I got up, I took her by the hand and she called for assistance. Then one of the men came and struck at me. I struck at him, and brought him down - I had hold of the prisoner all the time. While I was down upon my back, she said, d - n him, kill him, he squeaks. Then Thomas Ind and 
               <persName id="t17450116-6-person83">
                  Benjamin 
                  Meadows 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person83" type="surname" value="Meadows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person83" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my assistance, and the men got off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a dark night?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that the Prisoner's hand was in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. Yes; because no body was by but the Prisoner and the two men, and I am sure neither of their hands were in my pocket, and I kept hold of her all the time till we got her to the watch-house; she would not speak one word before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you receive that guinea?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. Mr. Mildmay in Strutton Street paid it me about four hours before for carrying him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was by myself: was there any men along with me?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I did not see any man till after you had laid hold of me.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174501160006"></xptr>Prisoner. He asked me to drink, and said, he would give me a shilling to have some conversation with me: I said, I did not come out upon that account, but he persuaded me, and gave me the guinea instead of a shilling, or else I should hardly have kept it in my pocket till next morning.</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I did not say any thing to her but what I mentioned before - I did not give her the guinea, I never offered her any money, or promised her any.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I was as sober then as ever I was in my life.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He pulled me into an alley, and wanted to be concerned with me.</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I did not pull her into any alley.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-person84">
                  William 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person84" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person84" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable of the night, about one o'clock in the morning the Prosecutor brought the Prisoner into St. Martin's watch-house, and told me as he has said now, that she had robbed him by the assistance of two men of a guinea; that he had never let her go from him, and was sure she must have it about her. I searched her, took 2 s. and some half pence out of her pocket; I said to Ind search her behind and before (I ask pardon, my Lord) he has got a pretty good hand at searching; he searched her, and took the guinea out of her mouth; I was the more ready to have her searched, because the man was very positive and very sober. I took her aside, and desired her to give an account of her two accomplices, by which the might probably save her own life; instead of giving any direct answer to that, I think, to the best of my knowledge, she said, whether I had any assistance or not, I will make no confession: then she pulled me back, whispered me in the ear, (I thought she had changed her mind, and would have discovered her accomplices) and said, Mr. Constable, I know it is in your power to leave the watch-house door open, and let me go out, if you will, you shall have a - whenever you please.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-person85">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person85" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person85" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the house of correction at Tothill Fields Bridewell. On the 22d of December about nine o'clock at night I went to the goal with some prisoners, and said till near twelve. I was going home into Covent Garden, and just by the Bagnio at Charing Cross I heard an outcry, I thought there had been some quarrel; I saw Humphreys with the Prisoner in his right hand; he told me he was robbed by the Prisoner and two men, and desired me to go with him to the watch-house; when I came there, Mr. Dunn thought I was a proper person, and desired me to search her. I pulled off her stockings, searched all her clothes, and found 2 s. 4 d. and a bag of tobacco; then I searched her arm pits, and every where that I could, but could not find the guinea; then I said, D - n you open your mouth; she opened it, and turned out her tongue double; I put my finger into her mouth, and brought the guinea out: she said something afterwards in a vulgar manner, but I could not tell what it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He is a runner at goals, and gets his living that way; he said he would hang me.</p>
               <p>Ind. I never said any such thing, nor was I ever concerned in any goal till a little before Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-person86">
                  Paul 
                  Broadbent 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person86" type="surname" value="Broadbent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person86" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ( the Beadle ) I held the candle while Ind searched her, and at last he brought the guinea out of her mouth. I said she had better confess who were her accomplices; she said, if she was hanged herself, she would not bring in any other person to be hanged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-6-person87">
                  Benj 
                  Meadows 
               <interp inst="t17450116-6-person87" type="surname" value="Meadows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person87" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home between tweleve and one, and when I was against the Mewsgate, I heard watch cried out; I did not mind it at first, and walked softly on; when I came against my own door, I saw Humphreys have hold of the Prisoner by the hand; when I came up he was surrounded by several people; some said let her go, others said do not let her go; I heard Humphreys speak, and knew his voice: said I, Humphreys, is it you? he said, yes; and told me he was robbed of a guinea: said I, if you are robbed, do not let her go. We carried her to the watch-house, Mr. Ind searched her all over, and could not find it, but at last he pulled the guinea out of her mouth - I have known the Prisoner some years.</p>
               <p>Jury to Dunn. Do you believe the Prosecutor was down upon his back, for it was very dirty weather then, and his clothes must be dirty?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I did not enquire into that, but I believe by the terror and fright he seemed to be in that the thing was true, and that made me get the best hand in the watch-house to search her. <rs id="t17450116-6-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450116-6-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450116-6-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-6-defend79 t17450116-6-punish34"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
