<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460409-48">
               <interp inst="t17460409-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-48" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-48" type="date" value="17460409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460409-48-off200-c607" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-48-defend708 t17460409-48-off200 t17460409-48-verdict202"></join>
         
               <p>191. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-defend708" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-48-defend708" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-defend708" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-defend708" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that not having the Fear of God before her Eyes, but stirred and moved by the Instigation of the Devil, <rs id="t17460409-48-off200" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-off200" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-off200" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               falsly, deceirfully, and feloniously, to deceive and defraud, on the <rs id="t17460409-48-cd201" type="crimeDate">27th Day of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-48-off200 t17460409-48-cd201"></join>, 20 Pieces of false, forged, counterfeit Money and Coin, to the Likeness and Similitude of lawful and current Money, called Shillings, did coin and utter, against the Duty of her Allegiance, and against the Form and Statute in that Case made and provided
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person709">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person709" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person709" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person709" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How long have you known the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Jones. Fifteen Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, during that Time, what Way of Livelihood has she followed?</p>
               <p>Jones. At first she lived in a pretty Way. About ten Years we have been abroad together, and gone out together in this Affair, in making of Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her coin Money at any Time? What Fact have you known her guilty of, in respect of making of Money together. [Some Money was produced ]</p>
               <p>Withers. Had you that same Money from 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person710">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person710" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person710" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person710" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Jones. These same Pieces of Money viewed by the Justice, Mr. Withers, she and I made.</p>
               <p>Council. You must not talk of She's, there's five thousand of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner make these twelve Shillings?</p>
               <p>Jones. I can't say but I did help her?</p>
               <p>Q. Let us see what Part she did, and what Part you did, in making these Pieces. Who made the Mould of the Plaister of Paris ?</p>
               <p>Jones. I made the Impression by a good Shilling. The Prisoner held the Mould while I pour'd in the Metal.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the next Step to making them?</p>
               <p>Jones. She and I put them out, and I not being well that Night, when I went to Bed I desir'd her to get them ready, and she scour'd them and went down with one of the said Shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, she held the Mould made of Plaister of Paris, while you took the Impression off the good Shilling. Who cast them in the Mould?</p>
               <p>Jones. She and I together.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that you did cast them?</p>
               <p>Jones. In the Morning, at Four o'Clock, Sir: We were both concern'd together; I held the Moulds, and she pour'd the Metal in.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say that these twelve Pieces you produced, were produced by the Metal she pour'd into the Mould.</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know?</p>
               <p>Jones. These Pieces were ne'er out of my Custody before I gave them to the Justice; they were not, upon my Word and Honour.</p>

               <p>Q. Who fil'd these twelve? How came you by them?</p>
               <p>Jones. Sir, she was with me; we were both together when they were made.</p>
               <p>Q. Who scour'd them?</p>
               <p>Jones. The Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. After you had scour'd and finish'd them, what did you do with them?</p>
               <p>Jones. She and I used to go out together; she used always to take a Hand-Basket, and I used to go along with her: Sometimes she used to go to Market, and sometimes I. When I came to her, I used to give her the Change.</p>
               <p>Q. When you had put it off, what did you do then?</p>
               <p>Jones. Why then, Sir, I used to give her the Change; then I took another Shilling to put off.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090042"></xptr>Q. Now I would ask you, for how long a Time you went on in this Way ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Ten Years we have gone out together in this Way.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that you discover'd this iniquitous Practice to?</p>
               <p>Jones. I was very uneasy about it; for sometimes she would get drunk, and then she would threaten me. I first sent to the Gentleman, Mr. Buckman, within these three Weeks, and I said, I am very uneasy now my Children are grown out of the Way; and I am frighten'd and threaten'd by a Person what she will do; and I will now leave it off.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what Impression had the Moulds?</p>
               <p>Jones. King William the Third.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person711">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person711" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person711" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Would you ask her any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person712">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person712" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person712" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person713">
                  Walter 
                  Buckman 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person713" type="surname" value="Buckman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person713" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person713" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Look upon the Prisoner at the Bar, Do you know her?</p>
               <p>Buckman. My Lord, I never saw her in my Life, 'till this Affair was discover'd. The Evidence, Mrs. Jones, sent for me: When I came she said, I am something concern'd I did not send to you before; I have sent for you for something besides the Coat. When she sent to me she was very sober, and under a great Concern; and I was very sober myself. She said, I do assure you, Mr. Buckingham, I have something upon my Spirits that concerns me; I am determin'd to make myself a voluntary Evidence. An Evidence, In what? I said. Says she, I have been concern'd in Coining, and putting off bad Money. I said I would go and speak to a Person that I knew, who was one Vernon.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Vernon?</p>
               <p>Buckman. He is an Officer belonging to the Marshalsea Court.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Buckman. I am a Taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. So when you came to her about the Coat, she mention'd something to you about Coining, did she?</p>
               <p>Buckman. Yes; and she nam'd one Wilson.</p>
               <p>Court. You said you would send or go to one Vernon, Did you meet with him?</p>
               <p>Buckman. I brought him along with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Then what past in the Presence of Vernon, you and her, altogether?</p>
               <p>Buckman. She said, To be sure I am guilty of a very heinous Crime; I'll make myself a voluntary Evidence: I have two Children, and I am willing to discover the Thing. Said Mr. Vernon, Where does this Woman live ? So she sent her little Boy with us to the House where the Prisoner was; the Boy pointed to an elderly Woman, and the poor Woman fell a crying. I said to Mr. Vernon, this poor Creature looks like an innocent Person. The other Woman facing the Chimney-Corner seem'd to be sideling to get away; I said, I fansy that Woman must be the guilty Person; send for Mrs. Jones, to see if this is not the Woman. When Mrs. Jones came, she declar'd that was the Woman.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now, Mr. Buckman, tell the Court what 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person714">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person714" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person714" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person714" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had said of her being concern'd with any other in counterfeiting of Money before you went out with Mr. Vernon, Did she mention any Name?</p>
               <p>Buckman. Yes, a Name; but I can't remember the Name. She said she was concern'd with such a Woman, living at a Silver-spinner's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person715">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person715" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person715" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Would you ask this Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw him in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person716">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person716" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person716" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person717">
                  Richard 
                  Vernon 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person717" type="surname" value="Vernon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person717" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person717" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Look upon the Prisoner at the Bar, What is it that you know of her ?</p>
               <p>Vernon. I was drinking a Pint of Beer in Whitecross-Street; Buckman, the other Witness, came to me, and ask'd me to go with him, to be concern'd in taking a Coiner: I went up along with him to this Woman's, the Witness. When I came up she seem'd to be afraid, and said, I have been concern'd in Coining, but am willing to leave that Trade off. Said I, How many is concern'd with you? she said but one; which is the Prisoner at the Bar. Her Boy went along with me to shew me the House; but when I came in I made a little Mistake; I said, Madam, you must go along with me; you have been concern'd in Coining of Money. The Woman fell a crying; I saw the Prisoner at the Bar make a sideling about; I said, Don't you run away, for I fansy you are the Woman. So when Mrs. Jones came up, she said, that was the Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. As you was going before the Justice, had you any Talk with her?</p>
               <p>Vernon. I cannot say I was very curious to have much Conversation with her; but I said to her, that Coining was a very bad Trade; you have coin'd yourself in Rags. Said she, I wish I had been a little sooner, I would have turn'd Evidence: I wish I had been an Evidence myself; but now 'tis too late.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person718">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person718" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person718" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person719">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person719" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person719" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person719" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Look at the Prisoner; How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>Evans. Fourteen or fifteen Years; she shew'd me a Pair of Moulds about six Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she come to you ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090043"></xptr>Evans. She came to my Apartment in Whitecross-street, and said they were 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person720">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person720" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person720" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person720" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at them?</p>
               <p>Evans. She open'd them in her Hand, and there was King Williams's Head on one Side, and cross Bars, like ours; she said, that Mrs. Jones did this Sort of Business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say that she did any Thing to ?</p>
               <p>Evans. She shew'd me one Shilling, as she could not put it off; but she did not know how she (
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person721">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person721" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person721" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person721" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) put off so many.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it she shew'd it to you?</p>
               <p>Evans. At my own Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. May I speak to Mrs. Evans. Mrs. Evans, Have you not known me ever since the Death of old King George?</p>
               <p>Evans. Yes; and I never knew any Harm of you in my Life. When first I knew her she kept a School at Hoxton; I never knew an ill Character of her. She went to Service and Charing, and did little Matters for me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. And you know I have lodg'd with you two or three Years together.</p>
               <p>Evans. She never lodg'd so long together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this Mrs. Jones?</p>
               <p>Evans. The Prisoner told me she liv'd with this Mrs. Jones as a Servant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person722">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person722" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person722" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person723">
                  Anne 
                  Holster 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person723" type="surname" value="Holster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person723" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person723" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What is your Business?</p>

               <p>Holster. My Business is to make the Plaister of Paris.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Holster. I don't know but she may have been at my House, but I can't very well tell.</p>
               <p>Court. Go close to her, look at her; Do you know her or not ?</p>
               <p>Holster. I cannot say I do know her positively.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person724">
                  Matthew 
                  Solam 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person724" type="surname" value="Solam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person724" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person724" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I was charg'd by the Constable to aid and assist him to carry the Prisoner to New Prison. She said this wicked Woman has sworn that I coin'd with her ten or twelve Years, when I have never been concern'd in making Money for above three Months past. I hope, when Mr. North comes I shall be admitted an Evidence; because he has been try'd at Kingston upon such an Affair before; for Jones had said, For God's sake, if you inform against me, you will ruin me for ever. Further, the Prisoner said she was concern'd in putting them off, but had not coin'd with her above three Months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person725">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person725" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person725" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person726">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person726" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person726" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person726" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. Three Months and better.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her Character ?</p>
               <p>Brown. I have heard a good Character of her; that she always has been a Working Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person727">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person727" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person727" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person728">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Walton 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person728" type="surname" value="Walton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person728" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person728" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known this Woman?</p>
               <p>Walton. About ten Years; and she is an industrious laborious Creature, and always poor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she idle or willing to work?</p>
               <p>Walton. Willing to work; when she was sick I have beg'd many a Shilling of her Relations for her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person729">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person729" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person729" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person730">
                  Sarah 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person730" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person730" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person730" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Brown. Three Months; while she was with me she behav'd in a very handsome Manner.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to go from you to Mrs. Jones ?</p>
               <p>Brown. Mrs. Jones came and took her in our House; she said she could not rest nor sleep while she was with her, and said I am glad I am away from her. The Evidence, Jones, swore one Time, that she would swear through a Deal Board to be reveng'd of her; she swore this in my Mother-in-Law's House.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person731">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person731" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person731" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person731" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say this yourself ?</p>
               <p>Brown. Yes, I did, at White-Horse-Court in Whitecross-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person732">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person732" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person732" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person733">
                  Sarah 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person733" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person733" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person733" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Brown. This 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person734">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person734" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person734" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person734" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took Lodgings in my House: The first Night she came she made abundance of Confusion in my Room. The next Morning I went up Stairs; I said, Mrs. Jones, I desire you would quit my Room. She answer'd me, No, d - n you, I'll stay the Week. I often heard knocking and Confusion, and a Pack of Black-guards coming after her; with that I got shut of her. When she left her Room I went to clean it, and found some Metal among the Ashes.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say any Thing of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. I believe she is a very honest Woman, I have known her not above a Fortnight; but I know nothing of Wilson but Honesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person735">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person735" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person735" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person736">
                  George 
                  Wiskin 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person736" type="surname" value="Wiskin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person736" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person736" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-48-person737">
                  George 
                  Wiskin 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person737" type="surname" value="Wiskin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person737" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person737" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About five Weeks. I was at my Cousin Brown's, and they have entrusted her with a great Quantity of Silver and Gold, and they never missed any Thing in the World.</p>
               <p>Upon the summing up of the Evidence, his Lordship, among other Things, thus expressed himself: There are two Things very plain, that 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person738">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person738" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person738" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person738" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Witness, is an exceeding wicked Woman; that she hath been concerned in this Thing for a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090044"></xptr> Matter of ten Years, and 'tis, I think, as plain, that before this Woman came acquainted with Jones, she was a hard-working Woman; that she was extremely concerned during the little Time she lived with her; and that she was drawn into this Practice; therefore I could have wished that 
               <persName id="t17460409-48-person739">
                  Susannah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17460409-48-person739" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person739" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-person739" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             might have been prosecuted, and this poor Woman made an Evidence, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460409-48-verdict202" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-48-verdict202" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
