<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451204-32">
               <interp inst="t17451204-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-32" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-32" type="date" value="17451204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451204-32-off156-c273" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-32-defend323 t17451204-32-off156 t17451204-32-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-defend323" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Oakes 
                  <interp inst="t17451204-32-defend323" type="surname" value="Oakes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-defend323" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-defend323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17451204-32-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               High Treason, for that he, not weighing the Duty of his Allegiance, and devising and intending our Lord the King and his People to deceive, on the <rs id="t17451204-32-cd157" type="crimeDate">10th Day of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-32-off156 t17451204-32-cd157"></join> last, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17451204-32-crimeloc158">St. Giles's Cripplegate, London</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-crimeloc158" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's Cripplegate, London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-crimeloc158" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-32-off156 t17451204-32-crimeloc158"></join>, 40 Pieces of false, forg'd and counterfeit Money and Coin, to the Likeness and Similitude of good, legal current Silver Coin of this Realm call'd Shillings, did make, forge and counterfeit, against the Duty of his Allegiance, &amp;c. and against the Form of the Statute &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, I am Counsel for the Crown, and he stands indicted for High Treason, for counterfeiting the current Coin of this Kingdom. Gentlemen, I am not willing to aggravate this above its Demerit; not to inspire the Breasts of the Jury with Sentiments to prejudice them against the Prisoner at the Bar, who stands upon his Trial for Life or Death. Gentlemen, undoubtedly it is the Prerogative of the Crown to take Care of the current Coin of the Kingdom. The Prisoner at the Bar is indicted for coining of Shillings; and I beg that you would observe how this falls among the working Poor of the Nation. Suppose a Man works hard all Day for a Shilling, and at Night shall receive one of these bad ones, that is not worth a Farthing: What Distress does this bring into a Family, where there is a Wife and Children.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner at the Bar is an old Offender, and hath practis'd it 14 Years; and the Method of finding him out was by Mr. Smith. The Prisoner at at the Bar and Mr. Smith carry'd on this Affair: The first 10 coin, and the last to put them off when coin'd. The better to effect this, they often took Journeys, sometimes to Worcester, sometimes to Newcastle, sometimes to one Place, and sometimes to another; and then, when they took these Journeys, they carry'd a Quantity of these Shillings with them. But Smith happened to be detected at Basingstoke; a Quantity of them were found upon him. He acquainted us that the Person he was concern'd with was one Oakes, and that he liv'd in White-Cross Street. Now Gentlemen, it is not upon the single Testimony or Evidence of Smith that we are endeavouring to prove him guilty; for the Gentlemen of the Mint made an Enquiry, and they found in his Lodgings a great many Pieces ready made, and others almost finish'd; and they found the Instruments to carry on the Work, which are now in our Custody. Mr. Smith has a great many Times, and that Years ago, had Part of that Money to set out of Town withal, and he hath seen him coin it and wash it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, My Lord, put off my Trial for an Hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person324">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person324" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person324" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-32-person325">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person325" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person325" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Look at the Prisoner at the Bar. How long have you been acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>Smith. Fourteen Years. My first Acquaintance with him was in the Horse-Grenadiers; about six Years ago was the first Time he said any Thing to me: Says he to me, You have a Family, and he immediately pull'd out of his Pocket three or four Shillings. I went with him to the Noah's-Ark, and he put off one Shilling; and we went to the Coach and Horses, and there he put off another. He found out where I liv'd, and I went along with him, and he put off three or four Shillings at a Time. This pass'd on 'till Witsuntide. He liv'd then in Lamb-Court in Clerkenwell. When I came to see him, I open'd the Door, and I saw him coining with these Things; and there was Whiting and a great many ready coin'd, I believe to the Value of three or four Pounds. I saw with him a Pipe.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Composition?</p>
               <p>Smith. What is the Composition! I don't know;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174512040018"></xptr> but he made Use of that Mould; there was an Impression to make a Shilling, after he cut off the Stem, and he fil'd it. And after that he inveigl'd me to go with him into the Country; and we went to Newcastle and Peterborough, and we went with about 5 l. of them. I carry'd the Money that Time, and he put it off; and he told me he design'd to go to Worcester and Bristol.</p>
               <p>Q. And you was at Basingstoke. Did you carry any of that Money with you?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes. I have seen him file 10 or 12 Pieces of that Counterfeit Matter, which had the Similitude of an English Shilling. He had Salt and Wax-Candle to rub it over with, to make it have a dull Hue; and he stroak'd it round with a File, to take off the rough Edge.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went to Basingstoke, did he give you Money?</p>
               <p>Smith. He was to meet me behind Montague-House, and I agreed to go as the Monday-Sen'night after. Some Time after he brings me a Horse at Five o'Clock in the Morning, and I went upon the Expedition, and he gave me a Box and a White Rug.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What he says I shall prove to be false. I shall say nothing yet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person326">
                  William 
                  Rubby 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person326" type="surname" value="Rubby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person326" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are the Things we found in his Room. There was a Box.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person327">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person327" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person327" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Smith.) Is this the same that you receiv'd from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Smith. This is the same Sort of Counterfeit, this is the same Coin that I receiv'd; there is no Addition nor Alteration; I declare it to be the same Sort that he gave me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I shall ask no Questions. He swears as he pleases.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person328">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person328" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person328" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Rubby) Did you find this Mould in his Room? Are they proper for coining Shillings?</p>
               <p>Rubby. His Room is a lower Room; it was not locked up, but they were found amongst some Flocks.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any skill; are you concerned either in Silver or Brass; did you find any Thing else besides the Mould?</p>
               <p>Rubby. Some counterfeit Shillings, Mould and Flask.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Thing else besides?</p>
               <p>Rubby. There was Whiting and Wax-Candle, and there was a File.</p>
               <p>Q. in what Part of the Room?</p>
               <p>Rubby. Some in one Part and some in another: Some Pieces of Money lay upon a Ledge. We search'd the Fire-Place and found several Pieces of Metal. There was a Bed in the Room.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came into the Room, what did you meet with?</p>
               <p>Rubby. These several Pieces in several Places.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was thrown about the Room. I have no Counsel. I did not know what they were for; It was Smith that brought them and left them there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person329">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person329" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person329" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Rubby.) Was you in the Room? Look at the Things.</p>
               <p>Rubby. This is the Metal that we found; we found it upon a Ledge in the Wall higher than a Man's Head, on the 11th of October last. When these Things were found there, he surrender'd himself immediately. His Wife and Daughter seem'd surpriz'd. We found in a Basket of Flocks the Mould and the Flask. There seems to me to be some small Particles of the Metal in the File. I have look'd upon the Money, and it is all counterfeit.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person330">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person330" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person330" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-32-person331">
                  Hannah 
                  Lister 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person331" type="surname" value="Lister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person331" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Look at the Prisoner at the Bar. Do you know him?</p>
               <p>Lister. He called once at my House at Tottenham-Court. He once kept the House that I now live in. Last Tottenham-Court-Fair was two Years, he call'd at my House to drink, and he gave me a bad Shilling; but I saw it, and told him of it, and he gave me a better.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. About the 5th of September I met Mr. Smith, and he ask'd me if I could tell him where he might put a Horse to Grass. I said there was Grass enough now, but I told him I did believe that the Man at the Royal-Oak at Vauxhall had Grass to let. My Lord, I and he drank together at the George in Tyburn Road; and I said I am now going to the Horse Ferry; and he fetched the Horse, and I put it for him to Grass at 12 s. a Month. As soon as I had done it and acquainted him with the Agreement, he said it was a great Price, and he would put it into another Place to Grass. I told him I did not care; but I did not see him for three Weeks; and when I saw him after, he was offering a Mare to sell. I looked up the Yard, and I said to the Man that was with me, stop a little, I shall speak to one here. And I went, and found that he was going to sell the Mare to one Mr. Taylor, a Gentleman of about 6 or 700 l. a Year. I said, your Servant Mr. Smith. Mr. Taylor said, do you know that Man? Yes, said I. Said he, I hope that he is an honest Man. Said I, as for Honesty, I can't give him a Character, for I don't understand how he should deal in Horses, seeing he has not wherewithal to carry on the Business. After this I asked Smith, when he would come and take his away? and sometime after this, he came one Day to my House, and left a Bag, and threw it down upon the End of the Counter. I went over the Way for a Pint of Beer: My Wife happen'd to tumble down the Bag, and these<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174512040019"></xptr> Things, all of them, sell out of it; and she stoop'd down, and took up a Piece of Wood, a File, and three or four Pieces of Pewter. The Bag was thrown aside. He never came for the Bag, nor after the Things. I heard no more of him 'till he came to take me up.</p>
               <p>Here the Prisoner called Persons to his Reputation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person332">
                  Joseph 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person332" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person332" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known this Man 15 or 16 Years; I never heard any Thing amiss in his Character: He is a <rs id="t17451204-32-deflabel159" type="occupation">Painter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-32-defend323 t17451204-32-deflabel159"></join> by Trade.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person333">
                  William 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person333" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person333" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Joiner. I have known him many Years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person334">
                  William 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person334" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person334" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know him very well. He is a good-natur'd Man: He has passed his Word for other People, and so has suffered by it. He has helped those that in the Time of his Trouble would not come near him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Bird. I live at a Hair-Merchant's in Green-Street, Leicester-Fields, at the Sign of the Lock of Hair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person335">
                  Stephen 
                  Greenlitt 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person335" type="surname" value="Greenlitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person335" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He used to come to my Father's; we are partly Relations, we are Cousins. About two Years ago he took an Alehouse in Castle Yard, but for want of Stock to carry it on, he was forced to leave it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person336">
                  William 
                  Backwin 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person336" type="surname" value="Backwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person336" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mr. Oakes these ten Years. I have worked for him in the Painting Way, and he is an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear that he was a Coiner?</p>
               <p>Backwin. So far from that, that he was always poor.</p>
               <p>- Wilkinson. I think his Character is as different from that of a Coiner, as I am from being a Woman. I have changed Guineas and Shillings for him, and I never had one bad one of him in all my Life. My Money goes to my Brewer and Distiller.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person337">
                  John 
                  Hodgley 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person337" type="surname" value="Hodgley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person337" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Carpenter. I have worked for him, and he for me in the Way of Painting. I believe he is a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person338">
                  Hugh 
                  Ruck 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person338" type="surname" value="Ruck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person338" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew him in Prison, and he lay with me there half a Year, and he always behaved as an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you there a Prisoner for?</p>
               <p>Ruck. For Smuggling, but by the King's Grace I came out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person339">
                  James 
                  Brittle 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person339" type="surname" value="Brittle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person339" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner at the Bar. I have built four Houses, and he hath worked for me, and I find him to be a Workman, and that he did his Business in a Workman-like Manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-32-person340">
                  Thomas 
                  Lister 
               <interp inst="t17451204-32-person340" type="surname" value="Lister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person340" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know much of him. I know the House that he kept, and I have heard that he is a Coiner.</p>
               <p>The Jury desired to withdraw, which was granted; and when they were withdrawn, they sent a Message, desiring that a Shilling or two might be brought to them with Instruments; which was done accordingly; and after sometime they returned and brought in their Verdict, not Guilty. <rs id="t17451204-32-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-32-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
