<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-27">
               <interp inst="t17441205-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-27" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-27" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-27-off171-c220" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-27-defend278 t17441205-27-off171 t17441205-27-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>39. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-defend278" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-defend278" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-defend278" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-defend278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17441205-27-defloc170">St. Mary le Bone</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-defloc170" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le Bone"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-defloc170" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-27-defend278 t17441205-27-defloc170"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17441205-27-off171" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-off171" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-off171" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17441205-27-victim279" type="victimName">
                        Isabella 
                        Harvey 
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim279" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim279" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in a certain field or open place, near the King's highway, putting her in fear, &amp;c. and taking from her a tin-box, value 2 d. her property, and 16 s. in money, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441205-27-victim281" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Deane 
                        <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim281" type="surname" value="Deane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim281" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-27-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-27-cd172" type="crimeDate">Sep. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-27-off171 t17441205-27-cd172"></join>.</p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's desire the witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Isabella Harvey. On the 17th of September, I was going from London to Kilbourn, I called at Paddington to drink a tankard of beer; the Prisoner came into the house where I was - the key and garter: my cousin Harvey was with me, and she and I had a pot of ale.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink to him?</p>
               <p>Harvey. My cousin drank to him; my cousin asked me how far I was going: I said I was going as far as Kilbourn to pay 16 Shillings to one Mrs. Waters.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell your cousin that?</p>
               <p>Harvey. No, I said I was going to pay a little money, I did not say how much - I paid three pence for the beer: when the beer was drank, my cousin and I came out of the house, and the Prisoner followed us out; my cousin parted with me at <placeName id="t17441205-27-crimeloc173">Paddington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-crimeloc173" type="placeName" value="Paddington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-crimeloc173" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-27-off171 t17441205-27-crimeloc173"></join>, and then returned to London: when my cousin parted from me, the Prisoner insisted upon seeing me safe to <placeName id="t17441205-27-crimeloc174">Kilbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-crimeloc174" type="placeName" value="Kilbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-27-crimeloc174" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-27-off171 t17441205-27-crimeloc174"></join>; I made answer, and said, I knew my way perfectly well, and wanted no company, but he would go with me, and in the third field he began to be rude with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from the highway?</p>
               <p>Harvey. I can't tell, 'tis in the Fields.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance is it from the highway?</p>
               <p>Harvey. 'Tis a considerable distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell me what he said or did?</p>
               <p>Harvey. He robbed me of my box and sixteen Shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he do it?</p>
               <p>Harvey. He put his hand into my pocket and took the money out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say anything to you?</p>
               <p>Harvey. No, he said nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say nothing to you?</p>
               <p>Harvey. He said he must have my money.</p>
               <p>Q. You said he began to be rude with you, do you think it was for lewdness, or what?</p>
               <p>Harvey. For lewdness.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think he would have robbed you then?</p>
               <p>Harvey. No, I did not, but after he had used me so, he robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use you as a lewd fellow, with a design to debauch you?</p>
               <p>Harvey. That was what he did at first, and then he took my money; I run after him, and desired he would give me the money, for it was not my own; and I was only entrusted to pay it - it was Mr. Dean's money.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you did not cry out thief. You thought he designed to rob you of your virtue, rather than your money?</p>
               <p>Harvey. I thought so at first.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any pistol?</p>
               <p>Harvey. He had not any pistol or stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor put you into any fear, did he?</p>
               <p>Harvey. No, no otherwise than being rude.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do to you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050016"></xptr>Harvey. He threw me down to be rude with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person282">
                  Thomas 
                  Littlewood 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person282" type="surname" value="Littlewood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of Sept. I saw the Prisoner follow this woman into the key and garter, and she called for a pot of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner drink with her?</p>
               <p>Littlewood. Yes, he did - he took the pot and drank, I can't tell what share he had.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he appear to be an acquaintance?</p>
               <p>Littlewood. No, she said she was going as far as Kilbourn, and he said, if she would accept of his company, he would see her safe there. I have not told you how I came to know the Prisoner: I happened to be at another place, and he was quarrelling with another person, and the landlady said she would not let him have any more than one pot of beer, for he looked like a thief, and she did not let him have any more, her name is Blaker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person283">
                  Robert 
                  Berridge 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person283" type="surname" value="Berridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person283" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable; on the 17th of Sept. one Blaker came to me to let me know, there had been a robbery committed, and wanted not to take the man; he said Mr. Littlewood knew him very well, and that he was a fighting man, and was at the fighting booth, and there I saw him; some people said it was an improper place to take him, for he would be rescued: I said the best way will be, to take him when the fight is over, for I will not spoil the gentlemen's diversion, nor spoil the house. Littlewood shewed me the Prisoner, I said let them part the money first; then the Prisoner came into the room: Mr. Blaker and Mr. Littlewood said he was the man, and some of them thought it dangerous to take him then. The Prisoner run away, and the man that keeps the booth said, push; Littlewood and some others ran, but the Prisoner run so fast that they could not take him. I heard he lived in Wych-street, and I took him about three weeks after: I think it was on the 25th of October. Is not that Crispin's day, my Lord?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person284">
                  William 
                  Rawhole 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person284" type="surname" value="Rawhole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person284" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I am going to speak, and I hope you will not let any body interrupt me. On the 25th of October, I think it was Crispin's-day, I was at Mr. Bird's, and he said the Prisoner was at Mr. Broughton's booth, and asked me, if I knew him. I said, I did know him, but he was not there. We went to his room, and there we took him. When he was taken, he desired to be put into a room with several men, to see whether the Prosecutrix knew him: and as soon as she came into the room, she said, That is the man that robbed me, though he was in another coat then. I am not going to say, I saw the man rob her. because I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person285">
                  Richard 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person285" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person285" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was asked, whether I knew the Prisoner. I said, very well; and we took him (I think it was on the 25th of October) in his own room.</p>
               <p>Q to Harvey. Where did you go after the Prisoner robbed you?</p>
               <p>Harvey. I went to Kilbourn, to one Mrs. Waters's, and staid there all night.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to her?</p>
               <p>Harvey. When I went in she asked me what made me look so much frightened; I said, I was robbed, and she went with me the next morning to see if we could get any intelligence of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you was down upon the ground, then you think he took the money out of your pocket, when you were upon the ground?</p>
               <p>Harvey. He did not take it then, he took it from me after I was up again upon my legs. I beg leave to say two words more, that when I spoke to him for my money, I observed he had a very great impediment in his speech; and the Prisoner has a very great one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person286">
                  Mary 
                  Blaker 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person286" type="surname" value="Blaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person286" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the house at Paddington, where the Prosecutrix says the Prisoner was with her. I come here to prove that the Prisoner is not the man that was at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prosecutrix, Isabella Harvey?</p>
               <p>Blaker. She was at my house, and drank a pot of beer, but it was another man that was with her; I never saw the Prisoner but once before this: she came with a young man in a blue grey suit with white buttons, he was a pale man, as pale as a Sheet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person287">
                  Catherine 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person287" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person287" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a servant to Mrs. Blaker.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Isabella Harvey come to your house at any time?</p>
               <p>Gray. Yes, but I can't tell when.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner the man that was with her?</p>
               <p>Gray. No, he is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he like him?</p>
               <p>Gray. No, he is no more like him than I am.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person288">
                  Thomas 
                  Littlewood 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person288" type="surname" value="Littlewood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person288" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sure the Prisoner is the man that followed Harvey into the house; I am sure he's the very man, - he was dressed in a blue grey coat, like that he has on. - I can't say that is the coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person289">
                  James 
                  Rubineau 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person289" type="surname" value="Rubineau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person289" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I think the Prisoner is a moulder. I happened to be at Mrs. Blaker's when the Prosecutrix came in the day after the robbery: she called Mrs. Blaker, and said, do you know that man that was with me last night? Why, said Mrs. Blaker? Says the Prosecutrix, he has robbed me.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050017"></xptr> Says Mrs. Blaker, I am surprized you should go over the fields with a man you never saw in your life: what did he use you ill? No, says she, no otherwise than in taking my money from me. Says Mrs. Blaker, you were certainly fuddled, and I would not let you have any more liquor; the Prosecutrix said then, she was robbed of a cloak, a hat, and a handkerchief; Mrs. Blaker said, you had no such things with you last night; I knew Evans very well, and when he was taken up, I went to see him, and somebody said Mrs. Harvey was a litigious woman; I said she was not litigious, but only wanted her 16 s. again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441205-27-person290">
                  Peter 
                  Blaker 
               <interp inst="t17441205-27-person290" type="surname" value="Blaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person290" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was a note given between the Prosecutrix and her brother, the constable, about the reward, and Littlewood said he would get the note away, and make away with it, and then they could not prosecute.</p>
               <p>Littlewood. I never saw any note.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of any?</p>
               <p>Littlewood. I never did. <rs id="t17441205-27-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-27-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
