<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420224-23">
               <interp inst="t17420224-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-23" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-23" type="date" value="17420224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420224-23-off100-c128" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-defend173 t17420224-23-off100 t17420224-23-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>21. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17420224-23-defend173" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Plummer , alias <rs id="t17420224-23-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-defend173 t17420224-23-alias-2"></join>Cricklow</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-defend173" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-defend173" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-defend173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17420224-23-off100" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-off100" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-off100" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17420224-23-cd101" type="crimeDate">21st of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-off100 t17420224-23-cd101"></join>, feloniously made, and forged, a certain counterfeit Order in Writing, directed to Mr. Alexander, in Wood-street, &amp;c. with Intent to defraud <rs id="t17420224-23-viclabel102" type="occupation">
                     
                        <persName id="t17420224-23-victim174" type="victimName">
                           Wm
                            Alexander, and Company<interp inst="t17420224-23-victim174" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17420224-23-victim174" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17420224-23-victim174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-off100 t17420224-23-victim174"></join>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-victim174 t17420224-23-viclabel102"></join>, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-23-person175">
                  Robert 
                  Hutton 
               <interp inst="t17420224-23-person175" type="surname" value="Hutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person175" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was on the 21st of January last, I was standing at Gray's-Inn-Gate, in Holborn, when the Prisoner came to me, and asked me, if I would go on an Errand for him. I told him, I would if he pleas'd: he had then an half Sheet of Paper in his Hand, and we went into the Elephant and Castle together. I saw him write this (here) Paper, and he directed me to go with it to Mr. Alexander's, a Brasier and I, against St. Alban's Church in Wood-street. Accordingly I went there, and as soon as I came into the Shop, I delivered the Paper to Mr. Coking, Mr. Alexander's Servant. Coking looked over the Paper, and seemed to suspect it: he carried to Mr. Combes, who asked me, if I came from Mr. Gough; I told him, I did not know who Mr. Gough was, but the Person who gave me that Paper, was then waiting at the Elephant and Castle. Upon this, they scrupled giving me the Goods, and after I had waited half an Hour and upwards Mr. Combes sent two of his Servants before, and one of them went with me to the Elephant and Castle. When we came there, the Prisoner was gone from thence; but had left Word, that he would be back in an Hour. When he returned, this Paper was produced to him, and he own'd it was his Hand-writing, and wondered why Mr. Alexander did not send the Goods, for he had a Coffin to finish in haste in Bloomsbury-Square.</p>
               <p>The Paper was read.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Alexander, over against St. Alban's-Church in Wood-street.</p>
               <p>Send by the Porter, one set of Brass Work for Drawers, fifteen Handles, nine Locks, six Scutcheons,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240010"></xptr> two Keys, one Tenant Saw, two sets of three Shilling Leather Castors, and a sett of Ditto Brass, for the Use of me,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-23-person176">
                  William 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17420224-23-person176" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person176" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Gough, I am an Upholder, and live in Westminster, I have dealt with Mr. Alexander heretofore, but I think it is near 2 Years since I had any Thing of him.</p>
               <p>Counc. Is that Paper your Hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Gough. No, I believe it to be the Prisoner's, for I have compared it with several Receipts which I received from him when he was an Apprentice, and the Writing agrees exactly.</p>
               <p>Mr. Combes. The Prisoner confessed over and over that this Paper was his Hand-writing. Hutton brought it to our House, and desired to have Goods upon it. He first gave it to my Servant, who delivered it to me, and we went to the Elephant and Castle, and found the Prisoner. He at first said, he would send for his Master Gough, but afterwards begged for Mercy, and owned it was his Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-23-person177">
                  Wm 
                  Coking 
               <interp inst="t17420224-23-person177" type="surname" value="Coking"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person177" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Foreman to Mr. Alexander and was the Person that received this Paper of the Porter. He told me, he came from the Elephant and Castle, and after I had shewn the Note to Mr. Combes, I went with another Man to see for the Prisoner. When we came to the Elephant and Castle, the Prisoner was gone from thence, but he afterwards came in, and I clapp'd, him on the Shoulder, and ask'd him how he did? He asked me if I had brought him the Goods? I told him, I did not care to give them to the Porter, upon which he told me, I was very much in the Right, but he should have been glad if I had brought them with me. He told me, the Paper was his Writing, but as he was Gough's <rs id="t17420224-23-deflabel103" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-defend173 t17420224-23-deflabel103"></join> he had wrote it in his Name.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gough. He never work'd for me but two or three Days, and I never sent him with an Order to any Person.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There has been somebody else in the Name of Mr. Gough as well as myself, and as to the Paper, that is not the same that I wrote.</p>
               <p>A Woman. I have known him a good while, but never knew him do any Thing before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420224-23-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420224-23-punish105" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-23-punish105" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-23-defend173 t17420224-23-punish105"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
