<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-16">
               <interp inst="t17400416-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-16" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-16" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-16-off92-c96" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-defend127 t17400416-16-off92 t17400416-16-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>206. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-16-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Taper  alias <rs id="t17400416-16-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-defend127 t17400416-16-alias-3"></join>Huntley</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-defend127" type="surname" value="Taper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-defend127" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400416-16-defloc91">St Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-16-defloc91" type="placeName" value="St Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-16-defloc91" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-defend127 t17400416-16-defloc91"></join>, was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17400416-16-person128">
                  James 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person128" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person128" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17400416-16-person129">
                  John 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person129" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not yet taken) for <rs id="t17400416-16-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-16-victim131" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Fellows 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-16-victim131" type="surname" value="Fellows"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-16-victim131" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-16-victim131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-off92 t17400416-16-victim131"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Cambrick-Stock, value 3 d. a Silver-Clasp, value 2 s. 6 d. and 5 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-16-cd93" type="crimeDate">March 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-off92 t17400416-16-cd93"></join>.</p>
               <p>Robert Fellows. About the third of March last, - I can't tell exactly the Day, - the Prisoner stepped up to me, as I was going along the Street, over against <placeName id="t17400416-16-crimeloc94">St Giles's Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-16-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="St Giles's Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-16-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-16-off92 t17400416-16-crimeloc94"></join>, about half an Hour after eleven at Night; she took me about the Neck, with one Hand before, and the other behind, and got away from me my Stock and a Clasp. I saw nothing of her till she came upon me, and being surprized, I turned short upon her, and then two Men came up to me, and struck me on the Breast, and knocked me down. I don't know who the Men were, but one of them struck me down with a Blow he gave me on the Breast. When I was on the Ground, they turned out one of my Pockets, and took my Money, - 5 s. I am sure I lost, I believe I had more. The Prisoner, I am positive, is the Woman that came up to me first, for I had seen her at a House where I had been drinking that Night, and she would have come into my Company, had I not refused her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him, if he was not disguised in Liquor; and whether I did not make him leave his Watch, at the House where he treated me with two half Pints of Wine?</p>
               <p>Fellows. The Man of the House told me, he would have me leave my Watch with him when I went away, because there was a Woman in the House who was just come out of Newgate *, but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160012"></xptr> she did not say any thing to me about it. I had been drinking a Pint or two of Beer, but I was not (concerned) in Liquor. When the Man knocked me down , they searched me, and one of them swore , I had not got my Watch about me.</p>
               <p>* See last February Sessions, the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17400416-16-person132">
                  Alice 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person132" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person132" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             alias Taper, No. 140, P. 79.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Ask him, whether he and I were not at a Place together, where we had four Quarterns to Girl and whether he did not give the Clasp into my Hand, and say, - as I was a good honest Girl , he would give it me, for perswading him to leave his Watch behind him?</p>
               <p>Fellows . No; I never drank with her in my Life .</p>
               <p>Prisoner . He had but 6 d. about him, and that he spent with me; ask him, if he did not desire me to lead him home, because I would not stay with him all Night, and whether he did not say before Colonel De Veil, that he neither knew where the Robbery was committed, nor whether the Clasp was taken off his Neck, or out of his Pocket?</p>
               <p>Fellows . It was taken off my Neck; and I said the same before Colonel De Veil, that I have said now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-16-person133">
                  Susan 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person133" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person133" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was coming past St Giles's Church the third or fourth of March, between 11 and 12 o'Clock, and saw the Prisoner's Hand about the Prosecutor's Neck: I had seen him before, and was acquainted with the Prisoner, and the other two Men. After she had taken her Hands from his Neck, 
               <persName id="t17400416-16-person134">
                  Jack 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person134" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person134" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17400416-16-person135">
                  James 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person135" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person135" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came up, and knocked him down in the Dirt. I saw this, but I was afraid to speak then for fear of having my Brains knocked out. But the Prosecutor coming next Day to the House, where he had left his Watch, I told him what I knew, and went with him before Colonel De Veil, where I gave the same Account I have given now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her, whether I did not see her, next Day, in the Constable's House; whether I did not ask the Prosecutor there, if he knew who robbed him; whether the Prosecutor did not say, No; and whether she did not point to me, and tell him, I was the Person? She has a Spite against me, because I once served a Warrant upon her.</p>
               <p>Brown . She never served a Warrant upon me in her Life: Mr Fellows said he knew her, the Minute he saw her, and said she was the Woman. I only told him then, that I had seen her use him ill. I saw the Prosecutor in the House, that Night he was robbed; he had been drinking, but was not in Liquor, - he was not drunk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-16-person136">
                  Ann 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person136" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person136" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 4th or 5th of March, I met the Prisoner, and gave her a Pint of Beer: and Nanny (says she,) I am going to sell these</p>
               <p>Clasps, which I got the Night before, and a little Money with it. She told me she had picked a Man's Pocket, the Night before , so I went with her to sell the Clasps, in Drury-Lane . She said at first, that she had picked a Man's Pocket, and afterwards she said, she got the Clasps off, with the Stock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As he had given me the Clasps on Saturday Night, and had fetched his Watch on Sunday from the House where he left it, I thought I should never see him again, so I got this young Woman to go with me to seil them on Monday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-16-person137">
                  Samuel 
                  Daley 
               <interp inst="t17400416-16-person137" type="surname" value="Daley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person137" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and the last Witness brought me the Clasps, and sold them to me on Tuesday or Wednesday the beginning of March. These are the Clasps.</p>
               <p>Fellows. They are mine: they were taken from me at the Time I have mention'd. <rs id="t17400416-16-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-16-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
