<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-13">
               <interp inst="t17460903-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-13" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-13" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-13-off47-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-13-defend188 t17460903-13-off47 t17460903-13-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>295. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-defend188" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah Mc 
                     Kensey 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-13-defend188" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-defend188" type="given" value="Susannah Mc"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-defend188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-13-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one Worsted-Damask Waistcoat, and a Silver Watch, the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17460903-13-person189">
                        John 
                        Davis 
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person189" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-13-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-13-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , taken out of the Dwelling-house
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-victim191" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-13-victim191" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-victim191" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-victim191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-13-off47 t17460903-13-victim191"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             the <rs id="t17460903-13-cd48" type="crimeDate">13th of July</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-13-off47 t17460903-13-cd48"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-person192">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person192" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person192" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person193">
                  John 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person193" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person193" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Morris. She came into my House one Night with a Man; they came as Man and Wife, and ask'd for Lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Morris. In <placeName id="t17460903-13-crimeloc49">Charles-Street, St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-13-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="Charles-Street, St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-13-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-13-off47 t17460903-13-crimeloc49"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say to the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Morris. She ask'd if her and her Husband might have a Lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she come?</p>
               <p>Morris. The 13th of July last.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your Answer?</p>
               <p>Morris. I told her I had; immediately they order'd a Candle and went to Bed; they did not stay a Quarter of an Hour; they hired one Pair of Stairs backwards; they hired it for no time but that Night. He that she call'd her Husband was along with her; so that I went to Bed, and made all fast.</p>
               <p>Q. What then ?</p>
               <p>Morris. After they had been in Bed and put out the Candle, I goes to Bed about Twelve o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. When did they go to Bed ?</p>
               <p>Morris. About Eight or Nine.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Morris. So about Break of Day the Man knocks at my Room Door, where I lay; then I got out of Bed, and he told me he had lost his Waistcoat, his Watch and Money. How can that be, said I; why, there is none could come in there? I ask'd him how he lost it? He said, the Woman was gone that came along with him as his Wife.</p>
               <p>Court. So he lodg'd in your House that Night.</p>
               <p>Morris. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took the Lodgings?</p>
               <p>Morris. She took the Lodgings.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he by; did he say any thing at all to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Morris. No, he said nothing at all to the contrary. When he told me that he was robb'd, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030018"></xptr> said, how can that be, I had made every Place of the House secure. So I immediately got up. He said, the Woman is gone from me; I said, I thought she told me last Night that she was your Wife. So I gets up, thinking I should find her in some of the Rooms of the House. When I went down Stairs, I found the Shop secure, and the Back-Door secure, every Place secure, except the Yard-Door; that I left bolted when I went to Bed; so when I went down, I found the Door half shut and half open; then I went into the Yard, and I found the Track of Dirt from her Shoes on my Water-Tub; so I went into the Yard of an empty House, and some of the Threads of her Stockings stuck upon the Pales, and I found that Yard-Door broke open; that Yard-Door went into an Alley. About Ten o'Clock she was found.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing upon her ?</p>
               <p>Morris. Yes, we found something that belong'd to the Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did you find her from you?</p>
               <p>Morris. She had made her Escape from me; she was brought before Sir Thomas, and there I saw her.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Thing that you found upon her that belong'd to the Watch.</p>
               <p>Morris. An Ear-drop, it was found in her Bosom. Whilst I was hunting after her, my Maid-servant, going up to make the Bed, found the Waistcoat, ripp'd at the Top, where Davis had put his Watch and Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sensible this is the Man that came in with that Woman as his Wife?</p>
               <p>Morris. This 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person194">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person194" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is the Man that went to-bed with that Woman as his Wife.</p>
               <p>Court. Well, in Point of Law, a Woman can't steal Things from her Husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say that he was not her Husband?</p>
               <p>Morris. He did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-person195">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person195" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person195" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person196">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person196" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person196" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say to Susannah, the Wife of 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person197">
                  Robert Mc 
                  Kensey 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person197" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person197" type="given" value="Robert Mc"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Davis. What I have to say, please you, my Lord, I was going home from the House of Call; at the End of Long-Acre I met this Woman, the Prisoner; she ask'd me to treat her; I said, Woman, if I go to bed with you I will give you something: She said, Will you go to a Publick-House by, or to my own Lodgings? I said, I will go to your Lodgings, if you lodge by here; and went to Mr. Morris's, (here present) and had something to drink, and I paid for it; then we went up one Pair of Stairs, and she went down again for a Pint of Small-Beer; in the mean Time I pull'd my Cloaths off my Back, and put my Money and Watch, and other Materials belonging to it, in the Lining of my Waistcoat, and I went to bed with her. When I awak'd in the Morning, my Waistcoat, and all that I put in it, was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your Waistcoat?</p>
               <p>Davis. Damask.</p>
               <p>Q. What your Watch?</p>
               <p>Davis. A Silver Watch, with a Silver Chain, and nineteen Shillings in Money: Also, I put a Pair of Silver Buckles, and an Ear-drop that was hanging to the Chain of my Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with your Waistcoat?</p>
               <p>Davis. The Waistcoat was in my Coat, left on the Chair at-the Bedside.</p>
               <p>Court. Then she went to-bed with you.</p>
               <p>Davis. I went to-bed, and she came to-bed to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When you awak'd in the Morning, what then?</p>
               <p>Davis. I miss'd the Woman, the Waistcoat, and all that I put in it. I went down Stairs, seeking for a Place to get out, but found none; I then knock'd on the Floor, and found a Man and Woman lying together; I apply'd to the Landlord to let me have my Things, for God's Sake, and said I was ruin'd, and must not shew my Face any more; said he, I will do my Endeavour to get your Waistcoat again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get your Watch or Money again?</p>
               <p>Davis (answering very mournfully) No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to indict her for stealing your Waistcoat, when she left that, and it was produced before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Davis. I don't know how that came.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any thing more against her?</p>
               <p>Davis. She was the only Person that carried me into the House. The Door was fasten'd when we went to bed, by setting a big Chair against it.</p>
               <p>Court. Then that was the only Fastening the Door had, the Chair put against it.</p>
               <p>Davis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the Ear-drop ?</p>
               <p>Davis. This is the very Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-person198">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person198" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person198" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person199">
                  Elizabeth 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person199" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person199" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you?</p>
               <p>King. My Husband being a Constable a Warrant was brought to me; I was desir'd to go before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person200">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person200" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person200" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they telling me the Prisoner was there; I went, and Sir Thomas order'd to search her, and she desir'd it might be by one of her own Sex; upon searching her was found this little Heart, or Ear-drop: The Colonel ask'd, who that belong'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030019"></xptr> to, and how it came there? she said she did not know, it flew into her Bosom, as far as she knew, for she knew not how it came there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-person201">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person201" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person201" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-13-person202">
                  Jane 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person202" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person202" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Morgan. I know nothing more of it, than that the Justice order'd me to go to Mr. Morris and fetch the Waistcoat, and desir'd me to keep it till the Trial: The Waistcoat was produced, with the Lining ripp'd by the Prosecutor to secure his Watch and Money, &amp;c. and the Woman's rip at the Bottom to get it out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-13-person203">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-13-person203" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-person203" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) What have you to say in your Defence ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was with me last Sunday se'nnight; he said then, that he would not appear against me. He knew that he had the Watch afterwards, spent eight Pence upon me, and said he would not hurt me, and would fain have gone to-bed there at Clerkenwell.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-13-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-13-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
