<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400522-9">
               <interp inst="t17400522-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-9" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-9" type="date" value="17400522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-9-off55-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend99 t17400522-9-off55 "></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-9-off55-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend101 t17400522-9-off55 t17400522-9-verdict61"></join>
         
               <p>258, 259. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-defend99" type="defendantName">
                     Arthur 
                     Bethell , alias <rs id="t17400522-9-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend99 t17400522-9-alias-3"></join>Bethwell</rs>, alias <rs id="t17400522-9-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend99 t17400522-9-alias-4"></join>Barwin</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend99" type="surname" value="Bethell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend99" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-defend101" type="defendantName">
                     Martha 
                     White 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend101" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend101" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-defend101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17400522-9-off55" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-off55" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-off55" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400522-9-victim103" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Edwards 
                        <interp inst="t17400522-9-victim103" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-9-victim103" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-9-victim103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-off55 t17400522-9-victim103"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in fear, &amp;c. and taking from him, a Silver Watch, val. 3 l. and 3 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400522-9-cd56" type="crimeDate">April 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-off55 t17400522-9-cd56"></join>.</p>
               <p>Edward Edwards. Last Saturday was 3 Weeks between 10 and 11 at Night, as I was coming into <placeName id="t17400522-9-crimeloc57">Drury-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-9-crimeloc57" type="placeName" value="Drury-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-9-crimeloc57" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-off55 t17400522-9-crimeloc57"></join>, I was knocked down, and robbed of my Watch; and after this, I was follow'd, and was robb'd of my Money, - 3 s. and three-half-pence. I can't tell the Name of the Street. - I think 'twas in Baldwin's (Short's) Gardens. After I had been knock'd down, and lost my Watch, I got up, and being frighted, I went away; but they followed me, and knocked me down again, and took my Money away. After this, I got up, and made the best of my Way home. There was 2 or 3 of them, but who they were, who were concern'd in these Facts, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Bethell. Ask him if he had not been in any Woman's Company that Night?</p>
               <p>Edwards. Yes: I had been with a School-fellow of mine, one 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person104">
                  Mary 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person104" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person104" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and only drank a Pot of Beer with her; and when I came out of the House where we had been drinking, this Woman (the Evidence) followed me. I had been drinking with my School-fellow, somewhere in Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Bethell. Was not you above Stairs with that Woman?</p>
               <p>Edwards. No,</p>
               <p>Bethel. Ask him if he did not want to go up Stairs at that House, with the Evidence?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I did ask to go up Stairs with her; but the People of the House would not let me; for, as the People of the House told me, I was a little in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Bethell. Did not you go out of the House with the Evidence, and walk a Quarter of a Mile with her?</p>
               <p>Edwards. When I came out of the House, I left my Country-Woman there behind me; she wanted to go home with me, but I would not let her; and after I had got into the Street, 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person105">
                  Margaret 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person105" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person105" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (the Evidence) followed me, and went Part of the Way with me; 'till she lit of the 2 Prisoners, and then I was robbed. I was twice knock'd down, but I did not cry out, for I did not see any body in the Street, and I endeavoured to get out of their Hands. They had my Watch among them, and pawn'd it by 11 o'Clock the same Night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you drink with Casey, in another House, after you had left your Country-woman?</p>
               <p>Edwards. Yes; she carried me to the Prisoner Bethell's House, where we had a Quartern of Liquor; but this was before I was robb'd. And when I went out of the Prisoner's House, they followed me, and knocked me down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person106">
                  Margaret 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person106" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person106" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in a House at Covent-Garden, last Saturday Night was 3 Weeks, between 10 and 11 at Night, and the Prosecutor came in with 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person107">
                  Mary 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person107" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person107" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and drank a Pot of Beer with her. While he was drinking, he took it into his Head not to like 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person108">
                  Mary 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person108" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person108" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , so I asked him to go up Stairs with me, but the Woman of the House would not permit us to go up together; because he was very much in Liquor: So I asked him to come along with me, and give me a Dram; he consented, and I carried him to the Prisoner Bethell's House, where we had a Quartern of Gin, which cost 6 d. Bethell said, He (the Prosecutor) has got a Watch, and Money I want, and Money I will have; and when he went out of the House, He, and 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person109">
                  Martha 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person109" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person109" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, followed him, - we all three followed him out of the House. He was not above 2 Minutes in the House, before he went out, alone, and we went after him directly, and in Short's-Gardens, Bethell knock'd him down, took his Watch, and gave it into White's Hand, and she put it into her Pocket Apron. After this he told us, He had as good be hang'd for an old Sheep, as a young Lamb, and he would follow him again. He did so, and in Drury Lane, at the Corner of Short's Gardens, he knock'd him down again, and took 3 s. and some Halfpence from him, which he likewise gave to White; and we had each of us a Shilling a-piece, but the Halfpence were not divided. Then we all came back to Bethell's House, and we looked at the Watch; 
               <persName id="t17400522-9-person110">
                  Martha 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person110" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person110" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took off the Seal, and the Green Ribbon, which<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220011"></xptr> was in the Watch, and pull'd off the Ribbon which was-upon her Head, and put into it. We then all went into Oxendon Street, to a Pawnbroker's, and Bethell went in with the Watch, while we stood at the Corner of the other Street, and pawn'd it for 22 s. (as the Pawnbroker tells us) tho' he brought us but a Guinea. As soon as the Watch was pawn'd, we went to a House at the Corner of Oxendon Street, and had 2 Pints of mull'd Wine together: Bethell changed a Guinea there, and gave me a Crown out of the Money, besides the Expence; the rest of it He and White kept to themselves. When the Man was knock'd down, he did not cry out, for he was so much in Liquor, that really he did not mind it, nor who did it, but seem'd glad to get away as he could. We all 3 went after the Prosecutor upon this Design, and were to have assisted him, had there been any Occasion. White heard Bethell say, he wanted, and would have Money, before we went out, and she was nearer to him, when the Man was robbed, than I was. She was not with me, when I first pick'd the Man up; but when I brought him to the Prisoner's House, she served us with the Gin. This is the same Watch, and this is the String White pull'd off her Head, and put into it.</p>
               <p>Bethell. Had you no more than one Quartern in our House?</p>
               <p>Casey. No, not a Drop, 'till we came home from pawning the Watch; we then had more Liquor together at Bethell's House, and I went in Liquor to bed with him and his Wife, (White.) I had been acquainted at the Prisoner's House before this Time, and have drank Drams in it before. I can't tell whether the 2 Prisoners are Man and Wife, or not: Col. De Veil committed them when they kept a disorderly Night-Cellar, for not being Man and Wife; I know they live together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person111">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person111" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person111" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Bethell brought a Silver Watch to me, on Saturday Night, the 26th of April, and borrowed 22 s. upon it. They have said it was about 11 o'clock, - I can't be positive to the Hour; I thought it had been sooner. This is the Watch, and I then took it in from him, but he had it again from me on the Monday following. I know it again, and describ'd it when Col. De Veil sent for me: And I told him I could swear to it, if I could see it. When Bethell brought it to me he was in Mourning, and had been with me, (2 or 3 Days before he pawn'd this Watch) to cheapen one for himself; and told me that an Aunt of his, in Jermyn-Street, had left him 20 l. When he came to pawn this Watch on Saturday Night, he told me, he had bought it of one Johnson in Holbourn; but it seems this Johnson is the Man to whom he sold it, after he had redeem'd it from me. I had seen him once or twice, before he came to cheapen the Watch; and when he came to pawn this, I thought it was his own, and believed he had bought one.</p>
               <p>Edwards. This is my Watch: I bought it of Mr Haddon, in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner White. My Husband (Bethell) and Casey, can both clear me, for I know nothing of the Matter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Bethell. Casey came into my House with the Prosecutor, and my Wife carried them a Dram. -</p>
               <p>White. Did I carry it?</p>
               <p>Bethell. Yes, you carried it in, and the Man paid 6 d. for it, and went out of the House. He wanted to go to Bed, but we could not let him, upon which he went out of the House, and Casey staid behind him 3 Quarters of an Hour; and after that she went out, and returned with a Watch, which she said was her Husband's who was in Gaol, and I, being in Liquor, pawned it for a Guinea, 22 s. and she had every Penny of the Money. On the Monday following I heard she had picked this Man's Pocket, so I went and redeemed it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person112">
                  Ann 
                  Eager 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person112" type="surname" value="Eager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person112" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr Richards, who keeps the House in Covent-Garden, where the Prosecutor came to call for a Pot of Beer; the Evidence (Casey) brought him into the House, but I do not know what Day it was; I know her to be a Pick-pocket, and my Master bid me turn her out of the House. Then I asked the Man if he had lost any Thing? He said no; and turning the Flap of his Wastcoat aside, I saw his Watch was safe. After this, He and Casey went out together, and no one else was with them. I saw no Woman with the Prosecutor, but Casey; she brought him in, and she went out with him. I remember his coming in, and going out; and I know the Prosecutor again. - That is the Man, and I saw no Woman with him, but the Evidence.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did they drink together at your House?</p>
               <p>Eager. No; not as I know of; they did not stay half a Quarter of an Hour in our House, because my Master saw him in Liquor; and so he bid him go home. When I first saw him, he was going up Stairs with Casey, but I pulled him down by the Coat, and then they both went out of doors together. Next Morning he came, and told us he had lost his Watch. I never saw either of the Prisoners before.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person113">
                  Edward 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person113" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person113" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that himself was a Man of very good Character, and that Bethell had lodged with him about 3 Months, and worked at one Jasper's, a Baker, next Door to his House, in Great Earl Street. That he received 20 l. from the King's Apothecary, about 3 Weeks before this Trouble came upon him. That he always behaved well, and bore a good Character, and that he set himself up with the 20 l. he had received, in this House, in Short's Gardens (where the Prosecutor drank the Gin) and kept a Chandler's Shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person114">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bethwin 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person114" type="surname" value="Bethwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person114" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave an Account that Bethell, alias Bethwin, was a <rs id="t17400522-9-deflabel58" type="occupation">Journey-man Baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend99 t17400522-9-deflabel58"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend101 t17400522-9-deflabel58"></join> at Highgate, last Summer was a Twelvemonth; and since that in St. John Street; and that afterwards, he lived with his Uncle, a Cutler. That she had married the Prisoner's Uncle, and she never heard any thing ill of him before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person115">
                  Sam 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person115" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person115" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had been acquainted with Bethell, ever since he was a Child, he never heard any thing amiss of him, but took him to be a little soft, (or foolish) and did not believe he could have the Heart to do such a Thing.</p>
               <p>Mrs Bethwin spoke to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person116">
                  James 
                  Desca 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person116" type="surname" value="Desca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person116" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known White about 4 Years; he let a Cellar to her Mother, and the Prisoner (White) had been in his Kitchen to fetch Water, and he had not missed any thing. He took her to be a lewd Woman, but never heard she was a Thief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person117">
                  William 
                  Raven 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person117" type="surname" value="Raven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew her, but had heard neither Good, nor Harm of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-9-person118">
                  William 
                  Meakin 
               <interp inst="t17400522-9-person118" type="surname" value="Meakin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             swore he saw Bethell and White married at the Fleet*.</p>
               <p>* The Law supposing every Wife to be under the Coercion of her Husband, White called this Witness to prove her Marriage, that she might receive the Benefit arising from thence.</p>
               <p>Bethell <rs id="t17400522-9-verdict59" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-verdict59" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400522-9-punish60" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-punish60" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-9-defend99 t17400522-9-punish60"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. White <rs id="t17400522-9-verdict61" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-9-verdict61" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
