<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-54">
               <interp inst="t17400903-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-54" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-54" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-54-off299-c300" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-54-defend391 t17400903-54-off299 t17400903-54-verdict302"></join>
         
               <p>423. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-54-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Kelly 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-54-defend391" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-defend391" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-defend391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-54-off299" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-off299" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-off299" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing eight Guineas, and 2 Half-Guineas
            </rs>, the Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-54-victim393" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-54-victim393" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-victim393" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-victim393" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-54-off299 t17400903-54-victim393"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17400903-54-cd300" type="crimeDate">September 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-54-off299 t17400903-54-cd300"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mary Collins. The Prisoner lodged with me in <placeName id="t17400903-54-crimeloc301">Plumbtree Street , Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-54-crimeloc301" type="placeName" value="Plumbtree Street , Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-54-crimeloc301" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-54-off299 t17400903-54-crimeloc301"></join>. We had 2 Rooms on the same Floor, and we made Use of each other's Room. On Tuesday last she asked me to go with her, and see a Room of Goods, in Drury-Lane . I went; and when I came Home, I found my Keys upon the Bed , and the Money mentioned in the Indictment was taken out of my Box. I had left the Key of my Door where I always did, that as<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030036"></xptr> she was to come Home before me, she might know where to find it; for she always dressed and undress'd her Child in my Room. As I could suspect nobody but the Prisoner, (for no one else had been in my Room,) I taxed her with it, and she deny'd it. I go a-washing for my Living; but my Husband left me Part of this Money for my Child, and desired me not to break it. When I came home, I found the Prisoner had come in, and was gone out again. I had been abroad 2 Hours, and there are 2 Families live in the House, (6 or 7 People in all) but nobody has the Privilege to go into my Room but the Prisoner. On the Saturday before, she said, she had laid out all her Money at Market, but 3 Pence; and when I charged her with taking my Money, she said, O Lord, I would not hurt you for the World, do you think I robb'd you? I have nothing but a little small Money. But I saw her have Money in her Hand, and told her of it; upon which she ran down Stairs, and I calling out to stop her, she dropped 2 Guineas and 2 Shillings in the Passage. This was the very Day I lost my Money. The Prisoner deals in Fruit, and I have lent her 4 or 5 Shillings several Times to go to Market with. When she was before Colonel De Veil, she took out a Guinea from these Rags, and gave it to the Colonel. The Rags I am sure were in my Box with the Money, but she insisted upon it, that the Money was her own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-54-person394">
                  Judith 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17400903-54-person394" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person394" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person394" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Upon the Woman's missing her Money, I went out to see after the Prisoner, and brought her home, and she went up stairs into her Room jingling some Money. Collins asked her what that was? Upon which she ran down Stairs as fast as she could, and Collins called out, - stop her, she has got my Money! I stopped her at the Threshold of the Door, and she dropped 2 Guineas and 2 Shillings. She told Colonel De Veil it was her Money, and she pulled out another Guinea out of her Petticoat, and said she had 2 Guineas more in her Stays; all which Money she begged for in the late hard Frost, and worked for on other Times. While she was at the Justice's, I was sent home, to search her Room, with the Constable, and we found 2 Guineas in her Stays, but she said, these too were her own.</p>
               <p>Collins . The Prisoner lodg'd with me a Quarter of a Year before I came to this House, and I know no Harm of her but this.</p>
               <p>Roach. The Prisoner and Prosecutrix had been but 3 Weeks, in my House. I did not enquire after the Prisoner's Character when she came, because she came with Collins, and I knew her before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-54-person395">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17400903-54-person395" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person395" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person395" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            *. I am no Relation to the Prisoner, but I know her to be a very honest Woman, and a very just Woman. She maintains herself by selling Things about the Streets, and she goes out with her Child, to look for a Bit of Bread. I know she offered to lend my Mother 2 Guineas, about a Month after the late hard Frost; but my Mother did not borrow it. <rs id="t17400903-54-verdict302" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-verdict302" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>* In the following Trial, (which came on immediately after this) Kelly appeared as a Witness for Shilcock the Fidler, by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17400903-54-person396">
                  Mary 
                  Marson 
               <interp inst="t17400903-54-person396" type="surname" value="Marson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person396" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-54-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
            </div1>
