<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-5">
               <interp inst="t17400227-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-5" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-5" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-5-off25-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend58 t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-verdict30"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-5-off25-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend60 t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-verdict30"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-5-off25-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend62 t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-verdict30"></join>
         
               <p>153, 154, 155. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-defend58" type="defendantName">
                     Eliz 
                     Hales 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend58" type="surname" value="Hales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend58" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-defend60" type="defendantName">
                     Eliz 
                     Jarvis 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend60" type="surname" value="Jarvis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend60" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-defend62" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Humphryes 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend62" type="surname" value="Humphryes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend62" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-defend62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of St. Brides , were indicted for <rs id="t17400227-5-off25" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-off25" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-off25" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-5-victim64" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Dickerson 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-5-victim64" type="surname" value="Dickerson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-5-victim64" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-5-victim64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-victim64"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17400227-5-person65">
                        Godfrey 
                        Nodder 
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person65" type="surname" value="Nodder"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-5-person65" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-5-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , putting him Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Barragon Coat, val. 25 s. a Pair of Gloves, val. 12 d. a Hat, 3 s. a Cambrick Stock, and a Bathmetal Stock-buckle, val. 6 d. and a green Parchment Pocket-Book, val. 6.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400227-5-cd26" type="crimeDate">Feb. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-cd26"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-person66">
                  Charles 
                  Dickerson 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person66" type="surname" value="Dickerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person66" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday Evening between 10 and 11 at Night, I was going home to the Middle Temple lane, and, as I went up Fleet-Street, Jarvis asked me to give her a Dram. I told her I would not: but she followed me, and at last I consented, and upon her Importunity, I agreed to give her a Dram. Accordingly we went to Godfrey Nodder's House, in <placeName id="t17400227-5-crimeloc27">Hanging-Sword Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc27" type="placeName" value="Hanging-Sword Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc27" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-crimeloc27"></join>, a little above <placeName id="t17400227-5-crimeloc28">Salisbury Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Salisbury Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-crimeloc28"></join>, in <placeName id="t17400227-5-crimeloc29">Fleetstreet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc29" type="placeName" value="Fleetstreet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-5-crimeloc29" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-off25 t17400227-5-crimeloc29"></join> . - 'Tis a Sort of a publick House; they sell strong Liquors in it, but 'tis not an Alehouse, nor did I ever drink in the House before. Jarvis went up one pair of Stairs as soon as we went in, and I follow'd her. When we were got into the Room, she called for a Quartern of Rasberry; and after we had drank the Rasberry, I call'd to know what I must pay for it? they told me, 6 Pence. I said it was too much, and was not willing to pay 6 Pence for it, but they swearing I should pay 6 Pence, I paid it, and was going away about my Business. Then Jarvis and Humphreys stopp'd me, and Hales coming up Stairs at the same time, they all three insisted on my staying longer, and that I should give them a Shilling a-piece. I told them I had made no such Agreement with them, and that I had only promis'd to give Jarvis a Dram. On my refusing to give them a Shilling a-piece, Jarvis and Humphreys took me round the Body, and flung me upon the Bed; then Hales got upon me, and held me down, and almost throttled me. I turned Jarvis and Humphreys off from me, and at last I got off the Bed from Hales. They were all three upon me at the same time, on the Bed; but when I had disengaged myself from them, and was got off the Bed, they all three came about me again, and swore they would have my Waistcoat, and Hales tore open the Buttons both of my Coat and Waistcoat, and Humpbreys swore, if I made any Resistance, she would rip me open. Then they took from me my Coat, swearing by their Eyes, that it was better than my Waistcoat; they likewise took my Hat, my Stock and a Bath-metal Stock-buckle, and a Pair of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270006"></xptr> Gloves They unbuttoned my Breeches next, and ransack'd all my Pockets, and took five Pence halfpenny from me, which I have not put in the Indictment. After they had thus robb'd me, Jar-vis and Hales kept me in hold, while Humphreys carried my Things down Stairs, and when she had convey'd them away , I was turned out of Doors. Upon this I went back (in my Waistcoat, and withthout my Hat, to some Friends that I had been with all the Afternoon, and having told them how I had been serv'd, this Man ( 
               <persName id="t17400227-5-person67">
                  Charles 
                  Tates 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person67" type="surname" value="Tates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person67" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) went back with me to the House, and I went in at the Fore-door and found Humphreys and Hales . I asked them for my Things; Humphreys pretended to be asleep , but Hales told me she knew nothing about them; she said she only knew that I had had a Quartern of Rasberry, and had paid for it. While we were talking to Hales and Humphreys, some other Friends came from the Place where I found Mr. Yates, and they brought a Watchman with them. After they were come in, Hales fell down upon her Knees, and protested that she knew no more of the Affair, than my only having had a Quartern, and paying for it; afterwards they both pretended that I had promis'd them a Shilling each, and that I had left my Coat for one Shilling, and my Hat for another. We then took them both (Hales and Humpbreys) to St. Bride's Watch-house, and had them secur'd. Soon after this, Mr. Gordon (at whose House the Coat was left) took Farvis , and brought her to us, and she was likewise secur'd with the others. Next Morning they were carry'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17400227-5-person68">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person68" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person68" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and they own'd I had been in their Company, and that I had not offer'd any thing (uncivil) to them, - only that I had given them a Dram. They pretended, indeed, that I had left my Coat and my Hat for two Shillings, but they gave no Account what they took the rest of my things for. Upon my Oath, the three Prisoners are the Per sons ; and I offered no Indecency to them, nor did I leave any thing with them in lien of Money, as they pretended.</p>
               <p>Jarvis . When Mr. Gordon gave you your Coat again, did not you find your Gloves, and Stock and Buckle in the Coat-Pocket.</p>
               <p>Dickerson No.</p>
               <p>Jarvis . If we attempted to throttle you, you may have Marks to shew. Have you any?</p>
               <p>Dickerson.  No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-person69">
                  William 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person69" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person69" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Sunday Night last, I had been from Home and when I returned, I was told that 
               <persName id="t17400227-5-person70">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Jarvis 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person70" type="surname" value="Jarvis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person70" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had thrown a Coat into our House. I went out to see after her, and found her by St. Bride's Watch-House . I asked her how she dared take the Liberty to leave such Things at my House? Lord, Mr. Gordon, says she, there's no Harm in it, for the Man left it with me for 2 Shillings. I had heard that Dickerson had been robbed of his Coat, so I told her, I cared not who left it with her, nor what it was left for, she must go with me; so I took her to the Barley-Mow in Salisbury-Court, and enquired for the Man who had lost his Coat. The Prosecutor came out to me in his Waistcoat; I asked him if he knew that Woman? He said Yes, and told me he had got the other two in Custody, and now he had them all. I told him, I had got his Coat safe, and took him and Jarvis with me to my House, and when I produced the Coat to the Prosecutor, I asked him if that was his Coat? He told me it was. - (I believe he has got it now upon his Back) - Upon his owning the Coat, I gave it to him, and said, - there's your Coat, and there's the Woman that left it in my House. Then we carried her to the Watch-house, and the Prosecutor charged her in Custody with the other two, whom I knew nothing of. The Coat, which the Prosecutor owned, was the same which Jarvis acknowledged she had thrown into my House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-person71">
                  Charles 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person71" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person71" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prosecutor, I, and others had been in Company together, that Night, at the Barley-Mow in Salisbury-Court: He left us there something after 10, and told us he would go home; but he returned to us again, in Half an Hour, without his Coat and Hat, and said he had been stripped in Hanging-Sword-Court. By the Advice of the rest of the Company, I went with him to the House, to see if we could recover his Things. He shewed me the House, and I knocked at the Door; Hales opened it, and I saw all the 3 Prisoners in the Room; but Jarvis leaped away [thro' a Passage which is wainscotted off] the Minute I got in. The Prosecutor followed me into the House, and Humpbreys pretending to be asleep, I asked Hales if they knew what they had been about? I bid them give the Man his Things again, and said, - You'll get no good by what you have done, for he'll certainly prosecute you. Hales pretended at first, that she knew nothing of them: afterwards she said, he had left his Coat and Hat with them for 3 Shillings. We had not been long in the House, before 3 or 4 Men, whom we left at the Barley-Mow , came after us: I opened the Door and let them in. Then Hales fell down on her Knees, and said if the Man would stay a little while, he should have all his Things again. Accordingly we staid, but she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270007"></xptr> being dilatory, we charged a Watchman, (who came with our Friends) with both Her and Humpbreys, and they were sent that Night to the Counter. When we had done this, we agreed to go and have one Pot more at the Barley-Mow , and while we were drinking it, Mr. Gordon came with Jarvis, and asked for the Man who had lost his Coat? The Prosecutor knew her again, and we all went to Mr. Gordon's House, and the Coat being produced, the Prosecutor owned it, and Jarvis acknowledged she had left it there: Upon which she was carried to the Counter with the other two Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-5-person72">
                  John 
                  Hickman 
               <interp inst="t17400227-5-person72" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same Account with the preceding Witness. The Prisoners had no Witnesses to call either to the Fact, or to their Character, and insisted upon it in their Defence, that the Prosecutor left his Coat and Hat with them, as Pledges for 2 Shillings. The Jury found them all <rs id="t17400227-5-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400227-5-punish31" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-5-punish31" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend58 t17400227-5-punish31"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend60 t17400227-5-punish31"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-5-defend62 t17400227-5-punish31"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
