<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-3">
               <interp inst="t17400227-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-3" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-3" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-3-off14-c40" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-3-defend46 t17400227-3-off14 t17400227-3-verdict16"></join>
         
               <p>+ 151. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-3-defend46" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Hill 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-3-defend46" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-defend46" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-defend46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of St Giles's in the Fields, was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-3-victim48" type="victimName">
                           Magdalen 
                           Fleetwood 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-3-victim48" type="surname" value="Fleetwood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-3-victim48" type="given" value="Magdalen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-3-victim48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-3-off14 t17400227-3-victim48"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , about three in the Night, and stealing 3 Copper Potlids, value 3 s. a Copper Coffee-pot, value 2 s. a Copper Chocolate-pot, value 2 s. a Pewter Cullender, value 4 s. 5 Pewter Plates, value 2 s. 6 d. a Box-Iron and a Heater, value 3 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400227-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">February 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-3-off14 t17400227-3-cd15"></join>.</p>
               <p>Magdalen Fleetwood . My Kitchen-Window was broke open, and I lost the Goods mentioned in the Indictment. The Prisoner now will not deny the Fact. I was call'd out of my Bed, about 7 o'Clock the next Morning, by a young Man who lodges in my House; but I rais'd my Servant first, who told me the House had been robb'd and when I got up, I found a Pane of Glass had been taken out of the Casement, by which Means it had been opened, and I found it open. There are no iron Bars in the Window-frame, and when the Pane of Glass was taken out, any one might put their Hand in and unhasp the Casement. When I went to Bed over Night, at 11 o'Clock, I am sure the Casement was shut, and the Shutter, which slides up and down before the Window on the Outside, was up; but I had lost the iron Pin which fasten'd the Shutter at the Bottom, so we used to push it up, and let it rest on a Skewer in the Pin-hole, thinking no one would find the Way into my Kitchen. This Shutter I found down in the Morning, and the Casement open, and a pane of Glass out. It must have been done between my going to Bed at 11 o'Clock, and my rising next Morning at 7; but it was broad Day-light when I got up. I was fretted at the Loss of my Goods; but as I sat at Breakfast, the Watchman, and one Miller, (who belongs to New Prison) came to me, and ask'd me if I had not lost such and such Things? I told them I had; and they bid me come along with them. Accordingly I went with them to the Constable's House, in Brooks-Market, where I found the Prisoner, and all my Goods, after I had told the Constable the Marks of them; and then we all went before a Justice in Kirby-Street, with the Prisoner and the Goods, where he owned every Thing, and said he had taken the Goods out of my House. 'I ask'd him how he could serve me so? and he said he believ'd he was be witch'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-3-person49">
                  Rich 
                  Robins 
               <interp inst="t17400227-3-person49" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-person49" type="given" value="Rich"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman, and on the 4th of this Month, which was Monday, I was at my Stand, (between 4 and 5 in the Morning) above Holborn-Bars , over against Warwick Court; and the Moon shining I saw the Prisoner coming, along with a Bundle upon his Back. Before he came near me, he went cross the Way, in order to Shun me; but I cross'd at the Six Cann's-door , and caught hold of him, and ask'd him what he had got there? Ho said, he had only got two or three Plates, and a Pewter Dish. But I found the Bundle very heavy, and hearing the Copper and Pewter rattle, I told him there were more than two or three Plates and a Dish, and I ask'd him from whence he came? He said he came from Hammersmith with the Goods, and that he was carrying them to his Master, Mr 
               <persName id="t17400227-3-person50">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilkes 
               <interp inst="t17400227-3-person50" type="surname" value="Wilkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-person50" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . However, I carry'd both him and the Goods to the Watch-house, and went in the Morning to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270005"></xptr> enquire of Mr. Wilkes , If the Prisoner was to bring him any Goods from Hammersmith ? Mr Wilkes said, - No, d-mn him, I know nothing of him. Upon this the Prisoner and the Goods were carried before Mr. Justice Poulson. Mrs Fleetwood saw them and swore to them: and I swear they were the same Goods which I took upon the Prisoner in a Sack. When the Prisoner was before Mr Poulson, he said he let down the Window-Shutter, and took a Pane of Glass out of a Window backwards, and open'd the Casement, and so got into the Kitchen; and he told us he got out again the same Way he got in. He did not tell us what Time he did this, but he own'd he carried away the Goods, and it was between 4 or 5 o'Clock, - before Day-break, when I stopp'd him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If I would have given him a Shilling, he would have let me gone off with the Goods.</p>
               <p>Robins. 'Tis false; he never offer'd me any thing: but I took hold of his Collar, and carry'd him down to the Watch-house. <rs id="t17400227-3-verdict16" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-verdict16" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400227-3-punish17" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-3-punish17" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-3-defend46 t17400227-3-punish17"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
