<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420603-5">
               <interp inst="t17420603-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-5" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-5" type="date" value="17420603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420603-5-off19-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-5-defend57 t17420603-5-off19 t17420603-5-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420603-5-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Pewcross 
                  <interp inst="t17420603-5-defend57" type="surname" value="Pewcross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-defend57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-defend57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17420603-5-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting and robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420603-5-victim59" type="victimName">
                           Miles 
                           Haviland 
                        <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim59" type="surname" value="Haviland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim59" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, and taking from him one Iron Cock Key, and a wooden Leaver, value 5 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420603-5-cd20" type="crimeDate">May 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-5-off19 t17420603-5-cd20"></join>, the property of the <rs id="t17420603-5-viclabel21" type="occupation">
               
                     <persName id="t17420603-5-victim60" type="victimName">
                     New-River
                      Company
                  <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim60" type="surname" value="Company"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim60" type="given" value="New-River"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-5-victim60" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-5-victim60 t17420603-5-viclabel21"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-5-person61">
                  Miles 
                  Haviland 
               <interp inst="t17420603-5-person61" type="surname" value="Haviland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person61" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 10th of May, about 12 at Night, as I was going through <placeName id="t17420603-5-crimeloc22">Hodgsdon</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420603-5-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Hodgsdon"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420603-5-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-5-off19 t17420603-5-crimeloc22"></join>, I met the Prisoner and another with him, the Prisoner was coming down the High-Road, and the other in the foot Path, the Prisoner came up to me, and clapp'd a Pistol to my Breast, and demanded my Money, I said I had none, he said D - m you, you have Money, and if you do not immediately deliver it, I'll shoot you through the Body, then the other came up and searched my Pocket, and I had only a Counter in it; he was then going to take my Watch, and I hit his Hand aside, then he took hold of my Throat, and almost choak'd me, I pushed him away, and then the Prisoner snapp'd his Pistol at me; then I turned him (the Prisoner) round, and ran away, to the Watch-house, the Watchmen came immediately with me, and in returning we met 2 Men, the Moon shining very bright, I knew them to be the Persons who robb'd me, I seized the Prisoner, and the other ran away.</p>
               <p>Court. Which of them took the Key and Leaver.</p>
               <p>Haviland. I can't tell which but they was taken off my Shoulder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-5-person62">
                  Thomas 
                  Lonell 
               <interp inst="t17420603-5-person62" type="surname" value="Lonell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And please you my Lord, on the 10th of May about 12 at Night, Mr. Haviland came to our Watch-house in a very great Fright with his Watch in his Hand, and said he was robb'd, we ask'd him where, he said just by the London-Prentice; we went to his Assistance, and found his Hat and Wigg going along, we had not got 50 Yards farther before we met 2 Men, he challeng'd the Prisoner and said this is the Man that presented his Pistol to shoot me, and the other ran away.</p>
               <p>Court. Were the two Men going back, or coming forward?</p>
               <p>Lonell. They were coming forward.</p>
               <p>Court. Do you know any thing of a Pistol?</p>
               <p>Lonell. There was a Pistol found the next Morning, but whether it belong'd to them or not I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Another Watchman. Mr. Haviland came to our Watch-house and said, he was robbed by two Men, we went immediately along with him, and he took hold of the Prisoner, and said, this is the Man that clapp'd the Pistol to my Breast and the other Man ran away.</p>
               <p>Court. Do you know any thing of a Pistol being found?</p>
               <p>Watchman. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Court. Was Haviland sober when he came to the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>Watchman. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Constable. I was Officer for the Night, the Prisoner was committed to my Charge; these Things I saw the Watchman take from the Prisoner, 2 Knives, 2 Flints, a Tobacco box, and a Heal-Spur.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Last Sunday 3 Weeks, I came to London from Herefordshire, to see my Sister that is married, whom I had not seen for 22 Years; when I came to her House, we drank together, and was very merry, and going out of her House to do my Occassions, I was taken up by these Men, there was nobody along with me, but God and myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-5-person63">
                  Anne 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17420603-5-person63" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person63" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-person63" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And please your Honour my Lord, the Prisoner is my Brother, whom I had not seen for 22 Years; he came to my House about 7 at Night the 9th of last Month, he lay at our House that Night, and staid 'till twelve the next Night, when he was taken up; he went out of the Door, and mist his way in returning; when he was going out, I said, Brother, where are you going, and he said, only to do that you can't do for me. He had no Arms with him, only two Knives, a Tobacco box, and Flint, which he used to strike Fire with when he smoaked. I live near the London 'Prentice.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420603-5-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-5-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
