<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440728-19">
               <interp inst="t17440728-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-19" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440728-19" type="date" value="17440728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440728-19-off115-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-19-defend247 t17440728-19-off115 t17440728-19-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>321. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-defend247" type="defendantName">
                     Archer 
                     Hard 
                  <interp inst="t17440728-19-defend247" type="surname" value="Hard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-defend247" type="given" value="Archer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17440728-19-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two books bound, together with silver clasps, one the book of Common Prayer, &amp;c. the other the holy Bible, value five shillings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-victim249" type="victimName">
                     Christopher 
                     Plummer 
                  <interp inst="t17440728-19-victim249" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-victim249" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-victim249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-19-off115 t17440728-19-victim249"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17440728-19-cd116" type="crimeDate">May 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440728-19-off115 t17440728-19-cd116"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-person250">
                  Christopher 
                  Plummer 
               <interp inst="t17440728-19-person250" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person250" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my brother-in-law, he came to see my wife, and took this Bible. I missed it the twentieth of May; I made an enquiry after it, and found he had offered to pledge it to a pawnbroker in Old Street Road for 5 s. He s aid he would not take it in, because he thought it was stolen, and told me he believed he was gone to the Three Balls in Golden Lane. I went there, and asked him if he had taken in such a thing as that ; he said he believed he had, and gave me a description of the person that brought it. I got the Prisoner to go with me to the pawnbroker's, and he said he could swear that was the person that brought it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I ever deny before the pawnbroker that I carried the book there?</p>
               <p>Plummer. No; the Prisoner said when he came opposite to the house he knew what I was going about, and said I should have the book in a fortnight's time.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he took it with a design to steal it?</p>
               <p>Plummer. I believe he would have returned it, and that he never did such a thing before, but was put to straits for a little money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-person251">
                  Anthony 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17440728-19-person251" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person251" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Three Blue Balls in Golden Lane, the Prisoner brought this book to me to pawn (I believe it was earlier in May than the Prosecutor speaks of) and asked 12 s. upon it, (he did not offer to sell it) he said it was a book he had a great value for, that he had a child lay dead, and had not money to bury it, and that was the reason of his bringing it. I offered him 5 s. upon it, he said that would not do, for he was very hard put to it, so out of compassion I lent him more than another would have done, I lent him seven shillings; he did not pledge it in the name he was indicted by, but in the name of 
               <persName id="t17440728-19-person252">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440728-19-person252" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Plummer came with him another time, and while they were in the shop, he asked the Prisoner for money, and the Prisoner said brother have patience with me, and I will pay you every farthing; he said this when the Prosecutor was pulling him out of my shop by the collar - I did not think it was stole the Prisoner gave so good an accounts of himself, and told me where he lived.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. After my brother had been with me at Mr. Barnes's, I went home, and stuck at my work till night, and was at work when my brother came and took me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to pawn this in the name of Smith ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had borrowed this book of my sister several times to pawn, and did not care my brother should know it. I had a child lay dead then, and I did not care to beg the ground. I believe my sister would have been here if my brother would have let her come.</p>
               <p>Plummer. I did not hinder my wife from coming.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-person253">
                  William 
                  Ogden 
               <interp inst="t17440728-19-person253" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person253" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house, I have known the Prisoner about a year; when he came to live in the neighbourhood he was recommended by a friend, who said if he should want to borrow<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174407280015"></xptr> a shilling or two you may let him have it, which I have done, and he has paid me very honestly . He is a very industrious fellow; I have heard that the Prosecutor should say that he would spare nothing to separate the Prisoner and his wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440728-19-person254">
                  John 
                  Buckland 
               <interp inst="t17440728-19-person254" type="surname" value="Buckland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has worked with me a year and an half, his character is very good, and he has been honest in all cases since I knew him.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Buckland gave him the same character, as also Mary Butler , who has known him between four and five years. <rs id="t17440728-19-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440728-19-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
