<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441017-1">
               <interp inst="t17441017-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-1" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-1" type="date" value="17441017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441017-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-defend30 t17441017-1-off2 t17441017-1-verdict5"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441017-1-off2-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-defend32 t17441017-1-off2 t17441017-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>423, 424. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17441017-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth
                      *Andrews
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend30" type="surname" value="*Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend30" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend30" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17441017-1-defend32" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Page 
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend32" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend32" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-defend32" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17441017-1-defloc1">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-defend30 t17441017-1-defloc1"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-defend32 t17441017-1-defloc1"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17441017-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441017-1-victim34" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Burton 
                        <interp inst="t17441017-1-victim34" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441017-1-victim34" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441017-1-victim34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-off2 t17441017-1-victim34"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a silver clasp for a stock, value 2 s. and a cambrick stock , value 6d. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441017-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">Sept. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-off2 t17441017-1-cd3"></join> .</p>
               <p>* Andrews said her name was Isabella Andrews.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-1-person35">
                  William 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17441017-1-person35" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-person35" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of last month, between the hours of one and two at night, I was going to my lodging in Covent-Garden; but it raining very hard I was obliged to stand up, and got upon the steps of a night cellar in the <placeName id="t17441017-1-crimeloc4">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-crimeloc4" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-1-crimeloc4" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-1-off2 t17441017-1-crimeloc4"></join>; the woman of the cellar ( as I supposed her to be) asked me what I wanted? I said, I only stood up for the rain; but thinking she expected I should call for something, I said, bring me a pint of beer, and then I shall give you no offence: she would have pulled me down stairs, but I did not care to go down. The pint of beer was brought, I called a watchman and gave it to him, and he called a link-boy to drink with him, and asked me if I did not want a link. I said I did not want a link: the watchman said you are very safe, you may step down and stay till the rain is over. I believe I went down two or three steps, and staid about five minutes; I found the rain ceased, and went homeward. About three or four perch from the place I met the two Prisoners, and they said, Sir, where are you going? I said, I don't want any thing with you; they laid hold of me, and began to pull me and hustle me, and riot me to pieces; in the struggle I missed my stock and clasp, said I, You damned jades what do you rob me of my stock? For I missed my stock; but it is possible in the struggling with them that it might fall off, for it has fell off my neck two or three times as I have been at my work. - I missed it about three minutes after the struggle began; I put my hand up to my hat and wig to secure them, and called out watch, upon which Page run up an alley by Hungerford-Market, the watch and I followed her and took her, and Andrews was taken the next morning upon the steps of the Round-house in St. Martin's-Lane. - There was a Sailor with them but he got away.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174410170003"></xptr>Q. Did you find your stock and clasp again?</p>
               <p>Eurlon . No, I never did; the next morning the Prisoners quarrelled among one another, one said you got it and you pledged it, one said she was innocent , and the other said she was innocent.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Page . He said either Andrews or I took it, and then he charged 
               <persName id="t17441017-1-person36">
                  Nan 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17441017-1-person36" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-person36" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-person36" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with it .</p>
               <p>Burton . The other woman she speaks of was in company with them, but I could not swear that she touched me , so she was discharged before the Justice . - I am a servant at the Mows coffee-house, but my wife and I live in James Street Covent-Garden .</p>
               <p>Prisoner Andrews . You said before the Justice, you could not charge me with it.</p>
               <p>Burton . These are the women that hustled me. - They were not searched, the watchman said it would be to no purpose, for if they had it they had found means to convey it away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a light or a dark night?</p>
               <p>Burton . It was a cloudy night, but I am sure the Prisoners are the women. <rs id="t17441017-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441017-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
