<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411204-17">
               <interp inst="t17411204-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-17" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-17" type="date" value="17411204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-17-off74-c103" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-defend139 t17411204-17-off74 t17411204-17-verdict76"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-17-off74-c104" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-defend142 t17411204-17-off74 t17411204-17-verdict78"></join>
         
               <p>25. 
               <persName id="t17411204-17-defend139" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Dutton 
                  , alias <rs id="t17411204-17-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-defend139 t17411204-17-alias-5"></join>Huntley</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend139" type="surname" value="Dutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend139" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17411204-17-defend142" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Bessier 
                  <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend142" type="surname" value="Bessier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend142" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-defend142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , were indicted for <rs id="t17411204-17-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 30 s. a Steel Chain, value 6 d. 2 Seals, value 2 d. the Movement of a Watch, value 6 d. and a Cotton Handkerchief, value 3 d. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411204-17-victim144" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Rose 
                        <interp inst="t17411204-17-victim144" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-17-victim144" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-17-victim144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-off74 t17411204-17-victim144"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17411204-17-cd75" type="crimeDate">Nov. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-off74 t17411204-17-cd75"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-17-person145">
                  Daniel 
                  Rose 
               <interp inst="t17411204-17-person145" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person145" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Tuesday was Sevennight I had been to the Black-Bear in Piccadilly ; and came from thence pretty late, and in Liquor , and before I got Home, I had my Pocket picked of my Watch. I am certain I had it when I left the Black-Bear, for I took it out of my Pocket to see what o'Clock it was, and as to my losing it, the next Witness Mr. Fish can give a</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040010"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>better Account than myself, for I was very much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-17-person146">
                  William 
                  Fish 
               <interp inst="t17411204-17-person146" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person146" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of Nov. about 12 o'Clock, I was going Home, and saw the two Prisoners and 
               <persName id="t17411204-17-person147">
                  Daniel 
                  Rose 
               <interp inst="t17411204-17-person147" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person147" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They had got him in a Door-way near Brownlow street in Holbourn . I saw Dutton with the Watch in her Hand Mr. Rose was very much in Liquor, and she bid him good Night, and ran 'cross the Way directly, and bid the other Woman run too. I perceiv'd by that that they had robb'd him of his Watch, so I went up to him, and asked him if he had lost any Thing? He said he had not, but as soon as he had felt in his Pocket, he attempted to pursue the Prisoners, but being very much in Liquor he fell down. Dutton ran up Warwick Court by the White Hart Tavern, and as soon as I had seized her, I asked her for the Watch, and she pulled it out of her Bosom and thrust it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the other Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Fish. She did not go away, but staid in the Court. This is the Watch I had of the Prisoner, and before Rose felt for it, he told me the Name on the Dial-Plate. The next Day the Prisoners were carried before Justice Poulson, where Bessier charg'd Dutton with taking the Guts of a Watch , and a Handkerchief from the Prosecutor in Lincoln's Inn-Fields . Dutton could not deny it, and they were fetch'd from her Sister in New Prison, by the Justice's Order.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-17-person148">
                  William 
                  Grasing 
               <interp inst="t17411204-17-person148" type="surname" value="Grasing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person148" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was Constable of the Night. The Prisoners were brought to me by Mr. Rose and Mr. Fish, and charg'd with robbing him of a Watch, and the Guts of a Watch besides. Rose was very much fuddled: He had fell in the Kennel, and was so muddy, that he could not see out of his Eyes. When he came to himself, he describ'd the Watch, and I took the Prisoners to New-Prison that Night. The next Morning they were carried before Justice Paulson , where the tall one Dutton desired to be admitted an Evidence; but Bessier charg'd her with taking other Things from the Prosecutor, and she appearing to be the principal Person, the Justice refused to admit her Information.</p>
               <p>Dutton. I had been with this young Woman to see her Mother, and coming through Lincoln's Inn-Fields, this Gentleman called after us. His Hat fell off, and I put it on again several Times, and left him. A Man that knew me happen'd to stop me in Holbourn , and the Prosecutor over took me. He put the Watch into my Hand, and in the mean Time Mr. Fish came up, and asked him if he had not lost his Watch? The Prosecutor said, he knew who he had given it to, and it was safe. He pulled his Handkerchief out of his Pocket, and the Guts of a Watch left out with it. I would have given them to him again, but he said they were of no Consequence, and I might keep them.</p>
               <p>Bessier. I was coming along with this Woman, and in Lincoln's Inn-Fields we met this Man, and the first Thing she took from him was the Guts of the Watch, and afterwards in Brownlow-street she took the Watch out of his Pocket .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-17-person149">
                  Mary 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17411204-17-person149" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person149" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can say no farther than that my Daughter (Bessier) never behav'd unhandsome.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Horn. I keep a House, and have a great many good Things in it, and I never knew that she wrong'd me of any Thing.</p>
               <p>Dutton <rs id="t17411204-17-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17411204-17-punish77" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-punish77" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-17-defend139 t17411204-17-punish77"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Bessier <rs id="t17411204-17-verdict78" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-17-verdict78" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
