<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-18">
               <interp inst="t17420909-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-18" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-18" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-18-off89-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-18-defend186 t17420909-18-off89 t17420909-18-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>73. 
               <persName id="t17420909-18-defend186" type="defendantName">
                  Magdalen 
                  Swawbrook 
               <interp inst="t17420909-18-defend186" type="surname" value="Swawbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-defend186" type="given" value="Magdalen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-defend186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17420909-18-defloc88">St John Evangelist</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-18-defloc88" type="placeName" value="St John Evangelist"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-18-defloc88" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-18-defend186 t17420909-18-defloc88"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17420909-18-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420909-18-victim188" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Pearce 
                        <interp inst="t17420909-18-victim188" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-18-victim188" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-18-victim188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-18-off89 t17420909-18-victim188"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , and taking from thence one Piece of Gold Coin called a Guinea, value 21 s. one Piece of Gold Coin, value 10 s. 6 d. and five Shillings in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420909-18-cd90" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-18-off89 t17420909-18-cd90"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-18-person189">
                  Charles 
                  Pearce 
               <interp inst="t17420909-18-person189" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-person189" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Sir, the Prisoner at the Bar I suspected, because she knew where the Money was, and no Body (as I know of) but she: I had Occasion to take some small matter of Money to lay out, and when I came the Money was gone, and the Thing that it was put in, and when I saw it was gone, which was a Disappointment to me for want of Money, I opened the Windows of the little House I lived in, and there was a Pane of Glass broke, I took the outside Shutters and turn'd them aside, and the upper Part of the Glass or Frame was upheld by a long sort of a Spike-Nail; so I conjectur'd she was the Person that did it; I met her in St Martin's Church-Yard in the Evening; the Constable who was with me took her up and carried her before a Justice of the Peace, she confessed nothing that I know of, for I could not hear if she did, for I am as deaf as this Board. I lost 39 s. and 6 d. from out of a Chest of Drawers which stood in a Ground-Room: The Window was fastened when I went to Bed, which is generally about 8 o'Clock, but I cannot tell what Time it was down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say, but that it is a malicious Prosecution; I suppose, Gentlemen, you know that it is my own Father.</p>
               <p>Court. Is she your own Daughter?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090010"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-18-person190">
                  Charles 
                  Pearce 
               <interp inst="t17420909-18-person190" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-person190" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I must pull out my Barnacles *. She is my Daughter; (and wept.)</p>
               <p>* The Prosecutor being quite deaf, he was sworn by a written Copy of the Oath, which he pronounced, and the Questions were all put to him by Writing.</p>
               <p>[His other Daughter was called for to be sworn.]</p>
               <p>Court. Is that your Daughter?</p>
               <p>Pearce. Yes: she is eleven Years of Age, and I am Four Score and Eight.</p>
               <p>[She appearing to be so young, and likewise an Accomplice, the Court did not think proper to admit her to give Evidence .]</p>
               <p>Radford. The 29th of July I had been by Water, and when I came Home at Night the Door of the Palace Yard was put to, which used to be open,'tis a Door between Justice Blackerby's House and the Bridge-Office , there's a Bench the Watermen have to sit upon, I saw the Prisoner at the Bar sitting upon it, and somebody else with her behind the Door. 'Tis under the Place where the King goes to the Parliament House, the Bench moves backward and forward; in the Morning I heard a Report that the old Man's House was broke open, and that his Daughters were gone; I believe she lived with her Father (from the Death of her Mother) till the Time this thing happen'd: Thinks I, I do not like this Thing; this young Witness was gone too, and it was told me that his Daughter was got into a Coach in King's-Street, Westminster, with a Horse-Grenadier : The old Man finding his Money gone, cried, What will no Body help me! So I being Constable, I took her up and carried her before Justice Manley, the next Evening about seven or eight o'Clock, and after some Examination, (it was taken in Writing, but not sign'd) she said her Husband, as she called him, was a Horse-Grenadier, and was going with the last Forces to Flanders ; she was going with him, for she was one of the four Women that was to go with the Troop. <rs id="t17420909-18-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-18-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
