<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480224-23">
               <interp inst="t17480224-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-23" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480224-23" type="date" value="17480224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480224-23-off131-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-23-defend216 t17480224-23-off131 t17480224-23-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>143. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480224-23-defend216" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Dickins 
                  <interp inst="t17480224-23-defend216" type="surname" value="Dickins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-defend216" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-defend216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17480224-23-defloc130">Finchley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-23-defloc130" type="placeName" value="Finchley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480224-23-defloc130" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-23-defend216 t17480224-23-defloc130"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17480224-23-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480224-23-victim218" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Saunders 
                        <interp inst="t17480224-23-victim218" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-23-victim218" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-23-victim218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-23-off131 t17480224-23-victim218"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   (her <rs id="t17480224-23-viclabel132" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-23-victim218 t17480224-23-viclabel132"></join>) on the <rs id="t17480224-23-cd133" type="crimeDate">25th day of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480224-23-off131 t17480224-23-cd133"></join> last, by beating and striking her on the head, back, belly, breasts and sides, and thereby giving her several<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240017"></xptr> mortal wounds and bruises , of which she languished, from the said 25th day of December to the 22d day of January, and then of the said mortal wounds and bruises died. The Indictment further faith, that the said 
                     <persName id="t17480224-23-person219">
                        Ann 
                        Dickins 
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person219" type="surname" value="Dickins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-23-person219" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480224-23-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   being void of all christian charity , after the 1st day of August last, and continually afterwards , to the 22d day of January, did not allow to the said Ann (an infant of the age of sixteen years) sufficient victuals, drink, and necessaries, to preserve life; and that the said Ann, by reason of the want of sufficient victuals, drink, and other necessaries , languished, and languishing did live from the said first day of August to the said twenty-second day of January, and then miserably perished and died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-23-person220">
                  Mary 
                  Bishop 
               <interp inst="t17480224-23-person220" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person220" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge the Prisoner with?</p>
               <p>Bishop. I charge her with what the child said, that she called upon the Prisoner for water, and she would not let her have any.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Bishop . The day before the shortest day.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before the child's death ?</p>
               <p>Bishop . About five Weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing of this a day or two before?</p>
               <p>Bishop . No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-23-person221">
                  Sarah 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17480224-23-person221" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person221" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person221" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn .</p>
               <p>Q. do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes; the Prisoner brought Ann Saunders into my house and beat her with a mopstick.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago was this?</p>
               <p>Holloway. About Christmas time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . It was about Michaelmas , my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the child die?</p>
               <p>Holloway . I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the child die of that beating?</p>
               <p>Holloway. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the child complain of this usage?</p>
               <p>Holloway. Yes, she said her mistress would kill her, and that she swore she would kill her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her beat her at other times?</p>
               <p>Holloway. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. With what?</p>
               <p>Holloway. With a whip, a stick, a handbrush, and other things.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before the death of the child, that you saw her beat her at all?</p>
               <p>Holloway. About a month.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this done?</p>
               <p>Holloway. At my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the child lie at your house?</p>
               <p>Holloway. No, she lay at her mistress's.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition was the girl in after this last beating?</p>
               <p>Holloway. She kept her bed several times; she was out of doors the day before she died, and the day after she died she had not a free place about her head, and her body appeared black and blue.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this?</p>
               <p>Holloway. It was told me by a woman who stood by when the girl was opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing further?</p>
               <p>Holloway. The Prisoner had a horse died, and she laid the cause of it to this child, and said that this girl should not be long after him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to lay the death of the horse to this girl ?</p>
               <p>Holloway. I cannot say any thing to that.</p>

               <p>Prisoner . I desire to know of her, why I took the girl to her house?</p>
               <p>Holloway. To shew me her nastiness, and how she was bedaubed with dirt* and water.</p>
               <p>* The deceased had an infirmity of nature, that she could not hold her water, &amp;c. and the Prisoner knew it before she took her, for the parish gave her six pounds with the child on that account .</p>
               <p>Pris. Would she ever let her shoes be tied? did not you see what a slattern she was?</p>
               <p>Holloway. The child was a slattern .</p>
               <p>Pris. Did not she deny every point of this the day after ?</p>
               <p>Holloway . Yes, she did, my Lord, but I was told, it was because she was beat so, that she durst not speak of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-23-person222">
                  Robert 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17480224-23-person222" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person222" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn .</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to charge the Prisoner with?</p>
               <p>Holmes . She is indicted for the murder of her maid. I saw the girl one day coming down stairs, and her mistress was following her, beating her with a stick as big as my thumb.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any great wounds made by that beating?</p>
               <p>Holmes . She struck her upon her head, but I did not see any wounds; I asked the Prisoner what she meant by that, and she said she would kill her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she strike the girl after you said that?</p>
               <p>Holmes . No, she went out of the house directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480224-23-person223">
                  William 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17480224-23-person223" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , surgeon. I opened the body, and examined it, and did not find any thing that might occasion her death; and it appeared by the upper and lower belly, that there was no inflammation, or any extravasated blood, that might occasion her death.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174802240018"></xptr>Q. Was there any thing black and blue upon it?</p>
               <p>Bailey. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any marks upon her body?</p>
               <p>Bailey. There was something upon her thigh, which looked red. The deceased was very much emaciated, and the mistress of the girl told me, she had had a Diarrhoea upon her for a great while.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17480224-23-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480224-23-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted her of the murder, and also acquitted her on the Coroner's Inquisition, and found that the deceased died a natural death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
