<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401204-17">
               <interp inst="t17401204-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-17" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-17" type="date" value="17401204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401204-17-off90-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-defend148 t17401204-17-off90 t17401204-17-verdict94"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401204-17-off93-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-defend156 t17401204-17-off93 t17401204-17-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>* 23 
               
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-defend148" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Legrose 
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend148" type="surname" value="Legrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend148" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17401204-17-defloc89">St. Mary, White-chapple</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defloc89" type="placeName" value="St. Mary, White-chapple"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defloc89" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-defend148 t17401204-17-defloc89"></join>, was indicted (with 
               <persName id="t17401204-17-person149">
                  William 
                  Yorke 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person149" type="surname" value="Yorke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person149" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , not taken) for <rs id="t17401204-17-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17401204-17-victim151" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Clack 
                        <interp inst="t17401204-17-victim151" type="surname" value="Clack"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-17-victim151" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-17-victim151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and stealing 31 Cloth Coats, value 30 s. 23 Cloth Waistcoats, value 20 s. 13 Cloth Jackets, value 10 s. 13 pair of Breeches, value 5 s. 6 Shirts, value 12 s. one pair of Leather Breeches, value 1 s. and 3 Shifts, value 3 s. the Goods of 
                     <persName id="t17401204-17-person152">
                        John 
                        Clack 
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person152" type="surname" value="Clack"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-17-person152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-17-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17401204-17-cd91" type="crimeDate">Sept. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-off90 t17401204-17-cd91"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-off93 t17401204-17-cd91"></join>. And,</p>
               <p>* For this Fact 
               <persName id="t17401204-17-person153">
                  Edward 
                  Mudder 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person153" type="surname" value="Mudder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person153" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17401204-17-person154">
                  Tho 
                  Clack 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person154" type="surname" value="Clack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person154" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were tryed last Sessions.</p>
               <p>24. 
               
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-defend156" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Frame 
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend156" type="surname" value="Frame"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend156" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-defend156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17401204-17-defloc92">St. George, Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defloc92" type="placeName" value="St. George, Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-17-defloc92" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-defend156 t17401204-17-defloc92"></join>, for <rs id="t17401204-17-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 10 Cloth Coats, 3 Cloth Jackets, and 13 pair of Breeches, Parcel of the said Goods, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-person157">
                  John 
                  Clack 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person157" type="surname" value="Clack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My House was broke open on the 17th of Sept and robb'd of the Things mention'd in the Indictment; my Doors were fast when I went to Bed, and when I was wak'd, I found 'em broke in a violent manner. The Lock on the inside was broke, and the Padlock taken off; I lost so many Things, that I was obliged to hire a Cart to bring them here last Sessions.</p>
               <p>Valentine Harman. The Prisoner Legrose, one Wood, and two Men that were try'd last Sessions, brought some Cloaths to my House: I live in Rag-Fair and deal in Rabbits, and was going to the Brew-house for Grains, when they came in, with each his Arm full of Cloaths; it was the 17th, of Sept. between One and Two in the Morning. They laid their Bundles down on the Ground,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174012040008"></xptr> and said one to another: Come, let us go back for some more. I asked where they had them from ? and the Prisoner said, from a House in Rag-Fair; they then went down the Alley, and I call'd up Mr. Studder, and shut him into a Closet, because they should not see him. In a little Time they knock'd at the Door, with each another Arm full of Cloaths, which they threw down on the Floor to the rest; the Prisoner was for going for more, but Clack (who was executed) said, No, let us have some Victuals and Drink first. Aye, said the Prisoner, let us have three or four Shillings worth of Bread and Cheese. I catch'd hold of these Words, and said, I would fetch some. I gave them a Candle, and desired them to go up Stairs; they did so, and I immediately went to the Watch-House for an Officer; we came back and let Studder out of the Closet; and took Madder, Clack, and Wood; but the Prisoner was gone, pretending to fetch his Wife. We carried them to the Watch-House, and the Prisoner having told me there were as many more Cloaths at Carlow's, as at my House, we went there, and knock'd at the Door; the Prisoner Frame, came to the Door, and said, she could not find the Key; I look'd through the Key-hole, and saw the Prisoner Legrose go out at the Back Door, and then we were let in. I look'd down the Cellar Stairs, and saw a great many Cloaths which the Prosecutor own'd to be his; he came to us soon after we had secur'd those three Men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-person158">
                  Thomas 
                  Studder 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person158" type="surname" value="Studder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person158" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd the above Evidence.</p>
               <p>Clack, again. When I was call'd out of Bed, I went to the House where that Gentlewoman who stands at the Bar lives, and we demanded Entrance; she kept us some time at the Door before she would let us in, and when we did get in, I saw a great many of my Cloaths on the Cellar-stairs.</p>
               <p>Harman. Mrs. Carlow, was at that Time gone to France, and the Prisoner Frame , was left to take Care of the House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Frame. I desire the Prosecutor may be ask'd, whether he found any of his Cloaths in my Room?</p>
               <p>Clack. I don't remember that I was in her Room.</p>
               <p>Harman. I am positive it was the Prisoner Frame that kept us out, for I saw her thro' the Key-Hole, and the Yard-Door was open, but I can't say that she knew of the other Prisoner's going out.</p>
               <p>Frame. I waited in the Room with his Witnesses all the last Sessions, and he said my Name was never mentioned; I drank Part of two full Pots of Beer with him.</p>
               <p>Clack. I did mention her Name here several Times; and as to drinking with her, I don't know but I might drink a drop of Gin with her.</p>
               <p>The Constable. I had Legrose's Commitment from Justice Fowke to bring him to Newgate, and in the Way thither I told him he had better have gone abroad; but he said, D - n it, it is too late now, but I wish I had the old Rogue (the Prosecutor) in my Place. He desired that I would speak for him, that he might be put in the same Place with his Accomplice Madder.</p>
               <p>Legrose. I know nothing of what is alledged against me.</p>
               <p>Frame. I was to have 2 s. a Week for looking after this Woman's House; I never saw this Man till I saw him in Prison .</p>
               <p>The Revd Mr. Guthrie. The Prisoner Frame liv'd with me as a Servant two or three Years, and I never heard but that she was an honest Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-person159">
                  Richard 
                  Yeomans 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person159" type="surname" value="Yeomans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person159" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her between five and six Years; I never heard any Ill of her, but she always behav'd herself well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-17-person160">
                  Margaret 
                  Cray 
               <interp inst="t17401204-17-person160" type="surname" value="Cray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person160" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She has been an honest Woman ever since I have known her; I was her Bail, and do not think that she would receive Goods knowing them to be stolen.</p>
               <p>Legrose <rs id="t17401204-17-verdict94" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-verdict94" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17401204-17-punish95" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-punish95" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-17-defend148 t17401204-17-punish95"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Frame <rs id="t17401204-17-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-17-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
