<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-20">
               <interp inst="t17420909-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-20" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-20" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-20-off98-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-20-defend197 t17420909-20-off98 t17420909-20-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>75. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Harris 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-20-defend197" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-defend197" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of London, <rs id="t17420909-20-deflabel97" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-20-defend197 t17420909-20-deflabel97"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420909-20-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four Linnen Shirts, value 40 s. four Pieces of Portugal Gold Coin, val. 36 s. each, and six Pieces of Gold Coin, called Guineas, val. 6 l. 6 s. in the Dwelling-House
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17420909-20-person198">
                  John 
                  Pauncefort 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person198" type="surname" value="Pauncefort"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person198" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-victim200" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Pauncefort 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-20-victim200" type="surname" value="Pauncefort"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-victim200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-victim200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-20-off98 t17420909-20-victim200"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             , <rs id="t17420909-20-cd99" type="crimeDate">July 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-20-off98 t17420909-20-cd99"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person201">
                  John 
                  Pauncefort 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person201" type="surname" value="Pauncefort"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person201" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live at the <placeName id="t17420909-20-crimeloc100">Angel and Crown without Bishopsgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-20-crimeloc100" type="placeName" value="Angel and Crown without Bishopsgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-20-crimeloc100" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-20-off98 t17420909-20-crimeloc100"></join>. On the 24th of July, I had a Bureau set on Fire about eleven a-Clock at Night. The best Part of my Linnen was in it; I believe I lost a Dozen Shirts, tho' I have laid but four in the Indictment. I was not at Home at the Time of this Fire. - I had a Suspicion of the Prisoner, because my Shop-Maid told me she found her at the Till the Day before, with a false Key. - When I came Home, I found my Bureau burnt up to the Well where the Money was; then I missed these Pieces of Money, and charged the Prisoner with taking them. She was then my Servant, she said she never wronged me of any Thing in her Life. I then took her up, had her searched, but did not find the Money upon her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Did you see the Bureau on Fire?</p>
               <p>Pauncefort . No; it was out before I came in, the Drawers were taken out, but I do not know who took the mout. - The bottom Drawer, where my Linnen was, was carried to a Neighbour's next Door. I cannot say I know how the Fire began; the Money, I apprehend, was lost by the Bureau being opened with a Key.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Had not you a good Character of me from Mr. Gardner of Gloucester .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person202">
                  John 
                  Pauncefort 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person202" type="surname" value="Pauncefort"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . My Sister, who sent her up, had a very good Character of her, both from her Master and Mistress.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person203">
                  Sarah 
                  Worral 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person203" type="surname" value="Worral"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person203" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I caught her at my Master's Till the 23d of July, between six and seven o'Clock in the Morning; she was alone in the Shop, in a very unseemly Manner to come down Stairs: I went behind<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090011"></xptr> the Counter, and found my Key there. I asked her how my Key came there, but she made me no Answer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you know any Thing of the Bureau's being broke open, or of the Fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person204">
                  Sarah 
                  Worral 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person204" type="surname" value="Worral"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person204" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never went up Stairs after five o'Clock, till it was quite out - The Drawers were carried to Mr. Smith's, and no Body went into the Room but him, that I know of, it was between ten and eleven at Night. I was in the Shop, when the People called out Fire. I told the Prisoner of it, and she made me no Answer. - I did not see her carry any Water up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person205">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person205" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 24th of July, very near eleven o'Clock at Night, I was called in a great Hurry, and told that Mr. Pauncefort's House was on Fire. A young Man in the Neighbourhood and I went up Stairs, and found the Prisoner at the Bar at the Kitchen-Door; when I came up into the Room where the Bureau was, which was a Pair of Stairs higher, I saw the under Drawer of the Bureau all in a Flame, and I threw a Pail of Water upon it and put it out. I called out for a Light to the Prisoner, who was below, but she brought none, neither did she come up, but some other People came up with more Water. I did not go out of the Room till the Fire was out; when the Fire was quite extinguished, I moved the Bureau from the Wall, for fear of it's setting Fire to the Paper Hangings. Then several Neighbours came up, and a Candle was brought; presently the Desk Part fell down, said I, this is surprizing, it has either been broke open, or was never locked. I looked at it, and the Bolt was shoved back. Soon after this, Mr. Pauncefort came Home. I told him what had happened, he said he had locked his Bureau in the Morning, and left his Money in it, and then he imagined that the Prisoner at the Bar had robb'd him; a Constable was sent for, and she was searched by the Constable ; but he did not find it upon her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person206">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ellcock 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person206" type="surname" value="Ellcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person206" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Hearing the Report of a Fire, I went to see how Mr Pauncefort's Sister did, for she had been in a Fit. A Constable was sent for, the Prisoner was searched, but there was no Money found upon her; but in searching her Room, I turned down her Bed, and there were four clean Shirts. I asked the Prisoner if she knew any Thing of them, she said she put them there in a Fright.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person207">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person207" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person207" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In letting down the Bed, I found four clean Shirts; the Prisoner said she put them there in a Fright.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person208">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Twigger 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person208" type="surname" value="Twigger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person208" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was charged by the Constable to search the Prisoner at the Bar, and I found only 9 s. and some odd half pence in her Pocket. - She said she took the Shirts out of the Drawer when the Drawer was in Flames, and when Mr Smith was in the Room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person209">
                  Sarah 
                  Washam 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person209" type="surname" value="Washam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person209" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are two of the Shirts. I know they are my Master's Shirts. The Gentlewoman showed me these two Shirts upon the Prisoner's Bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When Fire was cried out, I run up Stairs, and the Bureau was all on Fire. I took some Linnen out of the Drawer, and carried a Bowl of Water up Stairs to quench it, and took the Linnen up, and threw it upon the Bed, what Linnen it was I cannot tell. Mrs. Twigger, who keeps the Coffee-House, insisted on my not-moving, till I was searched, which I did not. They searched me but found nothing upon me. I have been very hardly used; they denied me all my Cloaths. I have been in Town from Gloucester but five Weeks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-20-person210">
                  Edward 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17420909-20-person210" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person210" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known this young Woman about twelve Months, she lived with Mr Gardner, a Minister in Gloucester, her Master always gave her a good Character; the Girl had the Keys of every Thing, and used to give me a Mug of Beer now and then. She had the Character of a good civil modest Girl. I used to serve Mr Gardner with Coals; his Brother was here all yesterday and to-day, but he is now gone, thinking the Trial would not come on to-night. <rs id="t17420909-20-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-20-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
