<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-26">
               <interp inst="t17431207-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-26" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-26" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-26-off144-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-defend217 t17431207-26-off144 t17431207-26-verdict148"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-26-off149-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-defend217 t17431207-26-off149 t17431207-26-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>+ 29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-defend217" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Geary 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-26-defend217" type="surname" value="Geary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-defend217" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-defend217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17431207-26-defloc143">St. Bride's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-26-defloc143" type="placeName" value="St. Bride's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-26-defloc143" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-defend217 t17431207-26-defloc143"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17431207-26-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431207-26-victim219" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim219" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim219" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him half a Guinea and one Penny, the Money of the said 
                     <persName id="t17431207-26-person220">
                        William 
                        Johnson 
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person220" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-person220" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , in the Dwelling-House
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17431207-26-person221">
                  Edward 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person221" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person221" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17431207-26-cd145" type="crimeDate">Nov. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off144 t17431207-26-cd145"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off149 t17431207-26-cd145"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person222">
                  William 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person222" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was Sevennight, as I was going through <placeName id="t17431207-26-crimeloc146">George Alley, by Fleet-Ditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-26-crimeloc146" type="placeName" value="George Alley, by Fleet-Ditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-26-crimeloc146" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off144 t17431207-26-crimeloc146"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off149 t17431207-26-crimeloc146"></join>, about a Quarter before seven in the Evening, a Woman laid hold of me, and the Prisoner opened the Door, and the Woman that picked me up forced me into the House. I was very loth to go in, but she said, I should make her drink something, or it should be the worse for me; when she got me in, the Door was made fast, and they insisted on my going up Stairs, while they went for something to drink; I went up just to the Stairs Head, and begged of her to let me go about my Business, for I was upon a Message; I went into a Room, and the Prisoner brought some Liquor; the other Woman got hold of my Watch, and I pushed her away several times - I did not let her pick my Pocket then. She called for more Help, and then I was afraid of my Life. The Prisoner came in, and laid hold of me - The Prisoner held me while the other Woman picked my Pocket of half a Guinea - She clapped her Hands upon both my Arms, and held me for about a Minute; I had one Hand upon my Watch; the other Woman got hold of my Watch, but I pulled it out of her Hand, and saved that: They called out several Names, but no Body came. I went away immediately to Mr. Sharrock, and he came and took her up - I was so much frightened, that a Child of ten Years old might have managed me - That Half Guinea was all the Money I had in my Pocket - I gave the Prisoner a Shilling to change to pay for what I had, and she gave me Six-pence before the other took the Half Guinea away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I any nearer to you, than only to give you the Six-pence?</p>
               <p>Johnson. It was after you gave me the Six-pence that you robbed me; I said, you have robbed me, and then I came away - There was no other Person in the House but the Prisoner and the other Woman, neither of her Side nor mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that is the Woman that held you? Was not you in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No, I was not; I can take my Oath I have not been drunk these three Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person223">
                  Henry 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person223" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person223" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (called by the Prisoner) I keep a House in George Alley; last Monday was Sevennight, between seven and eight in the Evening, my Wife and I were just come home, and I saw the Prisoner and this good Man (the Prosecutor) go in Arm and Arm together, and come out Arm in Arm together - I take it to be a notorious sort of a House?</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Man complain of any Thing?</p>
               <p>White. I did not hear him complain.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a Character does the Prisoner bear?</p>
               <p>White. I hear the good Woman at the Bar bears a very good Character - She is a Servant there.</p>
               <p>Q. Why you say it is a bad House?</p>
               <p>White . I have seen the good Woman a great many Times , and never heard of any Thing being laid to her Charge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person224">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person224" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person224" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I can say no more than my Husband has said, as to what I saw that Night; I knew her in creditable Families; and if the Matter was rightly considered, I believe her to be as innocent as your Lordship or I either.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person225">
                  Sarah 
                  Bassett 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person225" type="surname" value="Bassett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person225" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I lived with the Prisoner eleven Years ago at my Lady Kelly's in Hatton Garden; and I lived with her last at Mr. Plumber's, a Fanstick-Maker in Wild Street, about five Months ago, and never heard any Ill of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person226">
                  Frances 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person226" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person226" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and I were Fellow-<rs id="t17431207-26-deflabel147" type="occupation">Servants</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-defend217 t17431207-26-deflabel147"></join>; I lived Fellow-Servant with her at Mr. Blundell's, a Grocer in Bishopsgate Street ; she always behaved honestly, and in a very pretty Manner - I live with one Phillips , a Printer, in Wine-Office Court.</p>
               <p>- Bradford and 
               <persName id="t17431207-26-person227">
                  Eleanor 
                  Bradford 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person227" type="surname" value="Bradford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person227" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , in George Alley, and 
               <persName id="t17431207-26-person228">
                  Ann 
                  Humphreys 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person228" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person228" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave her the Character of a civil sober Woman. <rs id="t17431207-26-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>+ 30. 
               <persName id="t17431207-26-person229">
                  Eleanor 
                  Geary 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person229" type="surname" value="Geary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person229" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , was a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17431207-26-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431207-26-victim231" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Callin 
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim231" type="surname" value="Callin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim231" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-26-victim231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in the same Dwelling-House, putting him in Fear, and taking from him nine Shillings in Money, his Property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17431207-26-cd150" type="crimeDate">Nov. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off144 t17431207-26-cd150"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-off149 t17431207-26-cd150"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person232">
                  John 
                  Callin 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person232" type="surname" value="Callin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at Highgate to carry a Parrot to a Lady, whose Husband was Surveyor General of the Customs in New England. I cannot be certain to the Day - it was late at Night, for it was dark when I came from Highgate: As I was coming by a Corner a Woman asked me how I did, and whether I would not come in and drink a Dram? I said, with all my Heart; I went in with the Woman, and she and I went up Stairs, and another Woman (not the Prisoner) brought up a Pewter Thing full of Brandy - I cannot tell what Measure it was; the Woman who carried me up took hold of me, made use of some odd Expressions, and falls back upon the Bed, and tumbles me o' Top of her; said she, I must feel you; no said I, I do not want no Body to feel me, nor I do not want to feel no Body; why? said she, You Son of a B - h, you are poxed; I told her, if I was, I did not want to pox her nor no Body else, for you shall not feel me. So I asked her what was to pay for the Cup of Brandy; I put my Hand in my Pocket,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070013"></xptr> and pulled out half a Crown to pay the Reckoning; I put my Hand in my Pocket again, because I thought that was too much to trust them with, as believing it to be a bad House. I had in my Pocket two English half Crowns more, an English Shilling, two Six-pences, and some Halfpence, and I paid the other Woman (not the Prisoner) for the Brandy; I was coming down Stairs, and the Prisoner laid hold of me, and said, You Son of a B - h, you have not paid your Reckoning; and then she called to her Cousin, and a Woman came down - the Woman that carried me in: They opened my Breeches, and took my Money out; the Prisoner clapped her Arms round about me, the Woman who carried me in took all I had in one Pocket, which was two half Crowns, one Shilling, and one Six-pence; she opened my Breeches, and turned my left Pocket inside out; and the Prisoner slipped her Hand into the right Pocket of my Breeches, and took half a Crown from me and some Papers; I desired she would not keep my Papers, so she delivered me my Papers again: After they had plundered me, they wanted me to stay in the House all Night; they put the Money into a Girl's Hand, and sent her away with it, then I went out of the Door, and said, I was robbed; I was not above six Minutes in the House - I was prodigiously frightened when they took hold of me; I could not tell what to make of it; I did not know but they might have killed me. I found the Constable about six Minutes after in the House where I was robbed; the Coachman * had brought him in to take them up; I told the Constable, I was robbed, and gave him the same Account as I do now, and he secured the Prisoner: He asked me, if I could shew him the Room where I was; I said, yes; I took a Candle, but I was afraid to go up; said I, You must go up before me; he went up with a Sword, but we found nothing; I said, I believed, I had lost twenty five Shillings, but not being used to 
               <persName id="t17431207-26-person233">
                  Sterling 
                  Money 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person233" type="surname" value="Money"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person233" type="given" value="Sterling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person233" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I could not tell the Sum cleverly, either then, or now -</p>
               <p> * The Prosecutor on the other Indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-26-person234">
                  Edmund 
                  Sharrock 
               <interp inst="t17431207-26-person234" type="surname" value="Sharrock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person234" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Monday was Sev'night at Night, a Coachman came to me, and said, he was robbed of half a Guinea, and desired I would go with him; I went with him to Young's House, and while I was there, Callin knocked at the Door, I was fearful of opening the Door, till I heard him say, he was robbed, and that there was a Constable in the House, and desired to be admitted; accordingly I let him in, and he said, he was robbed of three half Crowns, and eighteen Pence; that the Prisoner did not rob him of the whole Money, but she had robbed him of half a Crown, and he charged me with her for that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, as I am a living Woman, if I was to do die for it, I never saw the Man in the House till he came with the Constable.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do not want to hurt her in any Shape, only to give her a Caution not to do the same thing again. <rs id="t17431207-26-verdict151" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-verdict151" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17431207-26-punish152" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-26-punish152" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-26-defend217 t17431207-26-punish152"></join>
               Death
            </rs> .</p>
               <p>The Jury recommended her to the Court for his Majesty's Mercy.</p>
            </div1>
