<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-27">
               <interp inst="t17431012-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-27" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-27" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-27-off121-c240" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-27-defend298 t17431012-27-off121 t17431012-27-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>490. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-27-defend298" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Blank 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-27-defend298" type="surname" value="Blank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-defend298" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-defend298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17431012-27-off121" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-off121" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-off121" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing eight Gallons of Brandy, value 20 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17431012-27-victim299" type="victimName">
                  Loth 
                  Leader 
               <interp inst="t17431012-27-victim299" type="surname" value="Leader"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-victim299" type="given" value="Loth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-victim299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-27-off121 t17431012-27-victim299"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17431012-27-cd122" type="crimeDate">Sept. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-27-off121 t17431012-27-cd122"></join>.</p>
               <p>Loth Leader. I had been collecting Money from Persons whom I deal with, and coming up Cloth-Fair I met the Prisoner with something upon his Back, which I perceived to be a Bottle which was full; I asked him where he was going? he said he was going to carry it to one Owen's in Long-Lane; and I found afterwards that he sold that Brandy for 2 s. which cost me 4 s. 6 d. or upwards. Owen and his Family are since gone off; he confess'd that he had taken the Brandy and sold it, and that he took the Bottle filled with Brandy four Times, I know the Bottle very well; I catched him on the Wednesday, and the Tuesday following I took him up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was no more than that one Time that my Master catched me, and he sent me about my Business.</p>
               <p>- Hill. On the 14th of Sept. Mr Leader sent for me and told me, I must take up the Prisoner, for he had been a vile Rogue to him. When I took him, I said, Jemmy, how can you be such a Rogue to rob so good a Master as you have; and Mr Leader said to him, how often have you done this, and he said only the Time that you catched me, and afterwards he said he went another Time; Mr Leader said, tell me the Truth, or it shall be the worse for you, and then he said he had filled the Bottle four times and sold it for 2 s. a Bottle. Then he asked him whether he had ever sold any Cags, and he confessed that he had taken twelve two Gallon Cags, and sold them.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to mention this?</p>
               <p>Leader. He had lived with me a great many Years, and I did not care to carry the Thing farther than what was necessary. <rs id="t17431012-27-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-verdict123" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17431012-27-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-27-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-27-defend298 t17431012-27-punish124"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
