<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-30">
               <interp inst="t17401015-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-30" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-30" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-30-off149-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-defend197 t17401015-30-off149 t17401015-30-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>463. 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Chace 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-30-defend197" type="surname" value="Chace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-defend197" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401015-30-defloc148">Twickenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-30-defloc148" type="placeName" value="Twickenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-30-defloc148" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-defend197 t17401015-30-defloc148"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17401015-30-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 3 36 s. Pieces, 3 Moidores, 6 Guineas, 1 Half-Guinea, and 5 s. 6 d. in Money, the Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17401015-30-victim199" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Hewitt 
                        <interp inst="t17401015-30-victim199" type="surname" value="Hewitt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-30-victim199" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-30-victim199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-off149 t17401015-30-victim199"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in her Dwelling-House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17401015-30-cd150" type="crimeDate">September 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-off149 t17401015-30-cd150"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person200">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hewitt 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person200" type="surname" value="Hewitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person200" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner lived with me three Months as a <rs id="t17401015-30-deflabel151" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-defend197 t17401015-30-deflabel151"></join>. On the 18th of September I had Occasion to go to my Bureau, and on looking over my Money, I missed 15 l. 4 s. I asked the Prisoner whether she had been in the Parlour, she said only to sweep and dust it, and that she saw the Bureau open. I told her, I had lost Money; but she said, she knew nothing of it, and persisted in a Denial of it, till the 20th, and then she own'd that she had taken the Money, and had filled the Bag with Stones, and thrown it down the Vault, where it was afterwards found by one of my Servants. After the Little-house had been search'd, and nothing but the Bag found, she confessed that there were 3 different Pieces of Gold; but she could not tell the Value of any of them but Guineas, and that she had hid it in a little Place I have in my House; but would not shew us whereabouts it was hid, though I had her up into the Place.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you threaten me, that you would go to a Conjurer about the Money?</p>
               <p>Mrs Hewitt. No; her Mother went to one they call a Cunning-Man .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was I in my Senses when I made this confession?</p>
               <p>Mrs Hewitt. I believe, I have several Gentlemen here, who heard, and saw her Actions, and know that she was not at all disordered.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person201">
                  Joshua 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person201" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person201" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Mrs Hewitt sent for me on the 18th of September, in the Morning, and desired me to see if her Money was right. I went to take the Money, but both that, and the Bag were gone. In the Evening of the same Day, going to the Little-house, I saw there were Women in it, and heard them say, hold the Door fast; in a short Time after this, I got a candle, and look'd down the Vault, and I saw a Place , where I thought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150013"></xptr> something had been thrown in, I searched it, and pulled out this Bag full of Stones. On the Sunday Evening following, being in the Kitchen, I asked the Prisoner about the Money, she told me that she first threw in the Bag, and afterwards dug a Hole and hid the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Why did not you charge the Women, who were in the Vault, with this Fact?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. They had no Business in the Room, from whence the Money was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Were there not some odd Methods made use of to discover the Thief?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. I did cover a Table with Soot, and made all the Maids come in, and lay their Hands on it, and told them, that the guilty Person would be black'd; but all their Hands were footed. I imagined that the Person that was guilty should pass by without touching the Table, for fear of being blacked. This was done without Mrs Hewitt's Knowledge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person202">
                  Sarah 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person202" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person202" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . When the Prisoner was suspected, I told her she might as well own where the Money was, if she knew any Thing of it: She said, that when I was coming into the Parlour she knew my Step, and could hardly get the Bureau shut down before I came in; that she had the Money in her Hand when I came in, and that she laid it on the lower Stairs, but afterwards put it down the little House, and the Bag after it - I know of no Threats that were made Use of to make her confess.</p>
               <p>- Hoskins . She confessed to me, that there were three Sorts of Gold, and some Silver, two of the Sorts she did not know the Value of. I am a Servant in the House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never mentioned any such Word, for I knew nothing at all of the Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person203">
                  John 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person203" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17401015-30-deflabel152" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-30-defend197 t17401015-30-deflabel152"></join> between 4 and 5 Years; I keep the Temple Eating-House in Sheer-Lane: She has been entrusted by me with Hundreds of Pounds, and in Abundance of Gentlemens Chambers. I never desire to have a better, nor an honester Servant while I live.</p>
               <p>Mr Wilson. I knew her when she was Mr Miller's Servant; I am a Dealer in Hair, and have trusted her in my Apartment, and she never wronged me of any Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person204">
                  Nicholas 
                  Humphries 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person204" type="surname" value="Humphries"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person204" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known her 3 Years or more; I have trusted her in my House with Things of Value, and always thought her an honest, industrious Servant.</p>
               <p>Mrs Woodward . I know her to be a very honest young Woman, and never stained her Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-30-person205">
                  Ann 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17401015-30-person205" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person205" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew her wrong any Body in my Life; she always bore a good Character <rs id="t17401015-30-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-30-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
