<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460702-15">
               <interp inst="t17460702-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-15" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-15" type="date" value="17460702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460702-15-off58-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-15-defend217 t17460702-15-off58 t17460702-15-verdict62"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174607020014"></xptr>257. 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-defend217" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-defend217" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-defend217" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-defend217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17460702-15-off58" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-off58" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-off58" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, nor regarding the Laws and Statues of this Realm, nor the Pains and Penalties there in contain'd, was indicted for shooting at 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460702-15-victim219" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Lewis 
                        <interp inst="t17460702-15-victim219" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460702-15-victim219" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460702-15-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-15-off58 t17460702-15-victim219"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , on the <rs id="t17460702-15-cd59" type="crimeDate">22d of October, in the Year 1743</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-15-off58 t17460702-15-cd59"></join>, with a certain Gun loaded with Gunpowder, with an Intent to kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Council. May it please your Lordship, and you Gentlemen of the Jury, I am Council against the unfortunate Prisoner at the Bar; the Indictment is grounded on an Act of Parliament wherein there are several Clauses; for Instance, if any Person shall unlawfully cut down or destroy Trees, set fire to any Barn, House, &amp;c. or shall willfully shoot at any Person, in any dwelling House or other Place, he shall be guilty of Felony: The clause we go upon is for willfully shooting at a Person. It may be necessary to shew for what Reason the Prisoner went to the House of Mr. Lewis, the Prosecutor, who is a <rs id="t17460702-15-viclabel60" type="occupation">Wheelwright</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-15-victim219 t17460702-15-viclabel60"></join>, and lives in <placeName id="t17460702-15-crimeloc61">East-Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460702-15-crimeloc61" type="placeName" value="East-Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460702-15-crimeloc61" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-15-off58 t17460702-15-crimeloc61"></join>: The Defendant, Mills, has been deem'd a notorious Cheat; he made it his Business to go to Mr. Lewis under artful Pretences, and is now confin'd for such an Offence, upon a like Account he lately stood in the Pillory. Mills knowing a Friend of Mr. Lewis's, with whom he had some Dealings, went to his House, and seeing a large Parcel of Wood, says, some of this wood grew in my Ground, I have a great Quantity coming to Town. Mills ask'd Lewis whether he was acquainted with Mr. Higgs, he said yes, and that he had had some Dealings with him; says he, I have more Timber coming up, and talk'd likewise of Sheep and Lambs coming up to Smithfield Market, though none were brought. This was to give him a Colour for Credit, and upon this he desir'd Mr. Lewis to go with him to one Mr. Jewel, and told him he should be much oblig'd to him to give a Note of Hand for 12 l. 12 s. 3 d. he expected to have receiv'd this Money the Friday following; but there were no such Persons as Mills or Nichols to be found: so, Gentlemen, upon this they made Enquiry, and after some time thought fit to go to this Place, Bassildon in Berkshire ; they went first to Mr. Higgs, where they got a particular Information of Mills; however he had Intelligence that Lewis was coming to his House. This is mention'd to shew that he willfully shot, and that he knew the Person, by Expressions or Words to this Effect: By G - d, Lewis, I'll shoot you; and he had no sooner spoke those words than he fir'd a Musket at him; but the Prosecutor hearing him say he would shoot him, fell down, so I suppose he miss'd his Aim: On finding the Man get up again, and endeavouring to run away, to shew him Malice, he said, G - d d - n him he is not dead, bring the Blunderbuss that I may blow his Brain, out; but it happily fell out that he escap'd. It may seem extraordinary that this Thing should end dormant so long; but Mills was backward and forward , and could not be apprehended sooner, so that the Prosecution could not be brought on before.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person220">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person220" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person220" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person221">
                  Thomas 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person221" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .) When was this?</p>
               <p>Lewis. The 9th of October, in 1743, the Prisoner came into our Yard, and said these are brave Felleys, I have a great Quantity of them. Mr. Nicholls was very handsomly dress'd, had a Silver Pair of Spurs, &amp;c. Says Mills, Master Lewis, do you know Mr. Higgs, I was recommended by him to you? They also wanted Lodgings, and I should have been glad to have lain out of my own Bed for them (with a View of buying a good Bargain;) but my wife was not willing; so I got them a Lodging elsewhere. Please you, my Lord, Mills and Nichollas had some Money of me; after this I went down to see if the Barges were come up; and when I came to speak to Mr. Higgs, I ask'd him how he could defraud me in the Manner he had done, and began to tell him the Story? He swore about Mills, and said, what has he been dealing in London again? When we went down to Bassildon he went with us to this Mill's House, which is near a Common; when I got to the Door Mills saw me, and said d - n you I'll shoot you, and levell'd a Piece at me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Distance was you from him when he said he would shoot you?</p>
               <p>Lewis. It might be about twenty Yards.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say after that?</p>
               <p>Lewis. He call'd for the Blunderbuss, and said he would blow my Brains out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was loaded with any thing?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I can't say whether it was loaded with Ball or Shot, it whistled by me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apply to any Justice of Peace against this Man?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What Justice did you apply to?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I can't tell the Justice's Name.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Lewis. At Straitly . I shew'd him the forged Note.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take your Information? Did you complain of his Shooting? Did you desire the Justice to grant you a Warrant against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lewis . The Justice did not care to do any Thing with him, he is such a bad Man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174607020015"></xptr>Q. Did you make Complaints to the Justice of this Matter, and desire a Warrant?</p>
               <p>Lewis . I shew'd him how he trick'd me. He he said they were very vile Fellows, and that they were not safe in lying in their Beds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you request a Warrant from the Justice, and desire him to take your Information?</p>
               <p>Lewis . I went to the Justice at Straitly for Advice.</p>
               <p>Court. That was for the Cheat, and not for shooting at you; did you tell him in what Manner you had been shot at?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Yes , my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to exhibit this Indictment against him now ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. My Lord, for shooting at me, when I went down to endeavour to get my Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever endeavour to find him out?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Yes. But I never could find him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you endeavour to take him up for the Cheat , or shooting?</p>
               <p>Lewis. For the Shooting, please you my Lord. And when we came away he said, Ah 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person222">
                  ye London 
                  Fools 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person222" type="surname" value="Fools"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person222" type="given" value="ye London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person222" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c..</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person223">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person223" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person223" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Brigs 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person224" type="surname" value="Brigs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Did you go down to Bassildon with Mr. Lewis?</p>
               <p>Briggs. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time in the Evening was it that you went to the Defendant's House?</p>
               <p>Briggs. We were at Bassildon about Four o'Clock in the Afternoon; we sent for 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person225">
                  William 
                  Higgs 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person225" type="surname" value="Higgs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Timber-Merchant, who was at work with his Men, and came from them between Five and Six o'Clock . We went up Bassildon-Heath to Mill's house .</p>
               <p>Q. When you went there, tell us what you saw Mills do to Mr. Lewis?</p>
               <p>Briggs. When we went to his House he stripp'd himself into his Shirt, and took a Piece, a Gun, or Musket, and he swore by G - d, Mr. Lewis, if you don't go away I'll shoot you; he levell'd at Mr. Lewis ; as soon as I saw it I run behind the Barn, or Straw-Cock, or something.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Briggs. He swore he would shoot, and fir'd off the Piece immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to Mr. Lewis?</p>
               <p>Briggs. As near as I am now. As soon as I saw the Piece I ran behind the Hovel, or stable. On Monday Morning when we came to set out, they said we were in Danger in going Home; and we got a Per or two to go with us for fear of meeting with him upon the Road.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time do you take it to be that you was at Mill's House?</p>
               <p>Briggs. It was about Seven o'Clock. As fine a Moon-shine Evening as ever I saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person226">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person226" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person226" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Will you ask this Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Lewis stood with a Penknife drawn, and swore he would stabb me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person227">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person227" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person227" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Lewis) Had you at that Time a Penknife in your Hand; did you threaten to do any Thing?</p>
               <p>Lewis . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. If you could have got your Money would you have prosecuted the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person228">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person228" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person228" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person229">
                  George 
                  Rishton 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person229" type="surname" value="Rishton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person229" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) Pray how long is it since you had any Dealings with the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Rishton. Nichols and Mills came to me three Years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you endeavour'd to find him?</p>
               <p>Rishton. I went down to Reading-Jail and found Nicholls.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send to enquire after Mills?</p>
               <p>Rishton. Yes, I sent one out of Berkshire to enquire after him.</p>
               <p>[
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person230">
                  William 
                  Nicholls 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person230" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is now a Prisoner in Newgate, was call'd upon as a Witness for his Acquaintance, Mills.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-15-person231">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person231" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person231" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Nicholls) What have you to say in the Behalf of 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person232">
                  John 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person232" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; was you with Mills when Lewis came there?</p>
               <p>Nicholls. I know Mr. Lewis very well. I was not in the House when Lewis came there.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you know nothing of the shooting off the Gun .</p>
               <p>Nicholls. Nothing, but what I heard Mr. Mills's Man say; one 
               <persName id="t17460702-15-person233">
                  William 
                  Higgs 
               <interp inst="t17460702-15-person233" type="surname" value="Higgs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person233" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Carpenter, came up with them, and my little Boy was there.</p>
               <p>[As the Prosecution was so long after the Fact was committed, the Prisoner was <rs id="t17460702-15-verdict62" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-15-verdict62" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> of the Indictment .]</p>
            </div1>
