<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490222-28">
               <interp inst="t17490222-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-28" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-28" type="date" value="17490222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-28-off123-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-28-defend184 t17490222-28-off123 t17490222-28-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>189. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-28-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     Jeremy 
                     Casway 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-28-defend184" type="surname" value="Casway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-defend184" type="given" value="Jeremy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-defend184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17490222-28-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               violently assaulting in the King's highway, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490222-28-victim186" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Nash 
                        <interp inst="t17490222-28-victim186" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-28-victim186" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-28-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-28-off123 t17490222-28-victim186"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , with an intent to rob him
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490222-28-cd124" type="crimeDate">January 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-28-off123 t17490222-28-cd124"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-28-person187">
                  Stephen 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17490222-28-person187" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-person187" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 26th of January, betwixt eleven and twelve at night, the prisoner at the bar came to me in <placeName id="t17490222-28-crimeloc125">Well-close Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-28-crimeloc125" type="placeName" value="Well-close Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-28-crimeloc125" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-28-off123 t17490222-28-crimeloc125"></join>, he hit me a blow on the left side of my head; it stunned me a little. I did not quite fall to the ground; he laid hold of my collar, and said, stand and deliver your money; I told him he was come at a wrong time, for I had no money; he insisted on my delivering: I said I had not one farthing, and if you doubt it, said I, feel in my pocket; then he felt my wristbands for my buttons; saying, give me your buttons; I said they are but penny buttons , and will do you no service; he said they are silver ones, and I'll have them; I said, if you will have them, you shall; so I pretended to take them out myself to give him, so let me go; his stick being all the while over my head, and I feared another blow; I looked round and saw none else near me, with that I stepped in, and hit him a blow with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220009"></xptr> my fist; then we had something of a tussle together; he finding me resolute let the stick go, which fell to the ground; I took it up and ran after him, and cried out watch! watch! till I got down a place that comes into Ratcliff Highway, he turned towards East Smithfield ; when I was just at him he turned short down an alley, I think they call it White Horse alley; there is a step or two , and he fell down; and I jumped upon him and laid hold of his collar, and told him if he made any resistance I would knock his brains out. The constable met me with the prisoner, and before him at Justice Manwaring's he confest the thing: Likewise told us of a house in Church-lane, where, he said, if he carried any thing in the night, it would be received.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-28-person188">
                  Stephen 
                  Pett 
               <interp inst="t17490222-28-person188" type="surname" value="Pett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-person188" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am beadle of the parish of St. John's, Wapping; my duty at the watch-house is four nights a-week. On the 26th of January I was on duty; betwixt eleven and twelve, near twelve, in East Smithfield I heard the cry, watch ! watch! with that I ordered the watchmen to light up their candles ; I told them I thought some body was in pursuit; by and by I must the noise; presently I heard it again; then before we got well out at the door, the prosecutor was bringing the prisoner to the watch-house; he asked for the constable of the night, and had this stick in his hand: He told me this was the stick the prisoner struck him with; it had an iron ferrel on the end, but I have lost the ferrel; his face then was muddy, and a mark on his head like a blow with a dirty stick .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any blood?</p>
               <p>Pett. I saw no blood, my Lord. We went before Justice Manwaring with the prisoner; he said he was sorry for what he had done; adding it was the first time that ever he was out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I was a little in liquor when I did it, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490222-28-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490222-28-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-28-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-28-defend184 t17490222-28-punish127"></join>
               transportation
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
