<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480115-7">
               <interp inst="t17480115-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-7" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-7" type="date" value="17480115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480115-7-off38-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-defend106 t17480115-7-off38 t17480115-7-verdict42"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480115-7-off43-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-defend106 t17480115-7-off43 t17480115-7-verdict42"></join>
         
               <p>78. + 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-defend106" type="defendantName">
                  Isaac 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-defend106" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-defend106" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-defend106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17480115-7-defloc37">St. Leonard Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-7-defloc37" type="placeName" value="St. Leonard Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-7-defloc37" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-defend106 t17480115-7-defloc37"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480115-7-off38" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-off38" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-off38" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480115-7-victim108" type="victimName">
                           Hannah 
                           Maund 
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim108" type="surname" value="Maund"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim108" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17480115-7-viclabel39" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-victim108 t17480115-7-viclabel39"></join>, in a certain alley, called <placeName id="t17480115-7-crimeloc40">Bowl-alley</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-crimeloc40" type="placeName" value="Bowl-alley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-crimeloc40" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off38 t17480115-7-crimeloc40"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off43 t17480115-7-crimeloc40"></join>, in or near the King's highway; putting her in fear, and taking from her four pence
            </rs>.  <rs id="t17480115-7-cd41" type="crimeDate">Dec. the 13th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off38 t17480115-7-cd41"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off43 t17480115-7-cd41"></join>.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Couch. On the 13th of Dec. last, about two o'clock in the morning, as I was going home by the end of Hog lane, my sister, 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-person109">
                  Hannah 
                  Maund 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person109" type="surname" value="Maund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person109" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was along with me; the Prisoner came up to me, and asked me where I was going, I said, home, and he followed us into Bowl-court alley, and the Prisoner blew the candle out; then the Prisoner spoke to my sister, and asked her, what money she had; my sister desired he would not surprize her, and she would give him what money she had; and he took four pence from her. Then he came up to me, and took from me a shilling, a thimble, a necklace, and a bunch of keys; and said, if I made any noise, he would rip me up, for he had two razors, a penknife, and a cutlass. I desired him not to frighten me, for I had but a little while to go; there were two watchmen coming by, who did not cry the hour, and when they came up, I desired they would lay hold of that fellow, for he had robbed us: and the watchmen laid hold of him, and carried him to the watch-house, and searched him for what he had taken from us.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not the watchmen and you discourse some small time together in the alley, before I was secured?</p>
               <p>Couch. I never went from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. You said, he had some razors and other things; were any found upon him?</p>
               <p>Couch. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask her whether the watchmen did not search me in the alley?</p>
               <p>Couch No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you deliver the Prisoner into the hands of the watchmen in the alley?</p>
               <p>Couch . Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person110">
                  Hannah 
                  Maund 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person110" type="surname" value="Maund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person110" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As my sister and I were coming by the corner of Hog-lane, the Prisoner stood as if he was making water, and said some words which I did not understand. I had a candle in my hand, and carried it into Bowl-court ; he took the candle out of my hand and blew it out: then he took hold of me, and asked me, what money I had; I said, a groat, which he took from me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do to your sister?</p>
               <p>Maund. He took from her a shilling, a thimble, a necklace, and a bunch of keys; I begged him not to frighten my sister: he D - d me for a B - h, and said, he would stab me; for he had got two razors, a penknife, and a cutlass; then he went to my sister , and while she was talking with him, the watchmen came by, but I did not hear them beat the hour; I laid my right hand upon his collar, and my left hand upon his arm, and called the watchmen, and they took him to the watchhouse; he took a handkerchief out of his pocket, and tied it pretty tight about his neck, and said, he wished he had a halter about his neck tighter than that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask that witness, who calls herself a married woman, whether she did not blow the candle out herself?</p>
               <p>Couch. He blew the candle out himself.</p>
               <p>Q. When he blew the candle out, was there any body near?</p>
               <p>Couch. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the keys in his hand?</p>
               <p>Couch. Yes, I did see them in his hand, and he told Davis the watchman, if he would go to such a place, he would find a handkerchief, and in that handkerchief were the keys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person111">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person111" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person111" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going my rounds on the 13th of Dec. between two and three o'clock, and the women were crying out, give me my money; watch, watch, the man has robbed me; they said, he had robbed one of a shilling, and the other of a groat; I desired them to consider of it before they charged the man, and they said, do you think we are drunk or mad? and the Prisoner said, don't mind them, watchman , for they are a couple of B - s, and I have lain with them both: they charged him with having a hanger, I searched him, and found nothing but a handkerchief, and some papers; the Prisoner bid me go to such a gutter, and bring a handkerchief , which I should find there, and give it to him, and say nothing to any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the gutter?</p>
               <p>Davis. Near the watch-house .</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the handkerchief ?</p>
               <p>Davis. Only four keys .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174801150010"></xptr>William Rooke produced a handkerchief , which he said was sealed up before Justice Poulson : which Davis proved was the handkerchief he took up with the keys in it. Mr. Rooke likewise produced a necklace and a thimble: he said the Prisoner had two shillings, and about eight or nine penyworth of halfpence in his pocket: but he did not see them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you?</p>
               <p>Rooke. I was headborough that night the watchmen took the Prisoner, and the women gave me charge of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the women say thing about the necklace and thimble; that he had given them again?</p>
               <p>Rooke. Yes; and I think it was to Davis , that they said so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear them say so?</p>
               <p>Rooke. Yes.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Couch called again.</p>
               <p>Q. You charge the Prisoner with taking the necklace and thimble, how came you by them again?</p>
               <p>Couch. He said, take them again: for they will be of no service to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I work with my father (who lives by Shoreditch church) as a shoemaker, and he had paid me my wages; it was on a saturday night, and I went to the Hob in the well to meet some acquaintance: my father desired I would not make it late. One of my acquaintance came to me, and we had a dish of stakes, and I staid later than ordinary; I believe, till one o'clock. I was going by the end of Hog-lane, on my way home: I was not drunk, for I was as sober as I am now; says one of these women, hark you, my dear, I want to speak to you; one of them asked me, whether I would go home with her; I asked her where she lived, she said, in Bowl-court; I went with her a little way, and when I came to the end of the court, I said, it was too late to go up, and I went away, and she made an agreement with me for a groat; I take it to be the person who calls herself a single woman, but I agreed to give them a groat a piece, and had to do with them both; it was about two o'clock, and the watch was coming up: and one of the women said, I charge you with this man: I had the handkerchief in my hand, which your Lordship saw just now, and after I had had carnal knowledge of them, I felt in my pocket for my handkerchief , and could not find it: and the watchmen coming up, she put the handkerchief into my hand, and then they charged the watchmen with me; I had given the watchmen charge of them, but they would not take charge of the women, but took hold of me; and 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-person112">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person112" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             spoke to one of them , and took her up the court, and they were discoursing for three or four minutes: and then they said, take him away, he has robbed me. And as they took me away, the handkerchief dropped out of my hand. I said, watchman I have lost a handkerchief upon the road: it is not worth a great deal, but I hope you will go and see for it: which he did; but he would not give it me, for he said, one of the witnesses would swear to the keys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person113">
                  Thomas 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person113" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person113" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner upwards of two years, he is a shoemaker, and bears a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person114">
                  Samuel 
                  Stiff 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person114" type="surname" value="Stiff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person114" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner above seven years, and know his father too: he is as honest a man as ever was born in the world. I would trust him with all I have in the world, and I never heard any thing amiss of the Prisoner in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person115">
                  Samuel 
                  Ogden 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person115" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person115" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about three years, I have lived in the house with him, and he was as sober a young man, as ever I desire to live with: and his general character is such.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Prosecutors offered me four shillings to make this up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person116">
                  Bernard 
                  Gill 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person116" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person116" type="given" value="Bernard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Fletcher about twelve months, and I never heard, but that he behaved well in the parish where I lived.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person117">
                  Joseph 
                  Gill 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person117" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person117" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about four or five months, and never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person118">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person118" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called again,</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prosecutors offer to make it up for four shillings?</p>
               <p>Davis. I never heard any thing said of four shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-person119">
                  Mary 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person119" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person119" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What characters do Couch and Maund bear?</p>
               <p>Hopkins. A very bad one, and are not to be credited.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person120">
                  Thomas 
                  Mead 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person120" type="surname" value="Mead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person120" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They are both persons of a very bad character, and not to be minded.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person121">
                  Joanna 
                  Thornton 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person121" type="surname" value="Thornton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person121" type="given" value="Joanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known Couch and Maund several years, they bear a very bad character, and are not to be credited at all; and they keep late hours , and come in at three or four in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person122">
                  Thomas 
                  Kinchen 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person122" type="surname" value="Kinchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person122" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Couch and Maund some years, and lived in the house with them three months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is their general character among their neighbours?</p>
               <p>Kinchen. Their characters are, that they keep late hours, and are drunkards .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174801150011"></xptr>Q. Are they persons to be credited?</p>
               <p>Kinchen . No, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person123">
                  Margaret 
                  Racket 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person123" type="surname" value="Racket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person123" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prosecutors several years, their characters among their neighbours is but very indifferent.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480115-7-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>+ 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-person124">
                  Isaac 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person124" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person124" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17480115-7-off43" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-off43" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-off43" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17480115-7-victim125" type="victimName">
                        Elizabeth, the wife of 
                           <persName id="t17480115-7-person126" type="victimName">
                              James 
                              Couch 
                           <interp inst="t17480115-7-person126" type="surname" value="Couch"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17480115-7-person126" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17480115-7-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim125" type="surname" value="Couch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim125" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-7-victim125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in a certain alley, in or near the King's highway, called <placeName id="t17480115-7-crimeloc44">Bowl-Alley</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-crimeloc44" type="placeName" value="Bowl-Alley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-crimeloc44" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off38 t17480115-7-crimeloc44"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off43 t17480115-7-crimeloc44"></join>, putting her in fear, and taking from her one shilling in money, a thimble, a necklace, and a bunch of keys
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480115-7-cd45" type="crimeDate">December 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off38 t17480115-7-cd45"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-7-off43 t17480115-7-cd45"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person127">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Couch 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person127" type="surname" value="Couch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person127" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of December I was coming along Shoreditch with my sister, and at the end of Hog-Lane I met with the Prisoner; we went together to Bowl-Alley, and about the middle of the alley the Prisoner blew our candle out, and took from me a shilling, a thimble, a necklace, and a bunch of keys.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any further circumstances to give an account of, than you did on the other trial?</p>
               <p>Couch. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person128">
                  Hannah 
                  Maund 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person128" type="surname" value="Maund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person128" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have no further evidence to give, than what I gave upon the former trial.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person129">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Couch 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person129" type="surname" value="Couch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person129" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . desired some witnesses might be called in behalf of her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person130">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wangow 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person130" type="surname" value="Wangow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person130" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17480115-7-person131">
                  Hannah 
                  Maund 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person131" type="surname" value="Maund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person131" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to nurse me of a fever, and was with me that night; her sister came to fetch her home, and they staid at our house till past two. I know nothing of their characters; I never heard any thing amiss of them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-7-person132">
                  William 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17480115-7-person132" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person132" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never heard any thing amiss of them; one goes out a charing, and the other winds silk.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live near them?</p>
               <p>Allen. I live within twenty or thirty yards of them, where they have lived twenty-five or twenty six years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480115-7-verdict46" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-7-verdict46" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
