<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430413-52">
               <interp inst="t17430413-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-52" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-52" type="date" value="17430413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430413-52-off299-c511" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-52-defend630 t17430413-52-off299 t17430413-52-verdict301"></join>
         
               <p>247. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-52-defend630" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Benjamin 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-52-defend630" type="surname" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-defend630" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-defend630" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430413-52-off299" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-off299" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-off299" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing four Moidores, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430413-52-victim632" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Sheere 
                        <interp inst="t17430413-52-victim632" type="surname" value="Sheere"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430413-52-victim632" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430413-52-victim632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-52-off299 t17430413-52-victim632"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430413-52-cd300" type="crimeDate">Feb. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-52-off299 t17430413-52-cd300"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner not understanding the English Tongue, 
               <persName id="t17430413-52-person633">
                  Isaac 
                  Silver 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person633" type="surname" value="Silver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person633" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sworn an Interpreter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-52-person634">
                  Peter 
                  Winstanley 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person634" type="surname" value="Winstanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person634" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person634" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 1st of this Month, Mr Steere sent his Apprentice, 
               <persName id="t17430413-52-person635">
                  Henry 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person635" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person635" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person635" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with a Draught of 117 l. 13 s. on Messieurs Honeywood and Fuller, which he received, and set down the Particulars; just as he put it into the Shovel, and held it in his Hand upon the Counter, the Prisoner came into the Shop, with two Spanish Doubloons, as I apprehended, to sell; I weighed them, and thought the most ready Way, as he did not understand English, was to shew him what I would give him for them, which was six Guineas and six Shillings; and I laid the Money upon the Counter; he did not take this Money which I offered him, but went to the other End of the Counter, where the Shovel full of Money was, and took up a handful and separated them; there were 36 Shilling Pieces, and some Moidores; I thought he understood that Money better, so I ordered Arnold to give him the Money out of the Shovel; he said he could not pay him out of that Money, but he gave him three 36 s. and I gave him a Guinea and three Shillings; still I could not keep his Hand out of the Shovel, he had it in several Times: He pointed to his Knees, as much as to say he wanted a Pair of Knee-Buckles, he had no Buckles to his Knees: I pulled out the Drawer, he took out a Pair, I weighed them, and asked him eight Shillings for them, he said he would give me six Shillings. - He spoke a little broken, but he said six Shillings as plain as I do now; I said I would take no less than eight Shillings. A neighbouring Goldsmith came by, and gave me a Caution, for he said he had been in his Shop just before, and he suspected him. Just as he was going out of the Shop, he said he would give me seven Shillings, and went away. I took three Thirty-six Shillings, and gave them to Arnold to put into the Shovel. Now, says I, your Money is right, or should be right. I bid him tell it, and asked him if he had not taken any; he said there were four missing; he told it twice before I offered to go after him I thought I should light of him about Exchange Alley, but I did not: About an Hour afterwards I lighted of him, in Beavers-Marks, in Dukes-Place, in a Room with five or six more Jews. I took hold of him, and charged him with it; he seemed frightened, and said, as they told me, if I would be quiet, and make no Disturbance, he would return me the Money. I sent Home for my Master, he brought a Constable, and we had him before my Lord-Mayor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-52-person636">
                  Henry 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person636" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person636" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person636" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed every Circumstance of the former Evidence; and said he received at Mr. Honeywood's and Comp. 117 l. 13 s. viz. seventy-five Moidores, nine Thirty-six Shillings, and four Shillings, that he told the Money twice immediately after the Prisoner was gone, and missed four Moidores; that no Body else had been in the Shop; that the Money was never from him, nor the Shovel out of his Hand.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner (by his Interpreter) said, that he did not care to take Guineas, and only pointed to the Shovel; that he never touched the Shovel, nor any more Money than they gave him; that he did not know what they came to him about, till they came before my Lord Mayor; that he supposed it was a Fraud among the Servants, and so they laid t upon him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174304130040"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-52-person637">
                  Zipporah 
                  Silver 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person637" type="surname" value="Silver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person637" type="given" value="Zipporah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person637" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Levena Clervert, 
               <persName id="t17430413-52-person638">
                  Jacob 
                  Depaz 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person638" type="surname" value="Depaz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person638" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person638" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17430413-52-person639">
                  Jacob 
                  Aaron 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person639" type="surname" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person639" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person639" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17430413-52-person640">
                  Solomon 
                  Riatti 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person640" type="surname" value="Riatti"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person640" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person640" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave him the Character of a very honest Man, and have known him about two or three Years, that he is a Merchant, and goes abroad with Goods; that they have trusted him, and he has paid them very honestly; that he came from Gibraltar but the Day before this happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-52-person641">
                  Isaac 
                  Silver 
               <interp inst="t17430413-52-person641" type="surname" value="Silver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person641" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-person641" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Interpreter, has known him twelve or thirteen Years; was acquainted with him in his own Country; says that he has the Character of an honest Man, especially among the English and French; and that he cannot speak a Word of English. <rs id="t17430413-52-verdict301" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-52-verdict301" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The two last Trials were omitted in the Proceedings of the former Sessions, on Account of the extraordinary Length of Mr. Waite's Trial.</p>
            </div1>
