<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-58">
               <interp inst="t17431207-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-58" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-58" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-58-off300-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend451 t17431207-58-off300 t17431207-58-verdict305"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-58-off303-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend451 t17431207-58-off303 t17431207-58-verdict305"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-58-off303-c338" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend456 t17431207-58-off303 t17431207-58-verdict305"></join>
         
               <p>+ 66. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-58-defend451" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Eales 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend451" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend451" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of <placeName id="t17431207-58-defloc299">St. Mary le Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-defloc299" type="placeName" value="St. Mary le Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-defloc299" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend451 t17431207-58-defloc299"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend456 t17431207-58-defloc299"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17431207-58-off300" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-off300" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-off300" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17431207-58-victim452" type="victimName">
                        Pugh 
                        Willis 
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-victim452" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-58-victim452" type="given" value="Pugh"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431207-58-victim452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                    , putting him in Fear, and taking from him seven Guineas, his property, in the Dwelling-House
            </rs> of the said 
               <persName id="t17431207-58-person453">
                  Philip 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person453" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person453" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17431207-58-cd301" type="crimeDate">Nov . 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-off300 t17431207-58-cd301"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-off303 t17431207-58-cd301"></join>.</p>
               <p>67. 
               <persName id="t17431207-58-person454">
                  Philip 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person454" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person454" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-58-defend456" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Eales 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend456" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend456" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-defend456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17431207-58-deflabel302" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-defend456 t17431207-58-deflabel302"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17431207-58-person457">
                  Philip 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person457" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person457" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , were indicted for <rs id="t17431207-58-off303" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-off303" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-off303" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten Guineas
            </rs>, the property of Pugh Willis, Nov. 23.</p>
               <p>Pugh Willis. The 22d of November at Night, or the 23d in the Morning, about four o'Clock, I was coming from St. James's, and just before I came to Eales's Night Cellar in <placeName id="t17431207-58-crimeloc304">the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-crimeloc304" type="placeName" value="the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-58-crimeloc304" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-off300 t17431207-58-crimeloc304"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-58-off303 t17431207-58-crimeloc304"></join>, it is on the left Hand coming from St. James's by the New Church, four Men swore at me, and told me, that I should go down and drink - They did not go down, two of them went away, and two of them staid to see me go down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go down voluntarily? Did they use any Threats in order to make you go down?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They held up their Fists, and I thought it the safest Way to go down.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came down, what was the first Thing that presented itself to you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There were two or three people standing, and 
               <persName id="t17431207-58-person458">
                  Philip 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person458" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person458" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with another Man in a mean Dress like a porter were playing at Hustle Cap ; I called for a pint of Beer, and drank it; they asked me to play, I refused it, but they said I should play; I thought that the little Money I had in my pocket - five Guineas and some Silver, was not to be put in Competition with my Life; then there were six people come in with great Coats, and Brass Buttons, who appeared to be Chairmen - I did not play, but laid on Eales's Head - I did not know him, I never saw him before - I laid on his Head, because I thought him the most lucky person for me to lay on - I laid once or twice half a Guinea, and then a Guinea a Time afterwards - I did not win at all - I won but one 10 s. 6 d. and that he paid in Silver honestly, and what I lost I laid down upon the Table, and that the Man that played with him took up - I saw no more than about half a Guinea in Silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Man say when you laid such Wagers?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He said nothing in the World - I lost five Guineas, and eight or nine Shillings in Silver. There were four Fellows like Chairmen sleeping in a Box, and lying upon the Floor; Eales took them all four by their Legs, and dragged them out, and where-ever he laid them, they lay, and did not stir, and put me into the Box where they were; I did not remain there any longer than till a Candle was got, then he took me by the Arm, and carried me into an inner Room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this with or without your Consent?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was certainly against my Consent if I had my Will, but I was afraid; I had given my Watch to him before - for six Guineas he lent me; I went into this inner Room, and laid on his Side still till I lost these six Guineas - I never played myself at all - There were in this inner Room 
               <persName id="t17431207-58-person459">
                  Philip 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person459" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person459" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , this other Man that played, and I, and Eales's Wife, who lay upon the Bed in her Clothes; I said to Eales, if you will give me my Watch again, I will go home and fetch Money to redeem it; then he said, You owe me six Guineas, if you will bring me six Pounds nine Shillings and six Pence, you shall have your Watch; I went home in a Chair, and brought twelve Guineas; when I returned, I was introduced into this Room, and I immediately tendered him 6 l. 9 s. 6 d. and demanded my Watch; the Prisoner d - d me, and bid me hold my Tongue, and told me I should play with the other person that he had played with, and then I should have a Chance; I said I only came for my Watch, and desired he would give it me, and told him I would not play; he held up his Hand as if he would strike me, and swore by G - d I should play; I played, and in a little Time had the good Luck to win twelve Guineas - I won it of the Man that Eales was before playing with, and the Man paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Eales do with the Money he had of you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Eales said he had lost every Farthing of the Money, but he did not lose any Thing then as I saw; then as I was not a great Loser I was for going away, Eales then snatched up ten of these twelve Guineas which I had upon the Table just by me; I asked him what he meant by this, he swore G - d d - n him he would owe it me; I said, I did not understand that; he said, G - d d - n me, he would make me understand it, and he threatened to strike me, if I did not hold my Tongue, so I did not speak a Word till I saw Eales lose all this ten Guineas with the Man he played with before - It was about nine or ten o'Clock in the Day when I first came out; we played all the while by Candle Light; I believe it is dark there at all Hours of the Day.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070026"></xptr>Q. What was the next Thing that was done after Eales had lost the ten Guineas with this Man?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I was going to see for my Hat and Cane to go away, the Woman Prisoner got hold of me, and my Feet hitting against the Bed-post, I made a little slip, and she pulled me down upon the Bed, and wrapped me in the Blankets; I lay for about three Minutes, and then she went away and left me; he came in again, and said, who wrapped you up so; I said, his Wife; he d - d her for a B - h for serving a Gentleman so; she said, she thought it was the best way for me to sleep, for it would do me good.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not he jealous of you and his Wife?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am sure he had no Occasion to be jealous of me; he went out of the Room, and was not gone above half a Minute, before he brought in a Book, and swore that I owed him twelve Guineas upon a Book Debt, and that he would have all the Money in my Breeches for it, and then he put his Hand in my pocket, and took to the Amount of seven Guineas, and upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you paid Eales the six Guineas?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what Occasion were you at St. James's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was the Day that was kept for the King's Birth Day - I staid at St. James's till three o'Clock in the Morning -</p>
               <p>Q. Is not there a good deal of Burgundy going forward upon these Occasions?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do assure you I did not drink above three Glasses of Wine there, and then I came to this Place.</p>
               <p>Q. You say it was between nine and ten when you went away; when you were got to your Lodging, how came you to go there again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Because he had got my Watch, and it was a Watch that I valued.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not you have staid till Day Light?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was Day Light when I went away - I only took the two Chairmen who carried me to my Lodging - The people did not use any uncivil Expressions to me - I was afraid, because I conceived a bad Opinion of the people of the House - merely from being forced down there; for if these people made no use of me after they got me into the Cellar, what Occasion was there to force me down?</p>
               <p>Q. You said four people said you should go down and drink; did neither of these four go down?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Not that I saw - I did not observe that any of them were in Liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you in a gay Humour, and wanted to play without being asked?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by the Chair?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I cannot tell how the Chair was got, so I suppose they got it.</p>
               <p>Nicholson, a Chairman. I carried the Prosecutor home about ten in the Morning, and did not perceive him to be in Liquor.</p>
               <p>- Gray (Constable) I had a Warrant from Colonel De Veil , and went to Eales's Cellar, I saw his Wife in the Bar, and asked where her Husband was; she said, he was in Bed; the Prosecutor said there is your Prisoner, and charged him with robbing him; he went very readily with me, and said, the Gentleman was not robbed there: When we came before the Colonel, he asked him for his Gold Watch; Eales sent me home for it; I told the Maid I came from her Master for the Gold Watch, and she gave it me very readily.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-58-person460">
                  William 
                  Speck 
               <interp inst="t17431207-58-person460" type="surname" value="Speck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person460" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked the Prisoner when he was before the Colonel, where the Watch was; she said, I have made Money of it, and then he said it was at Home; the Prisoner afterwards begged my Interest with the Prosecutor; said he, Consider what Life and Death is, get them to make it up, and I will resign the Watch, and part of the Money.</p>
               <p>Justice De Veil. The Reason of my sending for the Prisoner was upon the Deposition this Gentleman made, and I think it is not the same he makes now: He came to me, I believe the same Morning he was robbed, a nd he was so much in drink then, that I refused to take it; I told you you were in drink; I am sorry to say you do not swear the same now as you did before me; you swore then you were hauled down Stairs. Both <rs id="t17431207-58-verdict305" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-58-verdict305" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
