<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431207-28">
               <interp inst="t17431207-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-28" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431207-28" type="date" value="17431207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-28-off160-c185" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend241 t17431207-28-off160 t17431207-28-verdict164"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431207-28-off162-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend244 t17431207-28-off162 t17431207-28-verdict164"></join>
         
               <p>32. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-28-defend241" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend241" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend241" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of <placeName id="t17431207-28-defloc159">St. Mary White chapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-28-defloc159" type="placeName" value="St. Mary White chapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431207-28-defloc159" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend241 t17431207-28-defloc159"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend244 t17431207-28-defloc159"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17431207-28-off160" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-off160" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-off160" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two Pound and a half of Souchon Tea, value three Shillings, and a quarter of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174312070014"></xptr> a Pound of green Tea, value four Shillings
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17431207-28-victim242" type="victimName">
                  Job 
                  Matthew 
               <interp inst="t17431207-28-victim242" type="surname" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-victim242" type="given" value="Job"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-victim242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              , <rs id="t17431207-28-cd161" type="crimeDate">Oct. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-off160 t17431207-28-cd161"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-off162 t17431207-28-cd161"></join>.</p>
               <p>33. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431207-28-defend244" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hume 
                  <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend244" type="surname" value="Hume"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-defend244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , for <rs id="t17431207-28-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Job Matthew. I live in White-chapel; on the 23d of October, Mr. Ellis at the Coach and Horses told me, that Davis (who was my <rs id="t17431207-28-deflabel163" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend241 t17431207-28-deflabel163"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431207-28-defend244 t17431207-28-deflabel163"></join>) had left a Handkerchief there with some Tea in it, and thought he could not come honestly by it, and told me some Body was to call for it; I bid him, if any Body came for it, to send for me; some Time after two Fellows called to know, if there was not a Parcel left for them; I got a Headborough to stay and see, whether any Body came for it; in a short Time Hume came, and asked for a Parcel ; said Mr. Ellis, is this the Parcel you wait for; he said, yes; said I to the Headborough, take Charge of that Man, for I have a Suspicion of these Goods being stolen from me; in a little Time Davis comes strutting into the Room, says he, Where are these two Thieves that wait for me; said the Landlord, come in and see where they are; when he saw me he was quite confounded, so that the Sweat dropped down from his Face; said I, William, do you know how you came by these Goods? he said, he did not doubt but he could tell me before he came to his Trial. I carried him before Justice Rickards , and he confessed the small Parcel was mine, but that he bought the large Parcel of a Smuggler. I weighed a Cannister of Soucbon Tea, which I suspected this to be taken out of, and by the Account I keep with the Officer of Stock, I found about two Pound and a half wanting: The Lid of the Cannister was loose, and two or three Ounces lay loose upon the Lid of the Cannister, as if some Body had taken it out in a Hurry - It is a Tea of a very strong Flavour, and I never knew any of this Sort of Tea run; and I think I can be positive it is some of my own Tea.</p>

               <p>Prisoner . I bought it of a Person I met in New Gravel Lane; he opened a Leather Bag, and shewed it me; there was about two Pound of Bohea, and a little Parcel of Green ; I gave him nine Shillings for the Whole.</p>
               <p>Job Matthew. He said before the Justice it was in a Linen Bag, and now he says a Leather one: This Fellow came with a false Letter when I hired him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431207-28-person245">
                  Robert 
                  Okey 
               <interp inst="t17431207-28-person245" type="surname" value="Okey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-person245" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he saw him buy a Parcel of Tea of a Sailor, in New Gravel-Lane, on the 20th or 21st of October, on a Saturday, about four or five in the Afternoon - about two Pound, and he bargained for nine Shillings - There was a large Parcel, and a small one - I did not see him look at it any farther than taking the Paper in his Hand, he did not open it - I did not see it opened, I do not know whether Davis saw it opened - I was Coachman to Justice Strong of Hampstead, and I was four Years Coachman to Mr. Weller of Lincoln's-Inn. <rs id="t17431207-28-verdict164" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431207-28-verdict164" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
