<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460409-2">
               <interp inst="t17460409-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-2" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-2" type="date" value="17460409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460409-2-off6-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-2-defend66 t17460409-2-off6 t17460409-2-verdict9"></join>
         
               <p>132. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-2-defend66" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-2-defend66" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-defend66" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-defend66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, and being mov'd by the Instigation of the Devil, did <rs id="t17460409-2-off6" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-off6" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-off6" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               assault 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460409-2-victim68" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Abroon 
                        <interp inst="t17460409-2-victim68" type="surname" value="Abroon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460409-2-victim68" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460409-2-victim68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-2-off6 t17460409-2-victim68"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in <placeName id="t17460409-2-crimeloc7">Downing Court</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-crimeloc7" type="placeName" value="Downing Court"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-crimeloc7" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-2-off6 t17460409-2-crimeloc7"></join>, and with both his Hands striking and giving him upon his Belly and Stomach several mortal Bruises, &amp;c. whereof he died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Q. (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-2-person69">
                  Thomas 
                  Thornhill 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person69" type="surname" value="Thornhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person69" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Thornhill. The House where this Thing happen'd I had lodg'd at; there was a poor Woman in the House that wash'd my Linnen; as I was going to her thro' the House, I saw five or six Soldiers playing at Cards in the Box.</p>
               <p>Q. What House is it?</p>
               <p>Thornhill. A Publick House, in King-Street, Westminster; I set down with the Landlady's Sister in a Box, about half an Hour, upon which I heard some Words arise between two Soldiers, and the Deceas'd swore that he had won the Game; the other ( the Prisoner at the Bar ) swore that he had not won it fair, and insisted upon its being play'd over-again, the other swore he would not; upon that he came out of the Box, the Prisoner at the Bar insisted that he would not pay, the other Man (the Deceas'd) came out to him, and swore he should pay it; with that they had a great many Words, at last the Deceas'd was in a great Passion, stripp'd into his Shirt, swore he would fight him if he did not pay it. Said the Prisoner, I will have a Knock with you over the Table; the Prisoner did not seem to be willing to go into the House to fight; so after a great many Words, at last they put their Clothes on again, for the People of the House said there should be no Fighting in the House; with that Words arose again, and the Deceas'd swore he would have the Pint of Beer, and call'd for it; the Prisoner at the Bar said he would not pay for it; with that the Deceas'd stripp'd his Clothes off again, and struck the Prisoner at the Bar, and swore he would have the Beer, and in a vast Passion, very forward to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090004"></xptr> fight, he call'd this Man a great many Names because he would not pay, and struck him once or twice, and the Prisoner did not return it, and did not seem to be free to fight with him; but after a great many Words, and many Provocations, the Deceas'd struck him again; at last the Prisoner at the Bar said, I can't fight against four or five of you, or else I should not be afraid to take a Knock or two with you; so the Corporal said, don't make such a Noise here, but if you have a mind to fight, go out, and no Man shall stir out here. The Corporal said to the Prisoner, I will give you five Shillings if any Man comes out to give you any soul Play. After many Provocations the Prisoner at the Bar said I'll go out and take a Knock or two with you, if I have fair Play; so they went out at the Back-Door and went up to Downing's-Court there to fight; I not being concern'd about it, but hearing all that pass'd I had the Curiosity to go out at the Street Door to see how the Battle would go; I might be about 30 Yards behind them: I saw the Prisoner at the Bar throw his Coat and Waistcoat off; they were just set to it, they made two or three Blows at one another; presently the Prisoner gave the other a Trip and he tumbled down; tumbling down he did not offer to get up again; so he not offering to get up, the Prisoner at the Bar said, if you will have any more of it get up; with that he gave him a little Pull by the Hand, and it seem'd as if the Man was afraid to get up again; but I saw he began to work at the stomach, and began to heave and froth at the Mouth; and I believe died in ten Minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How far off was you from them?</p>
               <p>Thornhill. Please you, my Lord, I was as near as the Door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-2-person70">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person70" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person70" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Will you ask the Witness any Questions ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-2-person71">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person71" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person71" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-2-person72">
                  Joseph 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person72" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person72" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Terry. I keep a Publick-House just facing this House; I was coming out to make Water? I saw the Prisoner at the Bar and the Deceas'd, they were both stripp'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you was not in the House?</p>
               <p>Terry. No, my Lord; but when I came up to them I believe there was four or five Blows between them both; I believe a Boy of twelve or fourteen Years of Age could have given a greater Blow than either of them: The Deceas'd fell backward; when he was down the Prisoner at the Bar put his Hand to his Breast, and said, take a good Heart and get up again. Coming back I saw the Landlady of the House at the Back Door, who said to me, Did you see it? Yes, I said, I believ'd it was all over. The Girl came back presently after me and said, the Man is dead, and he was brought down.</p>
               <p>Court. You saw him dead.</p>
               <p>Terry. I saw him dead; that is all I know of the Matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-2-person73">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person73" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person73" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-2-person74">
                  William 
                  Buchanan 
               <interp inst="t17460409-2-person74" type="surname" value="Buchanan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person74" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know of Prisoner? What Office do you bear?</p>
               <p>Buchanan. I am a Serjeant: I have known the Prisoner many Years; he always behav'd well as a <rs id="t17460409-2-deflabel8" type="occupation">Soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-2-defend66 t17460409-2-deflabel8"></join>; I never knew him brought into any Scrapes ? he receiv'd a Wound in Flanders, was taken a Prisoner to France, and was there five Months.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460409-2-verdict9" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-verdict9" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-verdict9" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460409-2-punish10" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-punish10" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-2-punish10" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-2-defend66 t17460409-2-punish10"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
