<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470604-8">
               <interp inst="t17470604-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-8" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470604"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470604-8" type="date" value="17470604"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470604-8-off34-c146" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-8-defend162 t17470604-8-off34 t17470604-8-verdict37"></join>
         
               <p>141. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-8-defend162" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Lar 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-8-defend162" type="surname" value="Lar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-defend162" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-defend162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17470604-8-off34" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-off34" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-off34" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Moidore , a Guinea, and fifteen Shillings in Silver
            </rs>, the Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470604-8-victim164" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Forster 
                  <interp inst="t17470604-8-victim164" type="surname" value="Forster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-victim164" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-victim164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-8-off34 t17470604-8-victim164"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470604-8-cd35" type="crimeDate">May 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-8-off34 t17470604-8-cd35"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-8-person165">
                  John 
                  Forster 
               <interp inst="t17470604-8-person165" type="surname" value="Forster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What have you to alledge against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Forster . Last Friday was 7-Night she pick'd me up in the Street, and pull'd me into a House, whether I would or no.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the Night was this?</p>
               <p>Forster. It was about 9 o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What Street was this in?</p>
               <p>Forster. In <placeName id="t17470604-8-crimeloc36">Newtoner's-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470604-8-crimeloc36" type="placeName" value="Newtoner's-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470604-8-crimeloc36" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470604-8-off34 t17470604-8-crimeloc36"></join> .</p>
               <p>Court. You seem to be a Country-man. What brought you there?</p>
               <p>Forster. She would pull me there, whether I would or no. I was going into Bishopsgate-Street, to pay this Money.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you acquainted with the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Forster. No; but she met me in Holborn, and had me down to Newtoner's-Lane . She spoke to me first: Ah Country-man, give us a Dram.</p>
               <p>Court. So upon that you went along with her?</p>
               <p>Forster. Yes, Sir; she made me go, whether I would or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober then?</p>
               <p>Forster. I had had a Glass or two. I was not quite sober; nor I was not quite drunk neither.</p>
               <p>Court. So you went along with her?</p>
               <p>Forster. She made me go, whether I would or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go with her?</p>
               <p>Forster . By Newtoner's-Lane . I was not willing to go in, but she pull'd me in by force.</p>
               <p>Court. So you could not help it, she haul'd you in, or did she shove you in before her?</p>
               <p>Forster. She pull'd me in, and shoved me in to.</p>
               <p>Court. When you got in what then?</p>
               <p>Forster. Then she pull'd me up Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. When you got up Stairs, what then?</p>
               <p>Forster. Then she pull'd up her Coats against me, and took my Money from me. There was a Thirty-six Shilling Piece, a Guinea, and fifteen Shillings in Silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was all this Money.</p>
               <p>Forster . In my Pocket, in a Purse, and the Note with it, where I was to fetch the Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take Purse and all?</p>
               <p>Forster. Purse, Money, Note, and all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Person with her in the Room?</p>
               <p>Forster . There was a Woman upon the Bed; but there was no body touch'd me but this Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lie down upon the Bed?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040017"></xptr>Forster. No, Sir; nor sit upon the Bed neither .</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you there?</p>
               <p>Forster. Not above half a quarter of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink nothing while you was there.</p>
               <p>Forster. Not a Drop.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Room a dark Room, or had you a Candle?</p>
               <p>Forster. It was a light Room, as light as it is here.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss your Money?</p>
               <p>Forster. As she threw her Coats up, so I miss'd my Money directly; I saw the Purse in her Hand; I followed her as last as I could, but she was too quick for me.</p>
               <p>Court. So when she had got your Money and Purse from you, she ran down Stairs.</p>
               <p>Forster . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this Woman before?</p>
               <p>Forster. Never in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see this Woman again?</p>
               <p>Forster. About two Hours after.</p>
               <p>Court. There was a Woman in the Room; did you make no Complaint to her?</p>
               <p>Forster. I said, I am undone! my Pocket is pick'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that Woman awake or asleep?</p>
               <p>Forster . She never stirr'd; she never troubled herself with me, nor I with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see her two or three Hours afterwards?</p>
               <p>Forster. I described her to some People about St Giles's , and they said they see her pull me along.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been in the Morning before, to get fudell'd?</p>
               <p>Forster. I went along with the Hempsted Waggon as far as Paddington.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it that you did not go on with it?</p>
               <p>Forster. I am a Porter to the Waggon; I am not the Waggoner. We had been drinking at Paddington . We had a Pot or two of Beer between four of us ; and when I came to St Giles's I had a Dram of Brandy.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Forster. Then, Sir, I was going to pay my Money in Bishopsgate-Street; and I lights with her, and she has me down to Newtoner's-Lane .</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet with again?</p>
               <p>Forster. At an Ale-House, the back side of St Giles's.</p>
               <p>Court. What then?</p>
               <p>Forster. Then I took her up, and carried her before a Justice at St Giles's.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she search'd; had she any Money about her?</p>
               <p>Forster. They found half a Guinea about her, and about two-pence half-penny, or thereabouts. She had the Money as sure as I stands here. There was half a Guinea in Gold found and I can't tell whether nine or ten Shillings in Silver, and some Half-pence.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Will you ask him any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was crying old Cloaths, and he told me, he could carry me to a Place where I might buy a Coat.</p>
               <p>Forster. There was nothing in it; she carried me to a Place where she took my Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember she was crying old Cloaths?</p>
               <p>Forster. No, Sir; nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>Court. You have mentioned she was search'd, You had a Purse, was that found?</p>
               <p>Forster . No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470604-8-person166">
                  Sarah 
                  Nelson 
               <interp inst="t17470604-8-person166" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-person166" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of Matter, or have to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Nelson. I was standing, above Nine o'Clock, at my Door, in Newtoner's-Lane , and I saw this man and Girl, coming up the Lane, on Friday was 7-Night. I wonder'd that an ancient Man should go with such a nasty common Creature; we know her very well to be a common Woman. I said, bless me what an antient Man is he to be along with that Creature. He stopp'd to make Water, and she pulled him in at the back Door.</p>
               <p>Court. Was there any degree of Violence used; did he make any Resistance. How did the Man appear; was he in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Nelson. He was very middling; he had a Dram, I believe; she pull'd him in at the back Door, at Mr Morris's, in Newtoner's-Lane .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174706040018"></xptr>Q. Does she live there?</p>
               <p>Nelson. I believe she plies there. As for crying old Cloaths she knows nothing what belongs to it.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. What have you to say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was crying old Cloaths in the Street; and he took me to this Publick House, under a Pretence of helping me to the buying of a Coat: When I came, the House was full of People; I says, I don't care to stay; so he he said he would call for a Dram for my Pains.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470604-8-verdict37" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470604-8-verdict37" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
