<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440223-13">
               <interp inst="t17440223-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-13" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-13" type="date" value="17440223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-13-off70-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-13-defend96 t17440223-13-off70 t17440223-13-verdict73"></join>
         
               <p>152. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-13-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Newton 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-13-defend96" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-defend96" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-defend96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440223-13-defloc69">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-13-defloc69" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-13-defloc69" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-13-defend96 t17440223-13-defloc69"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440223-13-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing half a guinea, and one shilling, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440223-13-victim98" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Jennings 
                        <interp inst="t17440223-13-victim98" type="surname" value="Jennings"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-13-victim98" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-13-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-13-off70 t17440223-13-victim98"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440223-13-cd71" type="crimeDate">Feb. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-13-off70 t17440223-13-cd71"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-13-person99">
                  George 
                  Jennings 
               <interp inst="t17440223-13-person99" type="surname" value="Jennings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-person99" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday, about 10 a clock at night, as I was going home to my master's (Mr. Haddock, who keeps a bagnio) the Prisoner picked my pocket of half a guinea in the <placeName id="t17440223-13-crimeloc72">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-13-crimeloc72" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-13-crimeloc72" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-13-off70 t17440223-13-crimeloc72"></join>, between Hungerford and St. Martin's Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she do it?</p>
               <p>Jennings. She took hold of me, put her hand into my pocket, and took out half a guinea, and some silver. - I caught her hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. In what pocket?</p>
               <p>Jennings. In the right-hand pocket of my breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take it out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find her hand in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What, before she had taken the money out?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss the money?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I missed it directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What, before her hand was out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you put your gold and silver together?</p>
               <p>Jennings. It was together then.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before was it that you saw your money?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I felt it as I was coming along.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Just before.</p>
               <p>Q. How much had you in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I had in all about 14 s. half a guinea in gold, and the rest in silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What pieces were they?</p>
               <p>Jennings. They were shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they all shillings?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ne'er a six-pence?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Not to my knowledge; I had changed a guinea at the Ship in St. James's-street, and had my full change.</p>
               <p>Q. You should have had more money, what did you do with the rest?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I paid some money there, and I had been drinking, and had spent some money.</p>
               <p>Q. How much had you spent?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I believe nine pence, for three pots of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Nine pence was a pretty deal, was not you disguised in liquor?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Very little, if any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find your money?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I found it in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you take it from her?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I could not open her hand; I called the watch, and secured her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever retrieve your money?</p>
               <p>Jennings. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say when you had called the watch?</p>
               <p>Jennings. She said, she had only taken a halfpenny from me, and she would give it me again, and I said, I would not take it; I had her to the watch-house, kept her there all night, and the next morning had her before a Justice, and then she owned she took a halfpenny out of my pocket, and no more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you offer me three pence at the water side, if I would oblige you?</p>
               <p>Jennings. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You said so at the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Jennings. By virtue of my oath I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you pull me and haul me about, and wanted to have to do with me?</p>
               <p>Jennings. By virtue of my oath, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You said you had been spending of money, or you would have given me more.</p>
               <p>Jennings. By virtue of my oath, it is false.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what pretence did she come up to you? Did she speak to you?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes, she came to pick me up.</p>
               <p>Q. What space of time was there from the beginning of this transaction to the end of it?</p>
               <p>Jennings. It might be a minute or thereabout.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pick her up, or did she pick you up?</p>
               <p>Jennings. She picked me up; when she came up<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230007"></xptr> to me, she took hold of me with one arm, and with the other picked my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she searched?</p>
               <p>Jennings. No, she was not searched, for when I proposed searching of her, she said, if she had three or four half guineas about her, what was that to any body.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was coming from my mistress's where I had been at work, by St. Martin's Lane; he asked me to drink, I said, No, I will not; then he said, he would give me three pence if I would go with him under the gate-way; I said, I did not value his three pence; he said he had been spending money, or else he would have given me more; and because I would not go with him, he d - d me and called me bitch, and charged the watch with me in a minute. <rs id="t17440223-13-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-13-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
