<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-3">
               <interp inst="t17431012-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-3" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-3" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-3-off10-c59" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-3-defend64 t17431012-3-off10 t17431012-3-verdict12"></join>
         
               <p>464. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-defend64" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Clayton 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-3-defend64" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-defend64" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-defend64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17431012-3-defloc9">St Botolph without Aldersgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-3-defloc9" type="placeName" value="St Botolph without Aldersgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-3-defloc9" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-3-defend64 t17431012-3-defloc9"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17431012-3-off10" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-off10" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-off10" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking open the Dwelling House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17431012-3-victim66" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Barlow 
                        <interp inst="t17431012-3-victim66" type="surname" value="Barlow"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-3-victim66" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-3-victim66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-3-off10 t17431012-3-victim66"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17431012-3-cd11" type="crimeDate">7th of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-3-off10 t17431012-3-cd11"></join>, in the Night-time, and stealing twelve large Silver-Buttons, value 22 s. twenty-six Waistcoat ditto, value 28 s. four Silver Snuff-boxes, value 2 l. 11 s. one Snuff-box, value 8 s. four Silver-Spoons, value 40 s. four Tea-Spoons, value 8 s. a half Pint Silver Mug, value 2 l. 11 s. one Silver Waiter, value 35 s. and four Corals, with Silver Sockets and Bells, value 30 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17431012-3-person67">
                  Henry 
                  Barlow 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person67" type="surname" value="Barlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person67" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person68">
                  Henry 
                  Barlow 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person68" type="surname" value="Barlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person68" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Blackmoor's-Head in Barbican: my House was broke open September the 7th, at Night; it was fast about ten o'Clock, when I went to Bed; there was a Piece of the Shutter of the Shop taken out by the Help of a Knife and a Gimblet, as I suppose, by the Appearance of it; the Hole was big enough to put an Arm through; the Plate that I lost stood within reach of that Hole, and must be taken out that way: The Prisoner pledged with Mr Kay a Snuff-Box, a Coral, and a Tea Spoon: On Friday September 9. I advertised them; and Mr Kay came to me, and told me, he found by an Advertisement, that I had lost such and such Things; showed them to me, and asked me if they were mine, and I said they were; these are part of them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How can you swear to those Things which have no Mark upon them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person69">
                  William 
                  Kay 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person69" type="surname" value="Kay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person69" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These Things were brought to me by the Prisoner on the 8th of September, with a Callimanco Petticoat; and I lent her 25 s. upon them all; an Advertisement coming out, I looked over my Day Book, to see if I had taken in such Things, and I found that I had; I went to Mr Barlow, and told him, there was a Woman had brought to my House yesterday a Snuff-Box, a Corral, and a Spoon; says he. There's no particular Mark upon them, but I believe if I was to see them I should know them; I showed them to him, and he said, they were his; and desired me, if the Woman came again to stop her, which I promised I would; I had not been at Home above an Hour and an half before the Woman came again to take these Things out from the Petticoat, but I refused it; and asked her how she came by them; she said she had bought them in the Neighbourhood, and made some little Sort of a Motion to go. I said I would stop the Things and enquire about it; she said I need not go, for she had actually bought them. and that she bought them in Turnmill-street. I said it was very odd that she should buy such Things as these in the Street, (as she deals in old Cloaths she might have bought a Petticoat in the Street,) but she still continued in the Story, that she bought them of a Man in the Street; but she would have gone away, and have left them in my Possession: She said she had them weighed, but could give no Account of the Weight, and that she gave 19 s. for them, which I suppose she thought might be about 5 s. per Ounce. I took her to be a very different Woman from what I find her to be, for I have known her a great many Years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought them very innocently; he looked like a decent creditable looking Man, and said his Wife was dead, and he had a Mind to sell them. I bought them at a fair Market Price; he asked me a Guinea for them, and I gave him nineteen Shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person70">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person70" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person70" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going out to washing, and coming along Turnmill-Street, I met the Prisoner, and a Man came up to her and asked her where there was a Pawnbroker's: She said there was one here and one there, and told him, if he had got any thing to sell she would buy them; he asked her 20 s. for the Snuff-Box and Coral, and she bid him 19 s. and she pulled off her Petticoat and pawned it with these Things to raise the Money to pay for them. - I think it was the 8th of this Month, it was the first Day of the Borough Fair; - she knew me an Infant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person71">
                  Susannah 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person71" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person71" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person71" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of September, I happened to meet the Prisoner, says she, Sut, will you go to see the Borough Fair? Says I, I will go To-morrow, but I cannot go To-day; we sat down at the Door of a Publick-House, I think it is the Sign of the Trumpet or Horn, and a decent looking Sort of a Man, pretty well dressed, came to her and said, Mistress can you tell me where there is a Pawnbroker's Shop; says she, here's one here, and another there. She said if he had got any thing to sell, she would buy it; so he pulled out a Snuff-Box and a Coral, and said his Wife was dead, and he had a Mind to dispose of them; says she, Sue, here's a Coral it will serve for my Child when I lie in; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120005"></xptr> laughed and said, What are you with Child? She asked him what he would have for them; he said 20 s. and she gave him 19 s. said she, You will stay with the Man while I go and get the Money; and she said she would go and pawn her Petticoat to make up the Money. I saw her loosen her Petticoat, as if she was going to take if off, and she came back in less than a Quarter of an Hour, and brought 20 s. The Man staid by me all the Time she was gone; - he trusted her with the Things while she went and got the Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person72">
                  Walter 
                  Buckland 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person72" type="surname" value="Buckland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person72" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner eight or nine Years. I knew her when I was Apprentice; I never heard any Harm of her.</p>
               <p>- Hornblower. I have known her thirty Years; she is a Person of a very good Character; I know her to be a very honest Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-3-person73">
                  Peter 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person73" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person73" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17431012-3-person74">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person74" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person74" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17431012-3-person75">
                  Sarah 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17431012-3-person75" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person75" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-person75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and two other Witnesses gave her the Character of an honest Woman: One of them had known her thirty Years, and another said he had trusted her with Cloth to sell, that he could not sell in his Shop, and she always paid him very honestly. <rs id="t17431012-3-verdict12" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-3-verdict12" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
