<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420224-58">
               <interp inst="t17420224-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-58" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-58" type="date" value="17420224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420224-58-off246-c305" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-58-defend417 t17420224-58-off246 t17420224-58-verdict249"></join>
         
               <p>60. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420224-58-defend417" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Kelly 
                  <interp inst="t17420224-58-defend417" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-defend417" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-defend417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17420224-58-off246" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-off246" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-off246" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing five 36 s. Pieces, 2 Moidores, 2 Guineas, 2 half Guineas, and a Porto-Bello Medal, value 4 s. the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420224-58-victim419" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Ottiwell 
                        <interp inst="t17420224-58-victim419" type="surname" value="Ottiwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-58-victim419" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-58-victim419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-58-off246 t17420224-58-victim419"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17420224-58-person420">
                        George 
                        Needham 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-person420" type="surname" value="Needham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-58-person420" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-58-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17420224-58-cd247" type="crimeDate">Jan 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-58-off246 t17420224-58-cd247"></join>.</p>
               <p>Ottiwell I was coming from the Rummer in Chancery-Lane, towards White chappel, and was stopp'd by the Prisoner at the End of a Court in <placeName id="t17420224-58-crimeloc248">Fleet Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-58-crimeloc248" type="placeName" value="Fleet Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-58-crimeloc248" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-58-off246 t17420224-58-crimeloc248"></join>, she took me by the Hand and asked me to drink a Glass of something; I told her I could not drink; why (said she) if you will not treat me, I will treat you. Upon that, she took me to a House, the Stairs of which open into the Court, and there we had Cherry-Brandy and other Liquors, and then - she pick'd my Pocket of upwards of 20 l. I felt her Hand in my Pocket, but she was too quick for me, and ran down Stairs immediately. I pursued her into the Court, and a Man struck me on the Breast in Order I suppose to stop me.</p>
               <p>Pris. Ask him whether he was not very much in Liquor when I was carried to the Watch-house?</p>
               <p>Ottiwell. I was in Liquor when I went into the House; but the Fright made me sober.</p>
               <p>- Kingsley. The Watchman brought this Man to the Watch-house, and said he had been robb'd. When the Prisoner was taken she was not search'd, for the Watchmen said, as the Money was lost in Needham's House it was secure, for it is a notorious House.</p>
               <p>Pris. I had been to Leicester fields to stand Godmother to a Child, and was coming from thence with some People between one and two in the Morning, I parted with my Company at White-Fryars, and just stept up this Alley, and immediately the Watchman laid hold of me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240024"></xptr>A Man. The Prisoner and I stood for the Child at the Christning. When it was all over, we came through Temple-Bar, and at White-Fryars Gateway I parted with her.</p>
               <p>A Woman. The Prisoner and I met at Temple-Bar and we came together into Fleet-street She just stepp'd up White-Lyon Court, and in less than a Minute I saw a Woman run out, and a Man after her, and presently the Watchman laid hold of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Another. I was going to Billinsgate, and met the Prisoner and a Man by Temple Bar. She told me she had been at a Christening, and (with that) the Man took his Leave of her at White-Fryars-Gate. There is a Court in Fleet-Street called White-Lyon-Court, and she desired us to stay for her while she just stepp'd up the Court - and then she was taken. I have known her these 5 Years to be an honest Woman.</p>
               <p>A Man. I have known her 8 Years: She made Gowns for my Wife, and her Husband made Shoes for me: I always took her to be an honest Woman.</p>
               <p>A Woman. She has made Mantuas for me these 5 Years, and I have recommended her to several People. <rs id="t17420224-58-verdict249" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-58-verdict249" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
