<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420714-18">
               <interp inst="t17420714-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-18" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-18" type="date" value="17420714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-18-off85-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-18-defend137 t17420714-18-off85 t17420714-18-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>21. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-defend137" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Shirley 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-18-defend137" type="surname" value="Shirley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-defend137" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-defend137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420714-18-defloc84">St Bartholomew the Less</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-18-defloc84" type="placeName" value="St Bartholomew the Less"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-18-defloc84" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-18-defend137 t17420714-18-defloc84"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420714-18-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               feloniously stealing 14 Ells of Linnen Cloth, called Washed Dowlas, out of the Shop of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420714-18-victim139" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Setcole 
                        <interp inst="t17420714-18-victim139" type="surname" value="Setcole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-18-victim139" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-18-victim139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-18-off85 t17420714-18-victim139"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17420714-18-cd86" type="crimeDate">June 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-18-off85 t17420714-18-cd86"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Setcole. The Prisoner at the Bar came into my Shop, in <placeName id="t17420714-18-crimeloc87">West-Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-18-crimeloc87" type="placeName" value="West-Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-18-crimeloc87" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-18-off85 t17420714-18-crimeloc87"></join>, the 8th of June, between the Hours of five and six, and she pretended to buy some Holland; her Behaviour during the Time she was in the Shop, gave me a Suspicion of her; when she went out, one of my Servants was ordered to go after her, but Mr Walker being in the Shop, offered his Service and followed her; while she was gone, I searched whether I had lost any thing, and missed a Piece of washed Dowlas, and in less than about 10 Minutes, Mr. Walker brought her back with the Cloth under her Arm; she came running into the Shop with the Cloth, and threw it down where she had been sitting. She was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17420714-18-person140">
                  Robert 
                  Godsehall 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person140" type="surname" value="Godsehall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person140" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she owned the Fact privately to us before, but did not own it before Sir 
               <persName id="t17420714-18-person141">
                  Robert 
                  Godschall 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person141" type="surname" value="Godschall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person141" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - She said it was the first Fact she had committed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Servant show her the Cloth or yourself?</p>
               <p>Mr Setcole. My Servant. She had agreed for three Ells of it, and paid one Shilling in part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person142">
                  James 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person142" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person142" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Mr Setcole's Shop the 8th of June, and saw the Prisoner at the Bar, bargaining with Mr Setcole's Servant for some cloth; as soon as she went out of the Shop, Mr Setcole said he was afraid she had taken some Cloth; he talked of sending a Servant to follow her, and I said I would follow her myself, which I did, and at the End of a Court, there was a Door, at which she went in and shut the Door; I immediately opened the Door, and saw her Petticoats up, and the cloth then coming from under them. I took hold of her, and told her, Madam, - I called her Madam, because she was dressed in a fine damask Gown, and fine Cloaths. - Madam, said I, you must go with me to Mr Setcole's the Draper, from whence you came; she immediately took the Cloth and put it under her Arm, and came along with me; coming thro' the Cloysters, she fell down upon one Knee and dropped the Cloth, I suppose with Design of leaving it, but she took it up and brought it with her, then I saw her go into Mr Setcole's Shop, she gave a little sort of a run, slipp'd into the Chair, threw the Cloth down, and threw another Piece of Cloth which was upon the Counter, upon the Piece which she brought in with her, and had thrown down before; immediately I took up that Piece of Cloth which she had under her Arm, and brought in and threw upon the Ground, and asked Mr Setcole, is that your Cloth? for that was the Cloth which that Woman took from under her Petticoats and brought under her Arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make a Mark upon it?</p>
               <p>Walker. I did not.</p>
               <p>Setcole. This is my Cloth.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Mark by which you know that to be your Property. -</p>
               <p>Setcole. Yes! the Mark is upon it now. - This is the Mark.</p>
               <p>Walker. I took her into the Counting-House, and sat with her about half an Hour, while Mr Setcole sent for a Constable; and she begged hard that I would not send her before my Lord Mayor or any Magistrate, that it was the first she ever committed, and had 4 Children.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make her any Promise of Favour?</p>
               <p>Walker. No:</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, Mr Setcole?</p>
               <p>Mr Setcole. No. I told her I would do her Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person143">
                  James 
                  Mabbs 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person143" type="surname" value="Mabbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person143" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of June, the Prisoner at the Bar came to Mr Setcole's Shop, under pretence of buying some Holland. I shewed her several Pieces, whereof we agreed for one: at the Time we were agreeing, I observed that she had something under her Coat, sometimes shuffling, as if she had something she was afraid should drop, by which I immediately imagined she had robbed us of a Piece of Cloth; after we had agreed for the Holland, she desired me to cut off three Ells, which I did, and put it into a Paper for her, and she gave me a Shilling Earnest; as soon as she was gone, we all agreed that she had taken something, and intended to send a Servant after her, but Mr Walker being in the Shop, he offered to go, and in ten Minutes Time she came back with the Piece under her Arm; she sat down in a Chair in the Shop, and flung the Piece of Cloth down upon the Ground, and endeavoured to pull another Piece of Cloth off the Counter to smother it, that I should not know which it was: In the Time that she was gone, I missed a Piece of Cloth, and found that Piece which I took up to be the same Piece which I before had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140007"></xptr> missed. - She desired my Master to forgive her, and offered to go down upon her Knees if he would let her go, but we are so much troubled with these Customers, he thought proper to do her Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person144">
                  William 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person144" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person144" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable, Mr Setcole came to my House and told me he had lost a Piece of Cloth, and that he had detected the Woman in the Fact, and desired me to come and take Charge of her; she begged I would endeavour to make the Affair up, and she would send for Friends and make Satisfaction, that she had 5 Children and desired me to make it easy.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner, in her Defence, said she went into the Court to make Water.</p>
               <p>Walker. I saw no Water. - I saw her pull this Piece of Cloth from under her Coats. - She very willingly came along with me; she was dressed in a very fine Manner. - I did not lead her along, for I was not afraid of her getting away.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not several Pieces of Cloth with the same Mark? -</p>
               <p>Setcole. Yes, but there were none such upon the Counter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have a great Number of Witnesses to my Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person145">
                  Thomas 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person145" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know her and her Husband very well, they have three or four small Children, her Husband is an honest Man, a Perriwig-maker. I have known her four or five Years. - I do not think she would do such a Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person146">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person146" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person146" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She is a Some. I have worked for her. I never saw, or heard, any thing amiss of her. She has three small Children.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person147">
                  Ann 
                  Craven 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person147" type="surname" value="Craven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person147" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs Shirley for about 2 Years, I have worked Plain-work for her. She is an industrious Woman, and works hard for her Living. I never heard any harm of her, she bears a very good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person148">
                  Mary 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person148" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person148" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She is a very honest Woman, and paid me very justly for what she had of me, and works hard for her Children. I never heard a bad Character of her, which made me the more surprized when I heard this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person149">
                  Mary 
                  Kew 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person149" type="surname" value="Kew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person149" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nursed her 2 Children, and she always paid me honestly. I never knew any harm of her, she is a House-keeper, and lives by Eagle-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person150">
                  William 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person150" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Gentlewoman about 4 or 5 Years, I never knew but she was an industrious Person, and always worked for her Bread.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person151">
                  James 
                  Gillingham 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person151" type="surname" value="Gillingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Woman has made Shirts for me, I never heard any thing of her but what was very honest, I never heard but that she had a good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-18-person152">
                  Thomas 
                  Singleton 
               <interp inst="t17420714-18-person152" type="surname" value="Singleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person152" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her a Year and an Half, she has behaved honestly to me, and I never heard she had a bad Character. <rs id="t17420714-18-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-18-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
