<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-1">
               <interp inst="t17420428-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-1" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-1" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend30 t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-verdict9"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-1-off2-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend32 t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-verdict11"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-1-off4-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend30 t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-verdict9"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-1-off4-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend32 t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>1. 2. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend30" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-defend32" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Craycroft 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend32" type="surname" value="Craycroft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend32" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-defend32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420428-1-defloc1">St. Mary Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend30 t17420428-1-defloc1"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend32 t17420428-1-defloc1"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17420428-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-1-victim34" type="victimName">
                           Edmund 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim34" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim34" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Field and open Place near the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 4 l. and 4 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420428-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">October 18th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-cd3"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>They were a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17420428-1-off4" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-off4" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-off4" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting. 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-1-victim36" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Rumley 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim36" type="surname" value="Rumley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim36" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Field, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 5 l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-1-victim38" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Bartrup 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim38" type="surname" value="Bartrup"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim38" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-1-victim38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 15 s. the Money of the said Rumley
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person39">
                  Edmund 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person39" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person39" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 18th of October last between 7 and 8 at Night, I was met just on this Side the Back of the <placeName id="t17420428-1-crimeloc5">Bowling Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc5" type="placeName" value="Bowling Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc5" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-crimeloc5"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-crimeloc5"></join>, in <placeName id="t17420428-1-crimeloc6">Stepney-Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc6" type="placeName" value="Stepney-Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc6" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-crimeloc6"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-crimeloc6"></join>, by two Footpads, who stopp'd me, and demanded my Money. They took from me my Watch, and 4 or 5 s. in Silver, or something more, and then made off towards Ratcliff. It was a very dark Night, and I was very much frighted, so that I can't say that I know any Thing of the Persons. My Watch was afterwards offer'd to pawn to Mr. Warner, in King-Street, near Tower-Hill, and after making some Enquiry, I found it there, and had it again.</p>
               <p>- Cresswell. I live with Mr. Warner. On the 20th of October, the Prisoner Wood brought this Watch to our House to pledge. He ask'd a Guinea upon it, and accordingly had it. About three Days afterwards he came for the Watch, and had it out again. On the 27th of October he brought it again, and had a Guinea and half upon it, and he never came to enquire for it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Pris. Wood. I bought this Watch at a public House: I humbly recommend it to your Consideration, that if I had stolen the Watch, I should not have pawn'd it in my own Name, and in my own Neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Jury to the Prosecution. Are the Prisoners like the two Persons who robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith I can't pretend to say that I made any Remarks of them.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person40">
                  Robert 
                  Rumley 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person40" type="surname" value="Rumley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person40" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of October last, between eight and nine in the Evening, I was stopped by two Men arm'd with Horse-Pistols, in the large Field adjoining to <placeName id="t17420428-1-crimeloc7">Whitechappel-Mount</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc7" type="placeName" value="Whitechappel-Mount"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-1-crimeloc7" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off2 t17420428-1-crimeloc7"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-off4 t17420428-1-crimeloc7"></join>. They made Use of a great many Oaths and Imprecations, and demanded my Money. I gave them about 15 s. and a Silver Watch, which<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280003"></xptr> was the Property of 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person41">
                  Thomas 
                  Bartrup 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person41" type="surname" value="Bartrup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person41" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Maker Graham, No. 101. These Men in Stature exactly answer'd the Prisoners; the short Man was in blue grey, he had on a Pair of red Breeches, and I think he was mask'd, for I could not see his Countenance. The other Man had a light coloured loose great Coat, and a light colour'd Wig, and was not mask'd, but I could not distinguish his Face. I advertis'd the Watch, and about three Days afterwards it was brought to me by Mr. Jacobson.</p>
               <p>- Jacobson. On the 24th of October, 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person42">
                  Samuel 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person42" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person42" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought a Watch to my House, and desir'd to have a Guinea and a half upon it. I asked him where he liv'd? he said, he was a Midshipman belonging to the Greenwich Man of War, and appearing handsomely dress'd, I lent him the Money upon it. I happen'd to be at the Coffee-House the Tuesday following, and saw this very Watch advertis'd, and next Morning I carried it to Mr. Finch's in Lambard-Street, according to the Direction in the Advertisement.</p>
               <p>Pris. Wood. According to the best of my Remembrance, this Gentleman said before Mr. Deveil, that he took my Name down, and where I liv'd, and when he found the Watch was stolen, why did he not send and secure me?</p>
               <p>Jacobson. I took no Account where he liv'd: he told me he came up to Town with the Lieutenant to see after some Men who had run away from the Ship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person43">
                  Alice 
                  Richard 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person43" type="surname" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person43" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoners being arrested, they sent me with another Woman to fetch the Watches out of Pawn. Craycraft desired Mrs. Carter to give a Letter to this Gentleman. I saw him deliver the Letter to her; it was seal'd up, and the Purport of it was, to desire the Gentleman to let us have the Watches, by the same Token, that one of the Prisoners had fetch'd a Hinger out of Pawn about a Week before. Craycraft said one of the Watches was his, and the other Mr. Wood's, and he hop'd the Pawnbrokers would let them be sold for more Money, or else buy them themselves. We went according to their Direction to these Pawnbrokers; but one of them had carried the Watch home that was pawn'd with him: and the other Pawnbroker refused to deliver his to any Person but the right Owner.</p>
               <p>Jacobson. I did receive a Letter sign'd 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person44">
                  Samuel 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person44" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person44" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but it was two Months after I had delivered the Watch.</p>
               <p>Richard. We carried two Letters, one to each Pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person45">
                  James 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person45" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person45" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Officer and arrested the two Prisoners for a Debt which they had contracted. I kept them at my own House the twenty-four Hours, which I had a Right to do, and then I was for carrying them to Prison. They told me, they had some Watches and lac'd Waistcoats in Pawn, and desired me to keep them a Day longer at my House, that they might sell them, and make it up with the Plaintiff. They had no Money, so I ask'd them what they would leave me for what they had eat and drank at my House? they said, they had a Brace of Pistols which were lock'd up in a 'Scrutore in their Lodging, but the Landlord would not let me have them. I then carry'd them to Goal, where they remain'd about six Weeks, and then were discharged. After this, Mrs. Richards fell out with them, and inform'd me of a Letter which she had carry'd concerning some Watches, and Jacobson telling me where he had deliver'd one of them, I found out the Prosecutor, who gave me an Account of his being robb'd. Upon this, I got a Warrant against the Prisoners, and they immediately flew from the Place which they frequented in Wild street, to Deptford, where I took them. I call'd Wood into a Corner, and ask'd him whether he had not better save his own Life and make a Discovery? He told me, he could not hang two, for what Robberies he had committed, were with Craycroft alone.</p>
               <p>- Rose. On the 7th of March, Mr. Barnes and I went to Deptford in Pursuit of the Prisoners, and on Monday Morning between 9 and 10 o'Clock, we were waiting in a Yard, and saw them go by the Door. We went after them and took them into a Public-house. Barnes took Wood into a Corner of the Room, and ask'd him if any Body else was concern'd with him, and he said, he never was concern'd with any body but Craycraft.</p>
               <p>Wood. Did you find any Thing upon us when we were taken into Custody?</p>
               <p>Rose. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person46">
                  John 
                  Thwaites 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person46" type="surname" value="Thwaites"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Wood twelve Years, and all the Time I have known him, I never heard any Thing amiss of him. I never heard of his being at Sea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person47">
                  Joseph 
                  Wingree 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person47" type="surname" value="Wingree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person47" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Wood between 4 and 5 Years, I brew'd at his Master's on Peter's-Hill. A very pretty <rs id="t17420428-1-deflabel8" type="occupation">Scholar</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend30 t17420428-1-deflabel8"></join> he is to be sure, and behav'd himself very handsomely.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person48">
                  Robert 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person48" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person48" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him some Years, and never heard any harm, or knew any by him. As for his Parents, they are very<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280004"></xptr> honest People, and brought him up in good Learning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person49">
                  James 
                  Thwaites 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person49" type="surname" value="Thwaites"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person49" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person50">
                  Samuel 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person50" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person50" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I am sorry such a Misfortune should happen to him now: I really believe he will reform; I hope so, and never be guilty of the like any more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person51">
                  Edmund 
                  Cadle 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person51" type="surname" value="Cadle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person51" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew all his Friends vastly well, and he was a civil young Man, and always behav'd well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person52">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person52" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known that Gentleman at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person53">
                  Sam 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person53" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person53" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , ever since he was 10 Years old, and never knew any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person54">
                  Wm 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person54" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person54" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten Years, and never knew no other but that he was a civil, honest, sober young Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person55">
                  John 
                  Flavil 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person55" type="surname" value="Flavil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17420428-1-person56">
                  Sam 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person56" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person56" type="given" value="Sam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a great while, and never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person57">
                  Thomas 
                  Cleeve 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person57" type="surname" value="Cleeve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person57" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have very little Knowledge of either of the Prisoners, but I went with Wood's Father to Mr. Rumley, and he said, he was very sorry he was put on to prosecute, for he would rather have lost all the Things.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rumley. Wood's Father and this Gentleman desired me to be as favourable as I could. I told them I could not, but must speak the Truth according to the best of my Judgment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-1-person58">
                  Wm 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17420428-1-person58" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person58" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been a Lodger in Wood's Father's House for 20 Months I never saw the Prisoner disguis'd in Liquor, but he always behaved himself with Duty and Respect.</p>
               <p>For Craycroft no one appeared.</p>
               <p>Wood <rs id="t17420428-1-verdict9" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-verdict9" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420428-1-punish10" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-punish10" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-1-defend30 t17420428-1-punish10"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Craycroft <rs id="t17420428-1-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-1-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
