<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-50">
               <interp inst="t17400116-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-50" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-50" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-50-off239-c322" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-defend437 t17400116-50-off239 t17400116-50-verdict243"></join>
         
               <p>139. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-defend437" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Chapman , alias <rs id="t17400116-50-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-defend437 t17400116-50-alias-5"></join>Johnson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-defend437" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-defend437" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-defend437" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-50-off239" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-off239" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-off239" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing 7 Yards 3 Quarters of Cambrick, value 40 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-50-victim439" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Higgins 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-50-victim439" type="surname" value="Higgins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-50-victim439" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-50-victim439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-off239 t17400116-50-victim439"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-50-cd240" type="crimeDate">January 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-off239 t17400116-50-cd240"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-person440">
                  Mary 
                  Higgins 
               <interp inst="t17400116-50-person440" type="surname" value="Higgins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person440" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person440" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17400116-50-crimeloc241">Lion and Lamb, a little beyond Chancery-Lane End, by Temple-Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-50-crimeloc241" type="placeName" value="Lion and Lamb, a little beyond Chancery-Lane End, by Temple-Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-50-crimeloc241" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-off239 t17400116-50-crimeloc241"></join>, and <rs id="t17400116-50-viclabel242" type="occupation">keep a Linnen-Draper's-Shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-50-victim439 t17400116-50-viclabel242"></join>, on Account of my Husband. I had formerly lost a great many Goods, and hearing somebody in the Shop, I came up out of my Kitchen, which is under the Shop, and seeing a Woman there, with a young Infant in her Arms, I stood upon the Watch, because there was a pretty many Goods on the Counter. The Prisoner was buying some Cambrick, and a Box of Cambricks being by her, I saw her hustle toward it, and throw the child's cloaths over the Box. Then I saw her put her Hand under the child's cloaths, and draw up a Piece of Cambrick, which she kept for 10 Minutes, or a Quarter of an Hour, and then she made off from the counter with it, and asked my Brother Wiseham, who serves in the Shop, for some Nun's Holland. I gave him an Item, that she had stole some Cambrick out of the Box; he, being surpriz'd, told her he had none that would do for her. Upon this she made off with the Piece of Cambrick towards the Door, but seeing me surpriz'd, and that I whispered him, she came back, and dropped the Piece of Cambrick a-cross the Box, which stood 3 if not 4 Yards from the Street-Door. I saw her bring the child to the Box, and saw her drop it; after which she went away, and I was angry with my Brother for not laying hold of her in the Shop, but he went after her, and took her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought 2 Bits of Cambrick, and paid for them.</p>
               <p>Mrs Higgins. Yes, she bought 2 half-quarters, and paid Sixteen-Pence for them; but what she stole, was a whole Piece un-open'd; and she took it up under the child's cloaths, while she was buying the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-person441">
                  William 
                  Wiseham 
               <interp inst="t17400116-50-person441" type="surname" value="Wiseham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person441" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I serve in the Shop: on Friday se'ennight the Prisoner came in, and asked for some Packet-cambrick, of 5 s. a Yard, with a child in her Arms. I fetch'd a Box, and snewed her some; Sir, says she, be so good as to hold the child, while I look at it at the Door; I did so, and we agreed for 4 s. and 6 d. a Yard. I asked her how much she wanted? She told me half a quarter, and I said then she must give me Seven-pence for it. She had the child in her left Hand, and she shov'd some Goods, which were on the counter, farther from the Door, and said, May be, Sir, my child may piss upon them, and damage them. I guess'd what Sort of a Customer I had got, for just such a Woman as she came with a child, a little while ago, and stole 5 Yards of cambrick. I did not cut off the cambrick she had agreed for, for she said she would have finer, and would go to 6 s. a Yard. So I went to an opposite counter, and fetch'd another Box, which I plac'd about a Yard from the Prisoner, on her left-hand, in which were 12 Pieces, 10 within Papers,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160039"></xptr> and 2 without Paper. And as I went toward the Door, to shew her the cambrick, I saw her hand toward the Box, and hearing the rustling of the cambrick under the child's cloaths, I was terrify'd. Then she pointed up to a strip'd Thing, and asked me what it was; and after this she asked for Nun's Holland; but I told her it would be too high for her; and expected her to go out of the Shop with what she had stole, because I thought the Law would have run more against her, if she had carry'd them out of the Shop*. So I waited for her going; but she returned from the Door, and said she would look on the Nun's Holland; and presently she hustled up to the Box, and I heard the rattling of the cambrick upon the Box. Then she went away and said, the Nun's Holland would not do for her. She did not take either of the 2 Pieces which lay uppermost in the Box, without Paper, but had the Art to take a Piece under them, which was paper'd. After she was gone, my Sister bid me go after her, and a Gentleman coming into the Shop, he said he would go too. So we watch'd her into an Alehouse, the Lion and Cat, and took her. I am sure she had the cambrick under the child's cloaths near a Quarter of an Hour, before she dropped it into the Box again.</p>
               <p>* The Witness was mistaken; for removing Goods, with a felonious Intention, though they should not be carried off, is Felony.</p>
               <p>Jury. When you found the cambrick, was it in the Box?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-person442">
                  William 
                  Wiseham 
               <interp inst="t17400116-50-person442" type="surname" value="Wiseham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person442" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found it a-cross the Top of Box. - When she was before the Justice, he knew her, and said, - Are you come again! He said her Name was Johnson, and that she had been transported about a Year and three Quarters ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-person443">
                  Thomas 
                  Wiseham 
               <interp inst="t17400116-50-person443" type="surname" value="Wiseham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person443" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the Prisoner before the Justice, where she did not deny she took the Goods, but only said, they had found nothing upon her. The Justice knew her, and told her so, and that she had been a Notorious Offender. When she was ordered to Newgate, I was forced to go and get a Party of Soldiers, before we could get her thither. I have heard of this very Woman's robbing with a Child, from Mrs Wright in Holborn and several other Shopkeepers, and gave my Brother and Sister a particular Caution about her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-50-person444">
                  Mary 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17400116-50-person444" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person444" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-person444" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had known the Prisoner between 2 and 3 Years, as a good Civil Neighbour in Bloomsbury. <rs id="t17400116-50-verdict243" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-verdict243" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-50-verdict243" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
