<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490405-13">
               <interp inst="t17490405-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-13" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490405-13" type="date" value="17490405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490405-13-off60-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-13-defend97 t17490405-13-off60 t17490405-13-verdict64"></join>
         
               <p>254. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-defend97" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17490405-13-defend97" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-defend97" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-defend97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17490405-13-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490405-13-victim99" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Parker 
                        <interp inst="t17490405-13-victim99" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-13-victim99" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490405-13-victim99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-13-off60 t17490405-13-victim99"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , widow, on the King's high way , for putting her in bodily fear , and taking from her three shillings in money
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490405-13-cd61" type="crimeDate">Jan. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-13-off60 t17490405-13-cd61"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050005"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person100">
                  Sarah 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person100" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person100" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Between the hour of 8 and 9 o' clock at night, on the 13th of January , I was going to <placeName id="t17490405-13-defloc62">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-13-defloc62" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490405-13-defloc62" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-13-defend97 t17490405-13-defloc62"></join> in the stage-coach, going along the high-way beyond the Turnpike, I saw the prisoner mounted on a shabby horse; he had a brown wig on, and handkerchief about his neck; he turned back, rode up to the coach-man, presented a pistol, and ordered him to stand; he came to the same side of the coach I sat on, and demanded my money. I gave him some; he asked me, if it was all ? I told him; it was not; he asked for more, I gave him a thimble, a knife, and some other things; he said, what must he do with that trumpery? and gave it me again; then I gave him all I had.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he be by the coach side?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. About ten minutes, within two yards of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain this is the man?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . The moon shone in his face directly, and I know him to be the man. I am very positive of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him again?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. Yes; as I was going through the Park to Chelsea on foot, he was going into London, and I towards Chelsea; it was between the two centinels boxes, on the Mall, my Mamma was with me, I asked her, if she knew that man? Says she, that is the man that robbed us, &amp;c. We stopped, and looked at him, and he looked back again . We went on to Chelsea. I told the gentleman with me, there we had met such a person .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after this?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. I was along with Mr. Matherson, and saw him again in Jew's Row; I said, there is the man that robbed me. Mr. Matherson said, be sure what you do. I said, he is the man. Says he, here a man's life at stake; he said, get out of the coach, and be fully convinced. I got out , and went towards the prisoner, and asked him, if he knew where Mr. Bates the baker lived? He told me , a little higher. I went from him, and said, if I had not seen the man, I should have known him by his voice. This was Feb. 25.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, what did you remark of him to know him by?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. He has a remarkable look about his eye. When he robbed me he had a white duffel coat on; and he had the same on in the Mall , and the same handkerchief ; and likewise , when we took him, he had the same.</p>
               <p>Cross examined .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the Prisoner before you was robbed ?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How many passengers was in the coach?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . There was my Mamma, myself, a servant maid, and a little master. Mamma and I sat with our faces to the horses; Mamma sat on my right hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side the coach did he come to?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . To my side.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear the prisoner is the person that robbed you?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . My Mamma and I took our oaths he is the person before Justice Ellis.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the colour of his horse?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you see the prisoner in the Park?</p>
               <p>S. Barker . I believe it was betwixt 1 and 2 in the day.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw him on the 25th of February, did you then have him seized?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. A gentleman went for a constable, and took him up in Chelsea then.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. I lived then in King's Road, Chelsea .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person101">
                  Johanna 
                  Frankling 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person101" type="surname" value="Frankling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person101" type="given" value="Johanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I can only repeat the same that has been already said by my daughter, which I am ready to do. On the 13th of January, between the hours of 8 and 9 at night, we were attacked in the coach going to Chelsea ; the prisoner at the bar rid by the coach, and looked in. My daughter said, I wish that man has no ill design upon the coach; he was drinking at the Turnpike, as the coachman told me, when we went by; he rode by us, said I, I wish he would ride slower, and guard the coach; by and by my daughter saw him turn, he rid up to the coach, and, with an oath, demanded her money. She then gave him some things , a thimble, a knife, and some little oranges , with some money. He said, what can I do with these? So, with an oath, gave her them again. I think I heard my daughter say thank'y; he asked her, if that was all? She said, No; two or three times he asked her: At last she said, she had no more; and added, if he doubted it, she would get out of the coach, and he should search her; he felt her hand for rings, and stripped her glove off her hand to see. In the interim I pulled off my glove with my ring in it, to shew him my hand, which I did, and said, you may see I have no ring. He asked me for my money, and the other woman : She said, she had but a few half pence . He asked the young gentleman for his money : Who said , pray don't shoot me, I have no money . After a time, he said to the coachman , you may drive on.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050006"></xptr>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling. I am as sure he is the man, as I am of knowing my own counsel, whom I have known for years.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the coach-window up or down?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Franklin. That on my side was up.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see him so well then?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling. I leaned forward all the while; but I never expected to see him any more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take hold of your hand?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling. He did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe him to take hold of your daughter's hand?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling. I did not see he did; he stripped her glove off her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Barker. Did he take hold of your hand?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a hard or soft hand?</p>
               <p>S. Barker. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. To Mrs. Frankling . Was you before Justice Ellis?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling . Yes, I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you as positive there as you are now, that the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling . Yes, I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you quite certain you was positive then?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling. Upon my word I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have known the prisoner, if your daughter had not been with you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling . Yes, I should.</p>

               <p>Q. How was he dressed then?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Frankling . He had a light-coloured coat on, a coloured handkerchief about his neck, a brown wig, and a very low horse. I made a Memorandum of him when I came home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person102">
                  Charles 
                  Mathewson 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person102" type="surname" value="Mathewson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person102" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went from London to Chelsea on the 25th of Feb. with Mrs. Frankling and Mrs. Barker; all of a sudden Mrs. Barker seem'd to change countenance; says I, what is the matter with you all on a sudden? Says she, Mamma, there is the man that robb'd us; said I, look out of the window, and see: She looked out, and said, that is the man. Says I to Mrs. Frankling, it is a matter of very great concern to take away a man's life. She and her Mother looked at him some minutes, she said, I am sure he is the man. Said I, you are to be certain; you had better get out of the coach , and I'll go along with you. Said she, if I can hear his voice, I shall be more sure, if possible . Said I, I shall not assist you till I find you are sure . She went, and asked him, if he knew where Mr. Bates , a baker , lived? He answered her, somebody else answered her too, and said , you'll see bread in the window. She said, when she was past him, I am sure that is the man; I know it is his voice, who robb'd me. That's all I know.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I was at Sir 
               <persName id="t17490405-13-person103">
                  Hans 
                  Sloane 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person103" type="surname" value="Sloane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person103" type="given" value="Hans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Lodge that evening in company, from about 5 o' clock till 10.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person104">
                  Sarah 
                  Hardy 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person104" type="surname" value="Hardy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person104" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Colonel 
               <persName id="t17490405-13-person105">
                  Du
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person105" type="given" value="Du"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person105" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Mar's in Chelsea: I was in the coach the 13th of Jan. when it was robb'd; I and my young master sat with our backs to the horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a good sight of the man that robb'd you?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy. I could not see him very plain; one of the wooden windows of the coach was drawn up on the left hand side.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it you were stopp'd?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy. It might be about 8 o'clock; St. Clement's clock had struck 7 before we came from the Strand .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the prisoner at the bar is the man?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy. I do not believe he is.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the man that robb'd you say to you?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy . He ask'd me for my money and rings; he felt of both my hands for my rings .</p>
               <p>Q. Upon feeling your hands , had he a hand like the hand of a hard working man, or was it soft ?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy. A very soft one; and, by the light of the moon, seemingly white; I did not take him to be a working man. I said before Justice Ellis, when the prisoner was taken up, I could not swear he was the man; and I do not now think he is the man; the same I told the Justice then: The man that robb'd us was with us about ten minutes. I did not hear him swear at all. I think the man that robb'd the coach was not so lusty .</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd ?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy . He had on a light duffel coat , almost new, and a dark brown wig.</p>
               <p>Cross examined .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his face that robb'd the coach?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy. I saw but one side of his face.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it for matter of light?</p>
               <p>S. Hardy . It was pretty light.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person106">
                  Thomas 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person106" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person106" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was in the coach on the 13th of Jan. when it was robb'd, I sat on the side the man came , with my back to the horses: I was frighten'd so I could not make great observations ; but I really think the prisoner at the bar is not the person that robb'd the coach .</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know the man were you to see him?</p>
               <p>Hunt . I think I should; he did not take any thing from me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904050007"></xptr>Q. Did you hear him swear?</p>
               <p>Hunt . He damn'd the coachman once, saying: Damn you, can't you stop?</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd?</p>
               <p>Hunt . In a white duffel coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with the prisoner before Justice Ellis?</p>
               <p>Hunt . Yes; and I said there, I did not believe he was the man that robb'd the coach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Hunt. Yes; he <rs id="t17490405-13-deflabel63" type="occupation">kept a public-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490405-13-defend97 t17490405-13-deflabel63"></join> going down to Ranelaugh : I have known him these six or seven years: I had sight enough of the man that committed the robbery, to have known him, had it been the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Cross examined .</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was his wig, that robb'd the coach?</p>
               <p>Hunt. I cannot say as to his wig.</p>
               <p>Q. What had he about his neck?</p>
               <p>Hunt . I cannot say as to that, his hat was put down a little.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you sworn at Justice Ellis's ?</p>
               <p>Hunt . I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person107">
                  Geo 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person107" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person107" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drove the coach that day: I am the owner of it. I have known the prisoner at least seven years; there were but few days, these three or four last years past, but I have seen him two or three times a day. I verily believe he is not the man that robb'd the coach. I am positive he is not the man. I had a view of the face of him that robb'd the coach for a little time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his voice like the prisoner's?</p>
               <p>Clark. It was not. I told Justice Ellis I believed the prisoner was not the man; and that he was a man of a fair character; I cannot say I know the guilty person; but I am satisfied this is not he.</p>
               <p>Cross examined .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never make any declarations you knew the man that robb'd the coach?</p>
               <p>Clark. The last time my coach was robbed was the 24th of February last. One person I believe robbed it three times: Then his horse was very much tired. When I came home, I said , I had been robbed again; and , I added, I would have been hanged if I could not have brought him into that place in an hour's time. That man , who robbed the coach , was no way so big as the prisoner, nor his voice, nor manner of behaviour . My coach has not been robbed since Mudget was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person108">
                  Charles 
                  Shafaley 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person108" type="surname" value="Shafaley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person108" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the prisoner these twelve years , and believe him to be a very honest man. I am a Waterman and Lighterman: On the 13th of January I brought some oil up by water, about 4 o'clock in the afternoon, for Sir 
               <persName id="t17490405-13-person109">
                  Hans 
                  Sloane 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person109" type="surname" value="Sloane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person109" type="given" value="Hans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I had a pot of hot in the Lodge, and the prisoner came in; he came in before five.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know to swear to that very day?</p>
               <p>Shafaley . I have a receipt in my pocketbook makes me remember the day: It was for Mr. Bockam and Mr. Pain. When I bring any thing to Sir Hans, the Porter, upon my delivering it, gives me a receipt: It was shewed in Court. After I had drank the hot pot, I went away. At six I came again, and I saw the prisoner at the bar there: I continued there, with him and others, till the bell rung nine; then I was upon going. I left the prisoner, and Mr. Pain, and Mr. Abott. Mr. King went away about eight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person110">
                  Raimont 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person110" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person110" type="given" value="Raimont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am porter to Sir 
               <persName id="t17490405-13-person111">
                  Hans 
                  Sloane 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person111" type="surname" value="Sloane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person111" type="given" value="Hans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Chelsea, I have known the Prisoner about seven years, his character is as good as any man's in Chelsea; I was in company with him on Friday the 13th of January with Mr. Abott, Mr. Squire, Mr. King and Mr. Shafaley , he came into our lodge about 5 o'clock in the afternoon, and I am sure he continued there 'till ten that night .</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember the day so positively?</p>
               <p>Pain. I remember it from this; on the 12th we were invited to the Magpye to supper, I left the Prisoner with others in the Lodge, I went and stay'd 'till ten o'clock; Mr. Abott had been paying some money to the window. Before they left my lodge they took down my bed, and took off one of the sheets, and doubled that one up so that I could not go to bed without shoving that down before my feet into the bed, and the next day the 13th, they came again, and I examined them about their playing that trick with my bed; and then Mr. Shafaley bringing the oil and minuting it down in my pocket-book, [which was shewed .] I always enter things down in this book as I pay for them, from these things I well remember the night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490405-13-person112">
                  Anthony 
                  Abott 
               <interp inst="t17490405-13-person112" type="surname" value="Abott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person112" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was in company with the two last witnesses and the prisoner at the bar that very night; the prisoner and I went away together about ten o'clock at night, and he was with me from before four o'clock: first we were at the Magpye, then we went to Sir Hans Sloane's lodge, and there we formed the company drinking the pot of Hot.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490405-13-verdict64" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490405-13-verdict64" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
