<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440113-4">
               <interp inst="t17440113-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-4" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-4" type="date" value="17440113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440113-4-off18-c51" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-defend60 t17440113-4-off18 t17440113-4-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>+ 106. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440113-4-defend60" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Eales 
                  <interp inst="t17440113-4-defend60" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-defend60" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-defend60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17440113-4-defloc17">St. Sepulchre's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-4-defloc17" type="placeName" value="St. Sepulchre's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-4-defloc17" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-defend60 t17440113-4-defloc17"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440113-4-off18" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-off18" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-off18" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 113 yards of Irish linen , value 7 l. 32 yards of German linen, value 50 s. fifteen yards of cambrick, value 3 l. 41 yards of printed linen, value 2 l. 10 s. 48 yards of printed cotton, value 4 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440113-4-victim62" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Hodges 
                        <interp inst="t17440113-4-victim62" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-4-victim62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-4-victim62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-off18 t17440113-4-victim62"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440113-4-cd19" type="crimeDate">July 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-off18 t17440113-4-cd19"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-4-person63">
                  George 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17440113-4-person63" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person63" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the King's Arms and Key in Cheapside, I have employed the Prisoner as a <rs id="t17440113-4-deflabel20" type="occupation">porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-defend60 t17440113-4-deflabel20"></join> these three years, on the 5th of July 1742, I delivered a truss to him myself, to carry to a carrier.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what goods were in that truss?</p>
               <p>Hodges. I have a memorandum of them here.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that memorandum taken from?</p>
               <p>Hodges . This is a copy that was taken from my day book.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver them with your own hands to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hodges . I delivered them to him with my own hands .</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the truss?</p>
               <p>Hodges. There were some ribbons, &amp;c. which are not in the indictment; five pieces of white Irish linen, 113 yards; one piece of long lawn, which is called 32 yards of German linen; two pieces of cambrick; two pieces of printed linen; and two pieces of printed cotton.</p>
               <p>Q. What were these goods stitched up in?</p>
               <p>Hodges . They were stitched up in what we call hessen .</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Prisoner ordered to carry them?</p>
               <p>Hodges . He was to carry them to the Red Lion in Aldersgate-Street, they were directed to Robert Shepherd, of Donnington .</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before you missed the goods?</p>
               <p>Hodges . It might be from a fortnight to a month, I cannot be certain, My correspondent wrote to me to know whether I had sent him the goods, and if I had, how he might come at them. I spoke to the Prisoner, and asked him concerning them: he said he had entered them in his book, (for I did not suffer him to scribble in my journal ) and that he had delivered them as I had ordered him; and I thought he was out of fault, and gave directions to sue the person he delivered them to; but having some farther information, I got a search warrant and went to Mr. Ferguson's in Barbican . and found some of my goods there, and Mr. Ferguson was so honest that he searched all his house, and sent me some goods that I could not have found.</p>
               <p>- [The goods were produced by Mr. Hodges , and proved to be his property.]</p>
               <p>Eliz. Eales . The Prisoner at the bar is my brother-in-law, my husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17440113-4-person64">
                  Thomas 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17440113-4-person64" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person64" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , he lives in Long-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Prisoner's bringing any goods to you, packed up?</p>
               <p>Eales . Yes, - it was to the best of my knowledge stitched up, he left it in my kitchen, and desired it might be carried up stairs, and in a few days he came again and said he wanted to speak with me; he came up stairs and said I must do a thing for him or else he was ruined for ever - he belonged to the fire-office; he said he had pawned his coat and badge, and if I did not pawn some things for him, he should be ruined for ever; so he took a knife out of his pocket, cut open the parcel, and took out some things. - the first things he took, to the best of my knowledge, were two pieces of printed linen, he put them into my apron and I went and pawned them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you carry them?</p>
               <p>Eales. I carried them into Barbican. I do not know the gentleman's name, it went by the name of Stone - I carried them at several times, one was a very beautiful piece, I can stand to that piece.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you carried that piece there?</p>
               <p>Eales. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. What money had you the first time?</p>
               <p>Eales. I had two guineas the first time - I cannot tell how many times I went.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money had you in the whole?</p>
               <p>Eales . I cannot tell - to the best of my knowledge it was about seven pounds .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with all this money, be it more or less?</p>
               <p>Eales . He had it all. I pawned the things by his direction.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174401130005"></xptr>Eales. I was entrusted with all the goods; my sister is guilty of perjury; I would scorn to tell a lie if I was sure to die for it. I had no more than one guinea. - I have nothing more to say than only to prove her perjured.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-4-person65">
                  William 
                  Cadwallader 
               <interp inst="t17440113-4-person65" type="surname" value="Cadwallader"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person65" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Ferguson , 
               <persName id="t17440113-4-person66">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Eales 
               <interp inst="t17440113-4-person66" type="surname" value="Eales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person66" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought all these goods to me at different times.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money had she of you?</p>
               <p>Cadwallader. I believe in the whole she had nine pound.</p>
               <p>Q. to Eales. Did the Prisoner live with you?</p>
               <p>Eales. No, he did not live with me, he lived in Ivy-lane.</p>
               <p>Q Where are your witnesses, you said you would prove this woman perjured.</p>
               <p>Pris. I was to carry these goods to the inn to go by Robinson and it was not his week, it was Drury's week, and I carried them to my brother's house till the next week came. I told her I wanted a guinea and she refused it me, and my brother denied it me, I speak with as much truth and justice as if I was before the god of heaven, that she pawned the things, and converted them to her own use.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Eales. I did it all by his desire, and he had the whole money if there's belief in a Christian.</p>
               <p>Prison. You are a wicked liar, how can you tell such a story you lying wicked jade. <rs id="t17440113-4-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-verdict21" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17440113-4-punish22" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-4-punish22" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-4-defend60 t17440113-4-punish22"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
