<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-22">
               <interp inst="t17400227-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-22" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-22" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-22-off128-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-22-defend226 t17400227-22-off128 t17400227-22-verdict130"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-22-off128-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-22-defend228 t17400227-22-off128 t17400227-22-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>176, 177. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-22-defend226" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend226" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend226" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-22-defend228" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Hill 
                  <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend228" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend228" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-defend228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17400227-22-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, val. 4 l. 10 s. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-22-victim230" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Grey 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-22-victim230" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-22-victim230" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-22-victim230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-22-off128 t17400227-22-victim230"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17400227-22-cd129" type="crimeDate">Jan. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-22-off128 t17400227-22-cd129"></join>.</p>
               <p>Alexander Grey . On the 14th of January, I came from Blackwall , and about 10 o'Clock at Night, I was coming up the Minories, and asked Robinson the Way to Aldgate. She asked me if I was not a Yorkshire Man , I told her yes, and that I came from Scarborough . She said, she came from Whitby , and after some Talk, she asked me to make her drink. I let her know I had no more than 5 d. in my Pocket , but I would give her a Pint of Beer, and accordingly we went in at Mr Goodchild's , and while we were drinking , Hill came in. I was not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270020"></xptr> above 10 Minutes in their Company, but in that Time Robinson picked the Watch out of my Pocket, either at the Door, or in the House, and then they both went off directly. On Thursday the 17th, (between Eleven and Twelve at Noon ) I found the two Prisoners a-bed in their Lodgings, according to the Directions they gave me while I was drinking with them. They deny'd the Fact, and I could not get a Constable, nor a Warrant for them, till the Monday following, and then their Landlady, an Irish Woman, told me they were gone over the Water. But in a Week's Time (the Monday following) I got a Constable and took them, and they were a-bed together then likewise. Robinson got out of Bed, and hit me a good Slap in the Face, and ask'd me whether I had the Impudence to charge her with taking my Watch? But when we got them to the Door, she told me if I would give her something to drink, she would let me have it again. So I went in and treated them with a Bottle of Wine mull'd; and then she told me her Landlady had pawned it for a Guinea to the Man I bought it of; tho' when I went to enquire after it, I found it had been pawn'd for 30 s. When they were before Justice Dennet, they confess'd every Thing, and the Justice said he would be here, and bring their Confession. The Man they pawn'd the Watch to is here: he has got it; but I know it again, there's E D in the inside Case, and was made by Freeman. This is the Watch; and Hill confess'd she had part of the Money it was pawn'd for.</p>
               <p>Robinson. He gave me the Watch to raise Money, because he had none, and Hill carry'd it to pawn. When she returned, he gave us half a Guinea a-piece.</p>
               <p>Gray. Upon my Oath I did not, I did not give it them to raise Money. I was told this would be the Story when I came here. I am positive Robinson was the Woman that took it, for the other was never near me. While we were drinking in the House, I pulled it out to see what o'Clock it was, after which I did not stay a Minute, but went to the Door and missed it immediately. Both <rs id="t17400227-22-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-22-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
