<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17491209-6">
               <interp inst="t17491209-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-6" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17491209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-6" type="date" value="17491209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491209-6-off44-c83" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-6-defend97 t17491209-6-off44 t17491209-6-verdict46"></join>
         
               <p>7. 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-defend97" type="defendantName">
                  Earret 
                  Lawler 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-defend97" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-defend97" type="given" value="Earret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-defend97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for that he together with 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person98">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person98" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person98" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not yet taken, <rs id="t17491209-6-cd43" type="crimeDate">Dec. the 27th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-6-off44 t17491209-6-cd43"></join>, <rs id="t17491209-6-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               about the hour of 10 in the night on the same day , the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17491209-6-victim100" type="victimName">
                           Adam 
                           Stewards 
                        <interp inst="t17491209-6-victim100" type="surname" value="Stewards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-6-victim100" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-6-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-6-off44 t17491209-6-victim100"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, taking from thence one pistol mounted with silver , val. 30 s. one pistol mounted with brass, 2 hangers mounted with silver, one silver hilted sword , val. 30 s. one brussels head, val. 3 l. one velvet cloak, val . 40 s. 7 silver spoons, val. 30 s. one silver cream-pot, val. 12 s. and other things
            </rs>, the goods of the said 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person101">
                  Adam 
                  Stewards 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person101" type="surname" value="Stewards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person101" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person102">
                  Adam 
                  Stewards 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person102" type="surname" value="Stewards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person102" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of Dec. my house was broke open. I live <placeName id="t17491209-6-crimeloc45">in Holborn, at the Ship and Sheers</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17491209-6-crimeloc45" type="placeName" value="in Holborn, at the Ship and Sheers"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17491209-6-crimeloc45" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-6-off44 t17491209-6-crimeloc45"></join>; my wife and I went out between 6 and 7 o'clock to sup with a neighbour, I return'd again about a quarter before 11, and found the door broke all to pieces, I believe it flew in a hundred pieces, the street door was left open for the lodgers, it was an entry door, but the door that was broke was out of the entry, opening into my parlour, which I left double locked.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the goods taken from ?</p>
               <p>Stewards. Some out of the parlour, and some out of the shop; there were six or eight coats and a laced waistcoat taken out of the glass case; I lost a silver mounted pistol, 2 silver mounted hangers, one silver mounted sword, these were taken out of the shop; in the passage of the shop there is a shelf where I put my fustians, I lost two pieces, one piece measured 20 yards, the other 24. I lost some, shirts, but I don't know the number, one brussels head, lappets, caul and ruffles, one velvet cloak, and one scarlet cloak not made up, 7 silver spoons, one silver punch ladle, and one silver cream pot. In July, some people came to me, and said there was a man taken up for a robbery over the water, who in confessing what robbery he had been guilty of, owned he was an accomplice in this; I went to Justice Clark, and told him what I had lost, the justice told me the man had made a confession of it, which person was 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person103">
                  John 
                  Bowen 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person103" type="surname" value="Bowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next witness; these two pistols are all the goods I have seen since, they were found by Mr. Hughs, who was robb'd by Supple and Mackey in Surry, who on searching the house of one 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person104">
                  James 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person104" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person104" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Dicks shore, where Moll Blare was taken, he found them concealed in a chest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person105">
                  John 
                  Bowen 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person105" type="surname" value="Bowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is he of?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060008"></xptr>Bowen. Picking of pockets and house-breaking, is all I know of. On the 27th of Dec. last, the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person106">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person106" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person106" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I, went out of Drury-Lane on purpose of lift up latches and sash-windows, to see what we could steal from thence. With this intent we went to the upper end of Drury-Lane, and turn'd, and went down towards Holborn, a pretty way down on the left hand side of the way; we thought it too late to go on what they call the evening sneak, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person107">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person107" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person107" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             open'd a street door and went in, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person108">
                  Garret 
                  Lawler 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person108" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person108" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went in after him, and I stood at the door to give the watch word; there was a door to an inward room, but they could not make the lock fly, they called to me, and I went in, and then we could not do it, we had lik'd to have broke the partition, the people called out, and we thought they were coming upo n us, we went out, and went a little higher up, Carter lifted up a latch and went in, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person109">
                  Garret 
                  Lawler 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person109" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person109" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             passed by, and I stood at the door to give the watch word; Lawler presently came back, then he went in, they saw no light, nor heard any noise, and finding a door in, the passage that was lock'd, they called me in, and I put my shoulder and hands to it, and we forc'd the pannel in, and drove a hole through the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Bowen. A little after 9 o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this was the Prosecutor's house?</p>
               <p>Bowen. I did not know till I saw the advertisement in the news. As soon as we had made the pannel fly, we all three of us listened, and found no one heard us, then we all of us went in again, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person110">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person110" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person110" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             stood to see if any body came upon us, I went and got a light in a little dark lanthorn, and all three of us went in and shut too the outward door, then the Prisoner and Carter went in through the hole of the door with the candle, they drew away some of the splinters to get in through the hole; there was a chest of drawers on the right hand side, which the Prisoner opened, Carter goes to a corner cupboard, the Prisoner brought several ruffles, 5 or 6 men's shirts, borders for caps, 2 or 3 stone buttons set in silver, and an old silver stud, a tortoiseshell snuff-box, and 7 s. in money. Says the Prisoner, see that I don't sink upon you, then Carter was fumbling about a looking-glass, said I, don't take it down, you can't hand it through the door, then he handed me a silver punch ladle, and a tea chest; then they turn'd round upon the left-hand side, and 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person111">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person111" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person111" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brings me 2 hangers, 2 small swords, and 3 pistols. one had either a dog's head, or a lyon's head at the end of it. I'll swear this is the very pistol, taking up such a one that lay by him, which the Prosecutor had swore too as his property. We took 3 pistols, then the Prisoner brings me 2 pieces of fustian, a black velvet cloak, and a small remnant, I believe it was a pattern for a cloak; then he goes back again, and brings me 6 men's coats; then they came out through the hole of the door, there was a scarlet waistcoat trimm'd with gold lace lay without sleeves, I took all these things out of the hole of the door, when we took the things, I had most of them wrapp'd up, and I strove to open the street-door, but could not, being fastened. I said somebody had put a trick upon us, the Prisoner said, he would go round and open the shop door, then I knew it to be a shop, then George Carter came and opened the door, and out we went, then we went down Drury-Lane. We carried them to Jemmy Field's up one pair of stairs, then the Prisoner nor Carter would not sell them; Lawler said he wanted a shirt, the other said he wanted another, said he, I'll have a shirt too, so we drew lots, and it sell to my lot to take the first choice, while I was chusing my shirt, Carter tries on the gold laced waistcoat, said he, I'll have this, and the next thing that we get which you like you shall have; the pistols, the tea-chest and the swords lay upon the table, said they at last to me, do you sell them: 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person112">
                  Margaret 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person112" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person112" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ask'd me what I would have for them, I answer'd eight guineas, said she, I'll give you 3, then she bid us 4, I said, we'll go try elsewhere; when we were going down stairs, she called and said I'll give you 5, this was for the cloaths and all, exclusive of the pistols.</p>
               <p>Q What is become of her?</p>
               <p>Bowen. I have transported her upon my information; then her husband came up, and I sold the 2 pistols to him for two guineas, we lost one pistol in going there; the whole was 7 guineas, which we divided amongst us three, we had 51 shillings a-piece, and to the odd shilling she was a shilling, so we had a bottle of wine, then she was 6 d. to our 6 d. a piece, so we had another bottle.</p>

               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been acquainted with this man.</p>
               <p>Bowen. Two or three months.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you discover this sooner.</p>
               <p>Bowen. Two or three months?</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you discover this sooner?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060009"></xptr>Bowen. I would have done it, but I could neither write nor read; and did not know which way to go about it; and they told me if I would not divulge any thing, I should make myself in time.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in Prison that very time in Ireland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person113">
                  Lawrence 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person113" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person113" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came from Dublin about five months ago to work, the prisoner and I were Prisoners together in the Marshalsea prison in Dublin in Ireland; he came in there fourteen nights before Christmas, I went out the latter end of January.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in that Gaol the 28th of December, in 1748.</p>
               <p>Savage. He was my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live now?</p>
               <p>Savage. In St. James's market, I am a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you land, and at what time?</p>
               <p>Savage. At Parkgate in the beginning of June.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you never here in your life before?</p>
               <p>Savage. I had a brother that went to sea, and I came to see after ne prize money of his.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you know the Prisoner, before you were prisoners together ?</p>
               <p>Savage. I knew him five years before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Bowen before?</p>
               <p>Savage. I never did in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bowen. Do you know this witness?</p>
               <p>Bowen. I never saw him in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Savage. How came you to be so certain as to the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Savage. The Man that put him in gaol, was an acquaintance of mine?</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman is he?</p>
               <p>Savage. He was born in Dublin, I never know him out of Dublin in my life, before he was brought here.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to find you out, to come and give your testimony upon this affair?</p>
               <p>Savage. I heard some of our neighbours speaking of it, that there were several men brought over, and one Lawler was with them.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you any conversation with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Savage. About a month before I left Dublin.</p>
               <p>Q. Since you came to England, when had you conversation with him.</p>
               <p>Savage. I never heard any thing about it, till within a fortnight ago, I went voluntary to him in Newgate, and told him I would be of service to him, upon which he subpoena'd me here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know before such time, when and upon what account the fact was charged against him.</p>
               <p>Savage. I did not, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Who acquainted you with the time of the year the fact was supposed to be done ?</p>
               <p>Savage. I heard of it, and I know he was in gaol in December, that is all I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to him, and say, I hear you you are to be tried, and I can be of service to you?</p>
               <p>Savage. I went to him about three weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you of his being in Gaol?</p>
               <p>Savage. A young fellow, a chairman.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he here ?</p>
               <p>Savage. No my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person114">
                  Thomas 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person114" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person114" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came over with the keeper of Newgate in Dublin, to guard the prisoner and others here to England.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of the Prisoners being in the Marshalsea prison in Ireland?</p>
               <p>Stanley. I left him there about a fortnight, or three weeks before Christmas last: I was the officer who arrested him fourteen or fifteen days before Christmas, and carried him in there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to see him there frequently after.</p>
               <p>Stanley. I saw him there for almost every day, for I believe five or six weeks, I have been there three or four times in a day. I arrested him in a suit of a person who kept a public house; with my lord Mayor's warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. For how much money?</p>
               <p>Stanley. For 5 or 6 and 30 s.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you bring him here ?</p>
               <p>Stanley. the first day of the last sessions.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say the prisoner remained more than a month in that Prison, for that debt.</p>
               <p>Stanley. I am sure he did my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. About what time was he discharged?</p>
               <p>Stanley. I believe in about two months time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him there, after he came out ?</p>
               <p>Stanley. I did my Lord.</p>
               <p>Acquitted.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted, for that he together with 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person115">
                  John 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person115" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (not yet taken) on the 27th of Dec. about the hour of one in the night of the same day, did break and enter the dwelling house of 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person116">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person116" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person116" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and steal, take, and carry away, 140 yards of holland, value 8 l. two petticoats, value 5 s. the Goods of the said 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person117">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person117" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person117" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060010"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person118">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person118" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person118" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bow-street, Convent Garden, my wife is a hoop-petticoat maker, my house was brook open the 27th of December, betwixt the hour of 12 and 1, in the morning, there is a street door that opens to a passage, and my shop door which opens into that passage, was burst open, and in a glass case on the other side the shop facing the door, they took out several pieces of hooping hollands, and several remnants, to the amount of upwards of 140 yds. We found some of the goods again, upon searching the house of one 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person119">
                  James 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person119" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person119" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Dick's shore, Limehouse.</p>
               <p>Mary Jones I am wife to the prosecutor on the 26 of Dec. I went to bed with both my servants, much about twelve at night, I fastened the door myself, it was bolted with a large broad bolt; I believe it was not locked: a little before two o'clock, a chairman that lives in the back yard knocked at my door, and said, do you know your shop door is open; I got up and went in and found the staple of the door was flew to the other side of the shop: I found the glass case broke, and every thing ransacked; and the till taken out : There were missing 9 pieces of holland, about 130 or 140 yards, with some remnants taken away; I saw them there on the Monday in the evening : We met with some of them about three weeks before the last sessions, at one 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person120">
                  James 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person120" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person120" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, a sort of a broker at Dick's Shore, Limehouse; here is about 130 yards I took from them, in court.</p>
               <p>Q. What induced you to go there for them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. Mr. Stewards who was robbed the same night, about 2 or 3 hours before by the same people, had been there to search for his things, and sent me word, there were a large parcel of hoopping hollands in this house, then I went to justice Bury's and got a search warrant, and found these hollands, and know them to be mine, but I don't know who they received them from.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person121">
                  Adam 
                  Stewards 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person121" type="surname" value="Stewards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person121" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Jones's house, at Dick's Shore, the 27th of Sept. last, searching for my goods, I found my two pistols there, and saw these other goods in a box, I sent Mrs. Jones word of them, knowing she had lost such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-6-person122">
                  John 
                  Bowen 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person122" type="surname" value="Bowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person122" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner at the bar I was acquainted with him, about 6 or 7 weeks, before the 27th of Dec. last; on that day, he the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person123">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person123" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person123" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I were drinking together at Jemmy Fields, in Drury Lane; about 12 at night of the 26th, 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person124">
                  Garret 
                  Lawler 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person124" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person124" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went out to make water, and came in again, and said to us, I think it is a fine night to go out upon the mill, that is what they call house-breaking, he asked 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person125">
                  George 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person125" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person125" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, if we were willing to go We all three agreed, we went a little way up Drury-lane, the first turning on the left hand side, of the way we turned down, till we came to Mr. Jones's house, next door or next door but one, to the brown bear. Then Garret Lawler lifted up the latch of the street door, and went in; he found another door on the right hand side, there was a brass knob on the inward door; he and Carter tried to open it, but they could not, then they bid me come in, which I did; then we all three thrust our shoulders against the door, and made the lock fly, or else drew the staple; however, the door flew open: we then left Carter at the door, and Lawler and I got a light, when we came back, they two went into the shop, and I stood at the door; there was a counter fronting the door, and a glass case on the other side of it; they went and opened this glass case, and took out six or seven pieces of check stuff, they call'd it holland; they gave me several remnants, and we had each of us a load; then we went up the street again, and came back to Jemmy Fields house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you think you broke open this shop ?</p>
               <p>Bowen. A little after one o'clock, we carried the goods into a room where we all laid that night, it was my lodging; the next morning when it was day light, Field's wife came up and over haul'd them, and said she could not put them off: we asked her six pounds for them, she bid us three guineas; we agreed for that; I dont know how they came to Jones's house at Limehouse; I know Field and Jones, had used to trade together; there was a gang and a guard of us used to use the Fox in Drury lane, just as the candles are lighted, they all meet there together; four or five set in one box, and two or three in another,; and entitle themselves the Family Men; they don't care what it cost them, or what they swear, to save one another's lives.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever on such enterprizes with the Prisoner after this ?</p>
               <p>Bowen I was not; but I have been with Carter since.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. The same as in the former trial.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060011"></xptr>Stanley, and 
               <persName id="t17491209-6-person126">
                  Lawrence 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17491209-6-person126" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person126" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . D'posed the same as before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17491209-6-verdict46" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-6-verdict46" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The latter was taken into custody, as soon as the Jury had given in their verdict; on suspicion of robbing a Person of a watch.</p>
            </div1>
