<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17491209-64">
               <interp inst="t17491209-64" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-64" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-64" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17491209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-64" type="date" value="17491209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491209-64-off288-c345" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-defend480 t17491209-64-off288 t17491209-64-verdict291"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491209-64-off292-c345" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-defend480 t17491209-64-off292 t17491209-64-verdict291"></join>
         
               <p>79. 
               
                  <persName id="t17491209-64-defend480" type="defendantName">
                     Nicholas 
                     Fagan 
                  <interp inst="t17491209-64-defend480" type="surname" value="Fagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-defend480" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-defend480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he being a disorderly person, and of a wicked disposition, not regarding the laws and statutes of this realm, or the Pains and Penalties therein contained, did on the <rs id="t17491209-64-cd287" type="crimeDate">16th of Oct</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off288 t17491209-64-cd287"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off292 t17491209-64-cd287"></join>. <rs id="t17491209-64-off288" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-off288" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-off288" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               in the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17491209-64-victim482" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Wright 
                        <interp inst="t17491209-64-victim482" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-64-victim482" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-64-victim482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off288 t17491209-64-victim482"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off292 t17491209-64-victim482"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17491209-64-viclabel289" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-victim482 t17491209-64-viclabel289"></join>; with a pistol loaded with gunpowder and lead, did shoot at the said Robert, with intent the said Robert to kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-64-person483">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17491209-64-person483" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person483" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17491209-64-crimeloc290">Rathbourn Place, Soho-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17491209-64-crimeloc290" type="placeName" value="Rathbourn Place, Soho-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17491209-64-crimeloc290" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off288 t17491209-64-crimeloc290"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-64-off292 t17491209-64-crimeloc290"></join>. On the 16th of October last, I came home about eight o'clock in the evening, and Mr. Clitron came to sup with me; a little after I had been in, I heard two knocks at my door, and as I expected one 
               <persName id="t17491209-64-person484">
                  Robert 
                  Nelson 
               <interp inst="t17491209-64-person484" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person484" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to come to supper, said I, that is certainly Bob's knock, I will open the door myself; I had my night gown, cap, and slippers on; as soon as I had opened the door to him, I said, he could finest when supper is ready, as soon as that was said, the Prisoner at the bar rushed in upon me, and struck me with a butcher's steel, on that I seized the steel and took it from him, then others rushed in; I can sware to upwards of three, there was one of them a lasty fellow that beat me prodigiously; so that I was obliged to let the Prisoner go, and the other and I fell down with our heads against the street-door; as soon as I was down, I called out to Mr. Clifton, to desire him to bring me any pistols, telling him that they lay on a marble slab in the parlour, Mr. Clifton had then I believe got into the entry; hearing this noise in an instant, before I could disongage myself<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060022"></xptr> from the man I was down with; the Prisoner came to the parlour door, and fired a pistol against me; I was just rising up at that time; immediately another pistol went off; there were a pair of pistols which I had loaded myself, four or five days before with gunpowder, and leaden balls cut to pieces; I had prim'd them that morning, and tried them and found them loaded; I saw Mr. Clifton fall at the second firing, and thought he had been killed; I said, Mr. Cliffton was killed, I did not see the pistol leveled at him; said the Prisoner with a great Oath I'll soon dispatch you, he cut my neck with a drawn hanger, as soon as I had received this cut, some of my neighbours got in at my parlow windows and came to my assistance, they called out they had taken one of them, which was the Prisoner: The bullets are now sticking in the door; my head lay against the street door, while I was down; there was some Person unknown to me striking with an iron crow at the door, I believe; for some of the marks tally with it exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what were the reason of their coming into your house ?</p>
               <p>Wright. I have my Wives brother at my house who is a lunatick; the Prisoner told me that very night, at the black horse, he was hired to arrest my brother, and take him away at all events, whom he called the madmen, or else to murder me, and that he was to have three guineas, and Phillips 40, for doing it; of my wife. I was then taking out a commission of lunacy against my brother in law.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was sitting with you in the parlour ?</p>
               <p>Wright. Mr. Clifton and a young woman, one Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17491209-64-person485">
                  Mary 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17491209-64-person485" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person485" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person485" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not been to Clifford's Inn, to know if there was an Action out against your brother-in-law ?</p>
               <p>Wright. No Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you make use of such an expression as this my dear, now fire: to somebody.</p>
               <p>Wright. I did not. They were my pistols that were fired.</p>
               <p>Q. How could the prisoner get at these pistols in the parlour ?</p>
               <p>Wright. I was on the ground, and it is impossible to say how he got them, the door was open; when I was getting up my face was towards the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Clifton and Mrs. Wright come out to your assistance ?</p>
               <p>Wright. I never saw her. Mr. Cliffton came out and was knock'd down instantly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has this your wife's brother been with you ?</p>
               <p>Wright. About 5 months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a particular stratagem use d to get him to your house?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, not at all. I went down to Mr. Brown's house with a cheese, and took him back with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this Mrs. Wright fire a pistol?</p>
               <p>Wright. I verily believe not; the first pistol was fired when Mr. Cliffton was in the fray, the other after he was knock'd down; the Prisoner was standing up when I was shot at.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him shoot?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, as plain as I now see your lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. How high did the balls go into the door?</p>
               <p>Wright. About five foot and a half</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the gentleman come to the parlour door, and present a pistol to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wright. I never saw such a thing, the pistols are here in court, one is loaded and the other is not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There was no light at all, the candles were blown out.</p>
               <p>Wright. When I went out of the parlour, there were two candles standing on the table, and a large fire of wood and coals together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-64-person486">
                  William 
                  Cliffton 
               <interp inst="t17491209-64-person486" type="surname" value="Cliffton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person486" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Mr. Wright's parlour when some body knock'd at the door, and he went himself to the door and opened it; then came in Mr. Nelson, and I heard a great bustle in the passage. I took the candle and went in a hurry to see what it was, I found three or four people, I cannot say how many; and Mr. Nelson standing with his back against she parlour door, and Mr. Wright down, I had no weapon at all, I took hold of one that was upon Mr. Wright and pull'd him off, and immediately I receiv'd a blow on my shoulder, and another on my breast, and I fell; the instant that I fell, a pistol went off, there was not a second between; as I fell, I saw the firing from the street door way: the passage is about two yards long before you come to the parlour door, which turns in on the left-hand side, I fell close by the parlour door, and these people were in the passage betwixt the street door and the parlour door; the parlour door stood a jarr, and the ball made a hole in the parlour door which opens inwards: I arose and slept into the parlour, I found the boy there, I bid him open the study door and get out at the window and alarm the neighbours, I went out to another house and cry'd murder.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the street door open in the time of this fray ?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. I think it was half open.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave Mrs. Wright in the parlour?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. Yes, I did sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when Mr. Wright call'd for his pistols.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174912060023"></xptr>Cliffton. I was just got into the passage; hearing a disturbance there before he mentioned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was your face when the pistol went off?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. Towards the street-door, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear two pistols go off?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. I heard but one, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any body say, my dear, fire?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you take upon you to say, a pistol was not let off in the parlour?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. The pistol was fired from towards the street-door, the parlour door was half open, it open'd inwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the candle alight in the parlour?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. When I returned, the light was out.</p>

               <p>Q. Who fetched those pistols out of the parlour?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner, or any of his company in the parlour?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. No, I did not, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the distance betwixt the marble slab and the parlour door?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. I believe betwixt 3 and 4 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there any marks in the street-door with the pieces of bullets ?</p>
               <p>Cliffton. There are many marks with an iron crow in it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I was an assistant belonging to the Marshalsea-Court; I went along with Mr. Phillips an officer, to arrest Mr. Price; we watch'd an opportunity of seeing the door open; there came a gentleman to the door and knock'd, thinks I, this is the best opportunity we can have; imagined he was in the parlour, so we thought proper to make a push in after the gentleman; Mr. Wright's foot-boy shutting the door, we push'd before he could shut it too; the boy cry'd out, I saw Mr. Wright coming from out of the parlour, said I, I have got a writ against Mr. Price, and we are come to serve it: the next person I saw was the young gentlewoman, with a pistol in her hand, standing half-way out of the parlour door; it was levelled at me, she was within a yard and half of me; I defended myself, and took hold of the pistol, and in the struggle betwixt her and me, the pistol went off, I held it so that it should do no damage; then I received a blow on my arm, then the candles were blow'd out, I did not then know it was Mr. Wright I had hold on, but he and I had a tumble in the passage; he had another pistol with him, that did not go off, so the other man, Mr. Phillip's assistant, whose name is Douglass, who had the writ; he made his escape, and Mr. Wright and the other gentleman secured me in the passage, and cry'd out fire, the mob came and surrounded me; I had a hanger by my side belonging to Mr. Phillips, with a butcher's steel tied to my apron-string; I had been to arrest a gentleman that day, so I disguised myself as a butcher. Mr. Wright did not come to the outward door at all at that time; I had the two pistols in my hand, and would not deliver them till I found myself safe; there was but one pistol fir'd.</p>
               <p>Mr. Phillips the bailiff, and 
               <persName id="t17491209-64-person487">
                  William 
                  Douglass 
               <interp inst="t17491209-64-person487" type="surname" value="Douglass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person487" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd what the Prisoner had said in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17491209-64-verdict291" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-verdict291" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d time indicted for <rs id="t17491209-64-off292" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-off292" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-off292" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing these 2 pistols, valued at 3 s
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17491209-64-verdict293" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-64-verdict293" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Court granted a copy of the indictment to the Prisoner against Mr. Wright.</p>
            </div1>
