<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450710-28">
               <interp inst="t17450710-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-28" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-28" type="date" value="17450710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450710-28-off169-c195" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-28-defend246 t17450710-28-off169 t17450710-28-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>331. 
               
                  <persName id="t17450710-28-defend246" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Roach 
                  <interp inst="t17450710-28-defend246" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-defend246" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-defend246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17450710-28-off169" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-off169" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-off169" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver cream pot, value 30 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17450710-28-victim248" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Kahagan 
                  <interp inst="t17450710-28-victim248" type="surname" value="Kahagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-victim248" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-victim248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-28-off169 t17450710-28-victim248"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17450710-28-cd170" type="crimeDate">June 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-28-off169 t17450710-28-cd170"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-28-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Kahagan 
               <interp inst="t17450710-28-person249" type="surname" value="Kahagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About a fortnight or three weeks ago I lost a silver cream pot. I believe it was taken out of my house. The Prisoner at the bar carried the cream pot to be pawned.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the cream pot that was lost yours?</p>
               <p>Kahagan. I thought it was, I acknowledged it as such.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it pledged to you?</p>
               <p>Kahagan. It was not pledged to me, but it was in my custody.</p>
               <p>Q. If it was in your possession, how did you come by it?</p>
               <p>Kahagan. I did not buy it myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-28-person250">
                  Evan 
                  Scriven 
               <interp inst="t17450710-28-person250" type="surname" value="Scriven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person250" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Beasley, in St. Martin's lane. On the 27th of June the Prisoner brought this cream pot to me, and wanted 15 s. upon it. I asked her whose it was, she said it was her own. I told her I did not believe it was her own. Then said she give it me again; No, I said I would not. Then to tell, you the truth, it is my mitress's; I asked who her mistress was, she said, she was a pretty lady, and kept by some Lord. I said I would go and speak to her mistress. No, she said, I should not, she would not disturb the Lord, for she should lose her place if she did. I followed her to a Lord's in St. James's square, where her husband lives, and acquainted him with it; he said she was his wife, but he had no such pot. I took her up, and then she pretended she bought it at the shop of one Mr. Caprio, a silver smith in St. Martin's lane. I went to him, and he said some time ago he sold her a milk pot, but he could not tell whether this was it or not. Sir Thomas would not discharge the warrant, but directed us to advertise it. I advertised it, and Mr. Kahagan came to our house to enquire after it; he said if it was his it had a K upon each foot, ther care three K's.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by the pot?</p>
               <p>Kahagan. My wife, I believe, bought it. I am not positive whether she did or not; but the pot has been mine these three years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-28-person251">
                  Evan 
                  Scriven 
               <interp inst="t17450710-28-person251" type="surname" value="Scriven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person251" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She confessed before the Justice that it was Mr. Kahagan's, and that she stole it out of his parlour.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought that pot in Ireland, it is marked with three K's. <rs id="t17450710-28-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450710-28-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
