<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-25">
               <interp inst="t17470429-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-25" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-25" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-25-off105-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-25-defend211 t17470429-25-off105 t17470429-25-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>203. + 
               <persName id="t17470429-25-defend211" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Cramp 
               <interp inst="t17470429-25-defend211" type="surname" value="Cramp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-defend211" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-defend211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470429-25-off105" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-off105" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-off105" type="offenceSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               making an Assault upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470429-25-victim213" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Walthoe 
                        <interp inst="t17470429-25-victim213" type="surname" value="Walthoe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-25-victim213" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470429-25-victim213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-25-off105 t17470429-25-victim213"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , with his right First struck him on the left Side of his Temples, giving him a mortal Wound and Bruise, of which he instantly died
            </rs>; he was likewise tried upon the Coroner's Inquest, who found him guilty, not of Murder, but Man-slaughter.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-25-person214">
                  John 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17470429-25-person214" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-person214" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar? Give an Account of what you know of him in Relation to the Death of Walthoe.</p>
               <p>White. I went in at the Swan to have a Pot of Beer, at the Swan in <placeName id="t17470429-25-crimeloc106">Water lane, Black-Fryars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-25-crimeloc106" type="placeName" value="Water lane, Black-Fryars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-25-crimeloc106" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-25-off105 t17470429-25-crimeloc106"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>White. About a Fortnight ago; in going in for a Pot of Beer, where was the deceased Man, and he said he would give any Body a full Pot of Beer to laugh at this Man at the Bar; I very innocently goes in, and said, for a Pot of Beer I would laugh at him.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you laugh at the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>White. And when the Pot of Beer came in, I drank to the Man that is deceased, and before I got the Pot of Beer from my Mouth, the Accident happened ; this Man got up to drink some of the Beer , I suppose the deceased Man shoved him, and they went to quarelling; I did not see any Blows struck.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened then?</p>
               <p>White. The misfortunate Blow that was struck, knocked him down, and there he lay, and he laid for some Time; I saw him lie down and fetch no Breath, nor nothing in the World; I takes him up, and turns him upon his Backside, and I held my Hand under his Chin, till there came a Woman and took him out of my Hands, I saw no more of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he dead ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290018"></xptr>White. Yes, I saw no Life in him; they burnt a Piece of Rag under his Nose, to see if he would fetch his Breath; that's all I know.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-25-person215">
                  William 
                  Mumford 
               <interp inst="t17470429-25-person215" type="surname" value="Mumford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-person215" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was you there at this Time? Did you know the deceased ?</p>
               <p>Mumford. I saw him, but I don't know his Name ?</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see done ?</p>
               <p>Mumford. I saw him killed with a Blow with the Fist.</p>
               <p>Q. By whom?</p>
               <p>Mumford. By the Man that was there, whose Name is Cramp .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Quarrel ?</p>
               <p>Mumford. I saw no Quarrel; that Man laid a Wager that he would do with him any three things except fighting .</p>
               <p>Q. Who said so?</p>
               <p>Mumford. The deceased .</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Mumford . This Man went to take the Beer from the deceased , and the deceased said he should not have his Beer , he should set down; whereupon Cramp, the Prisoner , got up; I did not see the Blow struck, I saw the deceased's Hand up, but I did not see the Blow struck ; the Blow the Prisoner struck was an unfortunate Blow that killed the Man.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there no Body here that knew the deceased ?</p>
               <p>There was none acknowledged they knew the deceased, by which the Prisoner escaped having any Punishment .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-25-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-25-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
