<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440113-7">
               <interp inst="t17440113-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-7" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-7" type="date" value="17440113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440113-7-off36-c73" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend87 t17440113-7-off36 t17440113-7-verdict38"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440113-7-off36-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend89 t17440113-7-off36 t17440113-7-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>+ 109, 110. 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-defend87" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Burton 
                  *, otherwise <rs id="t17440113-7-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend87 t17440113-7-alias-2"></join>Appleby</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend87" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend87" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-defend89" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Henry 
                     Burroughs 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17440113-7-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend89 t17440113-7-alias-3"></join>Cobler</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend89" type="surname" value="Burroughs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend89" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-defend89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17440113-7-defloc35">St. James's, Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-7-defloc35" type="placeName" value="St. James's, Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-7-defloc35" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend87 t17440113-7-defloc35"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend89 t17440113-7-defloc35"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17440113-7-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440113-7-victim92" type="victimName">
                           Moses 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17440113-7-victim92" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-7-victim92" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-7-victim92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , about the hour of nine in the night, and stealing two woollen caps, value 18 d.
            </rs> the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person93">
                  Moses 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person93" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person93" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17440113-7-cd37" type="crimeDate">Dec. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-off36 t17440113-7-cd37"></join>.</p>
               <p> *He was an accomplice with, and evidence against 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person94">
                  Richard 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person94" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person94" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , tried in June sessions; see trial 335, page 203. And also against 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person95">
                  John 
                  Bunn 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person95" type="surname" value="Bunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person96">
                  Joseph 
                  Leach 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person96" type="surname" value="Leach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person96" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , tried in September sessions; see trial 417, and 418. page 242. who were all capitally convicted for robbing 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person97">
                  James 
                  Fennel 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person97" type="surname" value="Fennel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person97" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , a Taylor, near Rosemary-Lane; and last sessions received sentence of transportation for 14 years.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174401130007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-7-person98">
                  Moses 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person98" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person98" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of Dec. I went out about half an hour after seven in the evening, and about nine my maid came to fetch me home, and acquainted me that my shop window was broke, and she believed I was robbed: I came home directly, and missed some caps, I am sure to two double-seamed worsted caps, one of them was picked up in the street by my servant - the shop was not shut up then, the door was fastened, but the shutters were not put up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-7-person99">
                  John 
                  Thorne 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person99" type="surname" value="Thorne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 17th of Dec. the two Prisoners and I came out from Rag Fair together between six and seven o'clock, with a design to rob any body we could, or get what we could; when we came to Mr. Johnson's shop 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person100">
                  John 
                  Appleby 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person100" type="surname" value="Appleby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             broke the window, (I don't know that he went by any other name) he broke one pane first, to get at the show-glass, and then he broke another with design to come at some worsted caps; he could not come at the show glass, because there was another glass between - I cannot say whether either of the Prisoners took any caps or no, because I was upon the look out, to see if any body came along the street; upon the window's being broke Mr. Johnson's wife whittled out, stop thief, and I was presently taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what caps you had there?</p>
               <p>Johnson. There might be five or six dozen lying there for what I know, I missed two, but I might lose more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-7-person101">
                  Mary 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person101" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person101" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 17th of Dec. in the evening, about nine o'clock, when my husband was out the shop window was broke.</p>
               <p>Q. Who broke it?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I cannot tell, I was below stairs, and heard something break; I came up directly, and caught a man's hand in the window, with the caps in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose hand did you catch in the window?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Burrough's hand; I saw his face through the window, I took hold of the caps while they were in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at him and see if you are sure he is the man.</p>
               <p>Johnson. I believe it to be the same man, he in the blue gray, he was on the outside of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you see his face then?</p>
               <p>Johnson. There was a large candle in the shop, and I dout the candle to his face, before he would let go.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he hold of any more caps?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He had hold of a great many caps.</p>
               <p>Q. How many caps did you see drawn through the window?</p>
               <p>Johnson. There were some caps drawn through, for my servant found one in the street under the window, and I took it from her; how many they got before I cannot tell, for the window was broke in two places.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance was there between the panes that were broke?</p>
               <p>Johnson. There was one pane; there was a showglass with some silver ribbons in it, and they broke one pane to come at that, but they could not get at it for the glass in the inside.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body run away?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I did not see any body run, for I had a great door to open, and before I could get it open they were all gone - I saw no other person but him that I saw through the window - I cried out stop thief, and Thorne was immediately apprehended.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-7-person102">
                  Charles 
                  Shippey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person102" type="surname" value="Shippey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person102" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work next door to the place where this robbery was committed, I am a cooper, at the Hoop and Adze, I happened to go out to the door between eight and nine in the evening, and the Prisoners were at Mrs. Johnson's window and about the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see them do?</p>
               <p>Shippey. I will tell you if you please to give me leave. I had no suspicion when I first saw them at all, and I suppose they thought that I should tout them, or hinder them in their design; says he in the blue coat, [Burroughs] Jack, shall we have a pint of beer, or can we have a dream of gin; I made a particular remark of all three of them for then I thought what they were; they went into an alehouse, the Hoop and Adze, and called for a quartern of gin - I looked at the clock, and it was then between eight and nine. Burroughs had his hat flapping over his eyes, that I should not see his face, for I looked very hard at them, and after they had drank their gin, Burroughs gave the accomplice (Thorne) three half-pence to pay for it; when Appleby had got the gin in his mouth he held down his head to spit it out, and the other stooped, and was complaining of his shoes being worn out; and standing pretty near the fire, somebody asked him what made him so cold? He said, If you went as near the ground as I, you would be cold too. After they were gone out of the house, I said, these three fellows look as if they would break their necks in going to Paddington. Mrs. Spriggs, the woman of the house, said she believed they had a mind to rob somebody; said I, I believed they are going to rob Mrs. Johnson . Mrs. Spriggs went out to look, and came in again, and said my heart is ready to burst, there is one of them against Mrs. Johnson's window now, and another on the other side of the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174401130008"></xptr> way; and presently Mrs. Johnson cried out, I am robbed . I run out in a hurry and saw the accomplice, I seized him directly, and said, d - n you I know you, and I'll keep you.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know him?</p>
               <p>Shippey . I knew him by the sear in his face - I did not see any of them run away, but I was very quick in catching of him; I carried him, back to the Hoop and Adze , and asked him if he was not ashamed to rob people who work hard for their living? He said he did not come to rob any body; he said that he was going to Smithfield, and came in to drink with the Prisoners , but never saw them before in his life. We secured him, and the next morning had him before a Justice, and hearing of Long Charles , as they call him, his name is 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person103">
                  Charles 
                  Reddington 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person103" type="surname" value="Reddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person103" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and as he is a thief-taker, and conversant with such sort of people, we acquainted him with the affair, and asked him if he did not know any thing of them, and so they were apprehended.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Long Charles, and 
               <persName id="t17440113-7-person104">
                  Billy 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17440113-7-person104" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person104" type="given" value="Billy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the thief-takers, brought that man to swear against us. <rs id="t17440113-7-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17440113-7-punish39" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-7-punish39" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend87 t17440113-7-punish39"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-7-defend89 t17440113-7-punish39"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
