<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-19">
               <interp inst="t17400227-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-19" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-19" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-19-off114-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-defend208 t17400227-19-off114 t17400227-19-verdict118"></join>
         
               <p>173. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-19-defend208" type="defendantName">
                     Margery 
                     Akers , alias <rs id="t17400227-19-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-defend208 t17400227-19-alias-3"></join>Bunce</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-defend208" type="surname" value="Akers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-defend208" type="given" value="Margery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-defend208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400227-19-defloc113">St Bride's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-19-defloc113" type="placeName" value="St Bride's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-19-defloc113" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-defend208 t17400227-19-defloc113"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-19-off114" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-off114" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-off114" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Watch, val. 12 l. a Silver wrought Snuff-box, val. 20 s. and 8 Guineas
            </rs>, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17400227-19-victim209" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-victim209" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-off114 t17400227-19-victim209"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17400227-19-cd115" type="crimeDate">Jan. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-off114 t17400227-19-cd115"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400227-19-viclabel116" type="occupation">Mr</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-victim209 t17400227-19-viclabel116"></join> W - . On Thursday the 24th of Jan. between 8 and 9 in the Evening, as I was coming down Sheer-lane, I saw a young Woman very genteelly dress'd, and I stopp'd to look at her. Some Conversation pass'd between us, and I asked her to drink a Glass of Wine. She seemed a modest Woman, and said, No, she did not care for drinking, - she must go home. While we were talking together up came the Prisoner, and said she was going home, and if I pleased, I might go home with them. So we all went together to the Prisoner's House in <placeName id="t17400227-19-crimeloc117">Green's Rents</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-19-crimeloc117" type="placeName" value="Green's Rents"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-19-crimeloc117" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-19-off114 t17400227-19-crimeloc117"></join>. There was no Wine in the House, but she told us we might have a Tiff of Punch, but nothin g less than a 2 Shilling Tiff, and I paid for one Bowl before ever I tasted it. After this we had 5 or 6 more, and when it was between 12 and 1 o'Clock, I called for the Reckoning. The Prisoner told me she was a poor Widow-woman, and it would be Charity to assist her. I told her, it was late, and I did not care to go home, and as the Reckoning came to 12 s. if she would let me have a Bed, and a clean Pair of Sheets, there was a Guinea for her; but, says I, if I want another Bowl, you will not stand with me for that. She was thankful, and told me she would not. Between 2 and 3 I went to Bed, and I am sure I had my Watch and Snuff-box then, for I took several Pinches of Snuff, and never went out of the Room, but into the Bedchamber, which was on the same Floor. I believe it was between 1 and 2 when I went to Bed, - near 2. Between 3 and 4 I waked, and wanting a Pinch, I felt for my Coat, and searched my Pockets, but my Box was gone. This alarm'd me, and made me turn about and put my Hand under my Pillow to feel for my Breeches, and I found my Watch gone. Then I felt in my Side-pocket, where I had crammed down my Purse with my Money, and feeling the Strings of it, I imagin'd my Money was safe, but I afterwards found that was gone too. I told the young Woman, that her Landlady had robb'd me. I can't imagine (said she) how the Woman could serve you so, - I always took her to be honest. Upon this I knock'd with my Shoe upon the Floor, and a little Child came up and told me her Mother was gone out of Town. Why, says I, she was here an Hour or two ago, is she gone already? Yes, says the Child, she is gone into the Country. I was in a good deal of Confusion and laid me down again, thinking I would stay till Daylight. About an Hour afterwards, I thought I heard somebody come in,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270018"></xptr> so I call'd again, and the Child came and told me her Mother was gone. I questioned the young Woman about it; but she cry'd, and said she never knew her guilty of such a Thing before. In the Morning I went away, and the Prisoner absconded: she never came to the House, except it was at Midnight; for I set a Porter, who lived at next Door, to watch for her, and got a Warrant from Sir 
               <persName id="t17400227-19-person210">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17400227-19-person210" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person210" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to apprehend her, if I could light of her; but hearing nothing of her, I advertised the Things, and about a Fortnight afterwards, I had 2 Letters sent me to Will's Coffee-House , and upon the Receipt of them, I went down to the Fleet, and saw the Prisoner coming to her Husband in the Prison, but she ran away as soon as she saw me. I knew her again, and by the Direction of one in the Prison, I took her next Morning at the Queen's-Head Alehouse , in Holborn.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was the Door of the Room you lay in lock'd, when you went to Bed?</p>
               <p>W - . No. - When I took the Prisoner, she cry'd and wrung her Hands, and said, - You're a good-natur'd Man, - you'll not prosecute me if you have your Things again, and I have 5 Beds which I will sell, but you shall have Satisfaction. This was at the Justice's Clerk's House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I make the first Tiff of Punch for you?</p>
               <p>W - . You brought it up, - I don't know who made it. I own I had drank freely, and was a little elevated; - I can't say I was drunk. I am certain I had the Things in my Pockets when I went to Bed.</p>
               <p>Mr Murden. I am a Prisoner in the Fleet. The Prisoner's Husband was a School-Fellow of mine; and he coming into the Fleet short of Money, I took him into my Room from Saturday to Tuesday. In that Interim the Prisoner often came to him, and I found he had got a Gold Watch in his Pocket. I knew he never was capable of wearing such a Thing, so I ask'd him how he came by it? Phoo, says the Prisoner, I mason'd a Cull, and the Fellow has advertised it; but the Scoundrel was drunk, and did not know how much Money he lost. He advertised but 7 Guineas, and the Scoundrel lost more. She said the Scoundrel was drunk, and she mason'd him, and stole the Watch and his Snuff-box out of his Pocket. As soon as I heard this, I bid them get out of my Room; telling them I would harbour no Thieves; and I went down to the Turn-key, and desired him to send for a Constable to secure them, telling him I had Thieves in my Room, and I had discovered Villany; but there was none came, because Constables are afraid of being ill used in the Fleet. When I went up again into my Room, the Prisoner's Husband (who wore the Watch in his Pocket 2 Days) fell down on his Knees, and begged I would not turn them out of my Room, nor expose them: But I insisted on their being gone, and turned them out by Force. Both the Prisoner and her Husband told me the very Day when the Watch was first advertised, - the 6th of February. Upon the Discovery of this Villany, I went down to the Coffee-House in the Fleet-Prison, and found the things advertised on the 6th of February, and that they were lost at a Pretended Attorney's House; so I wrote a Letter to be left at the Coffee-House mentioned in the Advertisement, and the next Day the Prosecutor came to the Coffee-House in the Fleet, and the Prisoner was taken up. The Day I discovered the Villany, she came to her Husband and said, I met the Scoundrel in Carey-street , by Lincoln's-Inn-Fields, with his Horse in his Hand; and she described him and his Cloaths so well, that the Minute he came into the Coffee-House, I knew him and went up to the Table where he sat, and asked him if he had not lost a gold Watch?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr Murden what I pawned on Saturday?</p>
               <p>Murden. She came to her Husband, and said she had no Money; and she went out. When she returned, she said she had pawned a Ring off her Finger.</p>
               <p>Mr Richardson. There was a Gold Watch offered to be pawn'd at our House, (I think) by the Prisoner, but I can't be positive: I had seen her before, but I would not take it in, unless she could convince me she had a Property in it. She told me it belonged to a Gentleman of Ludgate, and upon my refusing it, she took it away again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-19-person211">
                  Francis 
                  Jeal 
               <interp inst="t17400227-19-person211" type="surname" value="Jeal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person211" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. When I took the Prisoner to Woodstreet-Counter , she cry'd bitterly in the Lodge, and said that one 
               <persName id="t17400227-19-person212">
                  Peter 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17400227-19-person212" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person212" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mrs Oldfield, (the Prosecutor's Mistress) had part of the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is the Woman which W - brought to our House. He was in her Company that Night, and 2 Nights following.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-19-person213">
                  Mary 
                  Oldfield 
               <interp inst="t17400227-19-person213" type="surname" value="Oldfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person213" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew the Woman to be guilty of such Things: but I saw the Gentleman have his Watch and Snuff-box just before he went to Bed. In the Night he wanted a Pinch, and missing his Box, the Girl came up with a Candle, but he could find neither his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270019"></xptr> Watch, nor his Box. I never saw the Prisoner till next Night, and then she came to the Sun Coffee-House , to bid me come Home, but I refused, and have never seen her since. The Prosecutor took me up, and kept me in the Counter, from Tuesday to Friday.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They locked themselves in, and I called and asked them, what they'd please to have for Breakfast.</p>
               <p>Oldfield. She did knock at the Door in the Morning, and the Gentleman bid me not say any thing for fear she should run away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I stay at Home all that Night?</p>
               <p>Oldfield. I am not a Judge of that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had not I a Servant that went away that Night?</p>
               <p>Oldfield. Yes; and she run away with a camblet Gown of mine. <rs id="t17400227-19-verdict118" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-19-verdict118" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
