<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-25">
               <interp inst="t17421208-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-25" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-25" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-25-off139-c191" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-defend240 t17421208-25-off139 t17421208-25-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>27. 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-25-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Pryor 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-25-defend240" type="surname" value="Pryor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-defend240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17421208-25-defloc138">St Ann, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-25-defloc138" type="placeName" value="St Ann, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-25-defloc138" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-defend240 t17421208-25-defloc138"></join> , was indicted for that <rs id="t17421208-25-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="assaultWithSodomiticalIntent"></interp>
               he, in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-25-victim242" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Porter 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-25-victim242" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-25-victim242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-25-victim242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-off139 t17421208-25-victim242"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , did wickedly and feloniously make an Assault, and with him the said William did commit that detestable, sodomitical Crime, called Buggery, which is not fit to be named among Christians
            </rs>. <rs id="t17421208-25-cd140" type="crimeDate">Nov. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-off139 t17421208-25-cd140"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-25-person243">
                  William 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17421208-25-person243" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner did wrong to me two or three Times one Night. - I do not know what Month it was; I believe it was about a Year ago; it was in the Winter. - I live with Mr Greener, a Currier, near <placeName id="t17421208-25-crimeloc141">Leicester-Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-25-crimeloc141" type="placeName" value="Leicester-Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-25-crimeloc141" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-off139 t17421208-25-crimeloc141"></join>. Pryor is <rs id="t17421208-25-deflabel142" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-25-defend240 t17421208-25-deflabel142"></join> to my Master.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, what did he do to you?</p>
               <p>Porter gave Evidence of a Penetration, but in such Language as is not fit to be committed to Paper.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him?</p>
               <p>Porter . I bid him not do it. - I did not bid him do it, he did it of his own Self. - He did do it indeed. - He did put it in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever served so before by any Body?</p>
               <p>Porter. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you strive to hinder him?</p>
               <p>Porter. He would do it.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you, whether you did not strive with him to hinder him?</p>
               <p>Porter . No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. So you were as willing as he?</p>
               <p>Porter . No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you endeavour to hinder him?</p>
               <p>Porter . He would do it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you let him do what he would?</p>
               <p>Porter. I did not bid him do it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080018"></xptr>Q. You are as strong as he; I do not think he could have done it, if you had endeavoured to hinder him?</p>
               <p>Porter. He is stronger than I am.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask him when I did offer to do any such Thing as that?</p>
               <p>Porter. It was over Night when I went to Bed. - Several Nights.</p>
               <p>Q. This is above a Year ago: When did you first complain of it? Did you tell your Master or Mistress first of it?</p>
               <p>Porter. I told my Mistress first what he did to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you told your Mistress of it?</p>
               <p>Porter. It is about a Week ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-25-person244">
                  John 
                  Greener 
               <interp inst="t17421208-25-person244" type="surname" value="Greener"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my Apprentice; the Witness goes of Errands; he is, what some call, a Slave. On Tuesday the 30th of November, I was out; the Prisoner at the Bar, said to his Mistress, I will stay up for my Master: No Tom, said she, I will stay up, you may go to Bed; she sat up for me: I came Home about eleven o'Clock, and sat down by the Fire talking with my Wife; said she, Mr Greener, do you hear how the Bed cracks? I said, It is an old Bedstead, and they are subject to crack. In about a Quarter of an Hour, the Bed made the same Noise again. Now, said she, Do not you hear it. Yes, said I, I do. Then, said she, Go and enquire what is the Reason of it. I did not go directly; then, said she, If you will not go , I will. Accordingly she went. - I know no more of the Affair, but what she told me; but I heard no more Noise of the Bed after.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did not you bring your Wife?</p>
               <p>Greener. I might have brought her, but she is not very well, and out of Modesty, she did not care to come.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it this Witness told you of the Fact?</p>
               <p>Greener. Not at all; he told no Body of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came this Man to be taken up? You can tell that without telling what your Wife said.</p>
               <p>Greener. I knew nothing of it 'till the 30th of November. Prior has been turned over to me about eleven Months; he behaved very well till about Michaelmas last, and then I found he was got acquainted with a Gang of young Wenches; he did not neglect my Business till the Princess's Birth-Day . <rs id="t17421208-25-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-25-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
