<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451016-19">
               <interp inst="t17451016-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-19" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-19" type="date" value="17451016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451016-19-off103-c144" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend182 t17451016-19-off103 t17451016-19-verdict106"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451016-19-off103-c146" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend186 t17451016-19-off103 t17451016-19-verdict106"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451016-19-off103-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend187 t17451016-19-off103 t17451016-19-verdict106"></join>
         
               <p>383. + 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-defend182" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Grace 
                     Usop 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17451016-19-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend182 t17451016-19-alias-3"></join>Tarras</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend182" type="surname" value="Usop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend182" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend182" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17451016-19-defloc102">St Leonard Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-19-defloc102" type="placeName" value="St Leonard Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-19-defloc102" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend182 t17451016-19-defloc102"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend186 t17451016-19-defloc102"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend187 t17451016-19-defloc102"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17451016-19-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               for the murder of her female bastard child, by throwing the said child into a privy belonging to 
                     <persName id="t17451016-19-person184">
                        James 
                        Leger 
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person184" type="surname" value="Leger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451016-19-person184" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451016-19-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , wherein there was a great quantity of filth and excrement , by reason of which throwing, and by reason of the said filth and excrement, the said child was choaked and suffocated , of which choaking and suffocating the said female bastard child died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17451016-19-cd104" type="crimeDate">September 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-off103 t17451016-19-cd104"></join>. And</p>
               <p>384, 385. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-defend186" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Leger 
                  <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend186" type="surname" value="Leger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend186" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-defend187" type="defendantName">
                  Magdalen, otherwise <rs id="t17451016-19-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend187 t17451016-19-alias-4"></join>Maudin Leger</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend187" type="given" value="Magdalen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-defend187" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his <rs id="t17451016-19-deflabel105" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-19-defend187 t17451016-19-deflabel105"></join>, were indicted for aiding, abetting, and maintaining the said 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person188">
                  Grace 
                  Usop 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person188" type="surname" value="Usop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person188" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to commit the said murder: and therefore they the said 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person189">
                  Grace 
                  Usop 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person189" type="surname" value="Usop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person189" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person189" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person190">
                  James 
                  Leger 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person190" type="surname" value="Leger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person190" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Magdalen, otherwise Maudlin Leger, the said female bastard child, feloniously, wilfully, and of their malice aforethought, did kill and murder, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person191">
                  Eleanor 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person191" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person191" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A few days before this thing was discovered, I went into Mr. Leger's house for half a pound of butter, and the Prisoner was there, and she was very bad. I asked her if no body was there but herself; she said her mistress was in the garden; presently her mistress came out of the garden in a very great flurry, and Mr. Leger himself came in in a very great flurry, and he said, Tarras, my girl, you are very bad, will you go to bed? and he said she should go to bed, and he called Maudlin to make the bed; said he, will you have the bed warmed? she said I don't care if I have: he said, Maudlin, my poor girl, is a very faithful servant, and she is very bad with them, and has strained herself with carrying coals, she wants the bed warmed. He asked what he should<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174510160012"></xptr> give her; and I said half a pint of ale with sugar and spice: and one Mrs. Lewis came in and said, Mrs. Johnson, have you heard of the murder? I said I had not; she said there was a fine boy in the vault: she put her hand down into the vault three times, and brought up nothing but soil, and the fourth time she put her hand down, she said, here's the child, and I could not think but it must be a girl, but there were some circumstances that made me think it was a boy, for the navel string hung between the boy's legs, and she thought it was a boy by that.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she married?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I don't know that she is.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that this girl had a child?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I heard so.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you don't know that she had a child?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I never had any thought of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then there was a child in the house of office, and the child was dead?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes; the child was dead when I saw it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person192">
                  Mary 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person192" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person192" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Grace about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she married?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Not that ever I heard of.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her having a child?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I don't know any thing of her having any.</p>
               <p>Coroner. Did she say any thing to you about the child?</p>
               <p>Lewis. On Thursday the first of September she went out for some rolls, I met her at Mrs. Johnson's house, and she said she was very ill with a pain in her bones. I went to Mr. Leger's house, and Mrs. Leger said that Tarras was very bad, so bad that she was forced to go up with a mop and a pail to clean the room: then I said to Mrs. Leger, with your leave shall I go up and see her? and she said, yes: I went up, and Tarras lay upon the bed with her clothes on: the room was wet, and I asked her who had been up to wash the room; she said her mistress had been up with a mop and pail, and cleaned it: she was very much out of order: I sat down by her, and asked her what was the matter with her: said I, have not you miscarried? said she, what makes you think so? I was backward and forward all that day, and Mrs. Leger said, how does Tarras do? I said she was very bad indeed, and that she would not be well of the months. On the ninth of this month one Bellache came and asked after Tarras; said I, what makes you ask after her? he said, if you want to know, go to the vault and satisfy yourself. I asked Mrs. Leger to let me go to her vault, and I went to the vault, and looked down, and saw something, which I took to be a child. I went to Tarras, and said, Tarras, this is your child; said she, Lord Jesus! Lord Jesus ! Molly don't say so. I came into the house, and said to Mr. Leger, there is a child in the vault; what in yours, said he? no, in yours, said I; and he went in, and there was no more said about it. I went to Mrs. Johnson's, and said there was a child in the vault, and we both went together.</p>
               <p>Coroner. Had you any talk with her afterwards whether she had a child?</p>
               <p>Lewis. She said she went to the vault, for she thought she had occasion to go there; and afterwards went into the shed, and said, sick, sick, sick; that she went up stairs, and leaned upon the window, and then she was delivered of the child; this was on the second of September.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that the child was found?</p>
               <p>Lewis. On the ninth of September.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it that Grace said she was delivered as she was leaning upon the window?</p>
               <p>Lewis. That was the day it was found out.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was she delivered?</p>
               <p>Lewis. She said it was on Sunday the first of September.</p>
               <p>Leger's Council. Did she say whether the child was dead, or alive, when she was delivered?</p>
               <p>Lewis. She did not say whether it was dead, or alive.</p>
               <p>Usop's Council. Was there any thing found under the bed in a box?</p>
               <p>Lewis . Yes; there was a box of child-bed linen, and Usop said she bought it in Rag Fair against she was brought to bed, unknown to any body.</p>
               <p>Dorcas Randolph. On Monday the second of September, which was Usop's birth-day, I was abroad with her, and she was very bad; and they said the child was born on the first of September, and was found in the vault on the ninth. I said to her, you have had a child, for there is a child found in the vault. I asked her if she had made any preparation for it; she said she had, and that the box was under the bed; said she, Mrs. Randolph, you are best able to stoop, put your hand under the bed, and pull it out, and I did. She said Mr. Leger had threatened her, and bid her lay it upon James, or the Baker; and then she said, must I tell a lie? and he said, ouy .</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Randolph. On the ninth of September Mrs. Leger did own before the Justice, that the child had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174510160013"></xptr> a bruise on the head: I said, how came the child to have a bruise on the head? she said that was nothing at all, for it was not done out of malice; and she emptied the pot with the after birth, and she pleaded ignorance, because she never had had a child; for people who have been in labour know more than those who have not.</p>
               <p>Council. When this discourse was with Tarras, was there any talk whether the child was born dead or alive ?</p>
               <p>Randolph. She said she was very bad, and her master came up and helped her in the birth, and parted one from the other, and took it in an apron, and carried it down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the child dead or alive ?</p>
               <p>Randolph. I cannot say any thing to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person193">
                  Joachim 
                  Bellache 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person193" type="surname" value="Bellache"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person193" type="given" value="Joachim"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One of my shop-mates discovered the child in the vault on Friday in the afternoon, and said, Mrs. Bellache, there is something in the vault that looks like a bundle of Rags. I went down in the night to ease myself; I had a suspicion of something, so I was very curious , and put my finger into the vault , and thought it was flesh. I put my finger upon the body, and felt the ribs, and then I was afraid of what really was , and found that it was a child, but, I did not care to speak to Mr. Leger about it then: and 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person194">
                  Mary 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person194" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person194" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person194" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in and said, there is a child in the vault: said I, Mr. Leger, it does not signify any thing talking, I told you before that your maid was with child, and he said she had had the ague and fever, and had taken too much bark, and it had hindered the courses; then I told him there was a child in the vault; he seemed surprized at it, and said, if it was so, he would send for an officer, and he ordered one 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person195">
                  Paul 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person195" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person195" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to fetch the beadle.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person196">
                  Ann 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person196" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person196" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person196" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , midwife. I saw a child that was taken out of the vault.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it born dead or alive?</p>
               <p>Baker. I could not judge whether it was born dead or alive.</p>
               <p>Coroner. Did the child come at the full time?</p>
               <p>Baker. It did not come at its full time, I am almost sure of it.</p>
               <p>Council. You say you could not judge whether the child was born alive, how could you know whether it was at its full time?</p>
               <p>Baker. Oh, Sir, that I am very sure of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person197">
                  Henry 
                  Gundy 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person197" type="surname" value="Gundy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person197" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I was sent for about the 13th of last month, and found a child which was very much putrified . I did not care to open the child, but found upon examining the child, that there was a violent pressure upon the skull, which if that had been given when the child was alive, must have been the occasion of its death.</p>
               <p>Coroner. Was the child full grown ?</p>
               <p>Grundy. In my opinion it was.</p>
               <p>Leger's Council. As to the pressure upon the head of the child, was that given before the child was dead. or after ?</p>
               <p>Grund. I cannot pretend to say whether the wound was given before or after .</p>
               <p>Leger's Council argued, that he could not think there was any evidence to affect Mr. Leger and his wife, and could hardly think there was any to affect the principal. That he was informed Mr. Leger has a wife of his own, and therefore very unlikely he should be guilty of the fact. And that in order to make it a murder, it must be first proved that the child was born alive. [Vide Statute 21. James I.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person198">
                  Eleanor 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person198" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person198" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called again at the desire of the Coroner.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after you found the child in the vault ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. When I found the child in the vault, I went into the kitchen, and fell into, and said to Mrs. Leger, this is a terrible case; and she said Tarras was very bad, and that women in her care are never well of the months. I came out to Mr. Bellache, and he clapped his hand upon my belly, and said, God bless your belly, and said, I hope you will not drop it as somebody has done. Another thing I remember, I saw the child on the 10th of September, and it bled out of one of the ears, I think it was the left ear. On the Tuesday Tarras's mother and another woman were there, and they sent for me, and Mr. Leger said, Mrs. Johnson, you must go up and tell Tarras's mother to bribe the midwife, or else Tarras will be hanged.</p>
               <p>Coroner. She has not answered the question yet. I ask you what Tarras said when you went up to her?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I told her there was a fine child found in the vault, and they said it is yours: and after I had got an acknowledgment from her, that she had been with child, I said, who is the father of the child? and she said my master; and she asked where her master was, and she said, call my master up. I went down to him, and he went up to her, and she wept bitterly: they talked together in French, and I could not understand them; and when he was gone, I asked her what her master<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174510160014"></xptr> said; and she said, he says I must lay it to James, or the Baker, or else I shall be hanged.</p>
               <p>Capt. 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person199">
                  James 
                  Dalbiac 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person199" type="surname" value="Dalbiac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person199" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mr. Leger forty years. I never heard any thing against his character in my life; he is a man of reputation, and a sober diligent man in his business.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17451016-19-person200">
                  Simon 
                  Dalbiac 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person200" type="surname" value="Dalbiac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person200" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him forty years, and I never heard any thing against him, he always bore the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ross. I have known him twenty years , he is a sober honest man, and a good natured man , and she is a sober industrious woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-19-person201">
                  Thomas 
                  Newland 
               <interp inst="t17451016-19-person201" type="surname" value="Newland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person201" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Mr. Leger and his wife are both people of very good characters.</p>

               <p>Mr. Perim gave him the character of a very honest man. These gentlemen being asked , whether they thought he would be guilty of aiding and assisting in the murder of the child; they said they believed he would not. They were all <rs id="t17451016-19-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-19-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> of the murder, and likewise of the charge on the Coroner's Inquisition; and the Jury found that the child was still born.</p>
            </div1>
