<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441205-53">
               <interp inst="t17441205-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-53" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441205-53" type="date" value="17441205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-53-off343-c553" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend682 t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441205-53-off343-c554" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend684 t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-verdict347"></join>
         
               <p>91, 92. + 
               <persName id="t17441205-53-defend682" type="defendantName">
                  David 
                  Shaddows 
               <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend682" type="surname" value="Shaddows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend682" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend682" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17441205-53-defend684" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Ruggles 
                  <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend684" type="surname" value="Ruggles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend684" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-defend684" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17441205-53-defloc342">St. Martin's in the fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-53-defloc342" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-53-defloc342" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend682 t17441205-53-defloc342"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend684 t17441205-53-defloc342"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17441205-53-off343" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-off343" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-off343" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17441205-53-victim685" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Church 
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-victim685" type="surname" value="Church"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-53-victim685" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441205-53-victim685" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-victim685"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , in a certain open place near the King's highway, called <placeName id="t17441205-53-crimeloc344">St. James's Park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-crimeloc344" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-crimeloc344" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-crimeloc344"></join>, putting him in fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a silver watch, value 40 s. a stock-buckle, value 5  and two shillings and two-pence halfpeny in money, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-53-cd345" type="crimeDate">Sept. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-cd345"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Church. On the 17th of September I had been at Hide- park-corner about a little business and going from Hide-park to St. James's Park, in order to go to Westminster, when I had got almost to the bottom of <placeName id="t17441205-53-crimeloc346">Constitution-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-53-crimeloc346" type="placeName" value="Constitution-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441205-53-crimeloc346" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-off343 t17441205-53-crimeloc346"></join>, in the Middle Park, before you come to Buckingham-house, I was met by a person who called himself Brown to the best of my memory.</p>
               <p>Q. What time o'night was it?</p>
               <p>Church. When these fellows light of me, it was not above half an hour after eight.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Brown say to you?</p>
               <p>Church. I don't know that he said any thing, unless that it was a fine evening. I did not much like him, and I walked the breadth of the table from the path, because I did not like him. In about a minute and an half, or two minutes time, I heard somebody running, and saw two persons running towards me. When they came up to me, I believe I could have thrown a stone to the bottom of Buckingham green-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were the persons that were running?</p>
               <p>Church. The two Prisoners were both running, I think I can be sure to both of them, but I am sure Ruggles was one; and I could swear to the other, but I don't choose it. There were three of them came up to me; they never said, Stand, and deliver; but one of them, which I take to be Shaddows, stooped, and took hold of my two legs, and threw me down.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Ruggles do?</p>
               <p>Church. I will not be positive what he did, but they threw me down upon my back, and beat me in a most violent manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they make use of sticks, or their fists ?</p>
               <p>Church. They made use of nothing but their fists, and I found them heavy enough, for they beat me so, that there was not such a spectacle seen: I had not an eye to see out of; nor could I open my mouth to take in my victuals: and one of them choked me: I can't be positive who it was, but I think it was Ruggles. Then they laid hold of my side-pockets, and tore them off. After they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174412050048"></xptr> had done that, they fell backwards, but did not fall quite to the ground. The man that was choking me, took my stock and stock-buckle off, and ran away to the rest; they took a silver watch from me, and two shillings and two-pence halfpeny, which I had in my pocket, and went directly to Hide-park-corner - I have not had my watch, or any thing again.</p>
               <p>Shaddows. Do you know what day of the week it was?</p>
               <p>Church. Yes, I do; it was on a Monday.</p>
               <p>Shaddows. What time o'night was it?</p>
               <p>Church. I have told that already.</p>
               <p>Shaddows. Do you know any thing of me?</p>
               <p>Church. Only what I have said.</p>
               <p>Rowling Brown. The two Prisoners and I met Mr. Church, not where he says, by Constitution-hill, but in the park; he was sitting upon a bench in the park, and I sat down by him, and falling into conversation, he said it was pleasanter walking than sitting, and asked if I would not take a walk. We walked in the middle of the park till we came to Buckingham wall, pretty near the ice-house, and then he began to meddle with me, and pulled out what he had, and put it into my hand, and wanted to feel what I had. I said, I believed there was a Molly. Shaddows and Ruggles came up, and we took him to the guard; he can't deny it, if he tells the truth; but I believe he was ashamed of it. We asked for his money, but he would not give it us; and so thinking he would be ashamed of the thing, we took his watch and money from him - we knew it was an ill thing; but we thought we had better take the watch and money, than expose him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you go there for?</p>
               <p>Brown. I did not go there for that purpose as some people go - we go to see who is there, and if we meet with any of these sort of people, if they have any money we take it from them.</p>
               <p>Church. I have received a threatening letter from them.</p>
               <p>Brown. You said you had received a threatening letter, but you said you believed it was from Jews.</p>
               <p>Q. If he offered such a thing as that to you, are you to rob him?</p>
               <p>Church. Ask him if he knows whether I am a girl or a boy?</p>
               <p>Brown. Yes, I do; for you put what you had into my hand: I think I should know.</p>
               <p>Church. Do you know what I am?</p>
               <p>Brown. I believe I know very well, and if you were to be searched, I could prove that I do.</p>
               <p>Q. When you adverticed your watch, why did not you advertise where you lost it; for you advertised it to be lost in Germain-street.</p>
               <p>Church. I could have had half the parish of St. Giles's to my character.</p>
               <p>Brown. He told me he was a joiner, and lived at Westminster.</p>
               <p>Church. You are such a rogue and a liar, that no body will believe you. He has made himself an evidence, I did not call him for a witness.</p>
               <p>One of the Jury said he had known Mr. Church three years, and that he was a man of a good character.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure Shaddows took you by the legs?</p>
               <p>Church. I don't chuse to swear to it.</p>
               <p>Q. You have sworn to Ruggles; can you swear that Shaddows is the man?</p>
               <p>Church. I believe as much one as the other, but I thought one was sufficient, so I would not swear to both. I verily believe he is the man. <rs id="t17441205-53-verdict347" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-verdict347" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17441205-53-punish348" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441205-53-punish348" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend682 t17441205-53-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441205-53-defend684 t17441205-53-punish348"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
