<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410225-51">
               <interp inst="t17410225-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410225-51" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410225-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410225-51" type="date" value="17410225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410225-51-off218-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-defend372 t17410225-51-off218 t17410225-51-verdict221"></join>
         
               <p>62. 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-defend372" type="defendantName">
                  
                     David 
                     Stochbury 
                  , alias <rs id="t17410225-51-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-defend372 t17410225-51-alias-3"></join>Touchbury</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-defend372" type="surname" value="Stochbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-defend372" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-defend372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17410225-51-defloc217">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410225-51-defloc217" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410225-51-defloc217" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-defend372 t17410225-51-defloc217"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17410225-51-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for that he not having God before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17410225-51-cd219" type="crimeDate">6th of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-off218 t17410225-51-cd219"></join>, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410225-51-victim375" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Porter 
                        <interp inst="t17410225-51-victim375" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410225-51-victim375" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410225-51-victim375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-off218 t17410225-51-victim375"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Peace, &amp;c. feloniously, wilfully, and of his Malice afore thought, did make an Assault, and with a certain Poinard or Dagger made of Iron and Steel, val. 6 d which he in his right Hand had and held, on the Breast, under the left Pap, between the 6th and 7th Rib of him the said Porter did strike and stab, giving then and there, &amp;c. one Mortal Wound, of the Breadth of half an Inch, and Depth of 5 Inches of which he instantly died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time charged, by Vertue of the Coroner's Inquisition, for the Wilful Murder of the said Porter</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person376">
                  John 
                  Galcoigne 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person376" type="surname" value="Galcoigne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of January, about 10 at Night, I and 3 more were going along <placeName id="t17410225-51-crimeloc220">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410225-51-crimeloc220" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410225-51-crimeloc220" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-off218 t17410225-51-crimeloc220"></join>, and saw 2 Men which proved to be the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-person377">
                  John 
                  Simkin 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person377" type="surname" value="Simkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knocking at the Three Crown's Door; immediately Simkin rushed on me, and knock'd me down, and hearing the Deceased's Voice in the House, as I lay on the Ground, I called him to assist me, but I did not see him till I saw him dead in the Rose and Crown Alehouse.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you see the Prisoner strike the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Galcoigne. No, I was fighting with Simkin.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you present when the Prisoner was before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Galcoigne. Yes, and this Tuck was shewn to him; he own'd it, and said it was given him by his Father to one Lloyd who went with him to Bromley, and that he brought it all the Way back to the Place where the Murder was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person378">
                  Henry 
                  Hollaly 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person378" type="surname" value="Hollaly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person378" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Headborough, belonging to Mile End Old Town On the 6th of January, I was in Company with the Deceased, and some others, and did not miss him out of the Company 'till I went away. I parted from the Company about 10 o'Clock, and going by the Rose and Crown, I saw 2 Men scuffling together; I went a little farther to the Anchor and Crown, and saw 2 other Men fighting. I turn'd about, and a Woman came out of the Rose and Crown, and said Porter was murder'd; I went into the House, and found him sitting by the Fireside, and the Prisoner standing by him: The Prisoner, said he, had been abused, and desired I would take his Part; the Deceased turn'd up his Eyes, and fell down; I saw some Blood on his Coat, and on stripping his Coat open, the Blood flow'd from him: I then ask'd the Prisoner if he had done it; and he said, he had been Fighting with him, and had done it.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was it before or after the Deceased fell from his Chair that this pass'd.</p>
               <p>Hollaly. I think it was after I had seen the Wound; I said Child, I hope you have not been Fighting and done this, and he said, yes, I have. After this, I search'd the Prisoner, but found no Weapon on him; upon that, I got a Candle and Lanthorn, and went to the Door, and a Person who was with me, found this naked Tuck, all dirty and bloody. I shew'd it to the Prisoner, and ask'd him if he knew it; but I was then deaf, and could not hear whether he made any Answer. The next Morning he was carried before Justice Ricards, and said there, that his Father lent that Weapon to Mr. Lloyd, of Bromley, who gave it back again into his Hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person379">
                  Sarah 
                  Campion 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person379" type="surname" value="Campion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person379" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person379" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming out of my own House, and saw the Deceased come out, and stand within the Step of the Three Crown Door. There were two Men fighting at the Door, and a third Man, which proved to be the Prisoner, stepp'd up between them; but the Deceased, push'd him off, and drove him by the Shoulders into the Rose and Crown, and never left him. Soon after this, I heard the Deceased's Wife scream out; I ran into the House, and saw the Deceased ( as I thought ) dead, and the Prisoner standing by the Fire. The next Morning the Prisoner was carried before Justice Ricards, and said, his Father lent the Weapon to Mr. Lloyd, of Bromley, that Lloyd gave him and another 6 d. a-piece, and a Tankard of Beer to see him Home, and that he brought the Tuck all the Way back himself.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you think that the Deceased push'd the Prisoner off in Order to keep the Peace?</p>
               <p>Campion. Yes, I believe it was to prevent his Interposing.</p>
               <p>Francis Green. On the 6th of January the Deceased was at my House, in Company with Mr.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174102250017"></xptr> Hollaly, and his Wife, and some other Neighbours. About 10 o'Clock, he left my House very sober, and in a short Time afterwards, I heard that he was kill'd, and carried into the Rose and Crown. I went there, and found him expiring, and the Prisoner standing by the Fire side; I search'd him, and found no Weapon on him, but presently this Tuck was brought in very dirty and bloody. I put the Prisoner and Simkin into the Cage, and I heard the Prisoner say, D - n you, I may thank you for this; Simkin, replied, You Rogue, Had you been my Lord Mayor, you would have done the same.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you ever hear the Prisoner own the Dagger</p>
               <p>Green. The first Time it was shewn to him, he deny'd it, but before the Justice, he own'd that Lloyd deliver'd it to him, and that he brought it all the Way to the Place where this happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person380">
                  Ann 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person380" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person380" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person380" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased's Widow My Husband had parted with the Company, and we were going Home to Bed; He went into the Rose and Crown, and I had hardly turn'd myself round, when I heard a Noise like 2 Men striving together; I turn'd into the Entry, and met my Husband holding the Prisoner. When I came in, my Husband let the Prisoner go, and said, There, that is he that has kill'd me, and pointed with his Finger to the Wound; he then fix'd his Eyes on the Ceiling, and never spoke Words more.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did your Husband speak loud enough for the Prisoner to hear, when he said, That is the Man?</p>
               <p>Porter. Yes; and the Prisoner said nothing at all to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person381">
                  Charles 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person381" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person381" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of January, the Deceased, and some other Friends had been at Supper: About 10 o'Clock, he left the Company, and in a few Minutes, News was brought that he was murdered. I went to the House where he was, and saw him dead, and the Prisoner standing by the Fire. We got a Light, and went out of Doors to look for the Weapon, and I pick'd up this Tuck all dirty and bloody, within six Yards of the Door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person382">
                  Sarah 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person382" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person382" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person382" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of January, coming by the Watch-House, I saw the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-person383">
                  John 
                  Simkin 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person383" type="surname" value="Simkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the Prisoner cried, and said, Oh! Mrs. Marsh, I am the Person that kill'd the Man!</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. How came you to go to the Watch-House?</p>
               <p>Marsh I live at Mile End, and going by the Watch-House, I saw a Croud, and look'd in. I ask'd the Prisoner what he was in there for, and he said, I am the Person that kill'd the Man</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you ever speak to the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Marsh. Yes, I serv'd his Father with Hay.</p>
               <p>Mr. Martin, Surgeon I was call'd to examine the Deceased, and to assist Mr. Woodward in opening the Body. We found a Wound about half an inch broad, between the 6th and 7th Rib, which was mortal, and on dilating the Thorax, and making an Incision in the Ribs, a large Quantity of Blood gush'd out, and we likewise found the Diaphragnia pass'd through. This Tuck was produced at the Opening of the Body, and by outward Inspection, tally'd exactly with the Wound.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person384">
                  Richard 
                  Peers 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person384" type="surname" value="Peers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person384" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next Door to the Rose and Crown, and hearing a Cry that Porter was murder'd, I ran in, and saw the Prisoner standing by the Fire-side; I said, sure young Touchbury, it is not you that have done this! He made no Answer, but the Deceased pointed to him, and said, That is he, and died instantly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person385">
                  Thomas 
                  Hiat 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person385" type="surname" value="Hiat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person385" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I ask'd the Deceased who did it, and he pointed to the Prisoner, and said, This is he: The Prisoner was close by him at the same Time and made no Answer to this.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you present when the Weapon was brought in?</p>
               <p>Hiat. Yes, and it was shewn to the Prisoner, but he deny'd that it was his.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person386">
                  Ephraim 
                  Holton 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person386" type="surname" value="Holton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person386" type="given" value="Ephraim"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mrs. Thorpe's, the Rose and Crown, and heard a Noise like Men fighting; presently the Deceased brought the Prisoner in seemingly by Force; but I did not hear him say any Thing.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Thorp. I keep the Rose and Crown. On the 6th of January, I went out of Doors, and saw the Prisoner and the Deceased scuffling together. The Prisoner had some Blood and Scratches on his Face, and without either Hat or Wig. The Deceased came into the House, and said, he was stuck, but I did not hear him charge the Prisoner with his Death.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you go in before the Prisoner and the Deceased?</p>

               <p>Thorp. Yes; and they followed me into the Entry.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you hear what the Deceased said in the Entry?</p>
               <p>Thorp. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person387">
                  John 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person387" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person387" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going from the Rose and Crown, to the Three Crowns, and on one Side of the Path, I saw the Deceased, and another, (whom the People said was Touchbury's Son) struggling together. There were Blows between them, but how many I can't tell. I went on a little farther, and saw Gascoigne and Simkin on the Ground. I took up Simkin, and went into the Three Crowns, where I saw the Prisoner sitting<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174102250018"></xptr> by the Fire-side, and the People said he had kill'd Porter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person388">
                  John 
                  Simkin 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person388" type="surname" value="Simkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person388" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday Night, I had done Work, and just at the Three-Crowns Door, Gascoigne tought with me, when we were on the Ground, he called Porter to assist him, and he came up and fell on young Mr. Touchbury.</p>
               <p>Councel. You were confin'd with the Prisoner, do you remember 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-person389">
                  Sarah 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person389" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person389" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person389" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's speaking to him?</p>
               <p>Simkin. No, I don't remember any Thing of that, She never spoke a Word that I heard. When I saw the Prisoner that Night, his Cheek was Bloody, and to the best of my Knowledge, Blood came out of his Ears.</p>
               <p>Councel. How long was Gascoigne engag'd with you, before he called the Deceased to his Assistance?</p>
               <p>Simkin. I had but one Blow before Porter came out; we were just going at it as he came out.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you on the Ground or not? you said just now you was on the Ground.</p>
               <p>Simkin. I was not quite down nor quite up; the Coat I had about me was enough to fling me down.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you not on your Back, and had not Gascoigne his Hand in your Collar?</p>
               <p>Simkin. Yes, he had his Hand in my Collar to be sure.</p>
               <p>Councel. If you was on the Ground how could you see what Porter was doing?</p>
               <p>Simkin. I was not quite down; - I was three Parts up, and three Parts down.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did not you and Gascoigne close together?</p>
               <p>Simkin. Yes, and when we were on the Ground, he was uppermost, but that was after Porter came out.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you remember the Prisoners having a Dagger.</p>
               <p>Simkin Yes, I went with him and Lloyd to Bronnly, and Lloyd gave it into his Hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person390">
                  John 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person390" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person390" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the Watch House with the Prisoner and saw that his Face was bloody, his Head was broke about his Temples, there was some Blood in his Ear, and a Bruise in his Neck. His Cloaths were very dirty, and look'd as if he had been tumbled in the Dirt. I have known him ever since his Birth, and never knew that he was quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410225-51-person391">
                  Joseph 
                  Chamberlain 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person391" type="surname" value="Chamberlain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person391" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-person392">
                  Thomas 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person392" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person392" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17410225-51-person393">
                  John 
                  Ring 
               <interp inst="t17410225-51-person393" type="surname" value="Ring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person393" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>Francis Green. I perceived only a little Blood on the prisoner's which might come from the Deceased.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17410225-51-verdict221" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-verdict221" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-verdict221" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty. Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17410225-51-punish222" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-punish222" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410225-51-punish222" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410225-51-defend372 t17410225-51-punish222"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
