<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410701-12">
               <interp inst="t17410701-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-12" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410701"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-12" type="date" value="17410701"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410701-12-off55-c106" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-defend131 t17410701-12-off55 t17410701-12-verdict58"></join>
         
               <p>17. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-defend131" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Scott 
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-defend131" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-defend131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-defend131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17410701-12-defloc54">St. Mary Stratford Bow</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-defloc54" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Stratford Bow"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-defloc54" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-defend131 t17410701-12-defloc54"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410701-12-off55" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-off55" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-off55" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Mare of a black Colour, val. 8 l.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-victim133" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Wash 
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-victim133" type="surname" value="Wash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-victim133" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-victim133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-off55 t17410701-12-victim133"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            ; <rs id="t17410701-12-cd56" type="crimeDate">May 31st</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-off55 t17410701-12-cd56"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-person134">
                  Thomas 
                  Wash 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person134" type="surname" value="Wash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person134" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have nothing to say but that I lost a black Mare from <placeName id="t17410701-12-crimeloc57">Colengale, in the County of Essex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-crimeloc57" type="placeName" value="Colengale, in the County of Essex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-12-crimeloc57" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-off55 t17410701-12-crimeloc57"></join>. I can't tell what became of it, but I afterwards found it at Mr. Edwards's the Bell at Bow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-person135">
                  Edward 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person135" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person135" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 31st of May, between 5 and 6 in the Evening, the Prisoner brought a black Mare faddled and bridled, to my House, the Bell at Bow. He left her with me all Night, and went away to lie at another House. The next Morning he came to fetch her away, and when she came to the Stable Door, I seeing her Shoes were bad, immediately suspected her to be stolen, and stopp'd her. When I had stopped her, the Prisoner came into the Yard, and I asked him whether the Mare was his own or not; he said he had borrowed it of his Master Smith, who lived at Halstead in Essex, that his own Name was Smith, and he was going to Hounslow to a Kinsman of his Master's. We were not satisfied with this, but took him before a Justice at Bow, and there he denied that his Name was Smith, and would not tell any Name, for he said if he did it would be the worse for him. The Justice then committed him to New-Prison, and I had the Mare cried at Rumford and Epping, and my next Door Neighbour, Mr. Cook the Collar-Maker, sent a Letter into the Country. On the Friday following, Mr. Wash came to my House, and owned the Mare, and had her away again.</p>
               <p>Wash. The Mare which I had from Edwards was the same that I lost.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from Bow is the Place where you lost your Mare?</p>
               <p>Wash. It is about 40 Miles, and I miss'd her at 5 o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-person136">
                  Robert 
                  Lay 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person136" type="surname" value="Lay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person136" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Neighbour of Wash's and designed to have come to Town with him to see after the Mare, but Business prevented me, so I sat out the Day after him. When I came to London, hearing that the Mare was at Bow, I sent to the Spread-Eagle in Grace-Church Street to inform Wash of it, and he and I and 
               <persName id="t17410701-12-person137">
                  John 
                  Darling 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person137" type="surname" value="Darling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went together to Bow. We found the Mare at the Bell, and I knew her to be same which Mr. Wash had lost. She was a black Mare, and had a white Spot on her Flank.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-person138">
                  John 
                  Darling 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person138" type="surname" value="Darling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with Mr. Wash and the last Witness when they found the Mare at the Bell at Bow. It was a black Mare, and I am positive that she was the same that Mr. Wash lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-12-person139">
                  Richard 
                  Mander 
               <interp inst="t17410701-12-person139" type="surname" value="Mander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person139" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried the Prisoner before Justice Haggard, and he refused to tell his Name, to I took him back, and carried him again several Times, but he would not let us know his Name, so he was committed as a Person unknown.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I came up to London to see for Work, but there being none to be got, I left my Things, at Bow, and returned Home. When I got Home my Friends persuaded me to fetch my Things away, and not to go to work. My Father follows the farming Business, and gave me the liberty to take a Horse whenever I would. I got up early in the Morning, in order to come away, and there were some Horses in the Road, which I thought to be my Father's, so I made bold to go into the Stable and take a Bridle and Saddle, and one of those Horses. I desire Mr. Wash may be ask'd concerning my Character.</p>
               <p>Wash. He is a Neighbour's Son. His Friends bear a very good Character, and I never heard any harm of him before this.</p>
               <p>Q. Does his Father live so near you, that your Horses run together?</p>
               <p>Wash. No, they never go together, and I live half a Mile from him.</p>
               <p>Lay. I don't know a great deal of the Prisoner; his Friends bear a very good Character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lived Servant with this Man.</p>
               <p>Lay. He did live with me about 3 quarters of a Year, and was a very good Servant to me. <rs id="t17410701-12-verdict58" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-verdict58" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17410701-12-punish59" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-12-punish59" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-12-defend131 t17410701-12-punish59"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
