<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-37">
               <interp inst="t17421208-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-37" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-37" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-37-off193-c281" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-defend352 t17421208-37-off193 t17421208-37-verdict195"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-37-off193-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-defend353 t17421208-37-off193 t17421208-37-verdict195"></join>
         
               <p>38, 39. + 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-defend352" type="defendantName">
                  Lot 
                  Cavenagh 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend352" type="surname" value="Cavenagh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend352" type="given" value="Lot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             *, and + 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-defend353" type="defendantName">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend353" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend353" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-defend353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , were indicted for <rs id="t17421208-37-off193" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-off193" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-off193" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-37-victim355" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Taylor 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-37-victim355" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-37-victim355" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-37-victim355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-off193 t17421208-37-victim355"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him one Fustian Frock with 12 Plate Buttons, Value 40 s. one white Duffel Coat, Value 15 s. one Cloth Waistcoat, Value 5 s. one Pair of Buckskin Breeches, Value 10 s, one Perriwig, Value 10 s. a Hat, Value 5 s. and a Pair of Silver Buckles, Value 6 s.
            </rs> Oct. 4.</p>
               <p>* Lot Cavenagh, was an Accomplice with, and Evidence against, 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person356">
                  James 
                  Lawlor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person356" type="surname" value="Lawlor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person356" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person357">
                  James 
                  Leonard 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person357" type="surname" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person357" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , condemn'd for robbing 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person358">
                  James 
                  Lines 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person358" type="surname" value="Lines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person358" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Denmark-Street. See their Trial, 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person359">
                  PERRY 
                  Mayor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person359" type="surname" value="Mayor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person359" type="given" value="PERRY"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Sessions 3. No. 127.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person360">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person360" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person360" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday, the 3d of October, I dressed my self to take a Walk, and went to one Beswell's in Tyburn Road; there I met with 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person361">
                  William 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person361" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person361" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; says he, How do you do? won't you drink with me? We went into the back Room, and that Man was there, I think his Name is Cavenagh ; we staid there till between two and three o'Clock; they persuaded me to go along with them, and we went to one Gascoign's, in Hockley in the Hole; they asked me to stay Supper; which I agreed to: We went up one Pair of Stairs, and there was that Woman, the Prisoner; I staid till nigh eleven o'Clock, and as I was coming away, it began to rain, so I did not care for going Home that Night, and asked if I could lie there; they told me I might; says I to the Woman of the House, Will you please to call me up betimes. (for being a Butcher I was obliged to get up early to go to Market.) She said she would, but I happened to get up my self; I believe it was then a little after three: I went out and pulled the Door after me; I had got but a little Way in <placeName id="t17421208-37-crimeloc194">Hockley in the Hole</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-37-crimeloc194" type="placeName" value="Hockley in the Hole"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-37-crimeloc194" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-off193 t17421208-37-crimeloc194"></join> Road , before the two Prisoners attack'd me; Cavenagh presented a Pistol to me, and bid me stand and deliver my Money; and she stood over me with a Hanger in her Hand. I said I had but Three-pence. (He took me into a convenient Place that goes from Hockley in the Hole Road to Saffron-Hill.) Says he, Damn you, if you speak a Word, I will blow your Brains out . Damn him, says she, shoot him, for he knows us; but he would not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person362">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person362" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person362" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . God forgive you, Billy.</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. He took my Hat and Wig off, and she stood with her Apron up, and he threw them into her Lap, and then she bid him take my Cloaths off, which he did. - He took from me a Dussel Great-Coat, a Silver Plate-button'd Frock, a black Cloth Waistcoat, a Pair of Buckskin Breeches, and a Pair of Silver Buckles; he took all but my Buckles, and she took them out of my Shoes: Says she, Do not let him have his Wedges, for they are Silver. After he was taken up, I saw him at the New Goal, on the other Side of the Water, with my Frock upon his Back, and my Wig upon his Head.</p>
               <p>Court. How do you know the Prisoners were the Persons that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . It was a Moon-light Night, and I saw their Faces as plain as I do now.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. Have not you and I been as intimate as two own Brothers?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . I have seen him two or three Times with one Wm Wilson; I was no father intimate with him than being acquainted by drinking together, and saying, how do you do, if I happen'd to meet him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to let you go away after they had robbed you?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . I do not know; it was their good Will not to Murder me; if they had killed me, I could not have gone away then.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080026"></xptr>Q. Where did you go afterwards?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. I went back again to the House; where I lay: I do not know the Man, but the Woman is here.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. Billy, you know the Man very well, Did not you take a Lodging there for me?</p>
               <p>Q. Were not you and she well acquainted together at that House?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. I never lived with her - I have been pretty conversant with her; but I never was in Company with her there, till that Sunday Night.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. He was frequently with me at that House. - This Gascoign is a Thief-taker: Wm Taylor gave Lot Cavenagh the Coat for Money that he owed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person363">
                  Wm 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person363" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person363" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never owed Lot Cavenagh a Farthing in my Life.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. This is an entire Piece of Jealousy, because he thinks I have been great with this Man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you and she ever lie together?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. I believe I have lain with her, but there is no great Matter in that, for Whores will lie with any Body. Every Body knows both of them to be Thieves; they have robbed me twice. - I have been Familiar with her, but I never took a Lodging for her.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. The first Lodging he ever took me to, was at this Gascoign's , the Thief-taker, and he allowed me nine Shillings a Week.</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. I never did take a Lodging for her, nor allow her nine Shillings a Week.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. Have you not paid Gascoign Money that I have run up, when you have been absent?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. No.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. He has been jealous of me a great while, and I cannot say, but at last I gave him Reason to be so: I cannot say but I did: He has swore several Robberies against me out of Revenge; he swore that I robbed him of seven Shillings, and has had a Warrant out against me for assaulting him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person364">
                  Alice 
                  Barron 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person364" type="surname" value="Barron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person364" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to Mr Gascoign, at the Corner of Summer's-Street , in Hockley in the Hole .</p>
               <p>Prisoners. That is Gascoign's Wife the Thief-taker.</p>
               <p>Barron. The two Prisoners at the Bar had a Room at my Master's House about a Fortnight; and one Sunday Evening about two Months ago; the Prisoner Cavenagh , this Wm Taylor, and Mr Wilson's Son, came to our Door in a Coach; the Coach happened to turn over at our Door; when the Coach was turned up again, and the Coachman gone, Cavenagh asked Mr Taylor if he would not go up to Supper; he said, he did not care if he did; they went up Srairs, and I fetched them two Half-Gallons of Beer; about half an Hour after Ten, or thereabouts, Mr Taylor was for going Home; then it rained; said Cavenagh, Pray do not go Home, Mr Taylor. Mr Taylor said, he must be up early in the Morning; said Cavenagh. You may get up soon enough in the Morning if you stay here: Then he concluded to stay, and desired I would call him. I told him, I would if I could. Cavenagh had a Room for himself, and the other Prisoner, which he paid Half a Crown a Week for: Cavenagh, and that Woman 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person365">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person365" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person365" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , went into their own Room, in order, as I supposed, to go to Bed; Mr Cavenagh made a great Noise for a Candle, and said, he would have a Candle if he paid a Penny for it; when Mr Taylor was in Bed, I went into his Room, took half his Candle, and gave it to Cavenagh; then I went to Bed, and saw no more of the Prisoners from that Time to this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Wm Taylor when he returned?</p>
               <p>Baron . Yes; - I believe it was about four o'Clock: - He had his Shoes and Stockings and Shirt on. - Nothing else. - When he knocked at the Door, I asked, who was there? he said, For God's sake let me in, I am robbed: When he came in, I said, How came you to be robbed? said he, Lot Cavenagh and Dilly have robbed me. - Dilly, that is, 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person366">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person366" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person366" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             : I went up Stairs into their Room to see if they were there, for I did not know they were gone out: When I came into the Room, there was no Body there; and I saw that they had not been in Bed at all, for the Bed was smooth, and not tumbled. - I helped to make it just before they came Home: I looked about for a Pair of Pistols, and a Hanger, that Cavenagh had, and they were all gone; I saw the Hanger in the Kitchen about three o'Clock that Sunday in the Afternoon, and she carried it up Stairs; as to the Pistols, I believe he had them in his Pocket: - My Master Gascoign lent Mr Taylor his Cloaths and a Wig and Hat to go Home in.</p>
               <p>Cor. Taylor. Did not Wm Taylor take a Lodging for me in Broad St Giles's?</p>
               <p>Baron. Never, that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that the Prisoner Taylor and the Witness ever liv'd together as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Baron . Not that I know of; they are acquainted with one another , and I believe were great together, but did not live as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. Is Gascoign a married Man?</p>
               <p>Baron . No, he is not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080027"></xptr>Lot Cavenagh. Does Mr Taylor owe Gascoign any Money for this Woman's Maintenance?</p>
               <p>Baron. I never knew that he did.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. Whose Child is that which is at Home? Is it Gascoign's or not?</p>
               <p>Baron. No, it is not, it is my own; I have a Husband, but he does not live with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person367">
                  James 
                  Webster 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person367" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr Taylor , the Prosecutor, hearing that Lot Cavenagh was on the other Side of the Water, informed me that he was robbed of his Cloaths in Hockley in the Hole , by Lot Cavenagh and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person368">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person368" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person368" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was waiting at the Bird-Cage in Southwark for Cavenagh , and saw him go by, and assisted in the taking of him; he had a Pistol charged with Powder and Paper, but no Ball; he had a Wig on, which Mr Taylor said he believed was his Wig. This is the Frock that Lot Cavenagh had on when he was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person369">
                  Alice 
                  Baron 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person369" type="surname" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person369" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen this Frock several Times. This young Man, 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person370">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person370" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person370" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had it on that Sunday Night at our House, and a white Duffel Coat over it.</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. I had this Frock on that Morning I was robbed. This is the Frock they took from me.</p>
               <p>- Robinson . To the best of my Knowledge, this is the Frock that was taken off Lot Cavenagh's Back before the Justice.</p>
               <p>- Hammond. I saw this Coat upon Cavenagh's Back once; there was a Pistol taken out of his Pocket when he was taken; there was Powder and Paper in the Pistol , but no Ball. This Hanger was taken out of Cordelia Taylor's Lodging in Mint-Street in the Mint.</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . She had a Hanger in her Hand when I was robbed, but I cannot swear to this Hanger .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person371">
                  Alice 
                  Baron 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person371" type="surname" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person371" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Hanger Lot Cavenagh had at our House , was almost as big again as this , with a Buckshorn handle to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person372">
                  George 
                  Holderness 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person372" type="surname" value="Holderness"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person372" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was present at the taking of Cavenagh : This Frock was taken from him; this Wig I took off his Head; he had a Pistol with him loaded.</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . I cannot swear to the Wig, but here is the Barber that made it.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. I know very well that I had both the Coat and the Wig from you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person373">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person373" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person373" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He was to give 3 l. 10 s. for them both.</p>

               <p>Lot Cavenagh . I had them of him for Money he owed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person374">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person374" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person374" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are all Thief-takers.</p>
               <p>Wm Palmer Hind . After we had taken Cavenagh, we went into Mint-Street, where the other Prisoner lodged, and broke open the Door, and there was this Woman fitting by the Fire , and this Hanger lay upon the Drawers.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. I desire to have my Lances and other Instruments again, that are used in Surgery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person375">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person375" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person375" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person375" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He took five Yards of Lace from me, and an Ell of Cambrick. - I do not know his Name, I only know him to be a Thief-taker.</p>
               <p>Hind. I have none of her Goods; I never touched any Thing in the Room, but the Hanger and a Knife.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person376">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person376" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person376" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It it very hard that we should suffer upon the Account of this Coat that Taylor gave to Cavenagh ; we have Witnesses that will give a different Account of the Matter; it is very improbable we should go to rob a Man that we were so intimate with, and who knew where to find us every Hour of the Day, and not murder him; it is plain they only do this to take away our Lives for the Sake of the Reward. This Sunday, about Eleven o'Clock, Lot comes into the Room with this Frock, says I, Lord! what has be paid you the old Score? Yes, said he; I might as well take this, as take nothing. Says I, I believe it will be a very dear Coat to you. We went out directly, and shut the Door; this was at Gascoign's . Then I went into Parker's-Lane , to one Mr Waper's , who keeps a Chandler's-Shop, and asked them for a Lodging, but they had none; we went over to the Golden-Hart Alehouse, and they had no Bed; we staid there drinking till past Three, and went over to the Chandler's-Shop, and staid till near Five, and left the Coat there, which Cavenagh had given into my Hand, and went to another Place, and said to the Woman, will you let this Man and I lie down upon the Bed? Accordingly we did lie down, and the Woman went out to work, and between Nine and Ten she came back, and we went to the Chandler's-Shop again, and then I gave the Coat to Lot Cavenagh . When Lot and you have come Home together, I have said, Billy, you bite your Lips upon the Account of Lot Cavenagh's locking so hard at me. Do not you know Lot has came up when I have been in Bed, and I have asked him who should treat, he or I? And sometimes one has treated, and sometimes the other has treated. You have oftentimes called me Bitch, as I have called you Names; and you have told me I have done so and so with Lot; you were as likely as ever Lot Cavenagh was, and I thought you as agreeable. Did not you give this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080028"></xptr> Coat to Lot Cavenagh? and now you say he took it from you against your will. You have said that Lot Cavenagh was a Fellow of so bad a Character, that if he was taken up for any Thing he would certainly be hanged. Did not you lay a Plot against him? Gascoign was to be Thief-taker, and you were to be Prosecutor, and I was to swear a Robbery against Lot Cavenagh; you know this to be true; you have sworn several Robberies and Assaults against me: It the Man did but look at me you were jealous ; if I was absent but a Minute, you would say, what has Lot been bussing you? What has Lot been kissing you? You Bitch, where have you been? &amp;c. You have charged a Woman with robbing you of your Silver Buckles, when you have thrown them down the House of Office. Consider the Nights you and I have lain at 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person377">
                  Jack 
                  Gascoign 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person377" type="surname" value="Gascoign"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person377" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's : You have given me Reasons enough to be jealous of you, as I have given you to be jealous of me: I am a fine stout Woman to hold a Hanger in my Hand to kill a Man, especially as I have lain ten Months by your Side: O! Billy , how can you be so base?</p>
               <p>Court. Have you any Witnesses?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person378">
                  James 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person378" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person378" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person379">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person379" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person379" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person379" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the Prosecutor have lived together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person380">
                  Charles 
                  Rivington 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person380" type="surname" value="Rivington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person380" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . About five or six Weeks ago, the Prosecutor and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person381">
                  Jack 
                  Gascoign 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person381" type="surname" value="Gascoign"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person381" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to enquire for Little Dilly: says he, The Bitch has stript me last Night of all my Cloaths, and run away with them. - He said, G - d damn the Bitch, when I was in Bed and asleep, she * run away with all my Things. Said I to the Prosecutor and Gascoign, What do you mean by running away with them? And this Gentleman, Wm Taylor, and Mr Gascoign did suppose, that when he was asleep, the little Bitch took his Cloaths and threw them out of Window: I believe she did rob him of his Cloaths, but not in the Manner he says. I come to do Justice; I come without Fee or Reward.</p>
               <p>* When she was called up to Judgment, she said, The Truth was, that seeing the Prosecutor in Bed with another Woman, in Revenge she took away his Cloaths, and gave them afterwards to Cavenagh .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person382">
                  George 
                  Waper 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person382" type="surname" value="Waper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person382" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 23 d of September, one Sunday Night about the Hour of Twelve, Lot Cavenagh and that Woman (the Prisoner) I never saw her before then, came to my House and asked for a Lodging; I told her I had none; we went to the Golden-Hart Alehouse, over-against my House, and they had no Bed; so we sat together till between 3 and 4 in the Morning, and then we went over to my House; the Watch went 4 when they left my House: That Woman had a Bundle in a Bird's-eye Handkerchief, and left it there till they came again about Eight in the Morning: She opened the Handkerchief, and took out a Coat or a Frock, with Plate Buttons, and gave it to Cavenagh - I am a Glass-Grinder; I live in Parker's Lane; my Wife keeps a Chandler's-Shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person383">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Mac Guire 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person383" type="surname" value="Mac Guire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person383" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person383" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Waper's: Lot Cavenagh and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person384">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person384" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person384" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into my Landlord's about Twelve o'Clock on Sunday Night, the 23d of September . - I have a Note here which I marked for a Memorandum, because I paid some Money that Night: I cannot read the Note.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you cannot tell what Sunday, only that it was one Sunday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person385">
                  Mac 
                  Guire 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person385" type="surname" value="Guire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person385" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Yes, I can; it was Sunday the 23d of September, [the 23d of September was Friday] they asked for a Lodging, and my Landlord said, he had none: I went with my Landlord and his Wife, and the two Prisoners, to the Golden-Hart Alehouse; I believe we had eight Pots of Beer there, and staid till past two o'Clock; I went from thence to my Landlord's House again, and there I sat till past Three; that Woman had a Bird's-Eye Handkerchief, with something in it, and left it there, and staid till the Watch came Four, and then they went out; and this Man and Woman came for the Handkerchief again, and she untied the Handkerchief, and I saw her give him a whitish Coat out of it, with Buttons that looked like Plate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person386">
                  Michael
                   Mac Guire
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person386" type="surname" value="Mac Guire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person386" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw them there till Four o'Clock in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person387">
                  Daniel 
                  Maddox 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person387" type="surname" value="Maddox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person387" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person388">
                  Anne 
                  Maddox 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person388" type="surname" value="Maddox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person388" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person388" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were called , but not examined, because they could only give an Account of what they heard from Gascoign , which was not spoke in the Presence of the Prosecutor .</p>
               <p>Court. When did you first see these People after this Robbery?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. It was about three Weeks after they took the Things from me, that I saw him in the New Jail with the Coat on, but not the Wig on.</p>
               <p>Court. I ask you, whether or no, from the Time you lost the Cloaths, that you did not hear, before Cavenagh was taken, that he used to wear your Cloaths?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080029"></xptr>Q. Did you ever see 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person389">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person389" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person389" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person389" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             after this Fact, at your Mother's Back-door?</p>
               <p>Wm Taylor. No; I never saw them till they were taken up.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. It is a likely Thing I should rob this Person, when we were so intimate together, and should wear his Cloaths!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person390">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person390" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person390" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That Witness [ Maddox ] says, she and her Husband can save both our Lives, if they were to speak the Truth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person391">
                  Mary 
                  Shrub 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person391" type="surname" value="Shrub"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person391" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live within two or three Doors of Mr. Waper's, and on Sunday the 23d of September, my Husband being out very late, I went there for some Small-Beer, and saw 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person392">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person392" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person392" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person392" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there with a Bundle, but what was in it, I cannot tell; I remember it was the 23d of September, because my Sister was brought to Bed that Day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person393">
                  Thomas 
                  Boyd 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person393" type="surname" value="Boyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person393" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Marshal's-Court Officer: I have heard Mr Taylor the Prosecutor, very often say, that he was robbed in Mr Gascoign's House, by that Creature Dilly, as they call her; and they have been as intimate together as can be; the next Day after Taylor was robbed, Alice told me, that 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person394">
                  Billy 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person394" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person394" type="given" value="Billy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was robbed; How? said I; said she, This Dilly and Lot Cavenagh went to Bed together, and Taylor and another Girl were together: and Dilly got into his Room, and took his Cloaths away; and said she, They must get out at the Window; she opened the Casement, and shewed me there was a little Piece of Brick broke out by the Window, and said, To be sure they must get out that Way, because the Doors were fastened; it was the Fore-Room, up one Pair of Stairs, where Lot Cavenagh and 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person395">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person395" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person395" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person395" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lay. 
               <persName id="t17421208-37-person396">
                  Alice 
                  Baron 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person396" type="surname" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person396" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is a comical Sort of a Bitch, for she has got a Husband, and does not live with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person397">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person397" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person397" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person397" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe there is a Gentleman there, (one of the Jury) that has seen Wm Taylor and I together.</p>
               <p>Juryman. I have seen them several Times together; he does not deny that himself.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Green. - (She was ordered to look for Wm Taylor, who stood just by her, but held his Hat a little before his Face) I cannot see him, though I know the young Man very well. - He is pitted with the Small-Pox. - He is a tall, thin Man. - He wears sometimes a light Wig, and sometimes a dark one. - This is the Man, I see him now: I saw him come into a House in Shorts-Gardens , where they sell Gin, and another Creature with him: The Woman of the House asked him, What he designed to do with little Dilly? says he, I have nothing to do with her, only the Thief-takers will oblige me to it: Damn her says he, I do not design to do any Thing to her, but the Bitch was so wicked as to take my Coat off the Bed, and carry it to an Irish Fellow.</p>
               <p>Lot Cavenagh. He did owe me thirty-five Shillings, but we were so intimate, that I did not care what I did for him: but lately I did want to make it come to 40 s. that I might arrest him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-37-person398">
                  Cordelia 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17421208-37-person398" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person398" type="given" value="Cordelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Gascoign has said, there is Lot Cavenagh , he must be hanged, and we may as well get the Money as any Body else; he may be a Stag for us, then he will bring in two or three more.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17421208-37-verdict195" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-verdict195" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17421208-37-punish196" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-37-punish196" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-defend352 t17421208-37-punish196"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-37-defend353 t17421208-37-punish196"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
