<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490411-22">
               <interp inst="t17490411-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-22" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490411"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-22" type="date" value="17490411"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490411-22-off97-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-defend146 t17490411-22-off97 t17490411-22-verdict101"></join>
         
               <note type="special">[Note: this edition of the Proceedings was misdated on the original title page. The correct dates for this meeting of the court are MAY 11, 12 and 13, 1749.]</note>
               <p>341. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-defend146" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Penoroy 
                  <interp inst="t17490411-22-defend146" type="surname" value="Penoroy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-defend146" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-defend146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17490411-22-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape
            </rs> on the body of 
               
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-victim148" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Batty 
                  <interp inst="t17490411-22-victim148" type="surname" value="Batty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-victim148" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-victim148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-off97 t17490411-22-victim148"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17490411-22-viclabel98" type="occupation">an infant between nine and ten years of age</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-victim148 t17490411-22-viclabel98"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490411-22-cd99" type="crimeDate">Mar. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-off97 t17490411-22-cd99"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person149">
                  Sarah 
                  Batty 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person149" type="surname" value="Batty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person149" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the mother of the child. She was born the 21st of January in the hard frost, it was nine years old last January. I live at the <placeName id="t17490411-22-crimeloc100">sign of the Crown, near the Vinegar Merchant's, in Worship street, near Hog-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490411-22-crimeloc100" type="placeName" value="sign of the Crown, near the Vinegar Merchant's, in Worship street, near Hog-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490411-22-crimeloc100" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-off97 t17490411-22-crimeloc100"></join>. The child did not complain of any hurt till the Friday after the 5th of March. I asked her what was the matter? She said, she was sore, and then complained sadly. I applied fuller's earth to her, thinking that would cool her, looking upon the disorder to be the scalding of her water.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you inspect the parts ?</p>
               <p>S. Batty . She appeared very red. She told me there was something more, for something ran from her ; she showed me a cloth she had put to her that night , which I have here; her shift was the same . I was surprized, and sent for a midwife who lived near me that afternoon; who, upon seeing her, told me, she feared the child had been abused by a man, for she had the foul disease. I would not believe any such thing, saying the child never went out of my house , and I had but two men lodged in the house, who I thought would never be guilty of such a thing; I thought I could trust my life with either. When she came again on the Tuesday, I said, I hoped the child was better, for she was easier; but my neighbour told me she was a great deal worse; and desired me to apply to a proper Doctor. Then I applied to Dr. Wathen , he is a Man-midwife and Doctor; I told him I thought my child had over-strained herself; he looked at her and said the child is foul. I was very much surprized, because she was never from under my care; he said it must be through the abuse of a man. The child still denied that ever a man had meddled with her, because, as she told me afterwards, he had threaten'd her life if she did tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person150">
                  Mary 
                  Maclemara 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person150" type="surname" value="Maclemara"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person150" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have had many children, and have laid many women. The mother sent for me on the 10th of March; she told me her child was very bad and had a running upon her. I looked at her shift , it was as stiff as buckram with corrupted matter. She said she had had a strain. A strain indeed , said I, the child is foul; said I, it is through the abuse of a man: said she, I have but two men in my house, and I never trust my child out of my house . She desired I would come of the Sunday; but I did not go till Tuesday the 14th. She said the child was better. I searched her by order of the Doctor the 18th.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find the child then?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . She was very red; I saw the running come down from out of her body.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think was the cause of it?</p>
               <p>Maclemara. I do really believe it was done by the abuse of some man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904110008"></xptr>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing a grown man had laid with a girl about nine years old; is it possible it should not be shewn by her walking before this time?</p>
               <p>Maclemara. I should think it must.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any swelling?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she torn?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you known as bad symptoms as that child's, which only proceeded from heat and strains?</p>
               <p>Maclemara. No, no; it could not be done by a strain; it was such a gross humour that it was impossible.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear of children being so without the abuse of a man?</p>
               <p>Maclemara. I have heard talk of such things, but I never saw such a case.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never know girls at fourteen or fifteen years of age that have had gleetings and runnings upon them, that proceeded from strains?</p>
               <p>Maclemara. I cannot say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was this child's bedfellow?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Batty. Have not you a son about 15 years of age?</p>
               <p>S. Batty. Yes, I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not frequently lie along with this girl?</p>
               <p>S. Batty. I, having a large family, have laid them in one bed sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time?</p>
               <p>S. Batty. He did not lie with her that week she was hurt; nor can I say he did the week before. They being brother and sister, I did not think any harm in so doing; he is now in court ready to be searched, if required.</p>
               <p>Q. to Maclemara . Did you look upon the linen?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What colours did you observe there?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . There was red and white mixed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no green?</p>
               <p>Maclemara . I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person151">
                  Jonathan 
                  Wathen 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person151" type="surname" value="Wathen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person151" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am an apprentice to my brother. I attended the child more than he did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been an apprentice?</p>
               <p>Wathen . About four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you attended any in the foul disease?</p>
               <p>Wathen . Yes, many, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account what you know of this child;</p>
               <p>Wathen . About the beginning of March last, the parent brought the child to our house; and talked of a rape committed on her, and that she had the soul distemper. Upon which my brother and I examined the clothes that had received the matter that came from her; and from its quantity, colour, and malignity , is it really the foul disease in both our opinions ; upon which we did prescribe things proper for her.</p>
               <p>Q. How is the child now?</p>
               <p>Wathen . All the bad symptoms are abated, and the child in a good way of recovery; I attended her ever since, and she has got a running on her now.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour is it?</p>
               <p>Wathen . White; which is what we apprehend a very good colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever inspect the parts of the child ?</p>
               <p>Wathen. Yes , my brother and I inspected her last Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find her?</p>
               <p>Wathen . The external lips of the womb are extended beyond their natural dimensions; the internal parts were very much inflamed, which, I believe was from the acrimony of the matter. I saw the running proceeding from the womb.</p>
               <p>Q. What was this matter?</p>
               <p>Wathen . The soul disease , very bad indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. By what means were the parts extended?</p>
               <p>Wathen . I believe by carnal copulation with a man .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think there could be the foul disease given to any child without penetration?</p>
               <p>Wathen . No; not to make its appearance in that manner .</p>
               <p>Q. Could there be any such thing acted on a child of that age, as a penetration without being lacerated by a man grown up?</p>
               <p>Wathen . Yes, Sir, I really think there may. I believe a man may copulate with a child of that age by introducing himself a little way without a laceration.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by a little way?</p>
               <p>Wathen . Far enough for emissio .</p>
               <p>Q. Are there not other means of communicating the soul disease than by penetration?</p>
               <p>Wathen . Yes; but then it would not make its appearance in this kind.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not possible that a small degree of disorder may be communicated without emissio , the man being foul?</p>
               <p>Wathen . That is not an impossible thing; there are many who catch diseases of this sort where there is no running.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904110009"></xptr>Q. If a man has a running, can that communicate itself to a child without emissio ?</p>
               <p>Wathen . Yes, it may .</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Batty. Do you know Mr. Herson , the Attorney?</p>
               <p>S. Batty . Yes, I do. He was concerned for me; he acted by my husband's and my advice, because the prisoner's friends wanted to make it up; but my husband would never yield to it. They offer'd us ten pounds upon the nail, and to pay all costs and charges.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person152">
                  Mary 
                  Batty 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person152" type="surname" value="Batty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person152" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the infant, sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the person that hurt you?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. The man in a white coat at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account of what he did to you?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. I had been up stairs to shift me, and had broke the tag of my lace, so that I could not lace myself. The woman below said, come to me and I'll lace you. I went down into her chamber; and when I was going up again the prisoner called to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. He said, come hither, I want to speak with you; I'll give you some money. He wanted a pint of ale, but I did not care to draw it for him, for he owed my mother some money. I went to him for the money he said he would give me; he was laid down on his bed in his own room; he took hold of me and laid me on the bed, and put one hand on my mouth, and with the other unbuttoned his breeches, and I thought he ran his double fist up my body.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you feel any thing wet then?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. Yes, I thought he made water in me. He told me, that if I told my father or mother, he would make them half murder me, and if they did not he would quite.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was this?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. It was on a Sunday between eleven and twelve o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mother then?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. She was below stairs then; the house was full of people.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not cry out?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. He held his hand to my mouth and I was almost strangled; and as he had threatened me, I was afraid to tell afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after this?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. On the Friday following, my mother thought I walked comically. My mother said, what is the matter with you. Said I, I am so sore I cannot walk. Says she, why don't you make a plaister of fuller's earth, and put it to you. She went up stairs into her own room , and I followed her; she looked at me, and was frightened to see what came from me; then she sent for the midwife.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pair of stairs was it up where he used you so?</p>
               <p>M. Batty . Two pair of stairs, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How many rooms on a floor?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. There are two rooms on a floor; there is a lodger and his wife on the first floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they at home?</p>
               <p>M. Batty . They were dressing there dinner, I went to her to be laced. This was under the room where the prisoner used me so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep your bed upon this?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. Yes, I did; I was once so bad I could not get out of my bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you once looking out at the window, and your mother called you away; telling you to keep private, or that you would swear your father's or mother's life away instead of the prisoner's?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. No, she never said any such thing. I know nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17490411-22-person153">
                  Frances 
                  Bletsoe 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person153" type="surname" value="Bletsoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person153" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. Yes, Sir, she lived servant with my mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep your bed before, or after that Friday your mother searched you?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. I lay a bed a good while on the Wednesday, but I did not say what it was for.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this was done was it, before you went down stairs?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. I believe it was about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry when you went down ?</p>
               <p>M. Batty. Yes, I did, but it was a very cold day; and when my mother asked me what I cried for, I said I was a cold.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Batty. Did the prisoner owe you any money at this time?</p>
               <p>S. Batty. Yes, he did, about 25 shillings, and has not paid me since; it was for victuals, drink, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Batty. Did you put a clean shift on between the Sunday and the Friday following?</p>
               <p>M. Batty . No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. This is a malicious prosecution; a piece of spite: I know nothing at all of it: I never had a pint of beer at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person154">
                  Frances 
                  Bletsoe 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person154" type="surname" value="Bletsoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person154" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I lived with Mr. Batty in March last.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell us what you know of this matter?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904110010"></xptr>Bletsoe . On the 19th of March, Mrs. Batty said to the child, when you come upon the trial, be sure to say, that I sent you to see what it was o' clock, and it wanted three or four minutes of eleven; and she bid her say it was done when she went up to shift herself. Then another time, the Thursday following, I went up stairs and the child was a bed; I asked her how she did; she said, her mother bid her say she was a great deal worse; and if the child was heard to speak louder than ordinary, or was looking out at the window, her mother used to send me up to ask her, whether she did design to hang her father and mother instead of the fellow ?</p>
               <p>Q. What do you apprehend was the meaning of that?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe . I think she was kept a bed on purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a son to Mr. Batty fifteen years old, who us'd frequently to lie with this child ?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe. Yes, he did lie in the same bed with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever search the child ?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe. I did once before the prisoner was taken up; and she was not swell'd nor torn no more than the back of my hand , nor red neither.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she a running?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe. Yes, she had a running.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that occasioned by a strain?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe. I cannot say whether it was or no.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been gone from Mr. Batty's?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe. About six weeks. I had warning before this thing happened, and I stayed my time up.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the brother very orderly?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe . He is well enough while near his parents; I know not how he is when he is out of their sight.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner a well-behaved modest man?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe . I never saw any harm in him, more than I do now in any one here.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not addicted to women?</p>
               <p>Bletsoe . Not to my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>The Court made enquiry if there was ever a Surgeon in court, upon which Mr. Guy answered.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-22-person155">
                  Richard 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person155" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person155" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in the business?</p>
               <p>Guy. Seven years for myself next Midsummer. Court. Take 
               <persName id="t17490411-22-person156">
                  Mary 
                  Batty 
               <interp inst="t17490411-22-person156" type="surname" value="Batty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person156" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into a proper place and inspect the parts, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>He, the child, and the child's mother, went into a room together; when they returned</p>
               <p>Guy. I have inspected, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Court. Pray give us your opinion of the case.</p>
               <p>Guy. There is the appearance to me, as though the child had been ravished by somebody, or other. As to the foul disease, I am ready to think the running she has is only the consequence of the lacerated parts; but I do not put it upon a certainty that it is so I have seen a great many children brought into the hospital; and it is usual for people to say it is venereal, when it only proceeds from an inflammation; but I cannot tell so well as the gentleman who had the first inspection on the child. It is certain, it appears to me that the child has been lacerated; and it is my opinion she has been carnally known by a man.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us your reasons for your belief ?</p>
               <p>Guy. The part is distended beyond what it should be for a child at her age: It is impossible it should be so without force.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it possible, if a full grown man was to lie with such a child, but it should be immediately discovered by its gate?</p>
               <p>Guy. I think it must: The child must have been so much inflamed I think it would be difficult for it to go about.</p>
               <p>There were five persons who spoke well as to his former character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490411-22-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17490411-22-punish102" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490411-22-punish102" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-22-defend146 t17490411-22-punish102"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
