<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490113-15">
               <interp inst="t17490113-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-15" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-15" type="date" value="17490113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490113-15-off76-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-defend118 t17490113-15-off76 t17490113-15-verdict81"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490113-15-off82-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-defend118 t17490113-15-off82 t17490113-15-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>110. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-defend118" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Tennant 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-15-defend118" type="surname" value="Tennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-defend118" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-defend118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17490113-15-defloc75">St. Botolph's without Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-15-defloc75" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph's without Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-15-defloc75" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-defend118 t17490113-15-defloc75"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17490113-15-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a Rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490113-15-victim120" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Craggs 
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim120" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim120" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17490113-15-viclabel77" type="occupation">infant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-victim120 t17490113-15-viclabel77"></join> under ten years old
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490113-15-cd78" type="crimeDate">Feb. 16. 1747-8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-off76 t17490113-15-cd78"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-off82 t17490113-15-cd78"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person121">
                  Hannah 
                  Craggs 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person121" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person121" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17490113-15-person122">
                  George 
                  Tennant 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person122" type="surname" value="Tennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person122" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my house, Feb. the 16th last, to speak with my husband, and I told him he would not be at home 'till night; he wanted him to serve in his room, he had got another place he said; he came the next day about 3 o'clock, and I told him my husband was not at home; he said his wife had got some company drinking tea, and said he did not like such women gossipping, so as I was going out, he said he would stay with my child, if I pleas'd; when I was gone to get some candles, and to see a friend that then lay very ill, which in all took me up about an hour, he committed the action.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner at your house when you came back?</p>
               <p>Craggs. Yes, and the child too.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the child complain?</p>
               <p>Craggs. She told me that he said to her, if she told me he would beat her, and I should whip her to death. I made observation upon her linen about three or four days after, and I could not think what was the meaning of it; I said to several of my neighbours, I could not think what was the matter with my child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you for relief for her apply to any person?</p>
               <p>Craggs. I sent for a gentlewoman that is an Apothecary's widow, and had some things of her for the child. I came to find it out by this means on the 1st of March; he serv'd another neighbour's child in the same manner, and that child went and told her mother of it. The woman was telling me what a vile villain he was, and said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174901130008"></xptr> this is the third or fourth child he has serv'd so; my child hearing this was ready to drop down; the woman and I both observ'd the child's countenance change; I sent her to the street-door, because I did not care she should hear the discourse we was talking about; so when the woman was gone the child came to me, and said dear mother, don't be frighted and I will tell you all the truth; I'll tell you how he serv'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Craggs. This was the 1st of March at night, when I sent for Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17490113-15-person123">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Mears 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person123" type="surname" value="Mears"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person123" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she and I went up stairs, and after she had examin'd her she sent her some powder directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did her private parts appear sore?</p>
               <p>Craggs. She had no skin all round her body but all as red as scarlet: the gentlewoman kept giving her some stuff, and she grew better by degrees; but she is now weak in her loins, and there is still a running upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>Craggs. This was in February; on the 25th of April following she was ten years old.</p>
               <p>Q. How come you not to prosecute the prisoner before now?</p>
               <p>Craggs. There were warrants issued out for him, but he always made his escape. Mr. Howel, the other child's father, apply'd, for that I had compassion for his wife and child.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live then?</p>
               <p>Craggs. He lived at that time about twelve doors from my house; he was my next door neighbour about six or seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the prisoner of the affair, after your child mentioned it to you?</p>
               <p>Craggs. As soon as I heard it I went and accus'd him of it in his own house: I was in a great passion, and call'd him many names, and he had not a word to say in his own defence; he said he had not hurt my child. My husband went to a Justice on the first of March, and his clerk was ill in bed, but he promis'd him on the morrow he would sign him a warrant, but he went to sea in three days after this discovery: he has since been to the West Indies.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person124">
                  Mary 
                  Craggs 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person124" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person124" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17490113-15-person125">
                  Mary 
                  Craggs 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person125" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person125" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person126">
                  Mary 
                  Craggs 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person126" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person126" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17490113-15-crimeloc79">Nightingal-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-15-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Nightingal-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-15-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-off76 t17490113-15-crimeloc79"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-off82 t17490113-15-crimeloc79"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that man?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. Yes, sir, it is 
               <persName id="t17490113-15-person127">
                  George 
                  Tennant 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person127" type="surname" value="Tennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person127" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Pray child tell us what he did to you?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. He heav'd me across a chair, and went and bolted the street and yard door; said I, what are you a going to do? he said, child, lie down, I will not hurt you: he made me lie down, and said if I cry'd out the neighbours would hear, and they would tell my mother and she would whip me to death.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lie down?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. He laid me down.</p>
               <p>Q. What else did he do?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. He put somewhat into my private parts that hurt me sadly: said I, you hurt me sadly; O says he, my dear, I don't; I know I don't, says he; says I, indeed Mr. Tennant, you do hurt me; says he, I know I don't.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing come from him wet?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. Yes, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, and what after that?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. After that my mother came home, says he, don't tell your mother; if you do your mother will whip you to death.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you first search'd?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. One madam Mears search'd me; my linen discover'd it soon after this, and I was search'd in two or three days after this.</p>
               <p>Court. You must speak the truth, here is a man's life at stake ?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. It will do me no good if I was to speak ill of him.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a window in this house that look'd towards the street?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. Yes, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you cry out, that the neighbours might come to your assistance?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. He said if I cry'd out he would lick me.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you think your mother would beat you for going to do so heinous a thing?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. I did not know what to think; I did not know better then, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you remember this very particularly, it being so long ago?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. Yes, sir, I can.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you get up?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. I could not get up, he lay upon me; and when my mother came to the door he got off me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he not unbolted the door till then?</p>
               <p>M. Craggs. No, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What did your mother say when he unbolted the door ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174901130009"></xptr>M. Croggs. Says my mother, what do you bolt the door for? said he, to keep the cold weather out; for it snow'd bitterly that day.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mears. I am a widow to a surgeon and apothecary, the child had a weakness, but I know nothing how it came; the child might be hurt, the private parts were a little sore, and there was a redness upon the parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the skin?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mears. Really I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her linen?</p>

               <p>Mrs. Mears. Yes, there seemed to be something of a bad colour, I gave the child physick, and it did her service.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apply any plaisters?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mears. No, sir.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I never touched the girl, or moved out of my chair, but sat by the fire till her mother return'd, and I staid about half an hour after she came in: I met her father two or three days after in Wapping, he spoke friendly to me as usual, and about six weeks after I saw the mother going by my hatch; I said to her, how do you do? she said, never the better for such a rogue as you; said I, for what? she said, you have used my child ill, she forc'd herself into my house, and I bid her go about her business, or I should make her.</p>
               <p>Capt. Holland to his Character. I have known the prisoner about seven months, I never had any reason to suspect him of being such a person; he has been a voyage with me, and behav'd himself like a sober <rs id="t17490113-15-deflabel80" type="occupation">officer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-defend118 t17490113-15-deflabel80"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person128">
                  Mary 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person128" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person128" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 16 or 17 years, I have lived some time his next door neighbour, and I am positive of it he would not be guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person129">
                  Jane 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person129" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person129" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about fifteen years: I believe this thing came chiefly from malice; I don't think him a man deserving such a character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person130">
                  Mary 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person130" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person130" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years, I always look'd upon him to be an honest and a modest man: I never heard him speak an ill word, and I cannot believe he could commit such a crime.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person131">
                  William 
                  Munroe 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person131" type="surname" value="Munroe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person131" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years. I don't believe, upon my oath, he would be guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person132">
                  Samuel 
                  Malcomb 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person132" type="surname" value="Malcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person132" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five years, I fail'd with him, I always thought him an honest man, and have been with him early and late.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person133">
                  Margaret 
                  Bready 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person133" type="surname" value="Bready"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person133" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from two years of age, and on my oath I do not think he would be guilty of such a crime.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person134">
                  Margaret 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person134" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person134" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he first wore breeches: I never knew of any indecent action of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hubbard. I have known him about twelve years, and never heard any ill of him 'till this thing came out: when I heard it, it made my hair stand an end.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person135">
                  Samuel 
                  Trevilian 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person135" type="surname" value="Trevilian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person135" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about sixteen years, I take him to be a modest man, and he had a very good character before this thing happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-15-person136">
                  Thomas 
                  Mopston 
               <interp inst="t17490113-15-person136" type="surname" value="Mopston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person136" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about seven years, I was chief mate, he was second mate, and I never heard any such thing of him before this.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he would be guilty of such a crime as he is here charg'd with?</p>
               <p>Mopston. I can say nothing to that.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-15-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for a <rs id="t17490113-15-off82" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-off82" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-off82" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490113-15-victim138" type="victimName">
                           Grace 
                           Howel 
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim138" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim138" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-15-victim138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17490113-15-viclabel83" type="occupation">infant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-15-victim138 t17490113-15-viclabel83"></join> of seven years of age
            </rs>; but on the account of her tender years the Court judg'd it not proper to admit her evidence; he was <rs id="t17490113-15-verdict84" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-15-verdict84" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
