<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440113-6">
               <interp inst="t17440113-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-6" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440113-6" type="date" value="17440113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440113-6-off31-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-6-defend74 t17440113-6-off31 t17440113-6-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>+ 108. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440113-6-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Read 
                  <interp inst="t17440113-6-defend74" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-defend74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-defend74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440113-6-defloc30">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-6-defloc30" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-6-defloc30" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-6-defend74 t17440113-6-defloc30"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440113-6-off31" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-off31" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-off31" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440113-6-victim76" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Richardson 
                        <interp inst="t17440113-6-victim76" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-6-victim76" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440113-6-victim76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-6-off31 t17440113-6-victim76"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting her in fear, and taking from her a camblet cloak value 2 s. her property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440113-6-cd32" type="crimeDate">December 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-6-off31 t17440113-6-cd32"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-6-person77">
                  Mary 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person77" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person77" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday before Christmas-day between 7 and 8 in the evening, I was knocked down in <placeName id="t17440113-6-crimeloc33">New-street by Covent-garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-6-crimeloc33" type="placeName" value="New-street by Covent-garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440113-6-crimeloc33" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440113-6-off31 t17440113-6-crimeloc33"></join>. - I cannot tell how many there were of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe more than one?</p>
               <p>Richardson. I cannot tell. - I don't know what part of the street it was in.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you knocked down with a stick?</p>
               <p>Richardson. No, it was with their fists. - I could not see whether they were men or women.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the blow light?</p>
               <p>Richardson. It was either upon my head or shoulders, they took my cloak, I begged of them not to take it but they would.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were you going then?</p>
               <p>Richardson . I was going home. - I am a pensioner in St. Martin's workhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come to know any thing of the Prisoner being the person that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Richardson. About a fortnight after my cloak was taken away, a woman came into the work-house and I was called down to her, she said, are you the woman who lost cloak , (I thought she was come to bring me my cloak again) I said yes, the woman said, if you will do me no harm it shall be two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174401130006"></xptr> or three cloaks in your way. I told her it was not in my power to do her any harm; for I could not find her out, but she did not come again, but afterwards they came to me about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-6-person78">
                  John 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person78" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On Sunday night before Christmas-day, the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person79">
                  Patty 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person79" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person79" type="given" value="Patty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, went out with a design to get money or what we could in the way of thieving, and we robbed this woman of a cloak.</p>

               <p>Q. What time of night did you set out?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. It was about half an hour after six. 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person80">
                  Patty 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person80" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person80" type="given" value="Patty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken up that night and carried to St. Martin's Roundhouse, and about the middle of New street very near St. Martin's-lane, Read and I met the Prosecutrix, Read knocked her down and I took the cloak off her shoulders, the cloak was very dirty.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did you knock her down, was it with a stick?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. No, he hit her with his fist.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was this woman that he knocked down?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. Because I knew the head of the cloak again when I saw her before the justice. - I am sure it is the same woman. After this we carried the cloak to our lodging, and offered to sell it to one 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person81">
                  Margaret 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person81" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person81" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she said she would not buy it; then the Prisoner took the cloak away and sold it, but I had no part of the money. - We did not take the head of the cloak.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-6-person82">
                  Margaret 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person82" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person82" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person82" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person83">
                  John 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person83" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person83" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived next door to me, and on Sunday night before Christmas between 7 and 8 o'clock in the evening, the Prisoner and Hawkins offered to me a cloak, I asked them how they came by it, they said they got it of an old woman by Covent-Garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them had the cloak in his hand when they came to you?</p>
               <p>Casey . When they came in I was in the yard, and they had laid the cloak down upon a box. - Both of them offered to sell it me - they offered it for 2 s. and I told them if they would let me have it for a farthing I would not have it?</p>
               <p>Q. Did they tell you how they came by it?</p>
               <p>Casey . They did not tell me that, I did not ask them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440113-6-person84">
                  William 
                  Atney 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person84" type="surname" value="Atney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person84" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking of the Prisoner. he was carried before a Justice and committed to New Prison for farther examination; as I was carrying him there he desired to be admitted an evidence, I asked him what he could do, he said he could do more than Hawkins could, I asked him what that was, he said he could produce the old woman's cloak for he was the person who sold it, to one 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person85">
                  Bess 
                  Keene 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person85" type="surname" value="Keene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person85" type="given" value="Bess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Cross-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any particular enquiry made into this before?</p>
               <p>Alney . Hawkins had made himself an evidence before that and confessed this particular fact. 
               <persName id="t17440113-6-person86">
                  Margaret 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17440113-6-person86" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person86" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-person86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew where he lived, and she and I went together to take him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at work at my father's when you took me.</p>
               <p>Atney. I know you were, Casey went in first and I afterwards.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Since I have been taken up my mother is dead, and all my friends are gone to her burial. - She is to be buried to day at Clermont . Mrs. Richardson declared before the Justice that she was drunk, and did not know how her cloak was taken from her.</p>
               <p>Richardson. I was a little in liquor, but they knocked me down and took my cloak from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you so drunk that you did not know any thing of the matter?</p>
               <p>Richardson . I cried out and begged them not to take my cloak.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the Justice that you were so much in liquor at that time, that you could not give a complete account of the matter.</p>
               <p>Richardson. They brought it out, they came to me, I did not know where to find them. - I really cannot tell what I said.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell before you lost the cloak?</p>
               <p>Richardson. I believe I did fall.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17440113-6-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440113-6-verdict34" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               The putting in fear not being fully proved, the Prisoner was acquitted of the robbery, and found guilty of the felony
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
