<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451204-33">
               <interp inst="t17451204-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-33" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451204-33" type="date" value="17451204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451204-33-off161-c291" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-33-defend342 t17451204-33-off161 "></join>
         
               <p>33. 
               
                  <persName id="t17451204-33-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Payne 
                  <interp inst="t17451204-33-defend342" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-defend342" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-defend342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for a Misdemeanour, in <rs id="t17451204-33-off161" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-off161" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-off161" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seditiousWords"></interp>
               uttering certain dangerous and treasonable Words against our Sovereign Lord the King, that is to say, D - n you and your King too, and drinking the Pretender's Health
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen of the Jury. Payne stands indicted for a great Misdemeanour, for Words spoken by him very disrespectini to his Most Excellent Majesty King GEORGE; and in Company with Smith and others he said, God bless the Pretender, and here's a Health to the British Arms, (meaning the Rebel Army) and saying to 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person343">
                  William 
                  Landey 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person343" type="surname" value="Landey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person343" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person344">
                  Matthew 
                  Dawney 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person344" type="surname" value="Dawney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person344" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , D - n you and your King too, and God bless the Pretender.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-33-person345">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person345" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person345" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person346">
                  George 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person346" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person346" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Look at the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Norman. I know him again. On the 7th of Nov. he was at my House at the <placeName id="t17451204-33-crimeloc162">Bull Inn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-33-crimeloc162" type="placeName" value="Bull Inn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-33-crimeloc162" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-33-off161 t17451204-33-crimeloc162"></join> in <placeName id="t17451204-33-crimeloc163">Bishopsgate-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-33-crimeloc163" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451204-33-crimeloc163" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-33-off161 t17451204-33-crimeloc163"></join>. I saw the Prisoner at the Bar about Seven at Night. I heard him drink King GEORGE's Health, and Success to the British Arms, and God bless the Pretender. There were two Soldiers in the Room: One of them was Will. Landey, and the other was 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person347">
                  Matthew 
                  Dawney 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person347" type="surname" value="Dawney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person347" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They were in the same Room, but I think not in the same Box.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any Words that passed between him and the Soldiers? and that the Soldiers should say, they would not have their Master abused; and that he should say, God d - n you and your King too?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would say something. Since I have been brought to Newgate I have had a great deal of Cold, that it has broke my Voice. I am slow in Speech, and short in Memory. This is the first Time that ever I was brought before a Court in all my Life; but when I was there I was in Drink, and very much intoxicated with Liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-33-person348">
                  Joseph 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person348" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person348" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Man was at our Inn. I am a Porter there. I thought I saw him Yesterday was a Month at our Inn; and when he first came in, there were two or three Songs sung, and he drinked, and he drinked Healths, and he said, Here's a Health to King George, Success to the British Arms, Here's a Health to the Pretender.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any Body in Company with him?</p>
               <p>Johnson. There was Dawney and Landey; and they said it was not their Duty to hear the King spoke against: And being a little stirr'd up, he said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174512040020"></xptr> to one of them, God d - n you and your King too.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, did not he give a Man three Halfpence to drink the Pretender's Health.</p>
               <p>Johnson. Speaking of the Pretender, he said that he pray'd for him daily, and it was the Duty of a Christian to pray for his Enemies.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, did you hear him drink King George's Health.</p>
               <p>Johnson. Yes; he both said King George and Royal George; and he said, God bless King George, Success to the British Arms, and here's a Health to the Pretender; and he always all along said it was the Duty of a Christian to pray for his Enemies.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober then?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No my Lord, very much in Drink.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-33-person349">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person349" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person349" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person350">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person350" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What did you hear him by, and to whom?</p>
               <p>Smith. When I come in, he had a Pot of Beer in his Hand, and he said, that they would not drink with him; and he said, God d - n them and their King too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451204-33-person351">
                  William 
                  Burr 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person351" type="surname" value="Burr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All that I can say is only this: That when I came in he said, God bless King George, and Success to the British Arms, and here's a Health to the Pretender. And I heard several Persons say, that they would have him go about his Business.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I believe I left off when I said I was intoxicated with Liquor [and here he made the Court smile; for he said that he was slow of Speech, that his Eyes were in the Eclipses, and his Memory short as the Top of a high Rock.] The Day that I drop'd into the Bull, I had been in Leadenhall-Street about Business, and it was to make a small Collection for a Gentleman's Servant reduc'd, and when I had done we had a Dish of Steaks, and with that we drank plentifully, and my Eyes began to be in the Eclipses. I went to the Bull to speak to a Gentleman's Coachman that was to be there; and light of another there in the Yard, and I ask'd him to go and drink. How much I did drink I can't tell. It was at Noon when I came into the Bull, and late at Night I went away, and the next Morning I found myself in the Counter. Next Morning I was hurry'd away to Guildhall, and then afterwards to Newgate. When I first went into the Bull I had 17 s. about me; and next Morning when I awak'd in the Counter, I had but one. Give me Leave; with Submission, if I might have Leave, I will give your Lordship an Account of the Pilgrimage of my Life and Conversation. When I came to the Bull I call'd for Liquor; what I call'd for, other People had. There was a Man there that did curse the Pretender; and I said that I was always taught to bless, and may God bless his Gracious Sovereign Lord King George.</p>
               <p>Here dropp'd Loyal and Eloquent Sentiments from Sir 
               <persName id="t17451204-33-person352">
                  Simon 
                  Urling 
               <interp inst="t17451204-33-person352" type="surname" value="Urling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person352" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Knt. Recorder of the City of London, who spoke to the Prisoner to this Effect: That in the midst of Justice, Mercy was remember'd; that he was not then in a Court of Inquisition, but in an open and free Court, where the Liberties of Englishmen are maintain'd in the highest Degree; that we had upon the Throne the best of Kings, who had always made the Laws of the Realm the Rule of his Government; and therefore the Prisoner would do well to have a venerable Regard to his Sacred Majesty King George, and to consider the Mildness of the Court that indicted on him only <rs id="t17451204-33-punish164" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-punish164" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-punish164" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-33-defend342 t17451204-33-punish164"></join>
               two Months Imprisonment
            </rs> and a <rs id="t17451204-33-punish165" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-punish165" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451204-33-punish165" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451204-33-defend342 t17451204-33-punish165"></join>
               Fine of five Shillings
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
