<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490705-4">
               <interp inst="t17490705-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-4" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490705"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-4" type="date" value="17490705"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-4-off20-c42" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend47 t17490705-4-off20 t17490705-4-verdict24"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-4-off20-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend49 t17490705-4-off20 t17490705-4-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>374, 375. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-defend47" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Shepherd 
                  <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend47" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend47" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-defend49" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Fryer  alias <rs id="t17490705-4-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend49 t17490705-4-alias-1"></join>Turnpine</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend49" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-defend49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17490705-4-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 8 l. the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17490705-4-person50">
                        Esther 
                        Vandome 
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person50" type="surname" value="Vandome"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-4-person50" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-4-person50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , widow, out of the dwelling-house of the said Esther
            </rs>. <rs id="t17490705-4-cd21" type="crimeDate">May 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-off20 t17490705-4-cd21"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-person51">
                  Esther 
                  Vandome 
               <interp inst="t17490705-4-person51" type="surname" value="Vandome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person51" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of May the two prisoners with another came into my house after ten o'clock at night. They sat down and eat their salmon, they sat till such time the house was clear, there were none left but the people that lodged in the house, I went backward, in the mean time they called for the reckoning; as I was coming in at the door, one of them, that is, Fryer, held a sixpence to me, two of them got to the door, and held it open; as he paid me he put his hand behind me where the tankard stood. A witness that is here cried out stop the boy, he has got the tankard; he pushed out of the house, I ran after him, and saw the bottom-edge of the tankard; he ran one way, and the others another, and, it being dark, we could not take any of them; we found one of their hats, but never found the tankard; it was the same tankard they had been drinking out of. I employed two or three people to look about for them, and one day last week one of the witnesses brought Shepherd to me. He said he did not steal the tankard, but one of his company did; he said the others were washing themselves in the river; we carried him before a magistrate, he denied it, and said he never was in my house before he was brought in; but he forgot himself, and said there were more people in the house, and why should I judge it upon him?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-person52">
                  John 
                  Hains 
               <interp inst="t17490705-4-person52" type="surname" value="Hains"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in Mrs. Vandome's house, I was standing at the bar the time the tankard was lost. I was in my night-gown and slippers, the little <rs id="t17490705-4-deflabel22" type="occupation">boy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend47 t17490705-4-deflabel22"></join>, Shepherd, and another came up to me, and asked me what was to pay? Says I, Mrs. Vandome is backward, I cannot tell; with that the biggest <rs id="t17490705-4-deflabel23" type="occupation">boy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend49 t17490705-4-deflabel23"></join>, Fryer, stood still with the tankard by him about four yards from me; there was no-body in that room but them, there were some people in the other room that lodged in the house: Fryer said, let us have another tankard, come back. This was when the other two were at the door, they did not agree to it; then, says he, let us have another pint. No, said they; Fryer called to pay, I went to him, the tankard was standing by him: says I, here are 2 tankards scored, I apprehend that is all; he gives Mrs. Vandome 6 d. out of his right-hand, and I observed he had his hat betwixt his legs in his left-hand; at the very moment the land-lady open'd the door, that moment he took the tankard, and went by her. He pushed very furiously through the room; I called to the people to stop him, I missed the tankard and him together; he must cover it with his hat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-person53">
                  Samuel 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17490705-4-person53" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person53" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the three boys come in, they went and sat down backwards, and called for a tankard of beer, I saw them drinking of it, and when they went out the tankard was missing; we went after them, but could not find them, or the tankard; they went through the room where I was, as before described; I saw Fryer's hat between his legs, as if it was to cover something.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-4-person54">
                  Robert 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17490705-4-person54" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person54" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the house when they came in, and went backwards, and called for a tankard of beer, they had some salmon of my wife, she was sitting at the door; they drank to my wife<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050005"></xptr> out of this tankard, I was sitting in the fore-room; and, when Mr. Hains called out, saying, they had got the tankard, I went out in pursuit of them, but we could not find them.</p>
               <p>Fryer's Defence. I never was in the house in my life, before I was taken up, and carried there.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I sat within a yard of them, and remember them both well.</p>
               <p>Shepherd. I never was in the house, nor drunk out of the tankard in my life.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17490705-4-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-4-punish25" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-4-punish25" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend47 t17490705-4-punish25"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-4-defend49 t17490705-4-punish25"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
