<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450116-1">
               <interp inst="t17450116-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-1" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450116-1" type="date" value="17450116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450116-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-defend30 t17450116-1-off2 t17450116-1-verdict8"></join>
         
               <p>123. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Baggonett 
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Baggonett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-defend30" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17450116-1-defloc1">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-defend30 t17450116-1-defloc1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450116-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450116-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Barber 
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim32" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim32" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in the dwelling house of the said Francis, putting her in fear, and taking from her a velvet pillareen, value 20 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450116-1-victim34" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Barber 
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim34" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim34" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450116-1-victim34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17450116-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">Nov. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-off2 t17450116-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person35">
                  Mary 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person35" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person35" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person35" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of November about four o'clock in the afternoon, I was going by the <placeName id="t17450116-1-crimeloc4">White Lion Tavern</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-crimeloc4" type="placeName" value="White Lion Tavern"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-crimeloc4" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-off2 t17450116-1-crimeloc4"></join> in the <placeName id="t17450116-1-crimeloc5">Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-crimeloc5" type="placeName" value="Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450116-1-crimeloc5" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-off2 t17450116-1-crimeloc5"></join>, the Prisoner was standing at the door with a blue apron on, and another fellow with him, who had a handkerchief about his neck; the Prisoner said, Drag that bitch in, I will make her pay for all the bitches that have bilked me; with that the other man, who is not taken, (his name is 
               <persName id="t17450116-1-person36">
                  Thomas 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person36" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person36" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as a chair-man told me) laid hold of me; I said, pray, Sir, let me alone, for I am going about my business; he took hold of me, and dragged me into the house (I thought the man of the house [the Prisoner would take my part, but he did not) pushed me into the parlour, and locked the door upon me, and said, D - n you, you hitch, if you do not let me do so and so, I'll murder you; I said I would not; for I was in a Christian country, and did not fear getting assistance; then I rung the bell, and the Prisoner came in, the other fellow said, bring some wine, with that the Prisoner brought a pint of wine, and said, I will make her pay for them if there were a hundred pints; with that he stripped the pillareen off my neck, and said, D - n you, you bitch, why don't you let the man do so and so to you? He had a knobbed stick, and struck me with it; I cried out murder several times; he said if I cried out murder any more, he would murder me, for he had got company in the house. - I defended my pillareen as well as I could, till I was so weak, that I had no strength in the world, and have a great many black spots on my body now to shew for it: then he kicked me into the street, and said, D - n you you bitch, I don't desire to see you any more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out murder in the house?</p>
               <p>Barber. Yes; and he kicked me into the street, and I was told he said, I should pay handsomly for it, and I lay sprawling in the street, but no<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174501160003"></xptr> body knew me there, nor nobody came to my assistance.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Council. Was you ever in the house before?</p>
               <p>Barber. Never but once, and that was to drink a glass of wine with a gentleman and his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. What Part of the House was you in when the Prisoner used you so?</p>
               <p>Barber. I was in the Parlour next the Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Do the Windows look into the Street?</p>
               <p>Barber. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dusk?</p>
               <p>Barber. It was not dark: It was between four and five o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you apply to somebody in the Street, to go with you into the House again, and get some Redress?</p>
               <p>Barber. Because nobody knew me: I went home afterwards, and then I did go there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever say you would not have prosecuted this Man, if he would have come down to you?</p>
               <p>Barber. I never said so. If there are twenty false Witnesses against me, I can't help it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go after you were out of the House?</p>
               <p>Barber. I took a Chair and went home directly, and got a Constable, but the Constable would not go into the House with twelve Constables, and a File of Musqueteers.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business are you?</p>
               <p>Barber. I live in Bell-yard, by Temple-bar.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you what Business you are of?</p>
               <p>Barber. I kept a Gentleman's House.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you now?</p>
               <p>Barber. I <rs id="t17450116-1-viclabel6" type="occupation">keep a Gentleman's House</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-victim32 t17450116-1-viclabel6"></join> now. - Mr. Mayne's, in St. Martin's-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live there now?</p>
               <p>Barber. He is fell under misfortunes, and has left off house-keeping - I work plain-work now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person37">
                  Joshua 
                  Brogden 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person37" type="surname" value="Brogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person37" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Barber applied first to Sir 
               <persName id="t17450116-1-person38">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person38" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person38" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for a warrant to take up the prisoner, he granted the warrant for assaulting and abusing her, and taking her pillareen, and bound him over for the assault; but she afterwards indicted him for a felony.</p>

               <p>Q. What did he say at that time concerning the fact?</p>
               <p>Brogden. He said he had the pillareen, but that he took it for the reckoning.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in the entry, the prosecutrix stopped a man in the street, and I heard her say, come will you give me a glass of wine; he said, he had no money; she said, you had as good come in, for it shall cost you nothing: they called for a pint of wine, about half an hour afterwards I went into the town, and the man said, this gentlewoman will pay you the reckoning; and she saying nothing, I thought she would. When I asked her for it, she said, d - n you, what business have I to pay the reckoning? and said she would not pay me. I said, madam, you use me very ill, you used me so before, but you shall not use me so now for I will be paid for the wines; she said she had no money, then she pulled of her pillareen, and said, d - n you take that, I'll a robbery against you, and have your life for it. Another time a gentleman came with her into the house and paid a shilling for a pint of wine, she took the shilling up and went about her business, and I lost that.</p>
               <p>Capt. Hopkins. I was at the White Lion Tavern in the Strand the 12th of November with M Wife from three o'clock till about a quarter six, waiting for Capt. Winslow to go to a play - I did not hear any crying out, nor any all; and if there had been any I believe I should have heard it, for I was in the bar room, pretty near to the room they were in. I have dined there ever since the 12th of April, and never heard any disorder there.</p>
               <p>Major 
               <persName id="t17450116-1-person39">
                  Wise
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person39" type="given" value="Wise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person39" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company with Capt. Hopkins and Capt. Winslow, and there was no sign of noise at all nor any thing like it: I have used the house these twelve months, and never heard anything disorderly, there are gentlemen of reputation come there frequently.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor's Council, to Barnes the constable. Did not you take a couple of gamblers out of the house?</p>
               <p>Barnes. There were gamblers frequented the house, but that was three years ago, before the prisoner kept it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person40">
                  Thomas 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person40" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person40" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he came to the house. I live next door to him. He is a man of a very good character. And if she had cried out, my men must have heard her, and would have gone to her assistance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person41">
                  William 
                  Frasier 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person41" type="surname" value="Frasier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person41" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live opposite the prisoner. I have known him ever since he came there, which is about two years. He is a man of a very good character.</p>
               <p>Jeffery Anwell. I am a next door neighbour to him. He is a man of a very good character; I do not believe there is an honester man in the world. I have the honour of lodging some gentlemen belonging to the Parliament. And I could not suffer a disorderly house next me. Indeed it was a bad house, and I got the people removed - I have seen the prosecutrix frequently about the streets picking up people.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174501160004"></xptr>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Anwell. A whore.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person42">
                  John 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person42" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he kept the house, and never heard but that he was a very civil, honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person43">
                  James 
                  Biggleston 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person43" type="surname" value="Biggleston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person43" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prosecutrix to be a common woman. I have seen her with fellows at 
               <persName id="t17450116-1-person44">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Fair 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person44" type="surname" value="Fair"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person44" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , when I attended pye powder court.</p>
               <p>Mr. Green. The prisoner is a very worthy man, and bears a very good character - I have seen the prosecutrix walking the streets frequently.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharp. The prisoner is a person of a very good character - the prosecutrix has been so impudent as at my own door to offer to pick me up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450116-1-person45">
                  Thomas 
                  Flower 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person45" type="surname" value="Flower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person45" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17450116-1-person46">
                  Mary 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17450116-1-person46" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person46" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-person46" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             from her infancy.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take her to be an honest woman?</p>
               <p>Flower. I can't tell you her original extraction. I know she was brought up very well, and put to the boarding-school.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she would take a false oath?</p>
               <p>Flower. I believe she would not have done so.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she would take a false oath now?</p>
               <p>Flower. Really I can't say.</p>
               <p>Mr. Blower. I take Barber to be a very honest girl - I hope she would not take a man's life away falsely - she <rs id="t17450116-1-viclabel7" type="occupation">kept a house of lodgers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450116-1-victim32 t17450116-1-viclabel7"></join> about 2 years ago. The last place I knew her at, she kept Mr. Mayne's house in St. Martin's Lane - I can't brag much of her general character. I have known her 12 years: she has a loose character. <rs id="t17450116-1-verdict8" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450116-1-verdict8" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Court granted the prisoner a copy of his indictment.</p>
            </div1>
