<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-37">
               <interp inst="t17470909-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-37" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-37" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-37-off157-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-37-defend307 t17470909-37-off157 t17470909-37-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>352. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-defend307" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Lawrence 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-37-defend307" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-defend307" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-defend307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, and the Indictment sets forth, <rs id="t17470909-37-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               That he, on the <rs id="t17470909-37-cd158" type="crimeDate">22d of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-37-off157 t17470909-37-cd158"></join> last, at the Parish of <placeName id="t17470909-37-crimeloc159">St Mary Woolnoth</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-crimeloc159" type="placeName" value="St Mary Woolnoth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-crimeloc159" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-37-off157 t17470909-37-crimeloc159"></join>, in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17470909-37-person308">
                        George 
                        Shelvocke 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person308" type="surname" value="Shelvocke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person308" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esq; and Christopher Robinson, Gent. feloniously did steal one Promissiory Note, commonly called a Bank Note, No. 112. dated London, the 30th Day of December, 1746, of the Value of 20 l. singed by 
                     <persName id="t17470909-37-person309">
                        Ralph 
                        Morrison 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person309" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person309" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , for the Governor and Company of the Bank of England; by which said Note he, the said 
                     <persName id="t17470909-37-person310">
                        Ralph 
                        Morrison 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person310" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person310" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did promise to pay to Mr Heavy Hayter, and Comp. or Bearer, on Demand, the Sum of 20 l. the same Note then being the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17470909-37-victim312" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Drewry 
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-victim312" type="surname" value="Drewry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-victim312" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-victim312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-37-off157 t17470909-37-victim312"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . and then being unpaid and unsatisfied to him the said 
                     <persName id="t17470909-37-person313">
                        Robert 
                        Drewry 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person313" type="surname" value="Drewry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person313" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-37-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>Council. Gentlemen, when you come to hear this Master, you will think it as just and necessary a Prosecution to be brought before you, as ever appeared in this Place. It is an Indictment against the Prisoner,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090029"></xptr> for taking a Letter, in the Post-Office, with a Bank Note included in it. You will consider the publick Credit, and publick Interest of this Kingdom, is extremely affected by Crimes of this Nature. Bank Notes are so publick, that if the least Check be put to them, it would very much affect Trade, and be a great Blow to the Credit of the Bank.</p>
               <p>Council. I am Council of the same Side for the Crown; and, Gentlemen, the Prisoner at the Bar stands indicted for a Crime in which as the publick Interest is extremely concerned, so the Legislature have thought proper to annex to it a very severe Punishment, by making it Capital. You know the greatest Part of the Commerce of this Nation could not be carried on but in an Epistolary Way; and the Legislature, in Acts of Parliament of the 2d and 9th Years of his present Majesty, has made it Capital, and of the same Value as Money, or Goods. I will not enter particularly into the Nature of the Offence, or the Prisoner's Employment in the Post-Office, but I shall go directly to the calling our Witnesses.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person314">
                  Robert 
                  Drewry 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person314" type="surname" value="Drewry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person314" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Drewry. At Lincoln.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your Father, or you, any Correspondence with 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person315">
                  Thomas 
                  Hewson 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person315" type="surname" value="Hewson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person315" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             here in London? Do you recollect whether, in April last, your Father, or you, sent any Letter to him?</p>
               <p>Drewry. Yes. On the 20th of April we sent a Letter to Mr Hewson, with two Bank Notes, 20 l. each. This Bank Note is my Father's Property.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this Letter sent?</p>
               <p>Drewry. I carried it to Mr Randes, Post-master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Father sold up the Letter in your Presence?</p>
               <p>Drewry. Yes, my Lord, I indors'd both of them, and seal'd the Letter, and carried it up directly. It was,</p>
               <p>No. 112. I promise to pay to Mr 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person316">
                  Henry 
                  Hayter 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person316" type="surname" value="Hayter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person316" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Co. or Bearn, on Demand, the Sum of 20 l. &amp;c. Signed,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person317">
                  RALPH 
                  MORRISON 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person317" type="surname" value="MORRISON"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person317" type="given" value="RALPH"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination]</p>
               <p>Council. You said this Bank Note was your Father's Property; How do you know it was your Father's Property ?</p>
               <p>Drewry. I paid 40 l. for both of them that very Day.</p>
               <p>[ There was a critical Remark made by the Council for the Prisoner, Thus by the Assignment to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person318">
                  Robert 
                  Hewson 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person318" type="surname" value="Hewson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person318" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , it became his Property; but it was answered, It did not because Hewson's till it came to hand.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person319">
                  Henry 
                  Randes 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person319" type="surname" value="Randes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person319" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the City of Lincoln.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you live there in April last?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Office?</p>
               <p>Randes. I was Post-master at that time.</p>
               <p>Council. As you live in Lincoln, I suppose you know 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person320">
                  Robert 
                  Drewry 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person320" type="surname" value="Drewry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person320" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes. He brought a Letter to me one Day, and he came to the Office-Door, and ask'd me how I did? Mr Lumley happen'd to be in the Room, and he was jealous, Drewry came to me to frank a Letter for him; and Mr Lumley said, Mr. Randes, you don't know what you are doing, for if there should be any thing in that Letter, Bill, or any thing of that Kind, you may be accountable for it? so with that he surpriz'd me a little; I took all my Letters, one by one, and took this Letter, and put it in between two large Letters, and put it into the London Bag, and sealed it with my own Hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect whether you saw any thing in this Letter?</p>
               <p>Randes. No, Sir, I only charged it as a single Letter. It was directed, To Mr Hewson, Salesman, in Smithfield, I think.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether all the Letters then were put into the Bag?</p>
               <p>Randes. Every Letter, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Bag go away with the Post-Boy ?</p>
               <p>Randes. I put them into the Bag, and buckled them down.</p>
               <p>Q. At this time did you send up the Number of Letters to the Post-Office?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been employed?</p>
               <p>Randes. Near thirty Years.</p>
               <p>Council. I ask you whether you recollect that the Post-Letters were sealed up by you, and sent to London ?</p>
               <p>Randes. All in general; no body does that Business but myself.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination]</p>
               <p>Council. If I understand your Evidence right; in the first place, you are not positive as to the Day; in the second place, you don't know that there was any Bill in the Letter; in the third place, I think you say, you only charged it as a single Letter; if there are Bills, don't you charge them double?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes, or treble; if he had told me there was three Bills, I should have charged it a Shilling.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090030"></xptr>Council. You did not know that this Letter had a Bank Note in it ?</p>
               <p>Randes. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you remember, in two or three Posts after, that Mr Drewry came and told you of Bank Notes being in it ?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes, he told me, there were two Bank Notes sent; and as he had no Account of them, he desired me to search if the Letter was not dropp'd aside any where.</p>
               <p>Council. So he complained that the Letter had not come to Mr Hewson's Hand ?</p>
               <p>Randes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person321">
                  Tho.
                   Ravenhill Assistant
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person321" type="surname" value="Ravenhill Assistant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person321" type="given" value="Tho."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to the North Road. I ask you, suppose a Letter should be put in, and set out from Lincoln the 20th of April, what Time is it before it comes to London?</p>
               <p>Ravenhill. On the 22d. All I can say is, that the Lincoln Bag came in it's regular Course upon that Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be sure of that, because it is a particular Day, nothing of any other Day will affect it.</p>
               <p>Ravenhill. The Method that's observed is this, when a Mail is open'd the Bags are read over to me one by one.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this Bag seal'd in a proper Manner?</p>
               <p>Ravenhill. I can't remember that.</p>
               <p>There arose a little Debate about the Signing [
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person322">
                  Ralph 
                  Morrison 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person322" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person322" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] the Council for the Defendant urg'd, that it could not be prov'd to be R. Morrison; but Mr Jesse was present, and gave Oath, That what remain'd of the Name he knew to be wrote by Mr Morrison, one of the Cashiers of the Bank; and also prov'd, that it was proper and customary to tear off part of the Name as the Note was paid at the Bank.</p>
               <p>Council to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person323">
                  Christopher 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person323" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person323" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Give an Account, whether you recollect the Northern Mail coming in safe in April last; did you find the Number of Letters agree with the Post Mark?</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination]</p>
               <p>Council. How came you to be so particular in the Number of Letters that Day? Are you sure that you was the Person that did it that Day?</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes, Sir, my Name was signed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person324">
                  Thomas 
                  Hewson 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person324" type="surname" value="Hewson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person324" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Clerkenwell Green, and Letters are directed for me, to be left at Marham's Coffee-house in Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you expect any Remittance of Money in April last?</p>
               <p>Hewson. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect, by the Post from Lincoln on the 20th of April, did you receive a Letter from Mr Drewry ?</p>
               <p>Hewson. I expected one but I did not receive it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr Drewry sent you Word, that he should send you a Remittance for any particular Sum?</p>
               <p>Hewson. Not a particular Sum, but a Remittance. The Post following he sent me a Letter, which ran thus: '' I hope you receiv'd my last, with two Bank '' Bills of 40 l.'' But I never received those Bank Bills.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person325">
                  Henry 
                  Potts 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person325" type="surname" value="Potts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person325" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; Comptroller of the Inland Posts. The Prisoner at the Bar has been employed for seven Years: When they receive a Charge in the Gross then they subdivide.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be positive this Letter did come to the Prisoner's Hand?</p>
               <p>Mr Potts. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. How is the Method in the Office?</p>
               <p>Potts. The Letter-Carriers sort among themselves to their particular Walks.</p>
               <p>Council. You won't take upon yourself to say, that same Letter came to his hand?</p>
               <p>Mr Potts. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether his Business lay in Smithfield?</p>
               <p>Mr Potts. He is one of the People appointed to carry to that Division of the Town.</p>

               <p>Council. Suppose every Person had done his proper Duty on that Day, and that Letter had been carried to Mr Hewson, as directed, would it have fallen into the Hands of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mr Potts Likely it might.</p>
               <p>Council. I think you say he has been in the Office seven Years; I would ask you, What Character he bore in the Office ?</p>
               <p>Mr Potts Not a very good one; about four Years ago he was deficient in his Cash, and could not make up his Account, and would have been turn'd out had it not been for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person326">
                  Josiah 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person326" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person326" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Inspector of the Letter Carriers. What is the Nature of the Prisoner's Employ in the Office.</p>
               <p>Mitchell. In the Office his Business is to sort Letters; he belongs to a Seat call'd Murral</p>
               <p>Council. In the Course of the Business of the Office that came from Lincoln the 22d of April, must it have fallen to his Share by virtue of his Office?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. There is a great deal of probability that it might fall into his Hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect whether the Prisoner was upon his Duty that Day?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I have reason to believe he was. I think that was the Day that the Chester Mail was robb'd, and I am sure he was at the Office that Day. He was there by another Reason; every Morning I call<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090031"></xptr> the Roll over, and I look'd and saw he was not upon the absent List.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination]</p>
               <p>Council. Are you always so very exact, that you could not be mistaken?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. Impossible. I write down every Man every Morning that is absent. There is seventy in all, so that I know who is absent every Day.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Seats are there?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. There are fifteen Seats and seventy Walks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person327">
                  Jonathan 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person327" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person327" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to Mr Hazard and Brett, at the New State Lottery Office. This Bank Note I took the 7th of May last. A Person came and ask'd me the Price of Lottery Tickets, which was then sold by Receipts. I said 10 l. 4 s. The Person ask'd me to make one out. I ask'd. By what Name? He said, by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person328">
                  Thomas 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person328" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person328" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He gave me this Bank Note, and I gave him 9 l. 16 s. in change, and the Receipt.</p>
               <p>Council. Are you very sure that was the Bank Note you received upon that Occasion?</p>
               <p>Powel. Yes; when I came to settle my Cash at Night, I takes and turns it about, and finds a Parcel of Indorsements upon it. As soon as Mr Brett came in, I show'd it to him. Mr Hazard is Residentiary Partner at the Exchange. It was sent to the Bank the next Morning, and stopp'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to the Man that brought it?</p>
               <p>Powel. I don't know that I can; I think I have seen him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person329">
                  George 
                  Brett 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person329" type="surname" value="Brett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person329" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you any Concern in this Office?</p>
               <p>Brett. I am Partner with Mr. Hazard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing of this Note being brought to your Office?</p>
               <p>Brett. I know this Note was delivered to me by our Man, 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person330">
                  Jonathan 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person330" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person330" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Now, can you take upon you to be sure, that that Note was delivered to you by your Clerk?</p>
               <p>Brett. Yes, Seeing the Indorsements, and hearing the Mail was robb'd, I desir'd; the next Morning, it might be sent to the Bank, to see if it was a good Note, or not. There it was stopp'd; and they sent for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they refuse paying the Money?</p>
               <p>Brent. Yes, Sir, but I did get it, after the Man and I had related the Affair. I told them as the Change was given out of the Note, I thought it was my Property, when they refus'd to pay me I determined to sue the Bank for it; I know nothing of the Person that brought the Note. I receiv'd 20 l. of the Bank, and it was cancell'd there.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person331">
                  John 
                  Hardwick 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person331" type="surname" value="Hardwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person331" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How long have you known the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Hardwick. I have known him ten or eleven Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Recollection of his giving you a Bank Note for any particular Purpose?</p>
               <p>Hardwick It was in April or May I believe.</p>
               <p>Council. Look upon the Note</p>
               <p>Hardwick I know the Note came from Lincoln, by what I look'd upon it, but as for any Number, or Person, or Name, I can't remember.</p>
               <p>Q. For what Purpose was it given to you.</p>
               <p>Hardwick Lawrence brought it to me, and said, a Friend of his had sent it up, and he desired I would go and get a Lottery Ticket, and they told me the Lottery Tickets were not come out. They told me a Receipt was as good as a Ticket, for that reason I paid 10 l. 4 s. for a Receipt, and they gave me in change 9 l. 16 s.</p>
               <p>Q. When it was given to you, what did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Hardwick. I returned it to Lawrence the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination.]</p>
               <p>Council. How came you take the Receipt in the Name of Marshall.</p>
               <p>Hardwick. I was in a hurry, and forgot the Name.</p>
               <p>Council. I want to know, whether you are positive that is the Note?</p>
               <p>Hardwick. I won't swear to that; but there was something upon it that show'd that it came from Lincoln.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any other Bank Note at that Time ?</p>
               <p>Hardwick. No.</p>
               <p>Court. The Prisoner told you, it was not to be in his own Name.</p>
               <p>Hardwick. No, he said it was for some Person in the Country, which I forgot; I forgot the Name, and mentioned a Name that I recollected.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person332">
                  John 
                  Grey 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person332" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Look upon that Paper you have in your Hand.</p>
               <p>Grey. I know the Paper; this is a Receipt for a Lottery Ticket, I had this from the Prisoner at the Bar; it is now, Sir, last Tuesday was sev'nnight, the 25th Day of August; he delivered it to me, and gave me Direction to go to Mr Brett's Office for a Lottery Ticket; and to sell it and bring him the Money. When I went to Mr Brett's Office, I said I came for a Lottery Ticket, I had a Receipt for it. Accordingly I took it out of my Pocket, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090032"></xptr> he asked me whether my Name was 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person333">
                  Thomas 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person333" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person333" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he seem'd to be in some Confusion, and I look'd upon a Piece of Paper hanging up at the Desk, and asked me again, where I had it, and whether my Name was 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person334">
                  Thomas 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person334" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person334" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? I told him, No. I ask'd him, why he ask'd me that? So he said, call a Constable directly; and they brought in a Constable, and charged him with me. Mr Brett said, here is the Receipt, No. 53.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that is the same Receipt?</p>
               <p>Grey. I am certain it is.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination.]</p>
               <p>Council. Where had this Receipt been before that?</p>
               <p>Grey. I don't know; they stopp'd me?</p>
               <p>Council. If they have had it ever since, how could you be so positive to it?</p>
               <p>Grey. It was No. 53. payable to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person335">
                  Thomas 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person335" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person335" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or Order; my right Name is 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person336">
                  John 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person336" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person336" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How came your Name to be altered to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person337">
                  John 
                  Grey 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person337" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person337" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? What is the Reason you change your Name ?</p>
               <p>Grey. I tell you, Sir; 'tis my Unhappiness (and which attends Thousands) to be in Debt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person338">
                  George 
                  Shelvocke 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person338" type="surname" value="Shelvocke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person338" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; Secretary to the Post-Office. When Lawrence was apprehended, he was brought before me to be examined; accordingly, in the Course of that Examination, it appeared he had given this Bank Note in Question, to Hardwick, to negociate for him; upon which, I sent immediately for Hardwick to be apprehended. I think he mention'd he gave it to Hardwick to buy a Lottery-Ticket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any Excuse when he was charged with the Affair.</p>
               <p>Mr Shelvocke. He said he found the Bank Note at first; and Grey, the other Witness, he said he found the Receipt.</p>
               <p>Court. You live, Mr Shelvocke, in the Post-house, that is, Part of the Office?</p>
               <p>Mr Shelvocke. I live in my Lord Leicester's Apartment.</p>
               <p>Court. This is laid to be in the Dwelling-house; Sir, I ask you, whether this Hall is part of your Dwelling-house?</p>
               <p>Mr Shelvocke. There was a Door into the Hall, but it is stopp'd up?</p>
               <p>Court. Then 'tis no Part of the Dwelling-house?</p>
               <p>Mr Shelvocke. It is as much part of the Dwelling-house, as a Merchant's Compting-house is part of his Dwelling house.</p>
               <p>Court. In the House you live in, separate from Mr Robinson's, is that tax'd to any Rate whatsoever ?</p>
               <p>Mr Shelvocke. I believe the whole is tax'd as one House.</p>
               <p>Court. If you had laid it in the Joint-House of the Company, you would be still wrong if you laid it upon the whole in general.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. The Question is, whether there is any Proof of his felonious taking of it all, I would say it is but a look kind of Evidence. What, because this Gentleman was concern'd in the Post-Office, and in the same Seat there was seven or eight other People, that therefore he must take this Bill out of the Letter; if he did not take it out of the Letter, then it will recur to the Confession he made to Mr Shelvocke and Mr Potts; Mr Shelvocke says he confess'd he gave the Note to Hardwick to buy a Lottery-Ticket, and he said he found it in the Post-Office Yard; if it be taken upon his Confession, then 'tis the standing Rule that it must be taken altogether, if he found it in the Post-Office Yard, tho' he did very wrong to convert it to his own use, but this is not a Felony. This Letter comes to Town the 22d of April; on the 7th of May he sends a Man, with this Bank Bill, which was remarkable, to a publick Lottery-Office; now this was the most improper time in the World for him to have sent it, if he had been sensible he had been guilty of any Kind of Felony. We have a great many Witnesses to his Character.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person339">
                  Edward 
                  Monday 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person339" type="surname" value="Monday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person339" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person340">
                  Daniel 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person340" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person340" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Monday. I have known him these twelve Years.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character has he bore all that while?</p>
               <p>Monday. Always a very honest Character.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would venture to commit a Felony, without Benefit of the Clergy, for the value of twenty Pounds?</p>
               <p>Monday. The last Man I should have thought would have been guilty of such a Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person341">
                  Thomas 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person341" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person341" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would have been guilty of such a Fact?</p>
               <p>Knight. I never thought he would.</p>
               <p>Mary Lane. I have known Mr Lawrence, the Prisoner, twelve Years, and he always bore a very good Character.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17470909-37-person342">
                  John 
                  Grey 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person342" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person342" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Harris, what Character does he bear ?</p>
               <p>Lane. I wish I could say altogether so well of him; I can say but little of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-37-person343">
                  Joseph 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17470909-37-person343" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person343" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mr Lawrence nine Years, and he has a good Character.</p>
               <p>There were seven or eight Witnesses more to the Character of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090033"></xptr>Council for the Crown. Mr Hassel says it is a loose Evidence we have given; I think we have given a good Evidence. The Prisoner pretends he found this in the Post-Office Yard, impossible to be true. Could he, as an honest Man, cross the Yard of the Post-Office, see this Piece of Paper, take it up; altogether unlikely, and no Evidence given of it.</p>
               <p>As it appeared there are separate Apartments in the Post-Office, the Jury could not find a Verdict against the Prisoner for stealing out of the Dwelling-house; but found him <rs id="t17470909-37-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-37-verdict160" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing in general, but not out of the Dwelling-house
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
