<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-9">
               <interp inst="t17460903-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-9" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-9" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-9-off33-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-9-defend106 t17460903-9-off33 t17460903-9-verdict34"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-9-off33-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-9-defend107 t17460903-9-off33 t17460903-9-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>290, 291. 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-defend106" type="defendantName">
                  Original 
                  March 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend106" type="surname" value="March"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend106" type="given" value="Original"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              and 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-defend107" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend107" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend107" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-defend107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17460903-9-off33" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-off33" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-off33" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing 14 lb. Weight of Hog's Bristles
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-victim109" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Yeomans 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-9-victim109" type="surname" value="Yeomans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-victim109" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-victim109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-9-off33 t17460903-9-victim109"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person110">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person110" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person110" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person111">
                  Thomas 
                  Yeomans 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person111" type="surname" value="Yeomans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person111" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoners at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Yeomans. I never saw the Man but once before, but the Woman I know; I have two Parcels of Bristles here, about 14 lb. Weight; these Bristles, and some in the Bag, are mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this Bag and Bristles found?</p>
               <p>Yeomans. These were sent to me by an unknown Hand, and the Bag was taken from the two Prisoners; that is all I have to say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person112">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person112" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person112" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person113">
                  George 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person113" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person113" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Stanley. Nothing to say, my Lord, but that this Original March offer'd these Bristles to my Wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present?</p>
               <p>Stanley. I was not present.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you understand any thing of it, besides what your Wife told you?</p>
               <p>Stanley. My Wife is a Person that sells Goods, Bristles, and Hair Brooms, &amp;c. about the Streets. On this Side of Leicester-Fields, this Original March took Hold of the Handle of one of the Brooms, and ask'd her some Questions, and said that he had a large Quantity of Bristles to sell: I also saw him myself, and he offer'd these Bristles to Sale; I ask'd him what he would have for them, but he could not tell; he ask'd me what I would give for them, so that I found he was ignorant; not only so, but I thought within myself that they were stolen, because there is no Person that has such a Commodity but Brush-makers. He told me he had a large Quantity of these Hairs to dispose of, 5 or 600 Weight. I follow'd him the whole Day, but would not seize this small Parcel, in Hopes of finding the biggest. It was on the 25th of July; I was a whole Day with him, and spent my Money upon him. I went again the 26th, on Saturday Morning; when I came there he was a Bed. I order'd the Landlord to call him down; I ask'd him to drink; I said Mr. March, as you have such a large Quantity of Bristles to sell, I would have you let me see them; he said he had no more at that Time, but if I would take them in Part, he would make them up a Quarter of a Hundred, and that he had them for a Debt of a Gentleman that was then in Ludgate, which was false, for he had them of Mr. Yeoman's Maid in St. Thomas Apostles; She put the Bristles in this same Bag, and he (Original March) took them of her, in order to pay a Debt of 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person114">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person114" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person114" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, (the other Prisoner) to one Mrs. Collins, in Tyburn Road. I carried him before the Justice, and he said 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person115">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person115" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person115" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the Hairs, and gave them to him. Then they were examin'd before my Lord, both of them own'd the Fact; one was committed to Newgate, and the other to Wood-Street Compter.</p>
               <p>Court. Now recollect the very Words.</p>
               <p>Stanley. As near as I can guess, the Woman said she took the Hairs, and gave them to O. March, and desir'd him to sell them to pay this Debt to Mrs. Collins.</p>
               <p>Q. Did March say he saw Deacon take them and put them into the Bag?</p>
               <p>Stanley. Yes, and that she gave them to him afterwards, and said, March, if you can take a few of these Hairs, and pay this little Money, if you have a Conscience that will do it; and March said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030012"></xptr> Conscience be hang'd. The Prisoner Deacon said she was sorry in one sense, and yet glad in another; for if it had not been found out, Things might have been worse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person116">
                  Jane 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person116" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person116" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , On the 24th of July this Original March overtook me (on this Side of Leicester-Fields) with Brushes, &amp;c. He ask'd me what I could afford to give him for such Brooms without Handels; he told me he had a great many Brush Brooms of all forts; he said also that he had a great Quantity of Hairs on Account of a Gentleman that ow'd him Threefcore Pounds, that was in Ludgate. He took me to his Lodgings; when I came there I expected to see Brushes and Brooms, &amp;c. so he brought me down that Bag with Bristles in them; he ask'd me 20 d. a Pound for them: I told him I believ'd they were worth more, but I told him I was not so good a Judge as my Husband, but I would send him in the Evening. My Husband went the next Morning, and spent the whole Day in order to have the other Quantity. March, the Prisoner, said he had kept Company with 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person117">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person117" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person117" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the Way of a Husband, for four Years; that he lay with her at several Times, eight Nights in all; that she gave him these Hairs to pay a Debt to Mrs. Collins, which she borrow'd of her in her Necessity.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person118">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person118" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person118" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person119">
                  Edward 
                  Speak 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person119" type="surname" value="Speak"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person119" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say in this Affair ?</p>
               <p>Speak. I have nothing more, than that I was present at the Time when the Goods were stopt. The Prisoner, whose Name is Original March, has acknowledg'd he had the Bristles from 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person120">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person120" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person120" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Servant to Mr. Yeomans, in 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person121">
                  Thomas 
                  Apostles 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person121" type="surname" value="Apostles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person121" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; that he had lay'd with her frequently there, and that she went for his Wife, but he was never married to her; she used frequently to let him in after her Master was gone to Bed, and to let him out in the Morning before they were up, and the last Night she gave him these Bristles. When the Fellow was stopt, I knowing Mr. Yeomans, I sent Mr. Stanley to give him Information; he came back to let me know that the Maid was secur'd, accordingly they were carried before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Court. Speak first as to March.</p>
               <p>Speak. March acknowledg'd he had them from Mr. Yeomans's Maid, to pay a Debt to one Mrs. Collins.</p>
               <p>Q. Did 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person122">
                  Sarah 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person122" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person122" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say any Thing?</p>
               <p>Speak. At the Time she was much surpriz'd, but as it was done, she could not help it. She acknowledged she had given the Goods to Original March, and he was there that Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person123">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person123" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person123" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Prisoner March) In the first Place what have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Woman, please you my Lord, had put up these Hairs in a Bag, and she said she had come honestly by them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-9-person124">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person124" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person124" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Deacon) Have you any Thing to say by Way of Defence?</p>
               <p>Katharine Yeomans. I am Wife to 
               <persName id="t17460903-9-person125">
                  Thomas 
                  Yeomans 
               <interp inst="t17460903-9-person125" type="surname" value="Yeomans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person125" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; all that I have to say of her is, that she is really capable of being a good Servant, and behav'd very well 'till she got into Company with this Fellow: He came into the House, and lay there when he took the Goods out. I believe he has been the Ruin of her, and, my Lord, I would pray that she may be forgiven.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17460903-9-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-9-punish35" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-9-punish35" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-9-defend106 t17460903-9-punish35"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-9-defend107 t17460903-9-punish35"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
