<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-4">
               <interp inst="t17421208-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-4" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-4" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-4-off21-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-4-defend50 t17421208-4-off21 t17421208-4-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080004"></xptr>4. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-defend50" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-4-defend50" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-defend50" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-defend50" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17421208-4-defloc20">St James's, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-4-defloc20" type="placeName" value="St James's, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-4-defloc20" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-4-defend50 t17421208-4-defloc20"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17421208-4-off21" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-off21" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-off21" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               she the said 
                     <persName id="t17421208-4-person51">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Davis 
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person51" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-4-person51" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-4-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the <rs id="t17421208-4-cd22" type="crimeDate">6th of October, in the 16th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-4-off21 t17421208-4-cd22"></join>, being big with a certain Male Child, the said Male Child she did alone and secretly bring forth alive; which said Child , by the Laws of this Land, was a Bastard; and she not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. as soon as the said Male Bastard Child was born, with Force and Arms, in and upon the said Child did make an Assault with both her Hands, and him the said Male Bastard Child in a Linnen Shift, Value 6 d. did wrap and fold, by Means of which Wrapping and Folding in the said Linnen Shift, the said Child was choaked and strangled, and that the said Child, by such Choaking and Strangling did die, and that she, the said 
                     <persName id="t17421208-4-person52">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Davis 
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person52" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-4-person52" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-4-person52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said Male Bastard Child did kill and murder
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>She was a 2d Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person53">
                  Ann 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person53" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person53" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One Sunday, about seven Weeks ago, a little after 7 o'Clock in the Evening, I went down to the Necessary-House, at Mr Hughes's in <placeName id="t17421208-4-crimeloc23">little Jermyn-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-4-crimeloc23" type="placeName" value="little Jermyn-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-4-crimeloc23" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-4-off21 t17421208-4-crimeloc23"></join>, and saw a Bundle of Linnen lie in the Necessary-House: I was somewhat surprized, and accordingly I came up and desired Mr Hughes and his Wife to see what it was. They unrolled it, and said it was a Child. *- I did not see the Child till it was wash'd the next Day, I was so frightened; then it was laid upon a Table. I examined it in every Part, and saw no Marks of Violence. - It lay there till the next Day.</p>
               <p>* 21st James I. Cap 27. If any Woman be delivered of any Issue of her Body, which, being born alive, should by the Laws of this Realm , be a Bastard, and she endeavour privately, either by drowning, or fact burying thereof, or any other Way, either by herself, or the procuring of others, so to conceal the Death thereof , as that it may not come to light, whether it were born alive or not, but he concealed: In every such Case, the Mother so offending, shall suffer Death, as in Case of Murther, except such Mother can make Proof by the Witness at the least, that the Child was born dead.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person54">
                  John 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person54" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs Gilbert , about the Time she speaks of, went down into the Necessary-Place, and came up very much frightened, and said she saw a Bundle of Linnen in the Vault (which is a Common-Sewer) endeavoured to be push'd into a Hole. She acquainted me with it: I let it lie that Night. Next Day I called to a Neighbour, and got a Pair of Tongs and took it out of the Vault. I pulled off one Linnen and then another, and discovered a Child's Hand and Arm. I was very much frightened, and went to a Justice of the Peace, to know what to do (for I did not know the Nature of the Affair) he ordered me to go to the Coroner. - It was discovered on Sunday Night between seven and eight o'Clock, but I did not take it out till Monday the 11th of October. It was a Male Child. When it was wash'd I laid it on a Table, in a convenient Place for the Jury to examine it. - There were no Marks of Violence upon it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person55">
                  Ann 
                  Tullock 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person55" type="surname" value="Tullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person55" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Midwife; I saw the Child upon a Table. There was no Appearance of any Violence.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon viewing the Child, how do you think it came by its Death?</p>
               <p>Tullock . I cannot say indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Thing provided for the Child ?</p>
               <p>Tullock. There were some Things provided for the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know she was the Mother of the Child?</p>
               <p>Tullock. No. - It is my Opinion the Child came to its full Time, but the poor Creature was ignorant.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think there was any Miscarriage?</p>
               <p>Tullock. I cannot be sure whether the Mother of the Child went her full Time. - I believe she might come pretty near to the Time. - She owned herself to be the Mother of the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say with Respect to the Death of the Child?</p>
               <p>Tullock. She said she was delivered of a dead Child, and that she did not think herself in Labour. - I believe the Child was born at a Relation's of her's in Piccadilly, at her Brother's; she was Serant there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you whether there was any Midwife attended on the Occasion.</p>
               <p>Tullock . She did not tell me that; but she told me the Child was carried and put into a Vault, to avoid her Shame. I asked her, if she had any Thing prepared for the Infant, and she said Yes; - It was after she was in Custody that she told me this; she said she had provided Things for the Child, and that they were in a Closet in the Room where she lay at her Brother's; and I went and found all the Things there as she said.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Closet locked?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080005"></xptr>Tullock . Her Brother was mov'd from that House to another. - The House was empty when I went to look for these Things; I got the Key of the Landlord, and went and found them there; these are the Things. - They are convenient Things for a Person in those Circumstances.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person56">
                  Roger 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person56" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person56" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am Coroner for the Liberty of Westminster; this is a Copy of the Examination * I took from the Prisoner at the Bar before the Jury, signed with her own Hand; she said the same in Substace to Mrs Tullock, tho' she did not chuse, it seems, to mention it.</p>
               <p>* 1st &amp; 2d, Philip &amp; Mary, Cap. 13. Sect. 5 &amp; 6. Every Coroner, upon any Inquisition before him found, whereby any Person or Persons shall be indicted for Murder or Manslaughter committed, shall put in Writing the Effect of the Evidence given to the Jury before him. - And shall also take Examinations, &amp;c. and certify them at the next Goal-Delivery.</p>
               <p>The Examination of 
               <persName id="t17421208-4-person57">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person57" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person57" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Spinster, of the Parish of St James, Westminster, taken this 12th of October, 1742.</p>
               <p>This Examinant faith, '' That on the 5th Instant '' she was delivered of a Male Child (which '' was still-born) at the Bear and Ragged Staff in '' Piccadilly, in the Parish of St James, Westminster; '' and that on the 10th Instant, she, this '' Examinant, unfortunately convey'd the same into '' the Bog-House, belonging to the House of John '' Hughes, in Li ttle Jermyn street, in the said Parish '' of St James, and cast it down the same.</p>
               <p>The Mark of 
               <persName id="t17421208-4-person58">
                  Elizabeth X 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person58" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person58" type="given" value="Elizabeth X"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Taken and acknowledg'd before me,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person59">
                  Roger 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person59" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person59" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Coroner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-4-person60">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17421208-4-person60" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person60" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . [The Prisoner's Brother.] When I examined her how she came to sign her Confession, when she can neither read nor write, she said she did not know what she did. As she is a young Body, and an ignorant Person, I hope the Court will take it into Consideration. She always behav'd well; I never saw her concerned in Liquor all the while she liv'd with me. I knew no more of this Affair than the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We were moving from one House to another, and carrying heavy Things, I hurt myself. I came before my Time, which I did not think I had been so near. I was up three Pair of Stairs by my self when I was deliver'd, and could not make any Body hear me. I was well enough when I went to Bed, and did not think of being in Labour. The Child was dead born. <rs id="t17421208-4-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-4-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
