<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490113-26">
               <interp inst="t17490113-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-26" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-26" type="date" value="17490113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490113-26-off126-c124" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-defend177 t17490113-26-off126 t17490113-26-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>121. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-26-defend177" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     George 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-26-defend177" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-defend177" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-defend177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17490113-26-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver quart tankard, value 7 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-26-victim179" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Francis 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-26-victim179" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-victim179" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-victim179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-off126 t17490113-26-victim179"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17490113-26-cd127" type="crimeDate">Dec. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-off126 t17490113-26-cd127"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-26-person180">
                  Charles 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17490113-26-person180" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person180" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17490113-26-viclabel128" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17490113-26-crimeloc129">King's head, little East Cheap</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-crimeloc129" type="placeName" value="King's head, little East Cheap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-crimeloc129" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-off126 t17490113-26-crimeloc129"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-victim179 t17490113-26-viclabel128"></join>; the prisoner came to my house the 21st of Dec. at about six o'clock, he told me he should have a person come to ask for him by the name of 
               <persName id="t17490113-26-person181">
                  William 
                  George 
               <interp inst="t17490113-26-person181" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; if such a person should come before he was return'd, he desir'd I would request him to stay, for he should soon return; he came much about the time himself, but no person had call'd. He called for a tankard of beer, paid for it; company being in the fore room, he desired to go into another, near the kitchen, joining the fire place: The boy brought him a tankard of beer, he said the gentleman was mistaken in the sign, where they were to meet. He desir'd the boy to go over the way, to the Bell and ask for one Hambleton; the boy went and came back again, and said, there was no such person there, and observed the prisoner drinking out of a pewter tankard. The boy came to me, and told me what he saw, and that the silver tankard was not in sight; I suppose the prisoner might overhear this. When I went into the room, I found he had his beer in the silver tankard; says I, have not you got a pewter tankard about you? He gave me but a slight answer; at last I found it concealed in an apron tuck'd about his waist. I shewed it to the gentlemen in the house, and observ'd it to be wet; I asked him how he came by it; he told me, he was a pewterer and made it himself. I believe, my lord, he did design to make an exchange with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-26-person182">
                  James 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17490113-26-person182" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person182" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I brought a tankard of beer to the prisoner, according to his order, in a silver tankard, with a King William and Mary's crown piece on the top of the lid; he paid for it, and bid me go over to the Bell tavern, and ask if one Hambleton was there; I returned and told him there was no such person. He said it was very well. He then bid me go to one Mrs. Skedny's, a chandler's shop, and ask for the same man; I went accordingly, but she knew no such person. When I came back, I saw him drinking out of a pewter tankard, and the silver one was not to be seen. I told my master there was a pewter tankard on the table. My master said he had not a pewter tankard in use. I did not go into the room with my master to see what pass'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-26-person183">
                  Edward 
                  Bowman 
               <interp inst="t17490113-26-person183" type="surname" value="Bowman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person183" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Francis's drinking the 21st of Dec. I had been out and coming in again, I turn'd my eye as I pass'd the door, there I saw the prisoner pouring beer out of one tankard into another.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I bought the pewter tankard of a woman in the street, she had a basket on her arm, and the tankard hanging on her finger, I was willing to try if it was measure; so before I drank, I pour'd out the beer into my pewter tankard; this gentleman comes and says, friend, I understand you have got a pewter tankard about you. Yes, says I, I have bought one to day; says he, my friend, it looks as though you had a design to make an exchange with me. I am no such man, says I; then the people got up in arms, and went for a constable, that is the whole affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-26-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of Felony.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-26-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-26-punish131" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-26-defend177 t17490113-26-punish131"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
