<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410405-31">
               <interp inst="t17410405-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-31" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-31" type="date" value="17410405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410405-31-off132-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-31-defend222 t17410405-31-off132 t17410405-31-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>33. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Castle 
                  <interp inst="t17410405-31-defend222" type="surname" value="Castle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-defend222" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted <rs id="t17410405-31-off132" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-off132" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-off132" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               for that he (with another Person unknown) about 8 at Night the Dwelling-House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410405-31-victim224" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           French 
                        <interp inst="t17410405-31-victim224" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-31-victim224" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-31-victim224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-31-off132 t17410405-31-victim224"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, with intent him the said French to kill and murder; and the Indictment farther charged, that he the said Castle the Dwelling-House aforesaid did break and enter with Intent the Goods of the said French to steal, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution having opened the Indictment and the Nature of the Evidence, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-person225">
                  Mary 
                  Wiat 
               <interp inst="t17410405-31-person225" type="surname" value="Wiat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person225" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Mr. French's House, in <placeName id="t17410405-31-crimeloc133">Plumb-tree Court, Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-31-crimeloc133" type="placeName" value="Plumb-tree Court, Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-31-crimeloc133" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-31-off132 t17410405-31-crimeloc133"></join>. On the 11th of March, a little after 7 o'Clock in the Evening, as near as I can guess, I went out, and latched the Door fast after me.</p>
               <p>Coun . What fastening is there to the Door?</p>
               <p>Wiat. There is an Iron Latch to the Door, and after I had shut it, I turned back and pushed against it that I might be sure it was fast.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-person226">
                  Richard 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17410405-31-person226" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person226" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Plumb-tree Court, Holbourn. On the 11th of March last, about 8 o'Clock, I and my Maid were at Work in the Kitchen; she sat next the Window, and I next the Chimney. As we sat thus, somebody knocked at the Kitchen Door with their Knuckles; I desired the Maid to see who it was, and as soon as she had opened the Door, a Man asked her if one Mr. Briton did not live there; she answered, no, and was going to shut the Door, and immediately the Prisoner and another burst in. The Prisoner came violently on me, and said, D - n you, you old Dog, I will do your Business for you: upon that, he made no more ado, but he put both his Hands about my Throat, to throttle me: I struggled and cried out Murder! as much as I could, but no Body came to my Assistance. When he had throttled me so, he threw me across the Kitchen Grate, with my Head on the back of the Chimney, and flung himself on me and clapped both his Hands on my Mouth to stop my Breath. I kicked with my Feet as well as I could, and broke his Hold from my Mouth, and then I cried Murder twice. He then put his Hands on my Mouth again, so that I was almost suffocated; at the same Time swearing, if I made the least Noise, he would certainly cut my Throat across. In this Condition I continued 'till my Servant, who was at Work in the Yard, being alarmed at the Noise, came and took the Prisoner from me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him whether I did not lodge with him some Time ago; and whether he did not threaten to serve me with a Copy of a Writ for Money which I owed him?</p>
               <p>French. He lodged about 7 Weeks with me, and owed me nine Shillings at that Time: I was very glad that I could get him out of my House, and never went after him in my Life for the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I propose to pay you some Money that Night?</p>
               <p>French. No, he never mentioned a Word of Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Could you not have seen my Face if we had been out of Doors, without a Light?</p>
               <p>French. No, I am certain I could not, for it was almost 8 o'Clock at Night, and it had been dark the best Part of an Hour.</p>
               <p>Coun. May not a Person lift up the Latch of your outward Door, without your hearing it?</p>
               <p>French. Yes, very easily.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-person227">
                  Sarah 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17410405-31-person227" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person227" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting at the Table with my Master on the 11th of March, and heard somebody rap at the Kitchen Door; I opened it a little Way, and saw 2 Men in the Passage: one of them asked for one Mr. Briton ; I told them he did not live in our House, and was going to shut the Door, but a Foot stopped it, and that Moment a Fellow pushed the Door open against me, and dragged me to the other Side of the Room, and threw me down. When I was on the Ground, he throttled me and squeezed my Throat all Manner of Ways, so that I was almost dead. The Prisoner flew on my Master, and threw him across the Grate, but the other Fellow used me in such a Manner that I was not able to make any farther Observations.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Time was this?</p>
               <p>Goodwin. It was very near 8 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it light?</p>
               <p>Goodwin. No, it was so dark that I am sure I could not have distinguished one Person's Face from another's in the Street.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I say that I came to pay her Master nine Shillings?</p>
               <p>Goodwin. No, there was not a Word spoke about Money; but the other Man asked for Briton, and the Prisoner was then standing behind him.</p>
               <p>Israel Mitchel. On the 11th of March, between 7 and 8 o'Clock, I was at Work in our Shop, which is in the Yard, and heard a Sort of a Noise, something like a rattling in a Man's Throat. I did not go down then, but hearing the same Noise about a Minute afterwards, I took this Stick and went into the Kitchen. When I came into the Passage,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174104050010"></xptr> I saw a Man stand with the Street Door in his Hand, and on going into the Kitchen, I saw the Maid standing in a frightful Posture, and my Master across the Grate, and the Prisoner before him with both his Hands on my Master's Throat.</p>
               <p>Coun. Where was your Master then?</p>
               <p>Mitchel. He was lying a cross the Fire, and the Prisoner was upon him with his Hands on my Masster's Throat. I stood still to observe what Motions the Prisoner made, but could observe no more than there is in this Stick Upon that I laid hold of his Collar, and fell to beating him as hard as my Hands would meet him; and he made out as hard as he could. I then pursued him and struck up his Heels and he fell down some Steps at the End of the Court, but before I could get up to him, he recovered himself and took to his Heels again, and was taken by a Man who was passing by.</p>
               <p>Prisoner, Is it not possible for People to go in and out of your House without your hearing of them?</p>
               <p>Mitchel. Yes.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I owed this Man nine Shillings when I left his House, and I not being able to pay him, he threatned to serve me with the Copy of a Writ, and that Night I went to his House to offer to pay him at 2 s. a Time. This Maid opened the Door, and as soon as the Prosecutor saw me, he flew into a violent Passion, and abused me grossly before I touched him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-person228">
                  Robert 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17410405-31-person228" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person228" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner between 3 and 4 Years; he always behaved himself honestly. I never heard that he was spiteful or malicious, and don't believe he would murder any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-31-person229">
                  John 
                  Peacock 
               <interp inst="t17410405-31-person229" type="surname" value="Peacock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Public-House, and have known the Prisoner 3 Months. I don't take him to be of a malicious Temper, and can't believe that he would be guilty of Murder. <rs id="t17410405-31-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-31-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
