<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430519-30">
               <interp inst="t17430519-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-30" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430519"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-30" type="date" value="17430519"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-30-off149-c215" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-30-defend275 t17430519-30-off149 t17430519-30-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>279. 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-defend275" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Sutton 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-30-defend275" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-defend275" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-defend275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430519-30-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three Holland Shirts, val. 3 l. 3 s. two Dimitty Waistcoats, four Linnen Handkerchiefs, two Cambrick Stocks, and a Silver Spoon
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-victim277" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Crisp 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-30-victim277" type="surname" value="Crisp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-victim277" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-victim277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-30-off149 t17430519-30-victim277"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17430519-30-cd150" type="crimeDate">May 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-30-off149 t17430519-30-cd150"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-person278">
                  Henry 
                  Crisp 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person278" type="surname" value="Crisp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person278" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner lived with me as a <rs id="t17430519-30-deflabel151" type="occupation">Footman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-30-defend275 t17430519-30-deflabel151"></join> near half a Year. About three Weeks ago, a Constable came to me with the Evidence, and said he had been at a Pawnbroker's, with a Silver Spoon, the Crest a Griffin (which is my Crest) upon which the Constable, two other Men, and myself, went, by his Direction, and found the Shirts at two different Places. This was on the Information of 
               <persName id="t17430519-30-person279">
                  George 
                  Ogden 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person279" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person279" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-person280">
                  George 
                  Ogden 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person280" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person280" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the Prisoner about a Quarter of a Year; the beginning of April, I was at Mr Crisp's and the Prisoner gave me a blue and white Linnen Handkerchief; I asked him what it was for, he said, it was something that he had taken in part of a Debt: There was in the Handkerchief two very fine Dimitty Waistcoats, one Shirt, and two Stocks; he said, if I could dispose of them, I should have half for my Pains. I carried the two Waistcoats and the two Stocks to Mrs Kitteridge , in Bow-lane, she asked me, how I came by them; I told her, an Acquaintance of mine had taken them for a Debt; she desired I would take Care, and not bring myself into any Premunire; and I sold the Shirt to Mrs Palmer for ten Shillings; I gave 
               <persName id="t17430519-30-person281">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person281" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person281" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 5 s. out of the 10 s. which I had for the Shirt: George gave me a Handkerchief with two other Handkerchiefs, and two Shirts in it,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190020"></xptr> which he said he took of the same Person, for part of the same Debt; I carried these to Mrs Kitteridge , said she, I wish you are not got into ill Company. and said, if I was and did not come honestly by them, she would not have them for the World: So I told her where the young Man I had them of liv'd, and his Master's Name, and left them with her; and I sold Mrs Palmer another Shirt, which was bran-new, for 10 s. and there was a Woman who keeps an Herb-stall gave me 1 s. for one Handkerchief, and 10 d. for the other; another Time he gave me a Silver Spoon, and desired me to dispose of it; I showed it to a Pawnbroker, the Pawnbroker look'd at the Spoon and said here's a Crest upon it I must stop the Spoon; he charged a Constable with me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Makepeace , the Constable. On the 3d of May I was charged with this young Fellow [Ogden] on Account of this Spoon being stopped at a Pawn-broker's, on Suspicion of its being stole; I told him I would not part with him, unless he would let me into the Affair, I said it is a Family Spoon, and if you will not tell me who it belongs to, I will go to the Heralds-Office and there I shall find it out; then he told me it was Mr. Crisp's; I went to Mr Crisp's, and found there had been a farther Robbery, and then by Ogden's Direction I found 1 Shirt and 2 Waistcoats at Mrs Kitteridge's on Garlick Hill, and 2 Shirts at Mrs Palmer's in Huggin lane, and the 2 Handkerchiefs I found at a Greens-shop , and they were all surrender'd very readily. [The Things were produced, and owned by Mr Crisp.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-person282">
                  Richard 
                  Peake 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person282" type="surname" value="Peake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person282" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , for the Prisoner. At the Time this Evidence was taken up, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief; I stopp'd him, and he own'd he had robbed Mr Crisp , and said that he was the principal Person that took away these things from Mr Crisp's , he own'd he took the Spoon, and the rest of the things, unknown to the Prisoner; he said he us'd to do odd Jobbs for the Footman or Servant-Maids; he said he took the things while the Prisoner and the Servant-Maids were playing in the Garden.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-30-person283">
                  William 
                  Elson 
               <interp inst="t17430519-30-person283" type="surname" value="Elson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person283" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . May 3, in the Morning, I was standing just by my Door, I saw Ogden and a Woman coming down Cloak lane, there was a pretty hot Dispute between them, but he went from her, and she cried Stop Thief; I asked her what he had stole; she said he had stole a Silver-Spoon; I told her she would not be safe without detaining the Man, for it was a Family-Spoon by the Crest; so she sent for Mr Makepeace and charg'd him with him; and he confess'd the taking the Spoon without the Knowledge of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs Walker gave the Prisoner a good Character. <rs id="t17430519-30-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-30-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
