<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-45">
               <interp inst="t17420909-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-45" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-45" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-45-off228-c407" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-45-defend503 t17420909-45-off228 t17420909-45-verdict231"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090040"></xptr>111. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-45-defend503" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Morell 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-45-defend503" type="surname" value="Morell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-defend503" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-defend503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17420909-45-defloc227">St Paul Shadwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-45-defloc227" type="placeName" value="St Paul Shadwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-45-defloc227" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-45-defend503 t17420909-45-defloc227"></join>, <rs id="t17420909-45-off228" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-off228" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-off228" type="offenceSubcategory" value="taxOffences"></interp>
               was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17420909-45-cd229" type="crimeDate">second Day of August, in the sixteenth Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-45-off228 t17420909-45-cd229"></join>, with Force and Arms, assaulted, hindered, opposed, and obstructed 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420909-45-victim505" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Messenger 
                        <interp inst="t17420909-45-victim505" type="surname" value="Messenger"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-45-victim505" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-45-victim505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-45-off228 t17420909-45-victim505"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , one of his Majesty's Officers in the Port of London, in the Execution of the said Office, against the Form of the Statute in this Case made and provided
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-45-person506">
                  Henry 
                  Messenger 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person506" type="surname" value="Messenger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person506" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed: That he was on Board the Ship called the Blessing, August the second, at <placeName id="t17420909-45-crimeloc230">Ratcliff Cross, in the Port of London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-45-crimeloc230" type="placeName" value="Ratcliff Cross, in the Port of London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-45-crimeloc230" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-45-off228 t17420909-45-crimeloc230"></join>, about eleven at Night, he saw a Boat come along Side the Vessel, which gave him a Suspicion that something was to be done, and laid his Hand upon Half an Ancher of Brandy; and then another; that he seized them, and no Man obstructed him. A Man came and struck him on the Shoulder, or pushed him violently, and struck him Head-foremost down the Ladder into the Stearage, followed him and beat him, and struck him several Blows; and he took half an Anchor and run away with it; that 
               <persName id="t17420909-45-person507">
                  John 
                  Morell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person507" type="surname" value="Morell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person507" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Prisoner beat him, and said he was Captain of the Ship; that he [Morell] was Boatswain of the Ship, Blessing; that the Sailors must know him to be an Officer, because they call them Partners, but he did not know whether Morell was present when the Custom-house-Officers came on Board; that he is sure this is the Man that abused and assaulted him, and that he must know him to be an Officer, because he had suffered him to carry some little Things on Shore.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-45-person508">
                  William 
                  Walls 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person508" type="surname" value="Walls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person508" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed: That he was a Tidesman on Board the Ship, Blessing: That he saw his Partner, Messenger, fall Neck and Heels down the Steerage, and saw a Man follow him, and saw him strike Messenger two or three Blows. That his Partner, Messenger, call'd out, What will you stay and see me murdered; and that then he turned out as fast as he could. That when he came into the Forecastle, he laid his Hands upon a Man's Legs or Thighs, and asked him, What Business he had there? He said, Damn your Blood, I am Captain of the Ship, What Business have you with me? That he (Watts) said to him, be you the Devil, I will hold you if I can; that he said to his Partner, Messenger, here's one of them. That then his Partner came to his Assistance; that before he came, he struck him three or four Blows on the Belly. That 
               <persName id="t17420909-45-person509">
                  John 
                  Morell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person509" type="surname" value="Morell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person509" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , the Prisoner at the Bar, is the Man. That they had no Occasion to declare they were Officers, for all the Ship's Company knew it. That Morell was Boatswain of the Ship, and came up from Gravesend with them. That they never show them their Deputations - That there was another Man came into the Forecastle with a Handspike, and struck at Messenger, and then they cried out Murder, and had Assistance from other Ships; three from one Ship, and one from another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-45-person510">
                  Jonathan 
                  Bonner 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person510" type="surname" value="Bonner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person510" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed: That hearing a Cry of Murder on Board the Ship, Blessing, they went on board her off the Forecastle into the Windlace, and from thence to the Main Deck; and before the Windlace they found Messenger had hold of the Prisoner at the Bar, and that Messenger kept his hold, till he, Bonner, laid hold of him, with the Assistance of the Rest of the Officers, and they carried him into the Cabbin, and continued with him all Night, and the next Day, till he was brought before Justice Dennet; and that the Prisoner at the Bar is the very Man: And that it can be no Secret to the Sailors that they are Officers when they go on Board, for they are always called by the Name of Partners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-45-person511">
                  Jonathan 
                  Crockson 
               <interp inst="t17420909-45-person511" type="surname" value="Crockson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person511" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-person511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , another Officer, deposed to the same Effect. But the Jury, thinking it was incumbent upon them to prove, that they had informed the Prisoner that they were Officers, (which they had not) he was <rs id="t17420909-45-verdict231" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-45-verdict231" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
