<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-23">
               <interp inst="t17470225-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-23" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-23" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-23-off102-c261" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-23-defend309 t17470225-23-off102 t17470225-23-verdict105"></join>
         
               <p>154. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-23-defend309" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Perindine 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-23-defend309" type="surname" value="Perindine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-defend309" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-defend309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-23-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one pair of Brass' Candlesticks, value 3 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-23-victim311" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Tempest 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-23-victim311" type="surname" value="Tempest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-victim311" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-victim311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-23-off102 t17470225-23-victim311"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470225-23-cd103" type="crimeDate">February 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-23-off102 t17470225-23-cd103"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-23-person312">
                  James 
                  Tempest 
               <interp inst="t17470225-23-person312" type="surname" value="Tempest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person312" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What have you to say against the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Tempest. On Saturday last, about two o'Clock in the Afternoon, she and her Husband came into my Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What Shop do you keep?</p>
               <p>Tempest. A Broker's Shop in <placeName id="t17470225-23-crimeloc104">Silver street, Golden-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-23-crimeloc104" type="placeName" value="Silver street, Golden-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-23-crimeloc104" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-23-off102 t17470225-23-crimeloc104"></join>. They took up a Poker, and cheapened it; we did not agree; Then they cheapened a Coffee-pot, and he bought it, and paid me for it. After he had bought that, my Lord, he asked for a Tea-kettle; he took up an old brass one that was not good enough, she wanted a better; Then they cheapened half a Dozen of Knives and Forks, and then they asked for Pewter spoons, and bought them, and paid me for them; He bought a Coffee-pot, a Tea kettle, six Knives and Forks, and two Pewter-spoons: Then they went away. When I went to put up my Things, and they were gone away, they had not been gone long, a little Boy at home says, the Gentlewoman has got a Pair of Candlesticks under her Cloak; I told the Boy to step after her: The Boy ran down James street, and the Boy said, Madam, I believe you have got something more than your own. Says she, I am a very honest Woman. She comes hastily to my Shop again, and from under her Cloak she draws out a Pair of Candlesticks.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she put them?</p>
               <p>Tempest. She put them upon a Pair of Chest of Drawers, and said they are there?</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Tempest. That's all that I know.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. I think you say that both Husband and Wife came into your Shop, and they cheapened your Goods. I would ask you, among those different Things, did not the Husband or Wife cheapen the Candlesticks?</p>
               <p>Tempest. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council Well, but, Sir; had you not at this Time in your Shop a Boy? Now did the Wife say nothing to the Boy in relation to those Candlesticks?</p>
               <p>Tempest. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Council. Where did those Candlesticks first of all stand?</p>
               <p>Tempest. They stood upon the Window on the Left-hand.</p>
               <p>Council. As to these Things, I think there was a Dispute, whether he should pay 10 s. 6 d. or a 11 s. I would ask you how far Distance the Woman was gone when you went out of the Shop?</p>
               <p>Tempest. I never saw her till she had been gone a great Way.</p>
               <p>Council. Did not the Buy say to her, you have taken away a Couple of Candlesticks among the rest of the Things ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250035"></xptr>Tempest. I heard him say this, they are under her Cloak.</p>
               <p>Council. Did not the Woman say, I thought the Candlesticks had been agreed for and paid for by my Husband ? When you came before the Justice of Peace, did not the Boy say before the Justice, that the Woman cheapened the Candlesticks ? Now, Sir, did not you check him, or rebuke him, for saying that the Woman had cheapened the Candlesticks ? The Justice asked the Boy whether she had cheapened the Candlesticks; and the Boy said, Yes; for 3 s. Did not the Boy say before the Justice, that she had talked about the Price?</p>
               <p>Tempest. No.</p>
               <p>Council. I have several Witnesses that the Boy said she had cheapened the Candlesticks, and you rebuked him for mentioning of it. I would ask you another Question. This Woman took these Things with the rest, and they were under one Arm, and the rest of the Things under the other Arm; did you see the Candlesticks under her Arm?</p>
               <p>Tempest. I did not pull up her Cloak in the Street; in Fact, she ran too fast for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-23-person313">
                  Johanna 
                  Turnwell 
               <interp inst="t17470225-23-person313" type="surname" value="Turnwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person313" type="given" value="Johanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday in the Afternoon, I had occasion to open my Window to look at something; and I saw the Prisoner at the Bar coming down from Mr. Tempest's Shop, with a Tea-kettle and Coffee pot; she called and asked her Husband if he had got the Spoons: Her Husband said they were in the Coffee pot. After they were gone out, I saw Mr. Tempest in a Hurry; in a very little Time I saw the Prisoner came back very fast, and set down a Pair of Candlesticks by a Chest of Drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live opposite?</p>
               <p>Turnwell. My Window faces Mr. Tempest's Shop.</p>
               <p>Council. You saw her set them down; do you remember where she took when from which she set down?</p>
               <p>Turnwell. I did not mind that.</p>
               <p>Council. Do you remember that she said that she thought her Husband had agreed for them?</p>
               <p>Turnwell I did not hear that.</p>
               <p>Council. Mr. Tempest was in a great Passion; was he not ?</p>
               <p>Turnwell. No, I thought he looked pleasant.</p>
               <p>Council. Don't you remember before the Justice the Boy said, that she herself said she thought her Husband had paid for them? Do you remember the Boy's saying, she had cheapened the Candlesticks ?</p>
               <p>Turnwell. I think the Boy said she had cheapened the Candlesticks, and his Aunt allowed them for 3 s.</p>
               <p>Council. Recollect Mr. Tempest did not upon this Occasion rebuke the Boy, and seem to be angry with him; he said 3 s. was too small, and he was a Blockhead for saying so.</p>
               <p>[No Answer to this Question by the last Witness]</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-23-person314">
                  Charles 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17470225-23-person314" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person314" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Bird. Please your Honour, I was coming by, and I wanted to buy a Pair of Bellows; seeing a Pair hang up at Mr. Tempest's Shop, when I came to cheapen them, Mrs. Tempest said a Woman had taken a Pair of Brass Candlesticks away, and Mr. Tempest was gone out after her. By and by in comes the Woman and Mr. Tempest, and she puts them down upon the Drawers: There they are says she, why do you charge me with them?</p>

               <p>Q. to the Prisoner. What have you to say in your Defence ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I went into the Shop, my Lord, on Saturday, as I had done in other Shops before, and cheapened these Candlesticks: The Boy told me they were 3 s. I was gone to look at a Coal-box, and I set down the Candlesticks; I let them alone till I had looked for a Coffee pot and Tea-kettle some Things we could not agree for as to Price, and I laid them down: We agreed for several Goods, and my Husband paid 11 s. We were in a Hurry, and came away.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Chapman. Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Chapman Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Council. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Chapman. In the Prince of Wales's Family; the Prisoner was the Necessary woman's Maid.</p>
               <p>Council. During this Time, in what Manner did she behave?</p>
               <p>Chapman Her Character at that Time was exceeding good, and she behaved in that Service better than others had done before her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Brett. How long, Sir, have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brett I have known her for about three Months.</p>
               <p>Council. What is your Station?</p>
               <p>Brett I belong to the Prince of Wales.</p>
               <p>Q. What Office there?</p>
               <p>Brett I belong to the Beer-Cellar.</p>
               <p>Council. During the Time she was in the Prince of Wales's Family, in what Manner did she behave?</p>
               <p>Brett. I never heard but that she behaved very well.</p>
               <p>Council: Do you know that she was entrusted with Things of Value?</p>
               <p>Brett. Yes, Sir; there were all Sorts of Plate Candlesticks, Salves, and a great many Things were in her Power to take away: I was with her Mistress<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250036"></xptr> this Day and I asked her what she thought of her; she gave her a very good Character; she was very ill, or she would have been here herself.</p>
               <p>Mr Tibb. I belong to the Clerk of the Kitchen; I know she was entrusted with Plate, and Things of Value; her Mistress said she never had a better Servants and the only Reason that she was discharged, was, because she was married.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Cousins What is your Station?</p>
               <p>Cousins. I am Servant to the Prince. I belong to the Nursery. The Prisoner was the Necessary woman's Maid, and was entrusted with every Thing; Cloaths and Jewels were lying about, and nothing was missed.</p>

               <p>Q. to Mrs. Hornsby. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hornsby. She was Fellow-servant with me; she had Plate, Rings and Jewels under her Care; every Thing as I had; and she behaved very well while she was in Service; I never heard any thing ill of her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Dod I think you are Landlord of the House where the Prisoner lives?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dod. My Father is.</p>
               <p>Council. I think this young Woman is lately married, and your Father has let her a House?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dod. Her Husband was Gardener to my Father, and she was at my Father's House as a Servant since she has been married, and has been entrusted with the Keys of my Father's Country-house, where there are Things of Value, and she always behaved well.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bell. I have known the Prisoner for two Years, and she bears an honest Character.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Matocks. Did you hear Tempest's Nephew say this Woman cheapened any Candlesticks?</p>
               <p>Matocks. When she was brought before the Justice, this Boy was examined; he likewise promised Mr. Paulson to bring the Boy here upon his Word; therefore the Justice did not bind him over.</p>
               <p>Tempest. The Reason I did not bring him, he is too young.</p>
               <p>Matocks. I'll give the Reason why I believe he did not. The Boy was examined. Says the Justice, what have you to say about this Woman; do you know any thing about her cheapening any Candlesticks? The Boy said, as they were cheapening the Candlesticks, his Aunt said they were 3 s. Mr. Tempest put himself into such a Passion, that I thought he would have struck the Boy; he said, You lye, Sirrah; I never put such a price upon them.</p>
               <p>- Orton. The Justice asked if any Body else were in the Shop, the Boy was mentioned; Justice Poulson said it was necessary to have the Boy brought; when the Boy came, Mr. Paulson asked him how old he was, he said thirteen; then he asked the Boy what he knew of the Affair of the Prisoner at the Bar; he said, the Prisoner at the Bar and her Husband came in, and he bought a Coffee-pot, half a Dozen Knives and Forks, and Mr. Tempest went into the Back room; and the Prisoner at the Bar ask what was the Price of a Pair of Candlesticks; Mr. Tempest went backward, and the Boy and his Aunt was in the Shop, and the Prisoner at the Bar asked the Price of those Candlesticks, and his Aunt said they were 3 s. and Mr. Tempest repremanded the Boy for saying 3 s. when always the set Price was 3 s. 6 d. The Boy was in the Shop when the Woman went out; when they were gone, the Boy said, Unkle, Did the Woman pay you for those Candlesticks? he said no; then he said they had got a Pair of Candlesticks not paid for; upon that, Mr. Tempest went after her as far as Queen street; when he came to her, she said she thought her Husband had paid for them.</p>
               <p>- Ashley. I was at the Justice's along with the Prisoner; I was afflicted with the Gout, so the Justice indulged me to sit down in a Chair, accordingly I did; there was some Talk of this Kind, but I can't charge my Memory particularly with it, because I did not take particular Notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Talk about the Price of Candlesticks?</p>
               <p>Ashley. What the former Witness has said of it, upon my Oath, I apprehend to be the Truth.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner was honourably <rs id="t17470225-23-verdict105" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-23-verdict105" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>It appeared to the Court to be a very rash Piece of Conduct in Mr. Tempest; and that Circumstance of his not bringing the Boy upon the Trial, according to his Promise, made his Cause appear doubtful. The Prisoner's Husband petitioned for a Copy of her Indictment, but that was not granted.</p>
            </div1>
