<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-33">
               <interp inst="t17420909-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-33" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-33" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-33-off172-c277" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-defend351 t17420909-33-off172 t17420909-33-verdict177"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-33-off172-c278" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-defend353 t17420909-33-off172 t17420909-33-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>97, 98. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-defend351" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Swinhy 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend351" type="surname" value="Swinhy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend351" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-defend353" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Biller 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend353" type="surname" value="Biller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend353" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-defend353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17420909-33-defloc171">St George's Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-defloc171" type="placeName" value="St George's Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-defloc171" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-defend351 t17420909-33-defloc171"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-defend353 t17420909-33-defloc171"></join>, were indicted with 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person354">
                  Mary 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person354" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person354" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , not yet taken, for <rs id="t17420909-33-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420909-33-victim356" type="victimName">
                           Winifred 
                           Owen 
                        <interp inst="t17420909-33-victim356" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-33-victim356" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-33-victim356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-off172 t17420909-33-victim356"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's High-Way, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a Handkerchief, an Apron, a Hat, and 17 s. in Money
            </rs>, her Property, <rs id="t17420909-33-cd173" type="crimeDate">Aug. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-off172 t17420909-33-cd173"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-person357">
                  Winifred 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person357" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person357" type="given" value="Winifred"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . <rs id="t17420909-33-viclabel174" type="occupation">I sell Milk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-victim356 t17420909-33-viclabel174"></join>. Last Sunday was three Weeks, between nine and ten in the Morning, as I was going homeward, towards Stepney, in <placeName id="t17420909-33-crimeloc175">Rag-Fair</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Rag-Fair"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420909-33-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-off172 t17420909-33-crimeloc175"></join>, I think they call it, I met with these Women, and asked them the Way to the Blue Anchor, they said they would show me: We went about three or four Stones throw together; then they shoved me into an Alley, and gave me a Blow on the Head.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Miller. Gentlemen, I desire they may be all turned out of Court, and examined seperately, which was granted.</p>
               <p>Owen. The Blow stunned me, (she is not taken that gave me the Blow, there were five of them) then I said, Lord, have Mercy upon me, What is this for. I clapped my Hand upon my Pocket in a Minute, and caught that little one's Hand (Miller's) in my Pocket. Said I, Lord, bless me, all my Money is gone; then one snatched my Apron off, and another my Handkerchief, and another snatched my Hat; the 17 s. in Money was tied up in a Rag.</p>
               <p>Miller. My Lord, please to ask her whether she was drunk or sober.</p>
               <p>Owen. I drunk! I thought I should have been murdered. God keep me from such People. So I run away, crying, into a little House, for to save my Life. I went to my Sister, and told her of it, who lives just by; and some of the People said, they knew that little short Body, and she was taken up directly. I went to the Watch House, and they asked me if I knew her? Yes, said I, that is the Woman that put her Hand in my Pocket. Said I, What have you done with my Money? She cursed and swore, and abused me sadly, and struck me before the Justice. I thought she would have killed me, and the Justice ordered her to be tied down. My Handkerchief was found upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure Swinhy was there?</p>
               <p>Owen. Yes and please you, my Lord, God bless you, I know her very well; the little one had a black Eye then; 'tis pretty well now: That Handkerchief is mine, I worked very hard for it, and that Hat and Apron are mine.</p>
               <p>Miller. Ask her if she did not ask for a Dram, and if I did not resent her having one.</p>
               <p>Owen. I did not call for any Liquor, God bless you, and please you, my Lord, it is she, if I was to die this Minute, God bless you. - That Woman in the blue Knot, [which was Swinhy ] she was in Company, but I cannot say she did what the others did; - She did not take any thing from me. - I am sure the little one robbed me; God Almighty bless you, I would not tell a Lye for the World: They snatched behind me, and did it so quick, I cannot tell who did it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-person358">
                  Joseph 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person358" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person358" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I was charged with this Woman to carry her to Prison; this Hat, Apron, and Handkerchief were delivered me before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-person359">
                  Thomas 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person359" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person359" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutrix came to my House, I am her Sister's Husband, and sat about Half an Hour one Sunday in the Morning. - Some time after she went away, I met her full butt between nine and ten, she was crying, and said she had been robbed by four Women, two small ones, a lusty one, and a middle sized one: I heard a Man say he saw four or 5 Women together talking about dividing some Money; I happen'd to go into the Black-Horse, in Well-Street, and there I saw 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person360">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person360" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person360" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she was selling the Handkerchief; then I took fast hold of her, and she put the Handkerchief into her Bosom, then I took her to the Watch-house, and charged Williams the Officer with her; he kept her in Custody, and then Eleanor Okley was taken, and she made her self an Evidence: Swinhy was taken up upon her Evidence by Inwin and Harris: A Woman came to me with the Apron and Hat, and said, I had these from the Woman that took them from your Sister-in-Law. - I saw Miller take the Handkerchief out of her Bosom, and gave it to another Woman, and that Woman gave it to me: When Swinhy was taken, she said, she was along with them when they went to sell the Goods, but she had no Hand in the Robbery. - 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person361">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person361" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person361" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person361" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me, she did not drink any Gin in the Prosecutrix's company.</p>
               <p>Owen. I drank no Gin with them that Morning, nor never saw them before in my Life.</p>
               <p>Miller. Pray, Sir, did not he pull me all along?</p>
               <p>Williams. I bid him pull you along because you would not go.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-person362">
                  Eleanor 
                  Okley 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person362" type="surname" value="Okley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person362" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person363">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person363" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person363" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person364">
                  Mary 
                  Swinhy 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person364" type="surname" value="Swinhy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person364" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person365">
                  Mary 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person365" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and myself, went one Sunday Morning to get a Dram at the New Exchange in Rag Fair, and we happened to meet this good Woman, the Prosecutrix,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090020"></xptr> and she asked for the Blue-Anchor. 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person366">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person366" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person366" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             made answer, come along with us and we will show you, we all four of us went along with her; when we came into the back Lane, 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person367">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person367" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person367" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , first and foremost took off her Hat; secondly, she took off her Handkerchief, which was upon her Neck. 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person368">
                  Mary 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person368" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person368" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the Woman the Blow on the side of her Head, then Jane Miller was trying to take off her Apron; then Mary Merrit came again, and between them both they untied it, and then we all run away. - I did not see any Body put their Hand into her Pocket - as for the Money I know nothing of it, nor never saw any; I had no intent to rob any Body when I went out in the Morning, and I believe they had not neither - we drank no Gin with the good Woman, we had Gin before.</p>
               <p>Jury. Were you sober, or were you in Liquor?</p>
               <p>Okley. We were not in Liquor, for we had but Half a Quartern a-piece. Swinby was with us, but she did nothing. - I went and left them, and heard no more of it till Miller was in the Cage. - Miller put the Handkerchief into her Bosom, the Hat and Apron 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person369">
                  Mary 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person369" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person369" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had.</p>
               <p>Miller. Ask her if she was not at Mrs Bun's drinking Gin with the Prosecutrix.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-33-person370">
                  Eleanor 
                  Okley 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person370" type="surname" value="Okley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person370" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not drink any thing with the Prosecutrix; I was not in any House with her.</p>
               <p>Miller's Defence. I was going down Rag-Fair, Okley stood at the End of an Alley with 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person371">
                  Mary 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person371" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person371" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they asked me to go to the New Exchange to drink a Dram; then I met the Prosecutrix, Okley took hold of her, said she, you shall drink a Dram, she said she did not care for a Dram for she had drank enough already: This Woman [that's Swinby ] and Bun's Daughter, went after the Woman, and brought her into a Gin-shop; then Swinby was sitting with her Mistress's Child upon her Lap: I being a little Body like 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person372">
                  Eleanor 
                  Okley 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person372" type="surname" value="Okley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person372" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they swear against me: Okley put her Hand in her Pocket and took out only seven Farthings, said I who must pay for the five Quarters of Gin; and then I took her Handkerchief off her Neck to pay for it: Okley made herself an Evidence against me, for fear I should be an Evidence against her; but I had no such Intention, because I knew it was a wrong thing.</p>

               <p>Okley. I do not know that Miller said any thing to the Prosecutrix, when she took the Handkerchief, that she did it to pay herself for five Quarterns of Gin. 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person373">
                  Jane 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person373" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person373" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17420909-33-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-verdict176" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of the Felony, but acquitted of the putting in Fear
            </rs>. 
               <persName id="t17420909-33-person374">
                  Mary 
                  Swinby 
               <interp inst="t17420909-33-person374" type="surname" value="Swinby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person374" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17420909-33-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420909-33-punish178" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-33-punish178" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-33-defend353 t17420909-33-punish178"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
