<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410701-13">
               <interp inst="t17410701-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-13" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410701"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-13" type="date" value="17410701"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410701-13-off60-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-defend140 t17410701-13-off60 t17410701-13-verdict63"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410701-13-off60-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-defend143 t17410701-13-off60 t17410701-13-verdict63"></join>
         
               <p>18, 19. 
               <persName id="t17410701-13-defend140" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Smith 
                  , alias <rs id="t17410701-13-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-defend140 t17410701-13-alias-4"></join>Rouse</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend140" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend140" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend143" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend143" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-defend143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of Pancras, were indicted <rs id="t17410701-13-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               for assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410701-13-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Minton 
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim145" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim145" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17410701-13-viclabel61" type="occupation">Infant about the Age of 5 Years</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-victim145 t17410701-13-viclabel61"></join>; putting her in fear &amp;c. and taking from her a Quilted Callimanco Coat, value. 4 s. and a Stay, val. 4 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410701-13-victim147" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Minton 
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim147" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim147" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-13-victim147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17410701-13-cd62" type="crimeDate">June 10th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-off60 t17410701-13-cd62"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-person148">
                  John 
                  Minton 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person148" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person148" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17410701-13-person149">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Minton 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person149" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person149" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my Daughter, and all that I know of my own Knowledge, is, that the two Prisoners were apprehended for stripping her, and confessed the Fact before Mr. De Viel and said it was to buy the Prisoner Smith a Gown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-person150">
                  Jane 
                  Shaw 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person150" type="surname" value="Shaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person150" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at my Lord Vine's in Albemarle-Street, and have this Child under my Care.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174107010010"></xptr> On the 10th of June last I drest her in this Coat and Stay, and about 5 in the Afternoon gave her leave to go to play in the Street; she was brought Home to me at 8, by a Boy who told me he found her sitting on a Dung-hill without her Coat and Stay, and the Skirt of her Frock was cut from the Body, and pinn'd about her. When I saw her she told me, she was carried away by two Girls, who promised her a plum cake, and took her things from her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-person151">
                  Ruth 
                  Bagley 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person151" type="surname" value="Bagley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person151" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Tottenham-Court, and being sent on an Errand to London, my Master's Daughter call'd to me as I was going along the Road. I ran to her directly, and going along the Fields the space of twenty yards, we saw a Child sitting on a Lay-stall or Dung-hill. My Master's Daughter said to me, '' Ruth, I will be hang'd if those 2 creatures '' have not stripped the Child, for I saw the '' old one have her by the hand.'' I went up to the Child and ask'd her where those Women were? She said she did not know, and that they had taken her Coat and Stay from her. We bid the Child sit still till we came back, and we would take them; and accordingly went in pursuit of the Prisoners, and took them within two Fields of Pancras. The great one, Rouse, made several attempts to get over a Bank, but she could not, so she slung this Coat and Stay into the ditch. I took it up and shew'd it to her, and she said we had stripp'd the Child ourselves and laid it on her, and began to grow robustical: upon that we called a Man to our assistance and carried them to my Master's, where we secur'd them till we got help and carried them before Mr. De Viel. When they were before Mr. De Veil they were examined, and the great one said to the other, '' Mall, '' if it had not been to buy you a new Gown, I '' had not committed this Robbery. ''the other said, It was to serve herself and not her, and that she was a Field off when Rouse committed the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Prisoner Smith say she was with Rouse when she decoy'd the Child away, or when she brought it back to the Lay-stall?</p>
               <p>Bagley. She said she saw Rouse decoy the Child away, and offer her a Plum-cake.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-person152">
                  Sarah 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person152" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person152" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going down the Road, and saw the last Witness, who is Servant to my Father: I call'd her to me, and saw this Child sitting on a Lay-stall. I said I believed those creatures had stripped the Child, for I saw the old one, Rouse, have her by the Hand, and the little one had something in her apron, but what it was I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the Lay-stall did you first see the Prisoners with the Child?</p>
               <p>Giles. Very near a quarter of a mile; they were leading the Child, and she said something to them, and they replied, Yes, we shall be there presently now.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw the Prisoners with the Child, had she her Stay on?</p>
               <p>Giles. No, she had only her Frock on. When we came up to the Lay-stall, we asked the Child if they had taken any thing from her, and she said they had taken her coat and stay: upon that we pursued the Prisoners, and got up with them. I asked the little one for the coat and stay, and she said she had none of it; the great one came up and beat me, and said she supposed we had stripp'd the child ourselves, and the little one was going to run away, but I catch'd hold of her, and 
               <persName id="t17410701-13-person153">
                  Francis 
                  Jennison 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person153" type="surname" value="Jennison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person153" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             coming to our assistance we secured them both. When we had secured both the Prisoners, we took them to our house, and when we had got an officer, carried them before Mr. De Veil, where the great one said that they took the child out of Albemarle-street, and the little one said, it was out of the Hay-Market. The great one, Rouse, likewise said if it had not been to have bought Smith a new gown, she should not have done this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-13-person154">
                  Francis 
                  Jennison 
               <interp inst="t17410701-13-person154" type="surname" value="Jennison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person154" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of June last, I and my wife were taking a walk to Pancras, and these 2 girls came down the Road crying stop thief! I took hold of the Prisoner Smith, and she said she would shew me the ditch where the things were: accordingly I went with her to the ditch and took out this coat and stay, and she said her sister took them from the child and threw them in there. The Prisoner Rouse was all that time in this young woman's hands, and we carried them to Mr. Giles's at Tottenham-Court, where the great one own'd she robbed the Child, and said it was to buy the little one a new gown. I kept them till a Constable came, and he carried them before Justice Trent, but he being busy, we had them before Mr. De Viel, where Rouse own'd they took the Child from Albemarle-Street, and carried her to Tottenham-Court, but I did not then hear them say what they did to her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Giles. Is this Dung-hill or Lay-stall near the highway?</p>
               <p>Giles. Yes, it is by the side of the highway.</p>
               <p>Bagley. It lies open to the highway, and there is neither hedge nor ditch between them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Rouse. I have nothing to say, but that I know nothing at all of the matter. <rs id="t17410701-13-verdict63" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-verdict63" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-verdict63" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Both Guilty, Felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17410701-13-punish64" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-13-punish64" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-defend140 t17410701-13-punish64"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-13-defend143 t17410701-13-punish64"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
