<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-44">
               <interp inst="t17430907-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-44" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-44" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-44-off227-c340" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-44-defend422 t17430907-44-off227 t17430907-44-verdict228"></join>
         
               <p>419 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430907-44-defend422" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Lewin 
                  <interp inst="t17430907-44-defend422" type="surname" value="Lewin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-defend422" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-defend422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , late of the Parish of <placeName id="t17430907-44-defloc226">West Ham in the County of Essex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-44-defloc226" type="placeName" value="West Ham in the County of Essex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-44-defloc226" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-44-defend422 t17430907-44-defloc226"></join>, Labourer, was indicted, That <rs id="t17430907-44-off227" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-off227" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-off227" type="offenceSubcategory" value="returnFromTransportation"></interp>
               whereas at a Sessions of Oyer and Terminer, holden at Chelmsford in the County of Essex, on Tuesday the 11th Day of March, in the 13th Year of his present Majesty, he was there indicted, for that he the said 
                     <persName id="t17430907-44-person423">
                        Joseph 
                        Lewin 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person423" type="surname" value="Lewin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person423" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , after the 24th Day of June, 1731, to wit, on the 14th Day of September, in the 13th Year of his present Majesty, with Force and Arms, in the said Parish in the said County. 64 Yards of Cloth made of Linnen, Cotton, and Yarn mixed, of the Value of 6 l the Goods and Chattels of one 
                     <persName id="t17430907-44-person424">
                        Richard 
                        Cross 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person424" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person424" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , out of the Whitening Grounds of 
                     <persName id="t17430907-44-person425">
                        Peter 
                        Robin 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person425" type="surname" value="Robin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person425" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17430907-44-person426">
                        Simon 
                        Burdcaux 
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person426" type="surname" value="Burdcaux"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person426" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-44-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did feloniously steal, &amp;c. That to this Indictment he pleaded Guilty, and put himself upon the Mercy of the Court, and received Sentence of Transportation for the Term of seven Years, according to the Form of the Statute in that Case made and provided, as by the Record does more fully appear; and the Indictment charges him that afterwards, to wit, upon the 27th Day of Aug. in the 17th Year of his present Majesty, feloniously, and without any lawful Cause, he was seen at large in Great-Britain, to wit, in the Parish of St Botolph without Aldgate, in London, before the Expiration of the Term of seven Years, for which he was ordered to be transported; against the Form of the Statute, and against his Majesty's Peace, his Crown, and Dignity
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-44-person427">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person427" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person427" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced the Copy of the Record of the Conviction of 
               <persName id="t17430907-44-person428">
                  Joseph 
                  Lewin 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person428" type="surname" value="Lewin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person428" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with the Order for his being transported; proved it to be a true Copy, for that he had compared it with the Original. Then the Record was read.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner to be the same Man that was tried and convicted at Chelmsford, for the Robbery which is set forth in this Record?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-44-person429">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person429" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person429" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, I was at Chelmsford at the same Time, and gave Evidence against him; when he was brought to the Bar, he pleaded Guilty.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the same Person?</p>
               <p>Harris. I took him myself, I am positive he is the Man: there was Judgment given against him, but I did not hear Judgment given.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when the Verdict was given against him.</p>

               <p>Harris. Yes, - it was in March Assizes, 1739.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him at large in Great-Britain?</p>
               <p>Harris. I did not see him at large before he was taken, I only saw him since he has been in Custody.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-44-person430">
                  Simon 
                  Burdeaux 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person430" type="surname" value="Burdeaux"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person430" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Sentence of Transportation pronounced against him. - I caused him to be taken in Whitechapel, on this Side the Bars last Saturday was Fortnight; as I was waiting for a Coach in Whitechapel, somebody told me the Prisoner was at the Bulhead Alehouse; as soon as he saw me he laughed, and took to his Heels, and run away. I cried out Stop Thief, and Paine stopped him. - I am a Printer, and live on the Road-side, between Bow and Stratford.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any Excuse for being at large?</p>
               <p>Burdeaux. None at all; he begged and prayed that I would not prosecute him, for if I did he was a dead Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-44-person431">
                  Thomas 
                  Paine 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person431" type="surname" value="Paine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person431" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday was Fortnight, the 27th of August, I was in Whichapel Butcher-Row, and hearing a Cry of Stop Thief, I turned my Head and saw the Prisoner spring by me very swift, and he turned into Somerset Street, in Aldgate Parish. I being a Headborough of St Mary Whitechapel, I run after him, but being slip-shoed I could not run fast enough, I cried Stop Thief; knock him down. Then he crossed from one Side of the Way to the other. I came up with him, and seized him by the Collar, which gave Way, so I thrust my Knuckles into his Throat, he said, for God's-Sake let me go, I have done no Harm, I have only returned from Transportation; said I, I will stay till the Prosecutor comes up. The People bid him go, and the Mob grew outragious; when Mr Burdeaux came up, he desired I would assist him, and said, that the Prisoner had robbed him, and had returned from Transportation, and that he had threatned Destruction * to him and his Family: I pushed him along as fast as possible towards my Lord-Mayor's-House; the People called us all the Thief-takers they could think of; the Mob arose in Battle-array, so that I said to the Prosecutor, I would assist him no further; but he begged I would. We<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070024"></xptr> got him into a Coach, and Dirt was thrown into the Coach by two Women, whom I took particular Notice of. I put him into the Poultry-Compter, and the next Day had him before the Alderman, he acknowledged himself to be the Man, and begged for Mercy; he said, he had suffered a great deal, and begged the Prosecutor that he would not take away his Life; he behaved himself very civilly all the Way.</p>
               <p>* At the Time they were conveying the Prisoner from Chelmsford, in order to be transported, as he pass'd by the Prosecutor's House, he threw Stones at Mrs Burdeaux, which broke the Windows, and narrowly miss'd her, using this Expression, G - d d - n you, you B - h, take that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I tell you that I was going on Board a Man of War directly?</p>
               <p>Paine. The Prisoner said he was going on Board a Man of War the next Day; and that he had been but five Days in England; he mentioned one Eades, a Butche, and said he was going in his Son's Room. I asked Mr Eades that, and he said he had no Son, so he could not be going in his Son's Room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I shipped myself at Philadelhia, the 15th of March, and was to take a Loading of Tar, and then to go to Leith in Scotland. I said to the Captain, it was very dangerous for me to go to London, for I shall be taken up for returning from Transportation; he said I should never fair out of the Ship; he said he would put in at Cowes, and instead of going to Cowes, he came to London; so I ventured on Shore, and there was a Gentleman's Son who was going on Board a Man of War, and I was to go in his Room, and to have five Guineas for it, and was going to the White-Hart in Lemmon-Street about it. I was told to take Care not to come in Mr Burdeaux's Way; it was but the fifth Day that I had been in London; the Ship arrived at London the 10th, and I was taken the 27th. My Captain has waited every Day till Saturday Night, and then he told me he could not attend any longer; he said he was going to Change this Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is your Captain?</p>
               <p>Pris. Captain 
               <persName id="t17430907-44-person432">
                  John 
                  Jewry 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person432" type="surname" value="Jewry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person432" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Ship lies at Horsly-down, the Merchant's Name is 
               <persName id="t17430907-44-person433">
                  Lawrence 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17430907-44-person433" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person433" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he lives in Tower-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not you have got some of the Sailors to have come and proved this?</p>
               <p>Pris. There were but ten Sailors, and seven of them were pressed. I have no Friends.</p>
               <p>- . I saw his Father last Friday or Saturday at Work, he is a Journeyman Stone Cutter against Whitechapel Church.</p>
               <p>Mr Paine being called again was asked whether he was sure the Prisoner was in London; he said when he first saw him he was in the County; but when he was taken, he is sure that he was 40 Yards in the City. <rs id="t17430907-44-verdict228" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-verdict228" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430907-44-punish229" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-44-punish229" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-44-defend422 t17430907-44-punish229"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
