<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440510-11">
               <interp inst="t17440510-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-11" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-11" type="date" value="17440510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440510-11-off59-c162" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-11-defend184 t17440510-11-off59 t17440510-11-verdict61"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100014"></xptr>257. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440510-11-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Shoeler 
                  <interp inst="t17440510-11-defend184" type="surname" value="Shoeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-defend184" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-defend184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17440510-11-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing seventeen pound weight of glass, commonly called a composition of glass, value 3 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440510-11-victim186" type="victimName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Bowles 
                  <interp inst="t17440510-11-victim186" type="surname" value="Bowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-victim186" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-11-off59 t17440510-11-victim186"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17440510-11-cd60" type="crimeDate">April 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-11-off59 t17440510-11-cd60"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-11-person187">
                  John 
                  Morse 
               <interp inst="t17440510-11-person187" type="surname" value="Morse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Bowles, that fellow the (Prisoner) took seventeen pound of glass, which we call a composition of glass: there are ten colours in it. One Mr. Hakewell a jeweller in St. Martin's le Grand came to my master, and told him some of his servants had robbed him; for says he, there came into my hand seventeen pound of the same composition which I have had in my hand in your warehouse; Mr. Hopkins in Aldersgate Street brought me the glass, and I am satisfied it is yours: let your clerk come to my house, and I will get a light into this affair. I went to Mr. Hakewell's, he showed it me, and I was satisfied that it was our own: said he, if you will go to Duke's Place I will show you the person that sold it. I went into Duke's Place to 
               <persName id="t17440510-11-person188">
                  Samuel 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17440510-11-person188" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person188" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Jew, who sold it to Mr. Hopkins the jeweller; and he went with me to enquire after the Prisoner, and Levi took him at an alehouse in Tower Street. [There were several sorts of the composition produced;] that in the basket is what the Prisoner sold, and here is some of Mr. Bowles's of the same number and colour.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Morse. The Prisoner has had access to our warehouse, under pretence of buying wine glasses, which he used to get flowered round the edges, and when the warehouse keeper was gone into the soror, where the glasses are neiled, the Prisoner had an opportunity of taking this out of the baskets.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the use of this composition?</p>
               <p>Morse. It is for the jewellers, it is for making pendants for the lady's ears, and jewels for the kidies necks. He will tell you an idle story by and by how he came by it, but I believe that will be of no avail to him, for I am pretty sure no body makes this composition but Mr. Bowles.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to buy any of this composition?</p>
               <p>Morse. No; he bought nothing but drinking glasses.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have used his house ever since I came to England, I belong to the Queen of Hungary, I am of Prague in Germany.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-11-person189">
                  Samuel 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17440510-11-person189" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person189" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the bar came to my house in Duke's Place, and offered to sell me some composition of glass, I did not know the value of it, (I believe that is the same sort of glass) I told him I would go and enquire about it. I went and showed it to several people at the coffee-house, and nobody could tell what it was worth. I came back to him, and said I did not understand it; and said, if you think sit to leave it with me, I will show it to some gentlemen, and the Prisoner left it with me upon commission to sell for him if I could. I carried it to Mr. Hopkins a jeweller in Aldersgate Street, the Prisoner told me I must ask 4 s. a pound for it, and I asked Mr. Hopkins that price; he said that is too much, but if you will leave it with me, Mr. Levi, I will show it to a person who may buy it. I left it, and came to the Prisoner, and told him so, and that he must tell me the lowest price, and he told me I must take half a crown a pound, which was the lowest price, and Mr. Hopkins offered me half a crown a pound, and paid me two guineas: there was seventeen pound three ounces, and I brought the money to the Prisoner, and he gave me 3 s. and 6 d. for my trouble.</p>
               <p>Jury. Have not you seen large quantities of this glass in Mr. Hopkins's Shop ?</p>
               <p>Levi. No; I never saw any quantity of it in his shop, only the work that was made of it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I carried the glass to Mr. Levi to dispose of for me because I was a stranger to that sort, and left it with him for two days, and he brought me 2 s. a pound for it; I told him I would rather have my glass again, and I said bring me the glass again, and he said there was no such thing as getting it again, for the gentleman would not part with it, so I was forced to take the 2 s. a pound for it, thought it cost me more.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come by it?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I deal in glasses, I carry a basket about streets, I had it in exchange for some figured glasses, a pepper box, and several other things. I offered this glass to their warehouse-keeper to exchange for drinking glasses, and he would not take it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of this?</p>
               <p>Morse. I have been told so, our warehouse-keeper told me the Prisoner had been with three or four small pieces to change for drinking glasses, and that he made him this answer; our business is to sell this glass, we never take any again.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you sell it to any but jewellers?</p>
               <p>Morse. Never to any but jewellers as I know of.</p>
               <p>Jury. Is there nobody that makes this composition of glass besides Mr. Bowles?</p>
               <p>Morse. Not that I know of.</p>
               <p>John Brown, a Juryman Sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of any composition of glass of the same nature with this, which is sold by other people?</p>
               <p>Brown. Yes; there is Mr. Batailliard and another person, and there is an apothecary and surgeon by Moorfields who make this composition. <rs id="t17440510-11-verdict61" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-11-verdict61" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
