<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460702-4">
               <interp inst="t17460702-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-4" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-4" type="date" value="17460702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460702-4-off17-c95" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-4-defend104 t17460702-4-off17 t17460702-4-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174607020008"></xptr>245. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460702-4-defend104" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Dodson 
                  <interp inst="t17460702-4-defend104" type="surname" value="Dodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-defend104" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-defend104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460702-4-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing a Bag of Cotton
            </rs> , the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460702-4-victim106" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Grey 
                  <interp inst="t17460702-4-victim106" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-victim106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-victim106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-4-off17 t17460702-4-victim106"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , the <rs id="t17460702-4-cd18" type="crimeDate">13th of June</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-4-off17 t17460702-4-cd18"></join> .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-4-person107">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person107" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person107" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17460702-4-person108">
                  John 
                  Grey 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person108" type="surname" value="Grey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person108" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know in Relation to this Cotton?</p>
               <p>Grey. I think it was the 13th of June. On the Friday I happen'd to be out about some Business, and came home about Ten o'Clock. My Man, 
               <persName id="t17460702-4-person109">
                  John 
                  Dodson 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person109" type="surname" value="Dodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (the Prisoner) had packed up a Bag of Cotton, 30 or 40 Pounds Weight. I came home the Friday Evening; I had been receiving some Money, and I sent him for Acceptance of a Note ; he brought me a Draught upon Alderman Hankey. The next Morning my Sister said, What Cotton was that John carried out to Iron Gate? I said I sold no Cotton: I look'd at him, and said, John, What is the Matter of this? he said, Sir, Don't be frighten'd and uneasy, for you shall know the Truth of it. My Brother said, John, I am afraid you are a Rogue : Indeed, we were extremely frighten'd at the Thing. He went out as if he was going to make Water, and took to his Heels, and away he went, and I heard no more of him; both my Brother and I saw him go, but our Surprize was so great, we had not Power to seize him, or call after him; he was a Man we had a very good Opinion of. With this I went to Iron Gate , to the Sign of the City of Bristol: I ask'd the Gentlewoman of the House, who is a Woman of good Character and Fortune, about him; she said he had Lodged in her House frequently. I ask'd her if she knew of any Cotton; she said he had brought something or another, and that he should say that Cotton was exceeding dear, and that little Parcel of Cotton was worth three or four Pounds. The next Thing I did, I sent to a Relation's of his in Burr-Street, in St. Katherine's , and while we were at this House together, talking of this Affair, the Prisoner came in: As soon as he came in, the Woman of the House shew'd him up Stairs, and said, John, I hear a sad Character of you. When he came up, I said John , how is this Thing? You have committed a Robbery here. At first, my Lord, he deny'd it; his Relation prevail'd upon him, and I together, to confess the Fact: I said the Thing will be better for you, don't be desperate, but confess the Truth. He told me, if I would have Mercy upon him, or something to that Purpose, he would tell me the whole Affair: He told me that he did bag up the Cotton in the Afternoon, and he had brought it to that very House, and that he would get me my Cotton again. He went out with his Relation and a Friend of mine, in order to bring it again. I said to his Relation, what must I do in a Thing of this Nature? I don't know how to act in it: Will you be Security that this Man will appear on Monday or Tuesday, in order to go before the Justice, or what is necessary? and let me see him the Beginning of the Week: Indeed, the Relation said, 'tis so tender a Thing, if you had ask'd me to have been Security for a Thousand Pound, I should have gave it for him, but as these Things appear , I will have nothing to do with it. My Lord, I have known the Man many Years; he has been a Man in Trade for himself, and worth a Thousand Pounds. In my Surprize I could not tell what to do with him: I took him over Tower-Hill, with a Design to carry him to my House, and desir'd he would be very candid with me, and tell me the whole Thing; he then said, I sold 24 lb. of your Cotton to Mr. Scarsbrook.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-4-person110">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person110" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person110" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-4-person111">
                  Peter 
                  Scarsbrook 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person111" type="surname" value="Scarsbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person111" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you buy any Cotton of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Scarsbrook . The Prisoner came to my House between Eight and Nine o'Clock on Friday Night; he ask'd me my Name, and said, don't you buy Cotton? I said, I did. I ask'd him, who recommended him to me? He said, my Sister, that lives near the May-Pole. I ask'd, whether it was spun or unspun? He said he would fetch it in five Minutes Time; but he staid fifteen. He brought up the Cotton; I said, what do you ask a Pound for it. I don't know whether he ask'd 18 or 20 Pence for it. I ask'd him his Name; he said 
               <persName id="t17460702-4-person112">
                  John 
                  Dodson 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person112" type="surname" value="Dodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; I live, said he, at the Seven Stars in Bishopgate-Street , at a Tobacco-Cutter's . I ask'd him where he had the Cotton from; he told me he had it out of Gloucestershire from a Sister of his; I told him I would give no more than 18 d. per Pound. It weigh'd 23 Pound, and I gave him 34 s. 6 d. for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-4-person113">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-4-person113" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-person113" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to the Prisoner .) Will you ask him any Question?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in Liquor when I did it. <rs id="t17460702-4-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-verdict19" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460702-4-punish20" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-4-punish20" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-4-defend104 t17460702-4-punish20"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
