<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410116-6">
               <interp inst="t17410116-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-6" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-6" type="date" value="17410116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410116-6-off29-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-defend58 t17410116-6-off29 t17410116-6-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>6. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-defend58" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Murrel 
                  <interp inst="t17410116-6-defend58" type="surname" value="Murrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-defend58" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-defend58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17410116-6-defloc28">St. Leonard, Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-6-defloc28" type="placeName" value="St. Leonard, Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-6-defloc28" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-defend58 t17410116-6-defloc28"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410116-6-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Burdet Gown, value 5 s. a Velvet Hood, value 4 s. four Muslin Hoods, value 4 s. a Gold Ring, value 15 s. a pair of Silver Buckles, value 7 s. eight Portugal Pieces, val. 28 l. 16 s two Guineas and 11 l. 2 s. in Money; the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410116-6-victim60" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Griffith 
                        <interp inst="t17410116-6-victim60" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-6-victim60" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-6-victim60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-off29 t17410116-6-victim60"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling House
            </rs>, <rs id="t17410116-6-cd30" type="crimeDate">Dec. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-off29 t17410116-6-cd30"></join>.</p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's Request, the Witnesses were examined a-part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person61">
                  Richard 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person61" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person61" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of December last, between 2 and 3 in the Afternoon, I lost the Goods and Money mentioned in the Indictment. The Prisoner had been all the Forenoon cleaning the Room, where the Money was; and was sent out on an Errand, but not returning in the Time I expected her, I went up Stairs , and found my Drawers open, and the Goods and Money gone. About a Fortnight afterwards, she was taken with the Gown on her Back, my Buckles in her Shoes, and my Wife's Gold Ring on her Finger, and she confess'd the Fact to the Person that took her. - She was my <rs id="t17410116-6-deflabel31" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-defend58 t17410116-6-deflabel31"></join>, and had liv'd with me about five Weeks.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Is your Wife with you?</p>
               <p>Griffith. She was very ill in the Hospital when this happen'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not give me those Things?</p>
               <p>Griffith. No; if I was to die this Moment, I never did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not shew me your Wife's Things, and your Money, and say, when your Wife died, I should be your Second, and all would be mine?</p>
               <p>Griffith. No! on my Oath I never offered any Thing to her in my Life. She had my Wife's Gown on her Back when she was before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person62">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person62" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutor desired me to apprehend the Prisoner, and accordingly on the 20th of December last, I took her at Harwich , whither she went in order to go to Holland. I had known the Prisoner before, and asked her if she was not surprized to see me; she said she was; I then asked her whether she had spent all the Money? she said she had not, but put her Hand into her Pocket, and gave me a 3 l. 12 s. Piece, which she said was all that was left, except a little Silver. I took her Trunk to my Inn, and on my enquiring after her Mistresses-Ring, she pull'd it off her Finger, and said, she did not know that she had taken it, 'till after she went away: She had these Silver Buckles in her Shoes at the same Time, and before we came out of the Stage-Coach, she gave them to me. When I apprehended her, I ask'd her for the rest of the Things, and she told me they were in her Trunk, and I accordingly found an old Velvet Hood, which the Prosecutor own'd, and likewise four new ones, which the Prisoner said she had bought; she confess'd to me, that she had taken 83 l. 12 s. Pieces, a two Guinea Piece, a 36 s. Piece a Guinea and a Half, three Crowns, four half Crowns, and some Silver, which she said weigh'd about half a Pound, and that she took it out of a Drawer in the Prosecutor's House. She had this Gown on her Back when I took her into Custody.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person63">
                  William 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person63" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person63" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . This Gown was on the Prisoner's Back when she was before the Justice, and she own'd that she had taken a gold Ring and a pair of Buckles out of the Prosecutor's House: She was charged with the Money, but I can't say whether she confess'd that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person64">
                  Adam 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person64" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person64" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to see the Prisoner, and asked her if any Body was concern'd in this Affair, but she said she did it by herself, and had no<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174101160005"></xptr> Design of robbing her Master, 'till that very Morning she did it. She own'd that she had taken the Money out of a Chest of Drawers in her Master's Bed-chamber, but said that she did not break the Drawers open.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Thursday before I took it, my Master offer'd it to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person65">
                  Ann 
                  Kell 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person65" type="surname" value="Kell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person65" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner ever since he was born, and never knew her guilty of any Crime whatsoever.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person66">
                  William 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person66" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person66" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about five Years, she liv'd with her Aunt at my House a Year and half, and behav'd very honestly .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person67">
                  John 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person67" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person67" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known her between 5 and 6 Years and never heard but that she was an honest Girl.</p>
               <p>Mrs Sherrard. The Prisoner lived a Servant with me, about 15 Months ago, and never wronged me of any Thing .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person68">
                  John 
                  Sherrard 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person68" type="surname" value="Sherrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person68" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known her ever since she was 8 Years of Age; her Character was universally good, set aside this Thing that I hear now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-6-person69">
                  Eleanor 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17410116-6-person69" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person69" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her between 5 and 6 Years, and never heard any Misdemeanor of her before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17410116-6-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17410116-6-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-6-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-6-defend58 t17410116-6-punish33"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
