<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-18">
               <interp inst="t17470909-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-18" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-18" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-18-off76-c121" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-18-defend146 t17470909-18-off76 t17470909-18-verdict79"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-18-off77-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-18-defend150 t17470909-18-off77 t17470909-18-verdict79"></join>
         
               <p>331. + 
               <persName id="t17470909-18-defend146" type="defendantName">
                  Richard 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend146" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend146" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              was indicted for <rs id="t17470909-18-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a Black-brown Gelding, value 8 l.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-18-victim148" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Downs 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-18-victim148" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-victim148" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-victim148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . And</p>
               <p>332. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470909-18-defend150" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Harman 
                  <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend150" type="surname" value="Harman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-defend150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470909-18-off77" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-off77" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-off77" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-18-person151">
                  James 
                  Downs 
               <interp inst="t17470909-18-person151" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I put the Horse to Grass beyond <placeName id="t17470909-18-crimeloc78">Marybone</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-18-crimeloc78" type="placeName" value="Marybone"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-18-crimeloc78" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-18-off76 t17470909-18-crimeloc78"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-18-off77 t17470909-18-crimeloc78"></join> the 12th of July, but I never saw him from the 12th to the 22d.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it ever found again?</p>
               <p>Downs. The Field Keeper call'd and told my Wife he had heard of it, and that he had heard of it in St Giles's, that he heard one Mr Harman had such a Horse, and I went to Mr Harman to inquire whether he had such a Horse, and he said he had. From thence I went to Mr Hind's, and told him the Affair, and Mr Hind sent to his Collar-maker, and enquired what he had done with the Skin, and that was sent to Mr Cox's a Tanner in Southwark, there we found this Skin, the Skin of my Horse, which I believe I can swear to.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to the Skin of a dead Horse?</p>
               <p>Downs. Upon seeing the Skin, Harman offered to pay me for the Horse; coming over the Water he offered me 8 s.</p>
               <p>Court. Eight Shillings: You have laid the worth 8 l. Was this Skin of that dead Horse shewn you at the Request of Harman ?</p>
               <p>Downs. At the Request of Mr Hind and Harman.</p>
               <p>Court. Do you know how the Gelding was lost ?</p>
               <p>Downs. No, not of my own Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination. Sir, I would ask you, when he went so readily with you to the Tanner's, and before the Justice, did not he tell you how he came by that Horse?</p>
               <p>Downs. Mr Green is a Dealer in Horses, and Harman calls himself a Flesh-boiler.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how Green came by him?</p>
               <p>Downs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he tell you this was a stray Horse, and had the Glanders, and was turned out.</p>
               <p>Council. You have been valuing this Horse at 8 l. I would now ask you if this Horse, that you would not have taken 7 or 8 l. for, whether or no he was not a distemper'd Horse, was you not told by the Field-Keeper, that this Horse was turned out of the Field, because he should not infect others with the Glanders? And don't you know that this Horse stray'd up to Mr Green's House, and he gave him a Lock of Hay at his Door?</p>
               <p>Downs. I heard Mr Green say so, but none else.</p>
               <p>Q How far is Mr. Green's from this Place?</p>
               <p>Downs. Above a Mile.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask you, did you not declare before the Justice that Harman was guilty of no Offence<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090010"></xptr> at all? Did you not declare before Mr Johnson that sits here, that you believed Harman was an innocent Man, and guilty of nothing? [These were close Questions put to Mr Downs, but I think his Answer was in the Negative ]</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-18-person152">
                  Samuel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17470909-18-person152" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person152" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Can you recollect any thing of the last Witness's having a Horse at Grass in July last ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. On the 22d of July, Mr Downs came to enquire for his Horse; the Horse have been lately castrated. I look'd at the Horse if it were distemper'd; I found nothing was the matter with him. On the 22d of July, he came to enquire for his Horse; I told him it was in the Field; a Servant in my House went with his Man to look after it, and he told me it was not in the Grounds; so I called for the Field-Keeper to enquire, and he told me a Rail in the Bell-field was broke, there was none of Mr Downs's Horse to be found. On the 21st of July, I saw the Horse, and he gallop'd with the rest of the Horses, and I said that Downs's Horse comes on.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen his Skin? can you swear that to be the Skin of Downs's Horse?</p>
               <p>Lewis. The Skin is very much like it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined by Council. Might not this Horse be infected with the Glanders without your knowing of it; an Horse don't always run at the Nose when it has the Glanders ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No?</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say, that this Horse had not the Glanders?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I believe it had not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-18-person153">
                  Isaac 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17470909-18-person153" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person153" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Field-Keeper.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of this Horse of Mr Downs's that came in the 12th of July, what Order was he in when he came?</p>
               <p>Ford. I can't say he was in exceeding good Order.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been at this Business?</p>
               <p>Ford. Three Quarters of a Year; but I had been but a Quarter of a Year in this Place.</p>
               <p>Q. Had this Horse the Glanders?</p>
               <p>Ford. Not to my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any Disorder in the Horse?</p>
               <p>Ford. He had got a Cold in his Head.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the Horse miss'd?</p>
               <p>Ford. I miss'd it the 21st of July. I went to enquire after it, and I heard of it at one Mr Green's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to Green?</p>
               <p>Ford. I heard of it by the Neighbours. I did not see the Horse at Green's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go any where else to seek after him?</p>
               <p>Ford. I went to Harman's, and I ask'd him if he had bought such a Horse, and he told me that he had, that he had bought the Horse and paid for him; and I said, that was enough for me; I ask'd him if he had bought a black-brown Gelding, and he said he had bought such a one of one Green.</p>

               <p>Cross examined. Did you see Green at all?</p>
               <p>Ford. When he was taken, but had no Talk at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Value of the Horse when he was lost ?</p>
               <p>Ford. To the best of my Knowledge the Horse might be worth about 7 l.</p>
               <p>Q. You admitted that this Horse had got a great Cold. I would ask you whether this Horse did not run at the Nose ?</p>
               <p>Ford. He had run at the Nose, but he was got a great deal better.</p>
               <p>Council. Now when you had this Discourse with Harman, and he told you that he bought this Horse, did he not tell you that the Horse died of the Glanders?</p>
               <p>Ford. He told me that the Horse was dead, and if he had not died he would have killed him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470909-18-person154">
                  John 
                  Harley 
               <interp inst="t17470909-18-person154" type="surname" value="Harley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person154" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know Green the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Harley. Yes, Sir. All that I know is, that I saw him take a black-brown Gelding out of a Boy's Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice what he was?</p>
               <p>Harley. He was running just as if he had got the Glanders.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know that to be Downs's Horse?</p>
               <p>Harley. I did not.</p>
               <p>- On the 23d of July I help'd Mr Green to grease and clout his Cart; after that I went down St Giles's and got a Dram, and coming back again he had this Horse tied to the Cart-Wheel, and Hay before him.</p>
               <p>Q What Condition was he in?</p>
               <p>- He ran at the Off-Nostril, and bled at the Near-Nostril. Both the Prisoners <rs id="t17470909-18-verdict79" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-18-verdict79" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>. They petitioned for a Copy of their Indictment, but it was not granted. Mr Downs received a Reprimand from the Court for commencing such a Prosecution upon so very slight and uncertain Evidence.</p>
            </div1>
