<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430413-17">
               <interp inst="t17430413-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-17" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-17" type="date" value="17430413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430413-17-off104-c1" targOrder="Y" targets="NODEFENDR t17430413-17-off104 t17430413-17-verdict110"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430413-17-off107-c184" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-17-defend222 t17430413-17-off107 t17430413-17-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>199. 
               <persName id="t17430413-17-defend217" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-defend217" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430413-17-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 40 Yards of Flanne
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-victim219" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Staples 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim219" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim219" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17430413-17-viclabel105" type="occupation">the Elder</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-17-victim219 t17430413-17-viclabel105"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-victim221" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Staples 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim221" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim221" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-victim221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17430413-17-viclabel106" type="occupation">the Younger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-17-victim221 t17430413-17-viclabel106"></join>, and,</p>
               <p>200. 
               <persName id="t17430413-17-defend222" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-defend222" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-defend222" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for <rs id="t17430413-17-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, knowing them to be stole
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430413-17-cd108" type="crimeDate">March 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-17-off104 t17430413-17-cd108"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-17-off107 t17430413-17-cd108"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-person223">
                  William 
                  Staples 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-person223" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Junior. On Thursday, the 3d of March, about Ten o'Clock in the Morning, one 
               <persName id="t17430413-17-person224">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-person224" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person224" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my Warehouse, and another Woman with her, and desired my Man to call me down; she told me, she wanted some Flannel; I asked her, What Sort; she said, A low Sort; I shewed her some, and told her, the Price was 10 d. per Yard; she said, she wanted something lower; I told her, there was but one Sort lower; she said, she wanted something of a Groat a Yard; I said, there was nothing of double the Price; she said, she had a Coat of that Price on, which she bought of John Brown, an old Cloaths-Man; and that some of her Acquaintance had bought some; she took me to the Monument-Alehouse in East-Cheap, where there were three Women who had bought Flannel, which I had Reason to believe were my Goods: I went with Mrs Harris to Mr James's, who keeps the White-Lion-Alehouse the lower End of Rag-Fair, to seek after this Brown: Says Mrs Harris, There is Brown sitting at the Table, and informed me that Mr James was a Constable: I spoke to Brown, and charged him with having sold Flannel at an under Rate, which I believed to be mine; he flew in a violent Passion, and said, he did not value what I could do; said I, Mr Constable, take hold of him: I saw a Door a little open, I went in, and upon the Bed were 4 Remnants of Flannel with my Mark upon them, which might contain, to the best of my Judgment, about 20 Yards each; said I to Mr James, the Constable, These are mine. Brown said they were his; said I, Mr Constable, I insist upon it, that you take Care of them and the Prisoner; Mr James was not very ready to take Charge of Brown; then I resolved to have him before my Lord-Mayor; I said, I would go and smoak a Pipe till my Lord-Mayor was at Leisure; and we went to the White-Lion-Tavern, in White-Chapel; while we were there, said I to John Brown, you had these Flannels somewhere; if you came honestly by them, you will tell me where you had them; and if you are an honest Man, you will give me an honest Answer. Said I, Pray how came you by these Goods? I will tell you plainly these are my Goods; he gave me for 
               <persName id="t17430413-17-person225">
                  Answer, D<interp inst="t17430413-17-person225" type="given" value="Answer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - n me, and a good deal of that Language, and said it was no Business of mine; and he would go to Jail rather than make a Discovery; then, said I, you shall go to Jail; for these Things have been pretty frequently practised in our Neighbourhood, and I am resolved to find out the Bottom of it. Then he said, Damn you, Sir, I had these from Dublin. Now I knew where the Flannels chiefly came from, and that there are very few which come from thence. When he was examined before my Lord-Mayor, he said he had them from one Brown, a Correspondent of his in Lancashirt, but my Lord threatening to commit him, he said, My Lord, if you will not commit me to Jail, I will tell you the Truth; then he said he had them at a Court in Threadneedle-street, of the Gentleman's Servant. - He owned he had them of my Servant, the other Prisoner; who, being sensible of his Guilt, confessed the Fact with Tears. He owned he had taken, at different Times, about eleven or twelve Pieces, which he had sold to this Brown; he said he sold them for 15 Shillings a Piece, two of them were worth 12 or 13 d. per Yard; and two of them about Eight-pence half-penny per Yard; the lowest priced Flannel we have is Eight-pence half-penny per Yard. The Prisoner had been my <rs id="t17430413-17-deflabel109" type="occupation">Servant</rs> about five Years; he was a Sort of a Porter to carry out Goods for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he never sell any Goods for you?</p>
               <p>Staples. I do not deny that he used to sell Goods for me sometimes when I was out of the Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-person226">
                  Samuel 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-person226" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person226" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3d of March Mr Staples came to my House with a Warrant, and he knows very well I told him I had bought that Flannel of Brown, and I showed him where it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What Price did you use to give him for them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-person227">
                  Samuel 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-person227" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person227" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I gave him different Prices, sometimes Six-pence, and sometimes Seven-pence or Seven-pence half-penny, never less than Six-pence; some of it was damaged, and not worth above a Groat a Yard. I believe I have bought to the Value of ten Pounds of him, and never got above two Shillings in the Pound by any Thing that I bought of him. - This Gentleman says in his Evidence, that I was loth to take Charge of Brown; but he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174304130015"></xptr> is mistaken in that Part of his Evidence; for I never refused to take Charge of him. The Gentleman went to the White-Lion Tavern in White-Chapel, and called for a Bottle of Wine; says Brown, Do you charge me with stealing these Goods? And Mr Staples said, If you did not steal them, you might have them of some Body that did. I said, as for my Part, I buy Goods of any Body that comes to my House; and you said your Man had sold several thousand Pounds worth of Goods for you.</p>
               <p>Mr Staples. I said he had sold Goods for me when I was out of Town, or not in the Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-17-person228">
                  Samuel 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17430413-17-person228" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person228" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . You did not say any thing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Brown say he had these Goods from Ireland?</p>
               <p>James. Yes, he did, but there was no Mention made of any particular Parcel of Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he say he had them out of Lancashire?</p>
               <p>James. Yes, he said he had some, or one Piece out of Lancashire.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he had them at Mr Staples's?</p>
               <p>James. He said at last he had them at a Warehouse in Threadneedle-street. Q. Have these been all the while in your Custody?</p>
               <p>Mr James produced the Flannels, and said they had not been all the while in his Custody, but believed them to be the Goods he bought of John Brown; and Mr Staples proved them to be his Goods.</p>
               <p>The Evidence not being sufficient to fix a Felony upon the Principal, they were both <rs id="t17430413-17-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-17-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
