<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-39">
               <interp inst="t17400709-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-39" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-39" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-39-off200-c243" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-39-defend322 t17400709-39-off200 t17400709-39-verdict203"></join>
         
               <p>330. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-defend322" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Watmore 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-39-defend322" type="surname" value="Watmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-defend322" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-defend322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400709-39-defloc199">St Mary Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-39-defloc199" type="placeName" value="St Mary Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-39-defloc199" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-39-defend322 t17400709-39-defloc199"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400709-39-off200" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-off200" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-off200" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 7 Bushels of Wheat-Flower, val.3 l. a Quartern Loaf, val.8 d. half-penny, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-39-victim324" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Findon 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim324" type="surname" value="Findon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim324" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . A hempen Sack, val.2 s.6 d. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-39-victim326" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Kimber 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim326" type="surname" value="Kimber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim326" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ;1 ditto, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-39-victim328" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Heffeild 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim328" type="surname" value="Heffeild"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim328" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , and 1 ditto
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-victim330" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Strutt 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim330" type="surname" value="Strutt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim330" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-victim330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , <rs id="t17400709-39-cd201" type="crimeDate">June 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-39-off200 t17400709-39-cd201"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person331">
                  Arthur 
                  Findon 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person331" type="surname" value="Findon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person331" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 26th of June I had Occasion to go out, in the Afternoon, and I came home about 8 o'Clock at Night. My Wife then told me the Uneasiness she had on her Mind concerning the Prisoner, for she said she had reason to believe the Prisoner carried out Flower and Bread in his Breeches; she being uneasy, I resolved to get a Constable to attack him, as he went out with his Bread; and the Constable was ordered to attend next Morning; but he slept too long and did not come at the appointed Time. The Morning after this, my Wife was very uneasy, because (she said) the Prisoner could hardly walk about the Shop, he had got such a Bundle between his Legs; so she called me down Stairs, and as he was going out with his Basket of Bread, as usual, she desired him to come back and set his Basket down. Accordingly he came back into the Shop, and seeing me there, he endeavoured to go backwards into the Bakehouse; I followed him, and perceived he wanted to get something out of his Breeches; but I took hold of him and brought him forwards, and he cried out<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090032"></xptr> for Mercy, and begged that I would not expose him. Not expose you! Yes, says I,'tis high Time,- your Deeds have been in the dark long enough; so a Neighbour coming in, we found a Quartern Loaf , of a pretty big Circumference, in his Breeches . I asked him, how he could be such a Rogue? Why the Devil (he said) put him on to do it . We told him, we believed he had wronged us of an hundred Loaves that Way. He said , no, not above 7. and at last he brought it down to 4. Then we sent for the Constable, who was to have come before, and told him we would get a Warrant to search his Lodgings for Flower: Upon which the Prisoner begged we would send him directly to the Counter; that he might (I suppose) have Opportunity to send to his Wife. No; we insisted upon carrying him before a Justice; and then to moderate the thing, he thought proper to confess: but being pretty artful, and knowing he had to deal with one, who never was in any such an Affair before, he desired the Constable would go out of the Room, and that I would go with him, into a secret Place. I went with him into the Bakehouse, and he confessed the Flower, and said it was at his Lodgings. Indeed he did not say, what Flower, but he said the Flower was all at his Lodgings, except a little with which his Wife had made a Pudding. Well, but how much is there at your Lodgings?- Indeed,(says he)'tis all there, and you shall have it all, except what my Wife has made a Pudding of. Upon this I took him before the Justice at Guildhall, and laid the Thing before him, about the Quartern Loaf in his Breeches, and for that, he was committed to Bridewell; and when that was done, I desired I might have a Search Warrant that I might take the Goods he had confessed, but he told the Justice he would let me have them, and I might go and take my Goods: so after he was carried to Bridewell, the Constable, my 'Prentice and I, went to his Lodgings, and found a Sack and a half of Flower, which was upwards of 7 Bushels. One of the Sacks, in which was the Flower, I can't say positively that it was any Person's with whom I deal; but there was one, which belongs to 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person332">
                  Joseph 
                  Strutt 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person332" type="surname" value="Strutt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person332" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I know it by the Mark. For Bakers are not accountable to the Meal-men for their Sacks, and 'tis very common for them to lose a great many by the Roguishness of the Journey-men Bakers, and I know 'tis Strutt's Sack, for I deal with him for Flower. There was another Sack of 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person333">
                  John 
                  Heffeild 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person333" type="surname" value="Heffeild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person333" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's , I deal with him for Oatmeal, and know it to be his by by the Mark. I am persuaded he took it out of my House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person334">
                  Edmund 
                  Cunningham 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person334" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person334" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 27th of June, I was called to take the Prisoner in Custody , and while I was with him, he confessed he had wronged his Master of 6 Quartern Loaves . I saw the Loaf, which Mr Findon said he had taken out of his Breeches and he own'd he had taken it from his Master. I heard nothing of the Flower,'till he came to Guildhall, and then he confessed that he had Flower of his Master's, but did not mention the Quantity . He was vastly desirons of having Pen and Ink, that he might send a Letter to his Wife, before he went to Guildhall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person335">
                  Anthony 
                  Tubby 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person335" type="surname" value="Tubby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person335" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner confessed at Guildhall, that he had Flower of his Master's, at his Lodgings in Rag Fair, I went with the Prosecutor thither, and there I saw 2 Sacks with Flower, and 2 without. Three of the Sacks I knew; one was 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person336">
                  John 
                  Strutt 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person336" type="surname" value="Strutt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person336" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; one 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person337">
                  John 
                  Kimber 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person337" type="surname" value="Kimber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person337" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and one 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person338">
                  John 
                  Heffeild 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person338" type="surname" value="Heffeild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person338" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's the Oatmeal Man's. I can't say, that I know these Men had lost any Sacks, but I know they were their Sacks by the Marks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person339">
                  Henry 
                  Spurdle 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person339" type="surname" value="Spurdle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person339" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Mr Findon detected the Prisoner, he called me over to his House, and I saw the Quartern Loaf taken out of his Breeches, and then I was call'd home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person340">
                  William 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person340" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person340" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             depos'd for the Prisoner, that 10 Months,(or upwards) ago, the Prisoner bought 2 Load of Flower of 
               <persName id="t17400709-39-person341">
                  Roger 
                  Noland 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person341" type="surname" value="Noland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person341" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and that he (the Witness) gave a Bond of 30 l. for the Payment of the Money for them; and that afterwards he saw 20 Sacks of Flower in his House. He added, that he had been a Master Baker, but he could not say the Flower found in his Room, was Part of the Flower he had formerly bought.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Whatley , who lived with the Prisoner, when he was a <rs id="t17400709-39-deflabel202" type="occupation">Master Baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-39-defend322 t17400709-39-deflabel202"></join>, depos'd to the same Effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-39-person342">
                  Ann 
                  Lemon 
               <interp inst="t17400709-39-person342" type="surname" value="Lemon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person342" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-person342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known the Prisoner about 5 Years, and gave him a good Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. William deposed, that Flower will not keep 10 Months, especially if the Weather be hot, unless 'tis sifted over after 'tis lumped. If it was Kiln-dried it would keep some time longer, but no such Flower comes to Queen-Hithe. He farther deposed, that the Prisoner had a very bad Character. <rs id="t17400709-39-verdict203" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-verdict203" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-verdict203" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 8 d. half-penny
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400709-39-punish204" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-39-punish204" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-39-defend322 t17400709-39-punish204"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
