<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-10">
               <interp inst="t17430907-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-10" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-10" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-10-off53-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-defend106 t17430907-10-off53 t17430907-10-verdict56"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-10-off58-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-defend106 t17430907-10-off58 t17430907-10-verdict56"></join>
         
               <p>379 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-defend106" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Hanns 
                  <interp inst="t17430907-10-defend106" type="surname" value="Hanns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-defend106" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-defend106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430907-10-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430907-10-victim108" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Cole 
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim108" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim108" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting him Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 40 s. one Guinea, and 20 s. in Silver
            </rs>, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person109">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person109" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person109" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17430907-10-cd54" type="crimeDate">July 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off53 t17430907-10-cd54"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off58 t17430907-10-cd54"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person110">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person110" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person110" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 9th of July, Mr Pearson, and I were going over <placeName id="t17430907-10-crimeloc55">Hounslow-Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-10-crimeloc55" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-10-crimeloc55" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off53 t17430907-10-crimeloc55"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off58 t17430907-10-crimeloc55"></join>, in an one Horse Chaise, the Prisoner came up to the Chaise with a Pistol in his Hand, and said to Mr Pearson. I must borrow some Money of you, Mr Pearson not minding what he said, he said again sharply to him, I must borrow some Money of you, whereupon Mr Pearson gave him half a Guinea, and about 3 s. 6 d. in Silver, and then he gave him his Watch - He held the Pistol very high close to Mr Pearson's Ear - The Prisoner was on Horseback - Then the Prisoner said to me, I must have your Money, with that I gave him about eight or nine Shillings first; then he said, You have got a Watch, and I must have that, and accordingly I gave it to him; then he said, put your Hand into your Pocket, for you have more Money, and I must have that; then I gave him a Guinea in Gold, and 12 or 13 s. in Silver. - He cocked his Pistol, and held it towards my Face. There was another Person with him who dropped a black Crape over his Face, and was on the other Side of the Chaise with a Pistol in his Hand, which seemed as if it was cocked; the Prisoner's Face was bare all the Time.</p>

               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was it?</p>
               <p>Cole. I believe it was better than half an Hour after Five.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Cole. I believe I have. - I knew him immediately when I saw him afterwards, at the George in Piccadilly, that Day Sev'nnight. - I went there about my Master's Business, and saw the Prisoner in the House. I asked the People of the House if they knew that Man, and they said yes; and I said that Man had robbed me. I then acquainted my Fellow-Sufferer, Mr Pearson, with it, and the next Day we went with the Man who keeps the George to the Prisoner's House: - He keeps a Publick-House, (the Rose and Crown) between Marybone and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070007"></xptr> Paddington, and before Pearson came quite up to his House, seeing the Prisoner standing by the Door, Pearson said, he was sure that was the Man that robbed us we went into the House, and had drank two Pots of Beer with the Prisoner, and had some Pipes and Tobacco, and a Quartern of Brandy, and came out of the House without saying any Thing to him about it, at that Time; the next Morning I got a Warrant from Col. 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person111">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person111" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person111" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and took him up.</p>
               <p>Q. When you drank with him, were you sure the Prisoner was the Person that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Cole. Yes, I was very sure of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem any ways shy when you were drinking ?</p>
               <p>Cole. While we were drinking the first Pot of Beer, I thought he looked a little Shy, and that he looked hard at Mr Pearson.</p>
               <p>Prisoner What Time of the Day was it that I was upon Hounslow Heath ?</p>
               <p>Cole. I believe better than half an Hour after five in the Evening.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What coloured Coat had I on?</p>
               <p>Cole. He had a Surrout Coat, a close bodied Coat, it was a very ordinary thread-bare Coat, with Holes in it, and a narrow brimm'd Hat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never had such a Coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person112">
                  John 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person112" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday in the Afternoon, July 9. 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person113">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person113" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person113" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I were stopped on Hounslow-Heath by the Prisoner, about half an Hour after five in the Evening, he said, I must have a little Money of you before you go any farther; I did not apprehend him at first, for I thought he was only in Joke; the second Time he spoke pretty sharply; I got up in the Chaise with my Whip in my Hand, and had a Mind to have struck him; but seeing another Person, who dropped a Crape over his Face, I kept back; I gave him half a Guinea in Gold and 3 s. 6 d. in Silver, and then my Watch; and my Friend gave him a Guinea, a good Handful of Silver, and his Watch; I said to the Prisoner we are a Couple of Servants came out to take an airing, and I think you have aired us very handsomely: I asked him whether he would not give me something to pay the Turnpike, and he give me a Shilling; I asked him whether he would not give my Companion something, and, he said, he would not; the other said, give him something, and then he gave him a Shilling; the Prisoner said, Now you are richer than we are; I said it was false; for they had got our Money, and we had none of theirs; the Sunday Sev'nnight following, my Mate told me, that he had seen the Man that robbed us, at the George in Piccadilly; we went to the George, and from thence to the Prisoner's House; and before I came to the House, I believe by half the Length of a Field, I saw the Prisoner at his Door, and said, that is the Man that robbed me; says the Man that kept the George in Piccadilly, are you sure of that? I said, I am sure of it, we had some Beer and a Quartern of Brandy - I believe this was about five o'Clock when we got to Hanns's House - That is the very Man that took the Money from me and my Mate, and no body else.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the Seven-Dials from Hounslow?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I believe about ten Miles.</p>
               <p>Q Do you think a Man can ride that in about half an Hour?</p>
               <p>Pearson. According as the Horse is - the Horse was wet with Sweat.</p>
               <p>Q. What Colour was the Horse?</p>
               <p>Pearson. It was a Sort of a Chesnut.</p>
               <p>Q. You say it was better than half an Hour after Five, are you sure it was not turned of Six?</p>
               <p>Pearson. It was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When you were drinking with him, and knew him to be the Person, why did not you lay hold of him then?</p>
               <p>Pearson. Because I would be sure before I got a Warrant to apprehend him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person114">
                  John 
                  Bowles 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person114" type="surname" value="Bowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Horse and Groom in George-Yard by Grosvenor square, the Prisoner has hired Horses of me several Times; for one Day at a Time, never any longer, and always kept very good Hours - I cannot swear he had a Horse that very Day - I think it was a 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person115">
                  Sorrel 
                  Horse 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person115" type="surname" value="Horse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person115" type="given" value="Sorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that he had that Day.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pearson. Do you know what coloured Horse he was on ?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I am not well skilled in Horses - I do not know whether it was a Sorrel or a Chesnut; Mr Bowles said he had a Horse of him, and that he had been upon some secret Expedition.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bowles. Had you any Discourse with the Prisoner about that ?</p>
               <p>Bowles Then the Prisoner came back again, I said, with you have any thing to drink, he said, he did not came to drink, he had been drinking pretty hard; at this he had a Quartern of Brandy, and said, he believed he had done the Business he went about very well - I believe it was between seven and eight in the Morning when he had the Horse.</p>
               <p>Col. 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person116">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person116" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person116" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he had received an anonymous Letter, in which was a Silver Watch, with the Name Pearson upon it; the Watch was produced by him; and Mr Pearson said, it was the same Watch that he was robbed of the 9th of July<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070008"></xptr> on Hounslow-Heath; that it had 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person117">
                  John 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person117" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person117" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             engraved on the Outside, by which he knew it to be his Watch. [ Neither the Letter sent to Col. 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person118">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person118" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person118" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , nor another received by Pearson, could be read in Evidence, not being proved to come from the Prisoner.]</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I deny the Robbery; I was at Dinner in Short's Gardens that Day, between two and three, and staid till between six and seven in the Evening.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person119">
                  Thomas 
                  Newbury 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person119" type="surname" value="Newbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person119" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick-House in Short's Garden, by Drury-Lane End; on the 9th of July (it was on a Saturday) the Prisoner came to my House about three o'Clock, we h ad Beans and Bacon for Dinner, he dined with us, and staid till about seven - he brought me half an Anchor of Brandy, I owed him for half an Anchor before, and I paid him 3 l. for both [The Bill of Parcels was produced, one half Anchor the 2d of June, and the other the 9th of July, with a Receipt in full] - It bore Date the same Day the Money was paid - we drank Beer after Dinner, and afterwards Bumbo - we sat in a little Room below Stairs next the Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What makes you think it was on a Saturday!</p>
               <p>Newbury. By the Receipt - I have no other Reason.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person120">
                  Thomas 
                  Burden 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person120" type="surname" value="Burden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person120" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I dined with the Prisoner at Mr Newbury's in Short's Gardens the 9th of July, between two and three in the Afternoon, and sat with him till between six and seven, and at that Time the Prisoner took Horse and went away - the Horse was a lightish Bay or Sorrel; I have seen the Man several Times, but I have no intimate Acquaintance with him - I am a Chandler, and live in Peter's-street, Soho.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you dined with the Prisoner between two and three, how long did you stay?</p>
               <p>Burden. I staid till near seven, we had Beans and Bacon for Dinner - we drank Beer, and Water and Brandy - we sat in a little Room next the Street - there was only the Gentleman at the Bar, Mr Newbury, and his House-keeper.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fox. The Prisoner has had several Hampers of Wine of me, and paid me very honestly. I have known him but a little while; the Gentleman that recommended him to me, gave him a good Character. I am acquainted with the Brewer who serves him. and he says he drew a great deal of Beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person121">
                  James 
                  Stone 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person121" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person121" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about sixteen Years, his general Character was that of a very honest Man; his Father was a considerable Farmer, and the Prisoner rented a Farm of 200 l. a Year. - This is about 16 Years ago. I do not know any thing of his Character now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person122">
                  William 
                  Crow 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person122" type="surname" value="Crow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person122" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about four Months, he has dealt with me for spirituous Liquors, and always paid me well.</p>
               <p>- Fuller. I have known the Prisoner about a Year, he has lived there about a Year and an Half, and I believe he got a comfortable Living. I know there is Bread to be got, because my Father lived there some Years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person123">
                  Jonathan 
                  Freer 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person123" type="surname" value="Freer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person123" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about two Years, I believe him to be an honest Man. I served him with Coals, and he always paid me very honestly. I live within Half a Mile of him.</p>
               <p>- Graham. I have known the Prisoner ever since he lived at Paddington. I am Foreman to Mr Barret, of Brentford, who is a Master Brick-maker, and Landlord of his House, and I always pay my Men there. I never heard any thing am is of him before; there are about thirty of Mr Barret's Men are obliged to use his House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person124">
                  Henry 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person124" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person124" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him near two Years, his Character is that of a very honest Man; he has very good Business. I have heard him say he could maintain himself handsomely by it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-10-person125">
                  Sarah 
                  Grange 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person125" type="surname" value="Grange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person125" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a Year and an half, and he has the Character of a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>One of the Prosecutors desired Col. 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person126">
                  Deveil
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person126" type="given" value="Deveil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person126" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to give an Account of the Character of Newbury, (the Prisoner's first Witness) to which he said, He was sorry that he was asked that Question, but he was obliged to declare that Mr Newbury is a Person of a most infamous Character, and not to be believed in any Court in the World. <rs id="t17430907-10-verdict56" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-verdict56" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17430907-10-punish57" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-punish57" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-defend106 t17430907-10-punish57"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>380. + He was a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17430907-10-off58" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-off58" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-off58" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430907-10-victim128" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Pearson 
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim128" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim128" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-10-victim128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, value 40 s. Half a Guinea, and 3 s. 6 d. in Silver
            </rs>, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17430907-10-person129">
                  John 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17430907-10-person129" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17430907-10-cd59" type="crimeDate">July 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off53 t17430907-10-cd59"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-off58 t17430907-10-cd59"></join>.</p>

               <p>The Evidence being near the same as on the former, the Jury found him <rs id="t17430907-10-verdict60" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-verdict60" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> of this Indictment. <rs id="t17430907-10-punish61" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-10-punish61" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-10-defend106 t17430907-10-punish61"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
