<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440510-5">
               <interp inst="t17440510-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-5" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440510-5" type="date" value="17440510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440510-5-off27-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-5-defend92 t17440510-5-off27 t17440510-5-verdict30"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100006"></xptr>248. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-defend92" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Saunders 
                  <interp inst="t17440510-5-defend92" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-defend92" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-defend92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440510-5-defloc26">St. George Hanover Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-5-defloc26" type="placeName" value="St. George Hanover Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-5-defloc26" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-5-defend92 t17440510-5-defloc26"></join> was  indicted for <rs id="t17440510-5-off27" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-off27" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-off27" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440510-5-victim94" type="victimName">
                           Jeremiah 
                           Martin 
                        <interp inst="t17440510-5-victim94" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-5-victim94" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440510-5-victim94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-5-off27 t17440510-5-victim94"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in a certain  field, or open place, near the King's highway, putting him in fear and taking from him a silver watch, value 50 s. a hat, value 2 s. and a perriwig, value 2 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440510-5-cd28" type="crimeDate">April 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-5-off27 t17440510-5-cd28"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person95">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person95" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person95" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday the 7th of April, I was going from London to Chelsea, and <placeName id="t17440510-5-crimeloc29">in a narrow passage, which we call the Five Fields, near Perrot's illuminations, about half way between that and the Horse and Groom</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-5-crimeloc29" type="placeName" value="in a narrow passage, which we call the Five Fields, near Perrot's illuminations, about half way between that and the Horse and Groom"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440510-5-crimeloc29" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440510-5-off27 t17440510-5-crimeloc29"></join>, between the two banks, I met Saunders the Prisoner and another person, and they bid me good night.</p>
               <p>Q. What time o'night was this?</p>
               <p>Martin. I judge it to be about nine o'clock; immediately after they had passed me, and bid me good night, I received a blow cross my temples, a very hard blow, but who gave it me, I cannot tell; I turned myself, and 
               <persName id="t17440510-5-person96">
                  John 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person96" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             struck at me with a stick, not so long as my cane, they call it a bludgeon, or a truncheon, it is what they use in this way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner strike you?</p>
               <p>Martin. The first blow was a very severe one; I turned about immediately, and I suppose the Prisoner struck me; afterwards there was a second man came up with a hanger, and gave me some cuts upon my cane; the Prisoner continued his blows, and then I received a blow with a hanger, from which I have a large wound now in my head, and I fell down into a ditch.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing further?</p>
               <p>Martin. Yes, when I was down in the ditch, 
               <persName id="t17440510-5-person97">
                  John 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person97" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person97" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             jumped upon my knees, and I said, What do you want? He answered, D - n your blood, your money, what do you think? I told him I had but very little money, but if he would let me get up, I would give it him. D - n your blood, said he, I know that you always carry a watch. I said, so I did, and he took it out of my pocket. I had a pair of very strong buckskin breeches on; he put one hand in my pocket, to tear it down, and the other on the other side. I told him I had no money there, and but very little in the other. He went to my side pocket; I said I had nothing there but a rule (for I am a carpenter.) Then he put in his hand, tore it down, and took two keys, &amp;c. out of my pocket; and said, G - d d - n your blood, you shall never go home again (then I believe he knew me, for I had known him about five years) and he said he would blow my brains out; but I did not see that he had any pistol; when he talked of killing me, the other man said, G - d d - n you, don't kill him, you have done enough to the man already; with that they both went away, and left me in the ditch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When they went away from you, which way did they go?</p>
               <p>Martin. They went towards London.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell certainly that this is the man? Was it light then?</p>
               <p>Martin. It was not very light, but I having known him some time before, I knew him as well as I did my own brother. I knew him by his voice, body and face; it is surprising he should have used me in that manner, and if the other man had not been more merciful than he, I should never have been here now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person98">
                  John 
                  Rowe 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person98" type="surname" value="Rowe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At near 11 o'clock at night, on the 17th of April, the constable (
               <persName id="t17440510-5-person99">
                  James 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person99" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person99" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) came and called me out, and told me, there was one Mr. Martin almost killed in the fields, and he desired me to assist him. I went along with him and three or four more into the Five Fields. The constable and some of them staid behind, and one of them went about an hundred yards before me. Presently I saw a man coming up a good pace, and he struck at me; I had a bayonet in my hand, and I struck at him, and I believe I struck his coat, and then I cried out, stop thief. Then the constable and his man met him, and knocked him down, and we took him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did this man prove to be?</p>
               <p>Rowe. The Prisoner at the bar. Then I took him to my house; when he came there, he put his hand round one of the door posts, and cried out, Murder! and would not go in, till he was forced in. Then I asked him where he was going? He said he was going to Esquire Man's on the other side of the college, and that he lived with one Esquire Chester, in Golden Square; but the next day, when Mr. Martin and we were going to Esquire Chester, to know the truth of it, he said, he did not live there.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went into the fields it was between ten and eleven, or near eleven, was Mr. Martin got home then?</p>
               <p>Rowe. He was got home some time before; for when the Prisoner came to my house, I sent for Mr. Martin, and as soon as he came in, he said, that is the man that robbed me, for I know him by his tongue, and he said, Mr. Saunders, how could you serve me so, when I have given you many a shilling, and many a meal's meat when you have been out of place; and the Prisoner denied then that he had done any thing to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him, whether I was the first person that met him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100007"></xptr>Rowe. There was one an hundred yards before me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Mr. Martin is an undertaker, and he buried a master of mine; there were four servants of us, two men and two maids, and he gave us a guinea apiece; I would ask him, whether he ever gave me any thing else?</p>
               <p>Martin. I did bury a master of his, and I gave three guineas among the servants; how it was disposed of, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever given him a meal's meat?</p>
               <p>Martin. I don't know that I ever gave him a meal's meat, I have given him money, and treated him when he has been out of place, when I have met him, and when we have gone in to drink, I never let him pay any thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When you came into the room where I was, did not you ask me which way I got my bread?</p>
               <p>Martin. I asked you how you lived, and where you lived; and you would not tell me; and if I did ask you, I had very good reason for it, for this is a bad way of getting bread. He said he was in place at Esquire Chester's; and when I told him I would go to Esquire Chester's, then he said, he did not live there, but only said so; and then he begged for mercy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person100">
                  James 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person100" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person100" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go over the Water Works Bridge, and saw Mr. Martin by the Two Star alehouse, and he said, that he was robbed, he did not say by who, he said, he should know the man again very well if he was to see him; I told him, I would do any thing to serve him; it happened to be my watch-night, and I said I would try if I could catch hold of any body. Mr. Fry was first, I said to Mr. Rowe, Do you go at such a distance; I was the third man, and my apprentice was the next; and we had a parson with us, but I don't know what's become of him; the Prisoner met Mr. Fry, and asked him, where he was going.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it that he met him?</p>

               <p>Wheeler. They met about forty yards on the other side of the Horse and Groom, between that and Perrot's illuminations, but it was nearest the Horse and Groom; when the Prisoner asked Mr. Fry where he was going, Mr. Fry said, he was going to London; then Mr. Rowe came, who was the second man; the Prisoner came up to Mr. Rowe, and, to the best of my knowledge, I saw him strike.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner strike Rowe ?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. Yes, I did; with that I cried out. Here's the villain; I struck at him, and happened to strike him just down the back with a gun; and afterwards came my apprentice and another person, and my apprentice knocked him down into the ditch, with the bar of a door (which was the first thing he could light on) and then he resisted very much, and we were afraid the other should come up; I fired the gun at him, to make him stand, and then he went with us very quietly.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you carry him?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. We carried him to the Two Star alehouse, just by Mr. Martin's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he oppose going into the house?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. Yes, he took hold of one of the pillars of the door, and we got him by the lock of * hair upon the top of his head, and he cried out, Murder! and at last we got him into the house; I told him, he must go in, or I would shoot him; then I sent my apprentice to Mr. Martin's, and he brought him; Mr. Martin said, as soon as he came into the passage, the man was in the house, he knew by his voice; and then I took the Prisoner to the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>* The Prisoner's hair was tied up, like many of the livery servants.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I say, take what I have, and spare my life?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. I don't remember that; I know I said if the law is on your side, you will be right; but if the law is against you, you must take what it will allow you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He told me, there was nothing but powder in the gun, and he fired it only to frighten me.</p>
               <p>Wheeler. I did not tell him any such thing.</p>
               <p>The Council for the Prisoner offered to prove where the Prisoner was from two o'clock in the afternoon till ten at night; and therefore if the robbery was committed at nine o'clock, the Prisoner could not be the person who committed this robbery; that he was informed, they had used some artisices to make him confess; but he always said, he was innocent, and that Mr. Martin sent a Romish Priest to tell him, that Mr. Martin was dead, and that he could not come to any damage, if he did confess the fact.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray Mr. Martin, did you send, or did you not send to Mr. Saunders, to let him know you was dead, and to desire that he would confess upon that account?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100008"></xptr>Martin. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you privy to any such thing?</p>
               <p>Martin. No, I never was privy to any such thing.</p>
               <p>Jury. Pray Mr. Martin, was you in liquor at that time?</p>
               <p>Martin. No, I was not, I was very sober; I had been about business: they would not have meddled with me if I had had any body with me; they had enough as it was, only they had got a hanger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person101">
                  Thomas 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person101" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person101" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of April, on a Tuesday, about ten o'clock in the morning, I went with the Prisoner to the Duke of , dined with Mr. Rothwell in Eagle Court, and at seven o'clock we went to Mr. Fowler's an Apothecary in the Strand; we did not sit down there, we came directly to my Lord Ailesbury's (I live with him now) we went to the Two Chairmen in Warwick Street, and drank a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from Lord Ailesbury's ?</p>
               <p>Watkins. It is about 100 yards from my Lord's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you parted?</p>
               <p>Watkins. It was somewhat more than a quarter after eight.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Prisoner going then?</p>
               <p>Watkins. He said he was going to Chelsea, and I advised him not to go; for he was to have gone to the Duke of Graston's the next morning, and he said he had no clean linnen in town. I never heard any thing further of him till I heard he was in Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person102">
                  Evan 
                  Mansprit 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person102" type="surname" value="Mansprit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person102" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Fowler, an Apothecary, facing Beauford Buildings in the Strand; the Prisoner and Mr. Watkins came to see me that Night-between seven and eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person103">
                  Henry 
                  Buck 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person103" type="surname" value="Buck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person103" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Two Chairmen in Warwick Street by Charing Cross; the Prisoner was at my house the 17th of April between eight and nine at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with him?</p>
               <p>Buck. There was one or two, my Lord Ailesbury's servant was one; they came in between seven and eight, the Prisoner went with him to my Lord Ailesbury's, and they came back again and staid a little while, and then said, Buck, I wish you a good night.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was that?</p>
               <p>Buck. That was after eight, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was it dark when you parted from him?</p>
               <p>Buck. Yes, I think it was; I had lighted candles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person104">
                  Richard 
                  Paty 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person104" type="surname" value="Paty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person104" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of April, I had been at the Bun-House at Chelsea, and met the Prisoner about quarter before nine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he walking or drinking?</p>
               <p>Paty. I met him there under the lamp.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>Paty. I was going to one Mr. Lerose's, to drink a pint of beer; for I intended to leave my watch there; we staid to drink a pint of beer at the dead wall; and he came with me as far as Hide-Park Corner; it was about five minutes after nine when I came from Chelsea, and I parted with him at Hide-Park Corner a quarter before ten - I have known him about ten years, he is a Gentleman's servant; he has been in several places, and I never heard him spoke disrespectfully of; he lived with Mr. Hutchins at Chelsea, and I don't think he would be guilty of any such act as this - I don't know how long he has been out of place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you meet any body in the Five Fields.</p>
               <p>Paty. No, there was a poor Scotsman lying among the pipes, we took him out of the ditch, and took care of him to Hide-Park Corner; he would have made us drink, but we would not accept of it.</p>
               <p>Watkins being examined, as to the Prisoner's character, said, he never heard any thing against his character in his life; and that gentle and simple always gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>- Lerose. I keep the Red Lion in Chelsea; on the 17th of April, the Prisoner came along with Paty (Mr. Mitchell's groom) to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come?</p>
               <p>Lerose. I believe, as near as I can tell, it was about nine o'clock, or a l ittle after.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is your house from the Horse and Groom?</p>
               <p>Lerose. A good way - it may be two miles and a quarter, if not quite, but it is very near.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he look cool, or was he at all heated?</p>
               <p>Patey. He was not at all heated - he was not in a sweat - he was cool in his countenance - he did not look as if he had been in any violent motion.</p>
               <p>Jury, to the Constable. Was he searched, or was any thing found upon them?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. I did search him, but I found nothing upon him; he had private pockets about him, and though I found nothing when I searched him, he had money afterwards, for he treated me.</p>
               <p>Jury. If he had had a watch about him, and you had searched him, do you think you should not have found it?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. I believe I should if I had searched him strictly.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was not you informed of Mr. Martin's having lost a watch?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174405100009"></xptr>Wheeler. Yes.</p>
               <p>Jury. Then why would you not search to find it?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. He had time enough to make it away before that, for I met Mr. Martin at a quarter after ten, and at the time I met the Prisoner it was nearer eleven.</p>
               <p>- Stanley, Esq; The first time I saw the Prisoner at the bar was in February was twelvemonths, at which time I was going down to offer my services at St. Albans, and having only one servant in town, my own servant, who had known him before, recommended him to me to serve me. I had during that time more than negative proofs of his honesty; for I sent my servant I had before, with more than 350 l. in bank notes to Mr. Child's, to desire him to let me have specie for them: my own servant brought me 250 l of the money, and the Prisoner brought me 100 l. very honestly, and by some circumstances I believe it would have been in his power to have taken away that 100 l. My own servant being disordered by riding in the country, I kept the Prisoner about a fortnight, during which time he was the only person intrusted with my linnen and clothes, and when he gave up the account of them there was nothing at all missing. I must also observe, that I never saw a more civil or sober servant than he was, and he always behaved himself in such a manner that I should not imagine him to be capable of the matter he is now charged with.</p>
               <p>- Lewis. I live in Bond Street, and am a hosier and haberdasher. I have known the Prisoner about two years, and during that time his character and behaviour (for what I know) has been honest and just. A young gentleman at my house wanted a servant, I enquired after several, and among them the Prisoner came, and he hired him from the character he had of him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17440510-5-person105">
                  Robert 
                  Rich 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person105" type="surname" value="Rich"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person105" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, which was as good as any man could have; and upon it he had the young gentleman's place, where he behaved honestly and soberly. He was backward and forward at my house very often: he is a very sober man, I never saw him drunk in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Stanley. You say in about a fortnight's time he went from you, did he go from you upon any misbehaviour?</p>
               <p>- Stanley, Esq; He went away from me because my servant was well again; but if he had continued ill, or I had wanted another servant, I would have taken him preferable to any body I knew at that time.</p>
               <p>Jury. When they returned, did they come in company with this money, or did they come singly?</p>
               <p>- Stanley, Esq; They came in company. I do not know how far it may be proper to mention in evidence what my servant told me, who is absent; for when they were upon the road they were not so much in company, but that if he had had a mind to have gone away with the money he might.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440510-5-person106">
                  Richard 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17440510-5-person106" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person106" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the Duke of Graston, I am one of his messengers. I have known the Prisoner twelve or fourteen years, he has been that time a gentleman's servant, and always had the best of characters; I believe he is a very innocent and honest man; I never heard any ill of him till this time in my life.</p>


               <p>Q. to Wheeler. What had the Prisoner in his hand when he was taken?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. It was a stick, and I think it was a little split at the end; whether he threw it over the ditch, or no, I cannot tell, but I could not said it. <rs id="t17440510-5-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440510-5-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
