<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-42">
               <interp inst="t17430114-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-42" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-42" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-42-off209-c430" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-42-defend511 t17430114-42-off209 t17430114-42-verdict212"></join>
         
               <p>120. + 
               <persName id="t17430114-42-defend511" type="defendantName">
                  Daniel 
                  Wicket 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-defend511" type="surname" value="Wicket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-defend511" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-defend511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-42-off209" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-off209" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-off209" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430114-42-victim513" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17430114-42-victim513" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-42-victim513" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-42-victim513" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-42-off209 t17430114-42-victim513"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her four Shifts, three Aprons, four Caps, three Handkerchiefs, and one Pair of Stays
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-42-cd210" type="crimeDate">December 28th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-42-off209 t17430114-42-cd210"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person514">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person514" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person514" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person514" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of December I was going from London to Hammersmith , and about three o'Clock in the Afternoon the Prisoner overtook me by <placeName id="t17430114-42-crimeloc211">Tyburn-Turnpike</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-42-crimeloc211" type="placeName" value="Tyburn-Turnpike"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-42-crimeloc211" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-42-off209 t17430114-42-crimeloc211"></join>, and said, Well overtaken Lady: said I, I thank you, Sir: Said he, Are you not Mr Smith's Daughter? I said, Yes: Said he, I know you very well: So we went together. There was a great Style in Tyburn-Field , and he asked me to hand my Bundle over for me: I said, No, I thank you, I can get over with it very well : Please to go along; so he did; and at the Style at the other End of the Field, he offered the same, which I refused. When I came to the Black-Lion at Bay's Water . I met with a young Man, who was going with a young Woman, whom he was going to delude away, but another young Man came and took her from him, and carried her home to her Friends; and the Prisoner said, that Man deserved the worst of Punishments, to delude such a Child away. When we came to the Bridge where the Black and the Soldier hang in Chains, there was a great Style, the Prisoner was foremost, and he wanted me to go over the Style first; and there being a great Ditch of Water on the other Side, and the Wind pretty high, I was afraid to get over first; I said, Pray get over first; he would not: Said he, Do you get over first, and damn'd me for a Bitch. When he found I would not get over, he hit me on the Side of the Head with a knobbed Stick which he had, and took me in his Arms and holl'd (threw) me into the Bush-Hedge, which was very prickly: He said, he wanted to ravish me, and swore he would. I begg'd him, for God's Sake not to do it, and asked him why he should do such a Thing to a poor honest Girl, as I was, who never did him any Harm, or wished any. I struggled with him a great While , and then was forced to kneel in the Dirt in order to get up; and I pray'd to God to turn his Heart: Then he damn'd my Blood, and said, if I made any Noise he would kill me. I got off my Knees, and then he holl'd me on the Bush on the other Side; then he came to me again, but he had not so much Power over me as he had on the other Side. Then he took me in his Arms again, and holl'd me on the Bush-Hedge on the Side I had been before; then he threw me on my Back, and damn'd my Soul, and bid me lie there till he had done what he pleased with me. I prayed to God Almighty to be my Assistance, to get me out of such a Rogue's Hand. I gave him all the good Words that ever I could, and yet he all the While damn'd my Blood and Soul, and swore that he would kill me: Then he put his Hand up my Coats, and holl'd my Clothes over my Head , and pull'd out what he had: I wrung my Hands and was frightened, and prayed to God for Assistance, that such a Rogue should not have his Will of me: He swore he would ravish me, or have my Life. I fought with him a good While upon my Back, and was almost too strong for him; then he kneeled upon my Stomach, and pulled a Knife out of his Pocket, and put it to my Throat, and swore if I spoke, or stirred, or made any Noise, till he had done what he pleased with me, he would cut my Throat. And<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140035"></xptr> I, Do you think I will lie in this Manner, and in Danger of my Life, and not make a Noise? Yes, I will for somebody to be my Assistant . He put his Hand upon my Mouth , and said, G - d d - n your Blood, you Bitch, will you speak? I will have your Life, or ravish you. I said, I will make a Noise and hollow as long as I have a Bit of Breath in me. So he put his Knife up again, and said, G - d d - n your Blood, you Bitch, as you serable with me so, and pray to God, I will take your Bundle away from you. With that he took my Bundle away from me, and run away with it to the Bottom of the great Grass Field, and damned me, and bid me come after him to fetch my Clothes; No, said I, do you think I will follow you into that bye Field to fetch my Bundle, I am very glad I can get off so ; said I, I know you very well. So I made the best of my way Home, I do not know which way I got over the Stile, and when I came to my Friends , my Hair was all torn off my Head, and my Face bloody and dirty. When I went in, I had my Petticoat under my Arm, it was torn off in scrabbling with him in the Bushes; here is the Apron I had on, it was made bloody with my Arm's being torn in the Bushes; when I got to my Unkle's, they were quite galletted to see me, and when I sat down I swooned away: 
               <persName id="t17430114-42-person515">
                  John 
                  Miles 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person515" type="surname" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person515" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person515" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Neighbour's Man, went with me to my Brother's, and they went to the Prisoner's House, at East-Acton , and brought him to the Constable's House, and there I said he was the Man - It was a Clasp-Knife which the Prisoner had - It was about 5 o'Clock, and Moon-light , when the Prisoner attacked me, - I know Mr Bristow very well, but I did not meet him upon the Road; I met another young Man upon the Road, whom I saw at the Constable's House.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner take the Bundle away from you with an Intent to rob you, or to make you come after him into that bye Field, in order to have his Will of you?</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person516">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person516" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person516" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person516" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot tell that.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person517">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person517" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person517" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . When my Sister came to my House, about 6 or 7 o'Clock, she said she was ruined for ever, for she was robbed of her Clothes by Jack Ragg (that is a Nick name he goes by) I saw her Apron and her Arms were bloody, and she had a Petticoat upon her Arm, but being surprized, I did not take much Notice: I went along with Miles and Cloudsly to see for this Man; when I came to his House, I knocked at the Door, and asked if Daniel was come home? they said, No, and asked me what I wanted with him; I said I heard he was out of Work , and I could help him to a Jobb; his Wife said he went to London in the Morning, and would not be at Home that Night ; we went out of the House, says 
               <persName id="t17430114-42-person518">
                  John 
                  Miles 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person518" type="surname" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person518" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I will be hanged if he is not at Home; we went in again, looked in the Room and under the Bed, and could not see him - we went into a little Orchard behind the House, and I saw him standing upright; I laid hold of him and asked him, how he could rob my Sister? he swore by G - d he did not know my Sister; I told him it did not signify any thing denying it, for he had got her Bundle, and must go along with us; he said, If I would let him go, he would give us the Bundle, he said he had left it by the Way; I said that would not do, he must go with us; then he said he would fetch us the Bundle; he unlocked the Door of an Out-house, and delivered the Bundle to 
               <persName id="t17430114-42-person519">
                  John 
                  Miles 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person519" type="surname" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person519" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then he said, For God's Sake let me go now you have got your Bundle: I told him that would not do, he must go with us; so we carried him to the Constable's House, sent for my Sister, and she was positive that he was the Man that had taken the Bundle; then he said he would down on his Knees and ask her Pardon, if she would forgive him, and she said No; how did he think she could forgive him, who, when she was down upon her Knees in the Dirt and Water, would not shew her any Mercy: Then he said, For God's Sake, young Woman , consider I have a Wife and four Children; she said, No, you shall have nothing but what the Law affords you; and she gave the same Account the next Morning, before the Justice; the Prisoner told the Justice, he called to her to take the Bundle, and said he run all the way after her, but could not overtake her.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person520">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person520" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person520" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person520" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being asked where the Bundle was during the Time of the Struggle, she said at first it was in her upper Coat, but that she was afterwards in such a Fright, that she could not tell whether he took it from her, or took it off the Ground.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person521">
                  John 
                  Miles 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person521" type="surname" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person521" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the Evidence of 
               <persName id="t17430114-42-person522">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person522" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person522" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with this Addition, that the Prisoner being asked how he could rob a Person who worked hard for what she got as well as himself, said, God forgive him, he had forsaken all Labour this Fortnight past, and they all said they were sorry for it; that he farther said, he had not done it if he had not been put on to do it; to which it was reply'd, no body but the Devil put him upon it - that he owned he gave her a Push, and her Foot slipped, and she fell down into the Briers.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence. The young Woman and I came almost from London together; when we came to Mr. Green's House, there is a Stile, and she asked me to carry her Bundle, I put my Stick cross the Bundle, and laid it over my Shoulder, when I came to the last Stile, I asked her to get over, she was almost<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140036"></xptr> over, and I laid my Hand upon her, but I did not touch her Flesh, and she slipped on one side into the Briers, and got up again directly, and swore she would make me pay for this, and then went away: I had the Bundle cross my Shoulder all the Time; I went to go directly homeward, and could not see her; I did not know where she lived; so I carried the Bundle home and locked it up in a back House, with a Design to carry or send it to her the next Morning. They say I went out at the Back-Door, I was obliged to do it; for there was a Warrant out against me, and I could not stay within Doors, it was not upon the Account of the Bundle; I said to Miles, Do you think I would offer to take her Bundle from her, as she knew me, and I know her? and he cursed and swore, and said, Yes , I would; and they said they would hang me.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person523">
                  William 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person523" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person523" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of December, I was coming from Acton, about a Quarter after 5 o'Clock in the Evening, as I was coming along the Field, a little below Mr Green's House, I met the Prisoner and a Woman along with him, but I cannot tell whether I should know her again if I saw her; the Man was foremost, her Hat blew off and she went back to fetch it; when I past him, he said, Good Night Master, and I said, Good Night John; he had then a Bundle or Hand-Basket, upon a Stick on his Shoulder - it was Moon-light, and light enough for me to see, I passed by them, looked after them, and stood still some time, and after she had pick'd her Hat up she run after the Prisoner - when I met them I believe I was about 100 Yards off the Stile she speaks of - I could not be 200 from them, at the Time this happened - if she had cried out I think I must have heard it, because the Wind blew the Way that I was going, and if I had heard any Noise I should have gone back again - I did not perceive she had any Bundle, I think if she had I must have seen it, if it had been in her Cloaths - I think I can take my Oath she had none at all.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person524">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person524" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person524" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did not you say, when you came back from carrying the Prisoner to Newgate, that he had no Bundle?</p>

               <p>Bristow. I do not know what I said in Company , but what I have sworn to is true, Smith said, that the Prisoner declared, a Man he met persuaded him to rob her: said I, That is calling me Thief by Craft, because I was the Person that met him. - I did say, that if he had not said these Words I should not have troubled myself about it; but as he called me Thief by Craft, I said, I would come in Favour of the Prisoner; and I believe this Prosecution is carried on for the Sake of the Reward.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person525">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person525" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person525" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did not you tell me you went along the Road?</p>

               <p>Bristow. No, I can safely say, I did not say that, because I met a Man by the Field Side and staid and talked with him.</p>

               <p>Banks. Seakings, Arnoid, Reynolds, Whittle, Peggs , Freeman Prince, and Bristow, have known the Prisoner several Years; some of them twenty all agree that his general Character is that of an honest Man, and always behaved well; and some say, if he was clear of this they would employ him as soon as any Man in England.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-42-person526">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-42-person526" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person526" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-person526" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was asked by the Jury, Whether the Prisoner had any Bundle? she said, He had no Bundle, nor Basket, only his Stick in his Hand.</p>


               <p>The Jury then withdrew, and after staying out for an Hour, brought in a Verdict <rs id="t17430114-42-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-42-punish213" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-42-punish213" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-42-defend511 t17430114-42-punish213"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
