<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410701-4">
               <interp inst="t17410701-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-4" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410701"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410701-4" type="date" value="17410701"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410701-4-off16-c46" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-defend55 t17410701-4-off16 t17410701-4-verdict20"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410701-4-off16-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-defend57 t17410701-4-off16 t17410701-4-verdict19"></join>
         
               <p>5, 6. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Steers 
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend55" type="surname" value="Steers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend55" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Gloide 
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend57" type="surname" value="Gloide"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend57" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-defend57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             of <placeName id="t17410701-4-defloc15">St. Martin in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-defloc15" type="placeName" value="St. Martin in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-defloc15" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-defend55 t17410701-4-defloc15"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-defend57 t17410701-4-defloc15"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17410701-4-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410701-4-victim59" type="victimName">
                           Arabella 
                           Strickland 
                        <interp inst="t17410701-4-victim59" type="surname" value="Strickland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-4-victim59" type="given" value="Arabella"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410701-4-victim59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-off16 t17410701-4-victim59"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a cloth Cloak, val. 7 s. a silk Handkerchief, val. 1 s. a linen Apron, val. 2 s. a linen Cap, val. 18 d. a Straw Hat, val. 2 s. and 6 s. 6 d. in Money
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of 
               <persName id="t17410701-4-person60">
                  Arabella 
                  Strickland 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person60" type="surname" value="Strickland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person60" type="given" value="Arabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; <rs id="t17410701-4-cd17" type="crimeDate">March 10th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-off16 t17410701-4-cd17"></join>.</p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's desire, the Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person61">
                  Arabella 
                  Strickland 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person61" type="surname" value="Strickland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person61" type="given" value="Arabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person61" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took a Coach No 248, at 2 o'Clock in the Morning, on the 10th of March, a little on this side Charing-Cross. The Prisoner Steers was then on the Coach Box, and I desired him to drive me to the highest end of Bridges-Street, by Covent Garden. When I came to <placeName id="t17410701-4-crimeloc18">Catharine Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Catharine Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410701-4-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-off16 t17410701-4-crimeloc18"></join>, I call'd out to him stop; he did not regard me, but continued going on till he came to Somerset House. When we got thither, I heard a Man say, D - n you, you Rascal, what Business have you with my Coach? The Prisoner Steers then open'd the Coach-Door, and I thought he was going to let me out, but instead of that, he came into the Coach to me, and one hand he employed in a very indecent manner, the other he put into my Pocket, and took out 6 s. 6 d. I begg'd for God's sake that he would let me alone, and I would pay him, but he paid no regard at all to what I said.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did any other Man appear at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Strickland. No, the other Man kept beating me with the Butt End of his Whip all the Time.</p>
               <p>Q. When you desired them to let you alone, what followed?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Steers went out at the Backside of the Coach, and the other came in, and offered to be rude with me. While Steers was in the Coach with me, another Man (I can't tell who it was) poked in his Whip at the Window, and with the Handle of it struck out two of my sore Teeth. As soon as Steers had pick'd my Pocket he went out, and the other Man came in; upon that I called out Watch as loud as I could, and then Steers took me by the Cloak and pulled me out of the Coach upon the ground. When I was out of the Coach, 2 Women came up and said, d - n you, you B - ch, what Business have you with our Husbands, and gave me several Blows; I cry'd out, and then the Prisoner Steers cut me with the small End of the Whip. This was over against Somerset House, and the Soldiers there hearing the Disturbance came to my Assistance, and the Men took to their Coach and drove away, to a Cellar by the New-Church.</p>
               <p>Q. What Condition did they leave you in?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Without my Cap, Handkerchief, Cloak and Apron; and all over Blood. I lost these Things at the same Time that I lost the Money,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174107010004"></xptr> and they took them from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoners are the Persons who robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Strickland. I can swear to the Prisoner Steers, and Gloide own'd before the Justice that he was with him.</p>
               <p>Q. When they stopped with their Coach at this Cellar-Door, what follow'd?</p>
               <p>Strickland. I went with 3 Watchmen to the Cellar, and they asked me if I knew the Men; I told them I knew one of them for he had a Scar on his Eye; so we went down into the Cellar, and neither of the Prisoners were there; but we found them both in a back Room, and although they had changed Coats, I knew Steers to be one of the Persons that robbed me. There were a great many Men in the Cellar, and the Watchmen were afraid of them, and told me if I took the Number of the Coach that was sufficient. This was on the Monday Morning about 2 o'Clock, and on Tuesday I went to the Hackney-Coach Office, and a Man there told me that Mr. Clark, the Master of the Coach, was a very civil Man, and the Matter might be made up for about 2 Guineas, but I was informed I could not do it; so Mr. Clark and Steers were both summoned to appear. On the Friday following I went again to the Office, and Clark appeared, but Steers did not. Mr. Clark desired that I would not indict his Coach, and gave me a Crown, and promised to get a Warrant against Steers to take him, and if he could not take him in a Week, he would give me another Crown. The Prisoners both kept out of the Way, and were not taken till the 14th of June, at which Time they were carried before Mr. De Viel.</p>
               <p>Q. As the Distance between the Commission of this Robbery, and the apprehending the Prisoners was so great, could you remember either of their Faces?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Yes, there were 2 Lights against the Place where Steers took me up; - it was just by St. Martin's Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Prisoners were taken could you remember any Thing as to Gloide?</p>
               <p>Strickland No, I could not swear to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you recollect that he was the Person whom you had seen in the Cellar with Steers?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Yes, I knew him to be the same Person.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Prisoners were before Mr. De Viel did they own any Thing?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Yes, Steers owned that he horse-whipped me, but I don't remember that he owned the robbing me; but I am sure the Person that horse-whipped me was the same that robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Gloide confess any Thing?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Gloide only owned that he attempted to commit Indecencies with me, but that I would not let him.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any Thing else that they confessed?</p>
               <p>Strickland. No nothing else; they said they horse-whipped me because they thought I was a Whore.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did not she own to several People that she was very much fuddled?</p>
               <p>Strickland. No, I never did, for I was not fuddled.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Do you know one Mrs. Murphey or Mrs. Rockham?</p>
               <p>Strickland. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did not you say the Women tore your Pocket off?</p>
               <p>Strickland. No, they only beat me, and asked me what Business I had with their Husbands.</p>
               <p>Steers. What was the Reason that you staid so long as from March to June before you took us up?</p>
               <p>Strickland. Mr. Clark told me he would take them up, besides I was taken very ill.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did not you hear that we were both at our Stand in the Day Time?</p>
               <p>Strickland. They were only out at Nights; besides I was ill and could not go about to look after them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person62">
                  Stephen 
                  Haydon 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person62" type="surname" value="Haydon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person62" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman. On the 10th of March, about 2 in the Morning, this Woman, Strickland, came to my Stand, the Corner of Catharine Street, and appeared to be very much abused. She desired me to go with her, for she had like to have been murdered. I told her I had heard the Lashes of a Whip for near half an Hour, but it being out of my Parish I durst not venture to go, except she could call the other Watchmen out of the Strand. She got 3 other Watchmen, and we all went together to Woodward's Cellar, where the Coach was standing. The other Men desired me to go down first; accordingly I did, and when I came down I saw the Coachman, Steers shuffling about from one Table to another, endeavouring to hide his Whip. I accused about half a dozen Men in the Cellar, and asked the Woman if she knew any of them; she said she did not, but when I came to Steers, she fell on her Knees, and wished she might never rise more if he was not one of the Men.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take Notice of any other Man at that Time?</p>
               <p>Haydon. No, she did not; she said nothing of Gloide then.</p>
               <p>Q. When you discovered Steers would she have charged you with him?</p>
               <p>Haydon. Yes, but I said the Number of the Coach was sufficient, and there were so many Men in the Cellar that I was afraid we should have our Brains beat out. In a little Time afterwards the Prisoner Steers came out of the Cellar, and I would have pushed the Woman away, but she looked in his Face and said, this is the Person that whipped<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174107010005"></xptr> me, upon which he turned about and said; d - n you, you B - ch, for half a Farthing I would horse whip you again. The next Day I went with the Prosecutrix to the Coach-Office about the Number of the Coach, and the Master of it was summoned, and on his appearing, he gave her a Crown, and promised her another if he did not take Steers in a short Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Justice with the Prisoners?</p>
               <p>Haydon. Yes, and I heard Steers own that he whipped her with a double thong'd Whip: The Justice asked them, what they went into the Coach for, and one of them, I think it was Gloide, smiled and said, with Intent to lie with her.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. When she came to you at your Stand, did she say she had been robbed?</p>
               <p>Haydon. Yes, she said she had been robbed of her Landlady's Cloak, her Cap, and 6 s. 6 d. in Money, and desired me to go and take the Persons.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did not she charge some Women with the Robbery?</p>
               <p>Hay don. No, she said she was robbed by 2 Men, and 2 Women came and beat her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person63">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person63" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person63" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the Time of the Commission of this Fact 
               <persName id="t17410701-4-person64">
                  Thomas 
                  Steers 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person64" type="surname" value="Steers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person64" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my Servant. On the 9th of March last, he drove a Hackney-Coach for me, No. 248, and on the Wednesday following a Summons came with a Complaint against that Number to appear at the Office on the Friday. On the Thursday Morning, I went up Stairs to call the Prisoner as usual, and informed him of this Summons, and of the Complaint: He said, he knew nothing of it, but however if he was to be sent to Newgate he would certainly appear. He lay a bed the best Part of that Day, and the next Day instead of appearing according to his Promise, he absconded, and I could not find him, so I went myself to the Office, and was informed that a Woman and two Watchmen had been to complain against me. I afterwards went into Covent Garden to see for Steers, but he was not to be found, so I went to the Office again, and the Prosecutrix was there, and told me she had been robbed of 6 s. 6 d., her Cloak, Apron and Cap. I told her it was out of my Power to produce the Man, but if she would not appear against me at the Office, I would give her a Crown then, and another if I did not take him in a Week. In about a Week afterward she was taken ill, and I went to see her, and gave her 5 d. or 6 d. to get blooded. We got a Warrant from Justice De Viel, and Steers was taken; Glide was taken the same Morning at 10 o'Clock, and carried before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed when you were before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Clark. Steers being asked why he left my Coach, said, he was taken ill at Temple-Bar, and sent Glide away with it, and ordered him to bring it again at 2 o'clock. He said, Glide, did not return with the Coach, upon which he went to see for him at Woodward's Cellar, where he had left Word that he was gone to Westminster. That he saw the Coach in the Strand, with a Linkman on the Box, and a Man and Woman in the Coach: that he pulled the Woman out of the Coach, and gave her 3 or 4 Strokes with his Whip. Gloide said he was in the Coach at the same time, and would have lain with the Woman, but did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Where does this Woman live?</p>
               <p>Clark. She lodged then at one Whitehead's in King's Court, Russel Street, Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Steers. Did not you see me from the time that you got the Warrant, to the time that I was taken?</p>
               <p>Clark. I have seen him once or twice since, but he kept out of the Way. I told him there was a Warrant against him, and he said he did not value it, for it was only going to Bridewell for 7 Days.</p>
               <p>- Black. I am a Constable in St. Giles's Parish. When I had Steers in Custody, I carried him before Mr. De Viel, but he not being at Home, I left him in the Custody of 2 or 3 Men at the 
               <persName id="t17410701-4-person65">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person65" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person65" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Bow Street, while I went to see after Gloide. I took him out of Bed, and told him I wanted him to come and speak in the Behalf of Steers; and he said he had nothing to say but what would hurt him. When we had them both together before the Justice, Gloide owned that he attempted to lie with the Woman, and Steers said he horse-whipped her with a double Thong.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Steers. I sent Gloide with the Coach, and thinking he staid long, I went several times to see after him. I went to Woodward's Cellar, and while I was there, the Coach stopped on the other Side of Somerset House Water Gate. I went to see what was the Reason that it did not come up, and saw a Fellow on the Box, and Gloide and this Woman in the Coach. The Woman got out of the Coach and went up Catharine Street, and I went to Woodward's Cellar again, and watered my Horses, intending to go Home, and Gloide gave me my great Coat, which I had lent him to drive in. In a few Minutes this Woman came with this Watchman to the Cellar, and she said she had been robbed by 2 Women. The Watchman asked her whether I belonged to the Coach, and she said I was one of them, and she would swear to my Coat.</p>
               <p>Gloide. This Man sent me with his Coach, and as I was coming by the Corner of Southampton Street, the Woman called after me and desired me to give her a Cast; so I put her into the Coach and asked her to do so and so; she asked me if I was found, I told her I was not, and then she said she would have nothing to say to me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174107010006"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person66">
                  David 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person66" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person66" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between 12 and 2 o'Clock, on the 10th of March, to the best of my Knowledge, I was locked out, and waiting at Temple Bar, for my Master Withers's Work, Gloide asked me to go to Westminster with him with a Job. As we came back from Westminster, that Woman was standing at the Corner of Southampton Street. Gloide got off the Box, and said, My Dear, will you take a Ride in the Coach; she said she did not care to trust herself with a Man, but if he would not hurt her she would. They both got into the Coach, and I drove on slowly to Somerset House, and then the Coachman came up, and cut me over the Legs with his Whip, for driving his Coach. Gloide jump'd out, and Steers took the Woman out, and used his Whip a little about her. The Woman cried out Watch! but as for seeing him put his Hands near her Clothes, I did not. The Coach stood about 2 Yards beyond Somerset House; and I did not go above 10 Yards, but stood by the Watch House all the Time, and saw what passed.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be locked out?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I had been drinking with my Brother in Law, Jemmy Scott, at the Night House, by Temple-Bar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person67">
                  Joshua 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person67" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person67" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Housekeeper in Lewkener's Lane. This Woman (Strickland) told me that the two Women took her Cloak, Hat, and Cap; that the Men had used her ill, but she was in Liquor, and could swear to but one of them that had robbed her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person68">
                  Mary 
                  Buckham 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person68" type="surname" value="Buckham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person68" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sell Smallcoal-Dust in Lewkener's Lane. I heard the Prosecutrix say at her own Lodgings, that the 2 Women robbed her of her Landlady'd velvet Hood and Cloak, and that Gloide did not hurt her, but Steers horse-whipped her. Gloide was taken at my House, and I desired the Man to let him go loose, and he did so.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go to Strickland's Lodgings?</p>
               <p>Buckham. About a Fortnight ago; Mr. Murphey was with me, and she said Steers horse-whipped her, the Women punched her, and she lost 6 s. 6 d. but Gloide did not hurt her, for she asked him a Question, and he told her the Truth, and she would not hurt him. Gloide's general Character is, that he is a Fool, and foolish 
               <persName id="t17410701-4-person69">
                  Tom 
                  Gloide 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person69" type="surname" value="Gloide"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person69" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is a common Word in our Neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person70">
                  Margaret 
                  Leneve 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person70" type="surname" value="Leneve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person70" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Dolphin in Dark-house Lane. Last Tuesday Morning, the Prosecutrix was at our House, and said she had been robbed in a Hackney Coach, but wished she might be damned if she knew the Men, till one of them was shewn to her in a Night-Cellar. She said the Man had a Scar under his Eye, and she would swear to that. She said the other was very rude with her, and I said, it may be he robbed you; she said he did not, and she would not hurt him, but swore she would hang Steers for he horse-whipped her as she came out of the Coach.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person71">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person71" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person71" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Leneve's last Tuesday Morning to get some Refreshment, and saw this Woman (Strickland) a Man, and Mrs. Leneve in Discourse together. Mrs. Leneve asked her who robbed her; she said she could not tell whether it was a Coachman or Tradesman, till he was shewn to her by a Man in the Night-Cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person72">
                  Thomas 
                  Marsham 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person72" type="surname" value="Marsham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person72" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Gravesend Waterman, and seeing this Woman and a Man go into the Dolphin in Darkhouse Lane, I plyed them, but they were not going by Water, so they asked me to go in and drink with them. I did so, and heard her say, some Men had prompted her to this, or else she had not done it, and if she could save one of the Prisoners she would, but would hang the other. She was asked who the Persons were that robbed her; and she said she did not know whether he was a Tradesman or a Coachman, and she could not swear to him till a Man shewed him to her in the Night-Cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person73">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Seymour 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person73" type="surname" value="Seymour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person73" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Father keeps an Ale-Cellar in the Strand: His Name is 
               <persName id="t17410701-4-person74">
                  William 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person74" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person74" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner Steers came to our Cellar about 2 o'Clock in the Morning, - I can't tell the Day: He staid some Time, and then went away; and in a quarter of an Hour or less, returned with the other Man, Gloide. They had not been there long before Strickland and the Watchman came down, and when somebody shewed her Steers, she said, this is the Man who whipped me out of the Coach. I was then in a back Room, and the Watchman said he would take the Number of the Coach, and they went away together without mentioning a Word of a Robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person75">
                  Stephen 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person75" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person75" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Coach and Horses in Charles-Street, Covent-Garden; and as to the Character of the Prosecutrix, she is a common Street-Walker. Steers always bore an honest Character, and I never knew him rob any Body in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person76">
                  Samuel 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person76" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person76" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Strickland 3 or 4 Months; she lives at one Whitehead's in King's Court, Russel Street, and is a common Street Walker. I have known Steers between 12 and 13 Years, and never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person77">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person77" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person77" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Steers about 18 Years, and never heard him accused of any Thing. He is as honest as myself, and I never robbed any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person78">
                  Samuel 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person78" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person78" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Steers a dozen or 14 Years; and he bears an exceeding good Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person79">
                  Thomas 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person79" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person79" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since I can remember, and his general Character is very good as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174107010007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person80">
                  Mary 
                  Stone 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person80" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person80" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Gloide ever since he was born, and he never wrong'd Man, Woman, or Child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410701-4-person81">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Emmery 
               <interp inst="t17410701-4-person81" type="surname" value="Emmery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person81" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Gloide ever since he sucked at his Mother's Breast, and never heard that he robbed or assionted any Body.</p>
               <p>Gloide <rs id="t17410701-4-verdict19" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-verdict19" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, Steers <rs id="t17410701-4-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17410701-4-punish21" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410701-4-punish21" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410701-4-defend55 t17410701-4-punish21"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
