<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460702-27">
               <interp inst="t17460702-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-27" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460702-27" type="date" value="17460702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460702-27-off116-c458" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460702-27-defend515 t17460702-27-off116 t17460702-27-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>274. 
               <persName id="t17460702-27-defend515" type="defendantName">
                  Johannah 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-defend515" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-defend515" type="given" value="Johannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-defend515" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460702-27-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               coining 30 Pieces call'd stallings, and one Piece call'd a Half Cown, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Council. I am Council in this Cause for the Crown; the Prisoner at the Bar stands indicted of High Treason, for counterfeiting the current Coin of these Realms; it is unnecessary for me to tell you, Gentleman, that it becomes the Prerogative of the Crown to take Care of the Coin of the Kingdom; it will be needless to mention to you the Inconveniency and Injury that must accrue by these counterfeit Pieces, as Shillings and Half Crowns, which generally fall hard among the poorer Sort of People: The single Question will be, whether the Prisoner at the Bar has been guilty of the present Offence or not; and, Gentleman, as she stands indicted for actual coining, I shall candidly admit we have no Evidence present at the Time of Coining; I don't apprehend it is necessary; because Persons going to commit an Offence of so high a Nature, will hardly call Witnesses at the Time when they commit the Offence; I shall only relate the Circumstances, Gentleman, and when I have open'd the Nature of our Evidence there will appear Reason to believe that the Prisoner at the Bar has been guilty of the Offence for which she is indicted: The cause of our Suspicion was upon this Occasion; she went to a Person that sold Straw and Leghorn Hats, I think the Agreement was for 18d. after that Agreement had been made she gave Half a Crown for the Payment of this Hat; that Half Crown was a counterfeit one; on finding this out she was immediately carried before a Magistrate, I believe our present Lord Mayor, and for that was committed; that giving Occasion a little to enquire into her Life and Conversation; she has acknowledg'd, as I am told, and I have to prove, that she has been guilty of these Sorts of Offences for 25 Years past; but that is not the Case for which she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174607020039"></xptr> is indicted, but for actual coining, Gentlemen; as for that Half Crown which she has utter'd she may possibly be to answer for on another Occasion, tho' that may be a material Circumstance to convict her of the Offence she is now charg'd with. The Solicitor for the Crown, who is concern'd for the Mint, and whose Duty it is to bring all Persons who have committed Offences of this Kind to Justice, being inform'd that if he went to the Prisoner's Lodgings he would not only find a great Quantity of counterfeit Money, but the Tools by which the said Money was counterfeited, and was likewise directed to turn up a board at the Foot of her Bed, where the said Tools were conceal'd; accordingly he went to the Place as directed in the Information that had been given him, and taking up the Board found there a good Number, above thirty Shillings actually coin'd and counterfeited , and this Half Crown; the Reason I mention the Half Crown is, that it exactly tallied and was certainly struck in the same Mold with that which was put off by the Prisoner at the Bar, therefore that will be some Circumstance to induce you to believe that the Prisoner at the Bar was the Person that coin'd them. We will call our Witnesses to shew that this Woman was first committed for vending this Half Crown; and her Confession shews that she has long been concern'd in Practices of this Nature.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person516">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person516" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person516" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Hudson) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar? Did she lodge at your House?</p>
               <p>Hudson. Yes, at my House the next Door to Gray-Inn-Lane Workhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Room did she lodge there?</p>
               <p>Hudson. In two Rooms up one Pair of Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she lodge at your House? Did she lodge there before the 1st of May?</p>
               <p>Hudson. She came the 6th of March.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she lodge there the 1st, 2d, 3d or 4th of May?</p>
               <p>Hudson. She was not there; I think she lay out the last Day of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the Lodgings her's after that?</p>
               <p>Hudson. I can't tell how it was between her and the other Woman; they took them together as I took it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Time that this Woman was taken up for uttering a bad Half Crown?</p>
               <p>Hudson. I never knew it 'till Mr. North came to our House the 6th of May.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mr. North come there upon?</p>
               <p>Hudson. Mr. North and another Gentleman and the Constable came there the 6th of May.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lodg'd there?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person517">
                  Hudson 
                  About 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person517" type="surname" value="About"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person517" type="given" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             seven Weeks; and the back Room was the Room where she lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other Woman continue to be three after the 1st of May?</p>
               <p>Hudson. Sir, she was acquitted by my Lord Mayor, she lodg'd there one Night and no more.</p>
               <p>Q. What Night was that?</p>
               <p>Hudson. The Day that she was acquitted by my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was the Night the Prisoner at the Bar left your Lodgings, and did not come home?</p>
               <p>Hudson. Neither of them came home that Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. North come to your House?</p>
               <p>Hudson. Yes, my Lord; I saw several Things; there were some Pieces of bad Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what else?</p>
               <p>Hudson. There were two large white Papers.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in them?</p>
               <p>Hudson. I cannot say, there were some Materials took out, Instruments of Coining.</p>
               <p>Q. What?</p>
               <p>Hudson. I can't tell. There were other Instruments taken out that Mr. North saw; there were Shillings and a Half Crown which the Gentlemen let me see .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person518">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person518" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person518" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Have you any Thing to say to this Witness?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Woman took the Room; I had no Concern in taking it.</p>
               <p>- North. My Lord, as to the Prisoner at the Bar, I have known her some Years, and she has been under frequent Prosecutions for uttering of counterfeit Money.</p>
               <p>Court. Pray Mr. North keep to Fact.</p>
               <p>North. I will. On the 5th or 6th Day of May I receiv'd a Letter by the Penny-Post without any Name, that inform'd me that if I went to Mrs. Wood's Lodgings, at Mr. 
               <persName id="t17460702-27-person519">
                  Hudson 
                  House 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person519" type="surname" value="House"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person519" type="given" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and took up a Board at the Feet of her Bed, I should there find several of her Materials; accordingly I took a Person along with me, who is now in Court, to be an Assistant, and we went to the Lodgings and took up the Board mention'd in the Letter; he said here are the Things: I saw him take out of the Place this Pair of Flasks, in which the Earth is contain'd, and these two Pieces of Metal .</p>
               <p>Q. What Metal do you call it?</p>
               <p>North. Grain Tin, the better Sort: These Shillings were wrapt up in a separate Paper, in the Condition they are now, which we take to be finish'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of these Shillings?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174607020040"></xptr>North. I believe about 35 or 36. Among the rest of the Things, were these other counterfeit Shillings, quite finish'd, and this Half Crown, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person520">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person520" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person520" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-27-person521">
                  Philip 
                  Shearer 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person521" type="surname" value="Shearer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person521" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Are you the Constable?</p>
               <p>Shearer, Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to search the Lodgings of Mrs. Wood? What did you find there?</p>
               <p>Shearer. At the Foot of the Bed, there was a Board about 18 Inches long and nine broad, it was cut so artfully that the Nails came up with the Board; I said, Here's the Nest. I took out, I think, thirty-six Shillings, a Half-Crown, and a Mould, that Mr. North said they cast their Money in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person522">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person522" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person522" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. North) Is this the same?</p>
               <p>North. Yes, I have had it in my Custody ever since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person523">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person523" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person523" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460702-27-person524">
                  Diana 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person524" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person524" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person524" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>White. I know her to be the Woman that gave me the bad Half-Crown. She came into my House in Newgate-Street, to buy a Hat, about six Weeks ago, and paid me with the bad Half-Crown: With that I took hold of her, and said, You are a Coiner; then I saw her begin to convey something to another. I said, I'll search you.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the Half-Crown?</p>
               <p>White. The Constable has it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person525">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person525" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person525" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. Welsh) Had you the Counterfeit Half-Crown deliver'd to you by that Woman?</p>
               <p>Welsh . Yes, my Lord, and a Shilling likewise.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460702-27-person526">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460702-27-person526" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-person526" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. North) Is that a Counterfeit Half-Crown?</p>
               <p>Q. Yes, and exactly the same Die, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460702-27-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460702-27-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               This Evidence could not convict the Prisoner of High Treason; but she is order'd to remain, to be try'd for uttering of false and counterfeit Coin, which is a Misdemeanor .
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
