<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450911-14">
               <interp inst="t17450911-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-14" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-14" type="date" value="17450911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-14-off69-c96" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-14-defend121 t17450911-14-off69 t17450911-14-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>314. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-defend121" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Moore 
                  <interp inst="t17450911-14-defend121" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-defend121" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-defend121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17450911-14-defloc68">Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-14-defloc68" type="placeName" value="Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-14-defloc68" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-14-defend121 t17450911-14-defloc68"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450911-14-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting, Sarah, the wife of 
                     <persName id="t17450911-14-person122">
                        John 
                        Price 
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person122" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-14-person122" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-14-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the King's highway, putting her in fear and danger of her life, and taking from her one gold ring, val. 10 s. and 2 s. 8 d. in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450911-14-cd70" type="crimeDate">July 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-14-off69 t17450911-14-cd70"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person123">
                  Mary 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person123" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person123" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of July last coming by Bayswater, near Kensington in a chaise with Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17450911-14-person124">
                  Sarah 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person124" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person124" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about six or seven o'clock in the evening (it rained prodigious hard.) A person came up to the chaise with a crape over his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Prisoner the person?</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-victim126" type="victimName">
                     Sarah 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17450911-14-victim126" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-victim126" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-victim126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-14-off69 t17450911-14-victim126"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you see his face if he had a crape over it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110008"></xptr>Price. He pulled his crape aside, as I suppose, to see who came each way. Then he demanded our money, and the gentlewoman who was with me, said, we have none. He damned us, and bid us give him what we had got. I said, I had 2 s. 8 d. and I gave it to him. Then he demanded Mrs. Taylor's money, she gave it to me, and I gave it to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was there?</p>
               <p>Price. There was 7 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take any thing else from you?</p>
               <p>Price. He took two gold rings, and rode off as hard as he could; we drove after him as hard as we could drive, till we saw two gentlemen; I then stood upright in the chaise, and cried out, a highwayman, a highwayman, he has robbed me, and they rode after him and took him.</p>
               <p>Q. In how long time did they take him?</p>
               <p>Price. I believe it could not be a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he never out of your sight?</p>
               <p>Price. He was never out of my sight. I saw them pull him off his horse, then we stopped, and they brought the Prisoner up to us, and asked us if we knew him: I said, yes, he was the person that robbed us, and he owned the fact.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Price. He was asked whether he was the person that robbed us, and he said, yes, he was, but he hoped we would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would ask the lady whether she knows me to be the man?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes; I saw your face, the crape was aside. This is the crape he had over his face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person127">
                  Sarah 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person127" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person127" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is the man that robbed us, and he was brought back to us, and the gentlemen that took him asked him whether he was the man that robbed us, and he said, yes, he was the man, and hoped that we would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Taylor being asked whether every part of Mrs. Price's evidence was true, she said it was, so she was informed it was needless to relate the account of the robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person128">
                  Ralph 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person128" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person128" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday the 19th of July, myself in company with 
               <persName id="t17450911-14-person129">
                  Henry 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person129" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person129" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were going to our respective homes. When we came to Tyburn turnpike, there was a cry of highwayman, (it rained violently hard) and the first person I saw was the Prisoner 
               <persName id="t17450911-14-person130">
                  John 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person130" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person130" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on a black horse. I got into the same track, and rode after him, and did design to ride over him, but he turned out of the way, (I suppose he was surprised to hear somebody so near him) and my horse rode before him: I could not immediately stop my horse; so soon as I would I turned my horse, and rode after him again, and he turned his horse against Mr. Stevenson's. I caught hold of his right hand, and we both came down together. Upon this Mr. Stevenson and I secured him; he asked what we wanted with him; I said there was a hue and cry after him, and if he had done any thing amiss he must answer for it, and he should. He struggled a little, and desired us to let him go; I told him I could not; he said, then I am a dead man. I said, how do you know that? He said it was the first robbery that ever he committed. I said it was too soon now, so Mr. Stevenson and I led him, he went between us, I laid hold of his left arm, and Mr. Stevenson of his right. In leading him along the road, he begged for mercy, and said he had robbed two women of a small trifle; I think he said of about 18 d. or 2 s. and some half-pence, and two gold rings, and desired us to let him go. We carried him up to them, and Mrs. Taylor said, I thank you, Sir, that is the man that robbed us. We went to the White-hart, and had a pot of beer, and desired the women to let me know where I might call upon them. The Prisoner had a pistol in his pocket loaded with shot. I think he had about three shillings in silver and some brass. I asked where the rings were, he said he had put them into his pocket. I desired him to sit down, and told him if he would not sit down, I would tie him. So I searched his breeches for the rings, but could not find them. He said there were holes in his pockets, and they might get into the lining, so I unbuttoned the knees of his breeches and they dropped out.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17450911-14-person131">
                  Henry 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person131" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person131" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you heard the evidence that has been given by Mr. Marsh?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it true?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a pistol?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. Yes; it was in his right hand pocket, and I took it out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I am a poor unfortunate unhappy fellow, it was the first fact that ever I committed. I never did any such thing in my life before, I never was a person that was extravagant in my life; nor I never did any wrong to any person in my life. My wife and family were ill and in distress, and I was drove to necessity, and that brought me to this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person132">
                  Walter 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person132" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person132" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is a fan maker, he is a very honest man, and has paid me pounds for work that I have done for him. He followed the trade till it grew so bad, that he could not live by it, and then he took to other business.</p>
               <p>Q. What other business did he take to?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110009"></xptr>Collins. He kept a vine vault. I have done work for him within these two years, in putting up a sign in Bridges street; he left that house and took another house in the Strand, but I did not do any thing for him there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person133">
                  Sarah 
                  Bigs 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person133" type="surname" value="Bigs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person133" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about five years, he lodged with me about a year and a quarter: he was a journey-man then, in the business of fanstick making.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>Bigs. It is about three years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person134">
                  Henry 
                  Deshorough 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person134" type="surname" value="Deshorough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person134" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about thirteen years, and have been pretty conversant with him till within these twelve months, and he had the character of a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person135">
                  Thomas 
                  Deshorough 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person135" type="surname" value="Deshorough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person135" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have had dealings with him, and he was always accounted a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person136">
                  Thomas 
                  Gurney 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person136" type="surname" value="Gurney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person136" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a perriwig maker. I have known him 14 or 15 years, and among our acquaintance he was reckoned one of the honestest men that we knew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person137">
                  Joseph 
                  Streng 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person137" type="surname" value="Streng"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person137" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 7 years, and he always bore a good character, and the character of an honest man for whatever I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-14-person138">
                  Thomas 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-14-person138" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person138" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor. I have worked for him fifteen years. - I have not worked for him for four or five years last past. He always bore a good character, and I never heard a person speak ill of him in my life. <rs id="t17450911-14-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-14-verdict71" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, <rs id="t17450911-14-punish72" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17450911-14-punish72" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-14-defend121 t17450911-14-punish72"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>.
The Jury begged the favour of the court to recommend him to his Majesty's mercy, on account of his being of a good family, and as they all believed it was the first fact that ever he committed
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
