<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-6">
               <interp inst="t17400709-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-6" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-6" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-6-off35-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-6-defend83 t17400709-6-off35 t17400709-6-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>291. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-6-defend83" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Milroy 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-6-defend83" type="surname" value="Milroy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-defend83" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-defend83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400709-6-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 30 lb. of Tobacco, val.10s.
            </rs> the Goods of a Person unknown, <rs id="t17400709-6-cd36" type="crimeDate">June 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-6-off35 t17400709-6-cd36"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-6-person84">
                  Thomas 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17400709-6-person84" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-person84" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am a Watchman belonging to Aldgate: as I was on Duty the 25th of June, between 11 and 12 at Night, I saw the Prisoner coming along with a Parcel on his Back, and I asked him what he had got there? He refused to tell me; upon which I insisted upon knowing. Then said he, I will go back to the Place, and tell you where I had it. I went a little Way with him, and he threw down the Bundle, and ran away. He got a little Way from me, but we took him in a few Minutes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him where he detected me first?</p>
               <p>Watson. I stopped him in Poor Jewry Lane, near Aldgate, at the Backside of the Three Tunn Tavern. He ran to Towerhill before he was taken; I am positive the Prisoner is the Man.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I happened to be going home to my Lodging, when the Watchman first detected the Prisoner, and asked him what he had got upon his Head. He desired him to go to the Watch-house, and shew him what it was. The Prisoner told him, he would go and shew him<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090013"></xptr> the Place from whence he had it, and it being in my way home, I went with them. But when he had got 10 or 12 Yards from the Place where he was first stopped, he threw down the Goods and ran away; and the Watchman followed him crying stop Thief. He was first stopped in Poor Jewry Lane, near Aldgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was come from on Board o'Ship at Deptford, and was going home to my Lodging in Wheatsheaf Alley; and as I was going over Tower-hill in my Way home, a Man stopped me, and they said I was the Person. I asked them what I had done, but they took me to the Watch-house, and said I was the same Man, because I had white Cloaths on, trimmed with the same.</p>
               <p>- Weaver. I am a Watchman belonging to Aldgate, and was at my Stand, when the Prisoner escaped from Watson. He cried stop Thief; I followed, and the Prisoner ran thro' Savage Gardens , where I lost Sight of him for 4 or 5 Minutes, by his turning the Corner, but I recovered Sight of him again, in that Time, and never lost it again till he was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How far was you from me when I was taken?</p>
               <p>- Weaver. About 7 or 8 Yards.</p>
               <p>Another Witness. As the former Witnesses were crying stop Thief, I stopped the Prisoner about the middle of Towerhill . He was coming round towards George-Yard , and I caught him by the Arm.- He was upon a full run.</p>

               <p>A Witness. I have know the Prisoner 3 or 4 Years; I never knew him wrong any body of a Farthing in my Life. He was a Gentleman's <rs id="t17400709-6-deflabel37" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-6-defend83 t17400709-6-deflabel37"></join>, and belonged to a Wine Cellar.</p>
               <p>A Woman. He is my Husband; I have nothing to say against him, to be sure.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known him 6 Years; and never knew him guilty of a Fault in my Life.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17400709-6-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-6-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
