<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17481207-15">
               <interp inst="t17481207-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481207-15" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481207-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17481207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481207-15" type="date" value="17481207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481207-15-off62-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481207-15-defend113 t17481207-15-off62 t17481207-15-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174812070006"></xptr>15. 
               
                  <persName id="t17481207-15-defend113" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Upman 
                  <interp inst="t17481207-15-defend113" type="surname" value="Upman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-defend113" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-defend113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17481207-15-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 14 china plates, value 15 s. two pewter plates, val. 2 s. one pair of brass candlesticks, val. 2 s. one pair of thread stockings, one china mug, two napkins, one table cloth
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17481207-15-victim114" type="victimName">
                  Perkinton 
                  Tomkins 
               <interp inst="t17481207-15-victim114" type="surname" value="Tomkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-victim114" type="given" value="Perkinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-victim114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481207-15-off62 t17481207-15-victim114"></join>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Perkinton Tomkins. I <rs id="t17481207-15-viclabel63" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17481207-15-crimeloc64">Shakespear's head in Covent Garden</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-crimeloc64" type="placeName" value="Shakespear's head in Covent Garden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-crimeloc64" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481207-15-off62 t17481207-15-crimeloc64"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481207-15-victim114 t17481207-15-viclabel63"></join>, the prisoner had lived <rs id="t17481207-15-deflabel65" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481207-15-defend113 t17481207-15-deflabel65"></join> with me about a month on the 12th of October, and in that interim I lost several things out of my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What things did you lose?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. Three china plates, two pewter plates, and other things.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found any of those things?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. Yes, my Lord, I found them at a private house in the Strand on this 
               <persName id="t17481207-15-person115">
                  Mary 
                  Upman 
               <interp inst="t17481207-15-person115" type="surname" value="Upman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person115" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17481207-15-person116">
                  Ann 
                  Bowers 
               <interp inst="t17481207-15-person116" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person116" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to find them there?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. By instructions I went up stairs, and found them together, and Bowers immediately told me my things were in a chest of drawers in the next room: upon that I got a search warrant and took them before Justice Green, who committed Upman to the gatehouse, and Bowers to the round-house. Bowers confessed there were 14 china plates this Upman had taken from me, at a house in St. Giles's. I went and found them at Thomas Morris's lodging, with one pair of brass candlesticks, one pair of thread stockings, one china mug, two napkins, one table cloth, some jelly glasses, all my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481207-15-person117">
                  Ann 
                  Bowers 
               <interp inst="t17481207-15-person117" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person117" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner being a servant, desired me to wash some things for her. She, in the things, tied up three pewter plates, two china ones, and a broken one, a candle and a bit of soap. She desired me to take them home, and put them up in a drawer, telling me she had only those dozen and half of plates against she married. One of the boys saw her give them to me, and told his master, and the gentleman came directly.</p>
               <p>Q. You was before the Justice; what did you discover to him ?</p>
               <p>Bowers. I told the Justice I had not seen her box for seven weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. to Tompkins. Did this woman make any confession before Justice Green of those plates?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. Yes, my Lord, and said Upman told her she need not be afraid of carrying those few plates, for there were more of the same sort at Morris's.</p>
               <p>Bowers. I told him of nothing but the dozen and half of plates. She told me they were in Brown's gardens, St. Giles's, in her box. I knew she lodged there when she was out of place.</p>
               <p>Morris. This woman did lodge at my house about three weeks before she came to Mr. Tompkins's house to live.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever come afterwards?</p>
               <p>Morris. Yes, my Lord, I know very little of her. Her box was brought when I was out at work. She having knowledge of my daughter, desired it might be lodged at my house till she got a place, I know nothing of what was in it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481207-15-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481207-15-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
