<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17491011-38">
               <interp inst="t17491011-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491011-38" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491011-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17491011"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491011-38" type="date" value="17491011"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491011-38-off170-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491011-38-defend242 t17491011-38-off170 t17491011-38-verdict172"></join>
         
               <p>646. 
               
                  <persName id="t17491011-38-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17491011-38-defend242" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-defend242" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <placeName id="t17491011-38-defloc169">late of St. Andrew, Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17491011-38-defloc169" type="placeName" value="late of St. Andrew, Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17491011-38-defloc169" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491011-38-defend242 t17491011-38-defloc169"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17491011-38-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving part of the goods for which the prisoner 
                     <persName id="t17491011-38-person243">
                        Mary 
                        Godard 
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person243" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491011-38-person243" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491011-38-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , alias Blare, was tried for knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17491011-38-cd171" type="crimeDate">July the 14th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491011-38-off170 t17491011-38-cd171"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Hains produc'd a copy of the record of Sup trial.</p>
               <p>Aug. the 3d.</p>
               <p>Mr Adams Wright depos'd as in the trial of 
               <persName id="t17491011-38-person244">
                  John 
                  Godard 
               <interp inst="t17491011-38-person244" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and also Mr. Hughes, which last witness proceeded as follows : I had reason to suspect the prisoner at the bar had bought some of the goods, if not all, by a person who had seen the ear-rings in his custody, and had broke up three such rings as I lost, in the prisoner's house, by his direction; upon this, I had a search-warrant, and went to execute it: I took the constable and jewels along with me the 28th of September to the prisoner's house, who lives in Holborn near the end of Leather lane; I went into the prisoner's house to the place I was directed without taking any notice of the prisoner, and order'd the prisoner from his door to come to me. (This was a little room joining to the shop backwards) I desir'd the prisoner to open such a buroe, telling him I had a search warrant, &amp;c. he open'd it, and I found there two drops of ear-rings in a pen-case, which I believe to be mine; I deliver'd these things to the constable, and desir'd a person present to fetch my wife; she came, and I desir'd to know if she could recollect these things; she made answer, that one drop may be like another, and said she could not swear to them; then she said, if they are mine, the middle one has been lately mended in a remarkable clumsey manner; the constable having them in his hand, he look'd at them, and said, madam, I believe this is it; at her seeing it, she made oath that it was her's; upon that I desir'd the constable to take charge of the prisoner; we took him to Justice Fielding's, and he was committed; the prisoner told me before he went there, that he had bought every thing, and I should have them all again if I would make things easy, if they were above ground. I told him I should do nothing but what the law would permit; he said he bought them of Moll Blare; two days afterwards he sent<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174910110011"></xptr> for me to New-prison, and acknowledged he bought my gold watch, three diamond rings, two ear-rings, and Mr. Wright's silver watch, all together for 24 l. The prisoner was my neighbour, and had ask'd me several times if I had heard of my things, and had commiserated my misfortune, (from whence I conclude by the things being advertised before he knew the things were mine ) he made a calculation of what he sold them for, and said he got about three or four pounds by them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491011-38-person245">
                  Sarah 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17491011-38-person245" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person245" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The stone drops which were found in the prisoner's house, I know to be mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491011-38-person246">
                  Moses 
                  Bargae 
               <interp inst="t17491011-38-person246" type="surname" value="Bargae"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person246" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a jeweller, I live in Summer-street at the bottom of Leather-lane, the prisoner sent for me in a hurry some time in July last, and to bring him a wax box, which I did to stick loose diamonds in; he desir'd me to call again another time, and I should see what diamonds he had to dispose of; he shew'd me some heads of rings, that is the stones in the collets without the rings; one or two of them were loose out of the collets; he desir'd me to break them up, which I did, and weighed them separately, the roses in one part, and brilliant in another; I set down how much money they weighed; it amounted to 8 l. 16 s. 6 d. I bought them and my partner paid the money: when I call'd again, he said he should have a pair of ear-rings, by which I might get three or four pounds profit; this was, I think, about the 15th or 16th of July; I kept the diamonds three or four days and sold them for 5 s. profit; he call'd about a fortnight or three weeks after this, and said it I would call such a day I should see the ear-rings, but I was not to bring my partner along with me; said I, I can do no business without him; but he insisted upon my coming without him, &amp;c. I went and saw the ear-rings in a little back room in his house where I broke up the rings; he said he would have 12 l. for them; I said, I would give him 6 l. 15 s. about a day or two after he said, if I would break them up I should have them; I said they were too good to be broke up; afterwards he gave me a caution not to tell one Robins that I had seen the ear-rings at his house: about a fortnight after this Mr. Robins came to me and shew'd one pair of ear-rings; said I, you bought these of Johnson; but afterwards I found he did not: but after Mr. Robins heard of this robbery, he came to me to know if I could describe these ear-rings I had seen at the prisoner's; he told me a worthy gentleman had been robbed, and carried me to Mr. Hughes's shop; I described the ear-rings by drawing them with my pencil, to Mrs. Hughes; she said, upon the account of the value they could not be hers; she particularly described the three rings that were broke up; then said I, these ear-rings must be yours.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Hughes. What do you value the earrings at?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hughes. About 18 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491011-38-person247">
                  James 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17491011-38-person247" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person247" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the constable deposed the same with Mr. Hughes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I bought those things for 26 l. 2 s. and sold them for about 3 l. 10 s. or 3 l. 15 s. profit. Mr. Hughes shall have the gold watch again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17491011-38-verdict172" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491011-38-verdict172" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
