<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420224-42">
               <interp inst="t17420224-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-42" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-42" type="date" value="17420224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420224-42-off181-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-42-defend280 t17420224-42-off181 t17420224-42-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>39. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-defend280" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Handley 
                  <interp inst="t17420224-42-defend280" type="surname" value="Handley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-defend280" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-defend280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420224-42-defloc180">St. Giles in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-42-defloc180" type="placeName" value="St. Giles in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-42-defloc180" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-42-defend280 t17420224-42-defloc180"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17420224-42-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               on the <rs id="t17420224-42-cd182" type="crimeDate">3 d of June, in the 14th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-42-off181 t17420224-42-cd182"></join>, and long before, one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420224-42-victim282" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Macdurmot 
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-victim282" type="surname" value="Macdurmot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-victim282" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-victim282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-42-off181 t17420224-42-victim282"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   was an Inhabitant in St. Giles's in the Fields, and then near a certain Place called Lincoln's Inn Fields, did keep a Coffee-House, known by the Name of Adlam's Coffee-House; and that the said Macdurmot was, and yet is, as well known by the Name of James Durmot as 
                     <persName id="t17420224-42-person283">
                        James 
                        Macdurmot 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person283" type="surname" value="Macdurmot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person283" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; and that he the said Handley well knowing the Premises, but not regarding the Laws, &amp;c. afterwards, on the 3 d of June, did cause and procure a certain Person unknown, personally to appear before Sir 
                     <persName id="t17420224-42-person284">
                        Thomas 
                        Abney 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person284" type="surname" value="Abney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person284" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , then and now one of the Barons of his Majesty's Court of Exchequer, in the Name and Description of 
                     <persName id="t17420224-42-person285">
                        James 
                        Durmot 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person285" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person285" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , of Adlam's Coffee-House, to acknowledge himself indebted to our Lord the King, in the Sum of 186 l. on Condition that if the said Handley should appear to satisfy all that should be required of him on an Information exhibited against him by Sir 
                     <persName id="t17420224-42-person286">
                        Dudley 
                        Rider 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person286" type="surname" value="Rider"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person286" type="given" value="Dudley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , &amp;c. or in Default thereof, if the said Handley should surrender himself, then this Obligation to be void, or else remain in full Force, &amp;c. the said 
                     <persName id="t17420224-42-person287">
                        James 
                        Macdurmot 
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person287" type="surname" value="Macdurmot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person287" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-42-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not being privy thereto, to the great Damage of the said James, and against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>+ This Offence was made Felony by a Statute in the 21st Year of James 1.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the King having open'd the Indictment, and the Nature of the Offence, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person288">
                  Charles 
                  Ayres 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person288" type="surname" value="Ayres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person288" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the Attornies of the Exchequer Office in the Temple; this in my Hand is an Information in the Name of his Majesty's Attorney; I had it from the King's Remembrance Office.</p>
               <p>The Information was read, and was in Substance as follows, viz.</p>
               <p>Dated Easter-Term, 14th of his present Majesty; Be it remember'd that Sir 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person289">
                  Dudley 
                  Ryder 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person289" type="surname" value="Ryder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person289" type="given" value="Dudley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , &amp;c. in his own proper Person presents, that certain Merchants unknown, did between the first of May 1738, and the Day of exhibiting this Information, import to Ratcliff within the Port of London, in a certain Ship by Way of Merchandise, 346 lbs. of Tea, 4 lbs. and half of Coffee, 51 Yards of Handkerchiefs, the whole amounting to the Value of 186 l. 1 s. the said Goods being liable to the Payment of Custom; and that the said Merchants did unship and land the said Goods before the Customs and other Duties were paid, &amp;c. and that the said Goods afterwards came into the Possession of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person290">
                  Thomas 
                  Handley 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person290" type="surname" value="Handley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person290" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he well knowing every Part of them to be imported, the Customs not being paid, against the Form of the Statute, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Counc. What is that other Parchment in your Hand?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. This is the Bail Piece; it was taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person291">
                  Thomas 
                  Abney 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person291" type="surname" value="Abney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person291" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who sign'd it twice in my Presence; first to the taking it, and then to the Justification. One 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person292">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person292" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person292" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and one Mr. Dowling, both swore in my Presence that they were worth-186 l. and that they were Housekeepers.</p>
               <p>[The Recognizance was read.]</p>
               <p>Counc. Was there any Notice given to you before this Recognizance was enter'd into, of Bail to be put in by the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. Yes, I was employ'd by Mr. Norton for the Prisoner, and I have the Notice in my Hand. Mr. Norton gave me the Notice, and I prepar'd a Bail-Piece accordingly. It was in order to put in Bail for the Prisoner, on an Information exhibited against him by Mr. Attorney General, for treble the Value of a Parcel of run Goods, upon the Statute of the 8th of the Queen.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you give Notice to the Sollicitor of the Customs?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. No, the Solicitor for the Defendant generally gives it. I can't take the Bail except it is approv'd of, and here the Notice is endorsed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240017"></xptr>It was read.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Metcalfe, Sollicitor of the Customs.</p>
               <p>Attorney General against 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person293">
                  Thomas 
                  Handley 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person293" type="surname" value="Handley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person293" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             by Information; Bail for 186 l. Sir, Bail proposed for the Defendant in the above named Cause, are 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person294">
                  Robert 
                  Dowling 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person294" type="surname" value="Dowling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person294" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Gray's Inn, Gent. and 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person295">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person295" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person295" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Adlam's Coffee-House Lincoln's-Inn-Fields, near the Duke of Newcastle's House. May 27, 1741.</p>
               <p>Your Humble Servant,</p>
               <p>Hen. Norton.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. It is indorsed - Mr. Metcalfe does not object to the Persons within mention'd, provided they justifie before a Baron, J. Tyton, for Mr. Metcalse.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who is Mr. Tyton ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. He is Clerk to Mr. Metcalse: I have seen him write ten thousand Times, and I take that to be his Hand.</p>
               <p>Pris. Ask Mr. Ayres whether I was in the Baron's Chambers?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. He went before me to the Baron's Chambers, and asked me whether it was necessary for him to go up? I told him he might do as he pleased, and I think he staid below Stairs.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. When this Matter was first mov'd in the Court of Exchequer, did not I attend without an Order?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres. I believe he did; - I really can't say, but I believe there was an Order made for him to attend, and upon his Attendance the Court order'd him into Custody.</p>
               <p>Heneage Norton. About the 20th of May, the Prisoner came to my House in Friday-street, and told me he had been arrested for running Goods, and that he wanted to give Bail to an Information. He inform'd me that he was recommended to me by Mr. Russel in the Temple. I then told him he must get two honest Persons to propose to the Sollicitor of the Customs. He said he was a Stranger in Town, but he believ'd he could get Friends; and accordingly he came to me sometime afterwards, and gave me this Paper, on which are written the Names of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person296">
                  Robert 
                  Dowling 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person296" type="surname" value="Dowling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person296" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person297">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person297" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person297" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He told me it was his own Writing, and those were the Persons who would stand as his Bail. Upon that, I wrote the Note which has been read, and gave it to Mr. Metcalfe's Clerk; and Mr. Metcalfe informing me that those Persons were not sufficient, I told the Prisoner of it, and he said Dowling was a Relation of his, a Man of Fortune, and lived in Grays-Inn; and that Durmot was a Man of good Repute, and liv'd at Adlam's Coffee-House. I inform'd Mr. Metcalfe of the Prisoner's Answer, and he then said that Dowling was an ancient Man, but however if they would justifie, he would have no Objection to them. I then gave Mr. Ayres this Note that has been read, and desir'd him to get the Bail Piece ready, and likewise desir'd the Prisoner to attend me at the Exchequer-Office, or at Brown's Coffee-House hard by, any Time that suited his Conveniency, and he said he would bring the Bail with him. Accordingly he came to me as I was at the Office-Door, and told me the Bail were ready, and were waiting at a Public House in Wych-street. I desir'd him to bring them down to the Office, and soon afterwards Mr. Russel told me, that Handley and his Bail were come to a Public House just above Brown's Coffee-House in Mitre-Court, and that they desir'd I would come and read the Bail-Piece to them. When I came there, I saw two Men, who answer'd to the Names of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person298">
                  Robert 
                  Dowling 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person298" type="surname" value="Dowling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person298" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person299">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person299" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person299" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and then I read the Bail-Piece to them: the Prisoner, to the best of my Knowledge was present all the Time. I told them the Consequence of it, and that they might sign it there if they pleased; upon which they took a Pen and Ink, and I observed that the old Man (Dowling ) wrote a very good Hand. From thence I took them to the Exchequer-Office to Mr. Ayres, and I told him those were the two Persons who had sign'd the Bail-Piece, and desir'd him to go with them before the Baron.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go with them before the Baron?</p>
               <p>Mr. Norton. No, the Prisoner and the rest went together, but I staid at the Office till Mr. Ayres came back. This is the Recognizance which I read to them, and I saw the two Persons sign it in the Names of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person300">
                  Robert 
                  Dowling 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person300" type="surname" value="Dowling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person300" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person301">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person301" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person301" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Pris. Ask him if I did not bring him Money to the Exchequer-Office ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Norton. I told him in Matters of this Nature, I was oblig'd to give the Clerk in Court 40 s. and I expected some Money of him before the Bail was taken; this was before the Bail Piece was sign'd; and he was not gone five Minutes before he brought me 4 Guineas.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did not you ask whether Durmot was the Master of that Coffee-House ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240018"></xptr>Mr. Norton. I asked when I went in whether Dowling and Durmot were not there, and they both answer'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-person302">
                  George 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person302" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person302" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the Beginning of June last, the Prisoner came recommended to me, and told me he had been taken up on an Information, and came up to London to put in Bail, upon which I recommended him to Mr. Norton. He told me one Mr. Dowling would become his Bail, and likewise one Durmot of Adlam's Coffee-House; but after that, he said there was some Difficulty with the Coffee-Man, and he was afraid it would not do. Instructions were afterwards sent to me, and I wrote this Bail-Piece by Mr. Ayres's Order. I was likewise present when the two Bail subscrib'd it; - it was at a Public House called the Vine, just by Brown's Coffee-House, and I saw them sign their Names; Mr. Norton was present at the same Time; I gave him Notice that they were there. Mr. Dowling I have known many Years by Sight, and he sign'd first: the other Man I did not take much Notice of, but I saw him write - Durmot, after it had been read over to them by Mr. Norton.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was the Prisoner present ?</p>
               <p>Russel. I think he was, but I can't be positive to that. After this when we were coming out of the House together, Mr. Norton asked me in the Passage for the Fees: I told the Prisoner of it, and he ran away to get the Money, and in a few Minutes brought it to Mr. Norton.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go with them before the Baron?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, I went no farther than the End of Mitre-Court.</p>
               <p>Counc. How came you not to see Durmot's Face?</p>
               <p>Russel. I had no Curiosity, for I apprehended him to be the Man of Adlam's Coffee-House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-person303">
                  James 
                  Macdurmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person303" type="surname" value="Macdurmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person303" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have kept Adlam's Coffee-House about a Year and 3 Quarters to the best of my Knowledge. I never was Bail for any Person, nor ever sign'd any Recognizance.</p>
               <p>Counc. Look upon that Recognizance, and tell the Court whether you ever sign'd it in one Part or another?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot No, I never did: I always spell my Name - Macdurmot; but the English call me - Durmot. About the middle of May last, the Prisoner and one Conrade came to my House and called for Coffee, and other Liquors. Conrade called me into a Back Room, and told me there was a poor Man accused on Account of some run Goods, therefore desir'd me to bail him. I told him if it was my own Brother I would not; and sometime afterwards I heard that somebody had bailed the Prisoner in my Name.</p>
               <p>Counc. How came you to hear of this afterwards?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. One of my Neighbours informed me that some Persons had been to enquire my Character, and whether I was worth 186 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ayres being ask'd whether this Witness was the Person who went with him to the Baron's Chambers, answer'd in the Negative.</p>
               <p>Counc. to Mr. Norton. Was that the Person who sign'd this Bail-Piece ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Norton. I can't take upon me to say whether he was or not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Russell. I can't say whether he is the Person, - I took no manner of Notice of him.</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. I always take my Receipts in the Name of Macdurmot, but a great many People call me Durmot.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Prisoner ever ask you to be bail?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. No, not that I remember.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you never consent that Bail should be put in in your Name?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. When this Matter became public, did you never declare, that you would deny it, and that you would hang one, and transport the other?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. I never did.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did not you employ Mr. Williscot to draw a Bond of Indemnity?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot Dowling came to my House with a View of making it up, and I not knowing any Thing of the Law, went to that Gentleman's House to ask his Advice, and he would not have any Hand in the Action. I desired one Mr. Grosby to ask Mr. Tomlin if Bail was put in, and at that Time it was not; but afterwards I heard that Bail was put in, in the Names of Dowling and Durmot.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Have you not a Brother ?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. Yes, his Name is 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person304">
                  Brian 
                  Macdurmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person304" type="surname" value="Macdurmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person304" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I believe he knew as much of the Prisoner as I did.</p>
               <p>Pris Q. Was I a Stranger to you when Conrade came to your House?</p>
               <p>Macdurmot. Yes, and he did not go into the Room with us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-person305">
                  Thomas 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person305" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person305" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was ordered to enquire Macdurmot's Character. I asked for him by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person306">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person306" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person306" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I enquired of 3 or 4 People, and every one of them knew him by<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240019"></xptr> that Name. I was told by them, that the Person who kept Adlam's Coffee-House, was 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person307">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person307" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person307" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Councel. How came you to enquire after him?</p>
               <p>Dennis. I belong to Mr. Metcalfe, and had Notice given me to enquire after him, because he was proposed for Bail for 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person308">
                  Thomas 
                  Handley 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person308" type="surname" value="Handley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person308" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am acquainted with Mr. Tyton's Hand, and I take this to be his writing: When Bail is proposed, this is the usual Way of signifying their Consent.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you not enquire whether the People knew who kept the Coffee-house?</p>
               <p>Dennis. I shewed them the Note in which was written 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person309">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person309" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person309" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Adlam's Coffee-House, and they said they knew him.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Did you ask for Durmot singly, or Durmot of the Coffee-house ?</p>
               <p>Dennis. I might ask both ways. I likewise enquired Dowling's Character of a Porter at Gray's-Inn-Gate, and told him, he was propos'd for Bail, and the Porter said, he would go and ask him whether he would be Bail or no, for perhaps he might get 6 d or 1 s. by the Job.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. What answer did he bring?</p>
               <p>Dennis. I can't tell, I believe he delivered it to Mr. Tomlin.</p>

               <p>Samuel Green gave an Account of his enquiring for Durmot, and that he asked at Adlam's Coffee-house whether one Durmot lived there, and was answered by the Woman of the House that he did.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. What Reward had you for goingupon that Enquiry ?</p>
               <p>Green. None at all; I belong to Mr. Graves, who carries on this Prosecution, and have not had so much as Money with my Subpoena.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>It was urged on Behalf of the Prisoner, that he being arrested in the Country, came up to Town, and was recommended by Russel to Mr. Norton; and it being necessary to put in Bail, he propos'd his Uncle Mr. Dowling, and having some Acquaintance with Conrade, who knew Mr. Durmot, they went together to Durmot's House. That Conrade went out of the Room with Dowling, and sometime afterwards, Conrade sent him (the Prisoner) Word, that Durmot would become his Bail; and accordingly a Person came with Durmot's own Brother, and that the Bail-piece was then sign'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-person310">
                  Robert 
                  Dowling 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person310" type="surname" value="Dowling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person310" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There came a Porter to me, belonging to Gray's Inn, to desire me to bail the Prisoner. I said, I would, because I knew him, and I thought he would surrender himself in discharge of his Bail! The Porter informed me, that he was sent by Mr. Metcalfe, and if I would stand as one of his Bail, the Man at Adlam's Coffee-house would stand with me. Accordingly the Prisoner sent me a Messenger to meet at the Swan in the Butcher-Row, and while I was about some Beef-Steaks, he came in. There were several People there, and one of them they told me was Brother to Macdurmot, and there was another who took upon himself to be 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person311">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person311" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person311" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While we were there, Mr. Russel brought in the Bail-Piece, and I read it over to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that Man ( Macdurmot ) the Man that din'd with you?</p>
               <p>Dowling. No, the Man who dined with us, and who called himself James Durmot, was tall than this Man. We adjourned from the Swan to the Vine, in Mitre Court, where we sign'd the Bail-piece. I sign'd it first, and then the other Man sign'd it by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person312">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person312" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person312" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q Was the Prisoner present then?</p>
               <p>Dowling. He was in and out, but whether he was present then or not, I can't tell. I have heard that he served a Bookseller, a Brother of mine 14 or 15 Years very honestly. I never saw him till May last; when he came up to Liverpool to discharge his first Ball, and I took it very well of him that he had so great Regard for his Bail.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Prisoner go with you to the Judges Chambers?</p>
               <p>Dowling. He went with us as far as Brick-Court, but whether he went up or not I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Counc. When you were at the House in tho Butcher-Row, who told you that the other Person was 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person313">
                  James 
                  Durmot 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person313" type="surname" value="Durmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person313" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Dowling. I was told so by the Prisoner: I understood by him and the rest of the Company, that he was the Man. There were in Company one Nethany, and a Man in a red Waistcoat, and one Molloy.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know that Durmot's Brother was there any otherwise than as you heard?</p>
               <p>Dowling. No. The two Durmots came in while we were at Dinner, and I believe they were directed to us, but by whom I can't tell. After we had given Bail, we all agreed to go to Durmot's Coffee-House, to take a Glass, and I followed them thither. We sat in the Public Room, and all the Persons who were there, knew we had put in Bail. This Man ( Macdurmot )<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240020"></xptr> was not in our Company, but served us with Liquor as we called for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the Brother of Durmot any Conversation with the Master of the House?</p>
               <p>Dowling. No, none that I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-42-person314">
                  Francis 
                  Moron 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person314" type="surname" value="Moron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person314" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person315">
                  Robert 
                  Dillon 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person315" type="surname" value="Dillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person315" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17420224-42-person316">
                  Thomas 
                  Meighan 
               <interp inst="t17420224-42-person316" type="surname" value="Meighan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person316" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of an honest Man.</p>
               <p>The Jury withdrew to consider of their Verdict, and after some Time returned, and found the Prisoner, <rs id="t17420224-42-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-42-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not Guilty
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
