<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-41">
               <interp inst="t17401015-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-41" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-41" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-41-off215-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-41-defend273 t17401015-41-off215 t17401015-41-verdict217"></join>
         
               <p>475. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-41-defend273" type="defendantName">
                     Barnard 
                     Crawley 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-41-defend273" type="surname" value="Crawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-defend273" type="given" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-defend273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401015-41-defloc214">St Andrew Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-41-defloc214" type="placeName" value="St Andrew Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-41-defloc214" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-41-defend273 t17401015-41-defloc214"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17401015-41-off215" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-off215" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-off215" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Gold Box for a Watch, val. 50 s. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17401015-41-victim275" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Peckover 
                        <interp inst="t17401015-41-victim275" type="surname" value="Peckover"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-41-victim275" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-41-victim275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-41-off215 t17401015-41-victim275"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the House of 
                     <persName id="t17401015-41-person276">
                        Christopher 
                        Potter 
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person276" type="surname" value="Potter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-41-person276" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401015-41-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17401015-41-cd216" type="crimeDate">Sept. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-41-off215 t17401015-41-cd216"></join>.</p>
               <p>Christopher Potter. The Prisoner came to my House, on the 27th of September, while I was gone out, and went up Stairs with my Men. When I came Home, I looked for this Box to lock up, but could not find it; I asked who had been there, they said no Soul had been there but the Prisoner. I immediately went to him, and desired him to let me have it, but he swore that he knew nothing of it; he came Home with me, and my Men would strip themselves to be searched, but the Prisoner refused to do so, and went away. I got a Constable , and took the Prisoner, and found part of the Box at Mr Davis's, a Silversmith, by Holbourn-Bridge . I am a Watch-Guilder, and live against St Andrew's Church ; the Prisoner lodged in a Cellar in Shoe-Lane .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There were 2 Men in the Garret besides me.</p>
               <p>- Oxton . My Fellow Servant and I were at work in the Garret, when the Prisoner was there; we went down Stairs, and left him alone, standing against the place where the Box lay. My Fellow Servant went down first, I came down afterwards, and he was the last Person left above Stairs. As soon as we had got up Stairs again, my Master came up, and missed the Box. We were both gone down before the Prisoner, and the Box was in the Garret when we were there. The 
               <persName id="t17401015-41-person277">
                  Garret 
                  Door 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person277" type="surname" value="Door"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person277" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is never lock'd, for there is nobody but my Master and the Maid live in the House, and she was not in the Garret at this Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-41-person278">
                  Mary 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person278" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person278" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on Sufferance in the Prisoner's Cellar: He came home one Saturday very drunk, Mr Potter came after him, and asked him, if he did not see a Box? he said, no, he knew nothing of it. He went home with Mr Potter, and came back again presently, and the next Morning I found the Bottom of a Box by the Prisoner's Bed side; when he saw it, he swore he thought it had been Brass, when he took it; he would have broken it to pieces, but his Sister pulled up some Stones by the Fire-side, and hid it. She afterwards gave me some Bits, and desired me to ask, whether they were Gold or Brass, and I am sure they were the same that she hid.</p>
               <p>Mr Davis. I bought some Gold of a person, who said he lived in Shoe-Lane, and the next Morning Mr Potter's Man came to me, and said, his Master had lost a Gold Repeating Box. I knew this to be a piece of a Gold Box, so I gave it to Potter, and left Orders with my Wife, to send for him, if any Body should come with Gold. One Juniper came with it, and not the Prisoner; Mr Potter took him up, but he was afterwards discharged.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-41-person279">
                  Thomas 
                  Newland 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person279" type="surname" value="Newland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person279" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner sat in the Garret, with my Shop-mate and me, some Time before my Master came in. I had Occasion to go down Stairs for something, and Oxton followed me down; my Master was then below Stairs, and hid me call the Prisoner down; he came down Stairs, but presently went up again by himself, he staid a great while above, and in 5 Minutes after he was gone the Box was missed.</p>
               <p>Oxton . I am very sure that the Box was in the Garret , when we left the Prisoner alone there.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174010150018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-41-person280">
                  Ann 
                  Barlon 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person280" type="surname" value="Barlon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person280" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner swore he never had the Box, but it was taken by Potter's Boy, and that the Boy had stole Brass Watch Cases from his Master. I said the Boy never wronged him of any thing: why then, says he, I cry cave .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-41-person281">
                  Catherine 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person281" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person281" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was going into the Prisoner's Cellar one Saturday to buy Pears, and this 
               <persName id="t17401015-41-person282">
                  Mary 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17401015-41-person282" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person282" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was on the Stairs; she told me, that a snubbed-nosed Fellow had dropt the Case of a Watch in the Cellar, and that she had picked it up: She desired me to go with her to sell it, but I could not.</p>
               <p>Giles . I never saw this Woman but once before, and never said any thing to her about it. <rs id="t17401015-41-verdict217" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-41-verdict217" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
