<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400709-34">
               <interp inst="t17400709-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-34" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400709-34" type="date" value="17400709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-34-off174-c216" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend282 t17400709-34-off174 t17400709-34-verdict177"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400709-34-off174-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend284 t17400709-34-off174 "></join>
         
               <p>324.325.+ 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-defend282" type="defendantName">
                     Tobias 
                     Isaacs 
                  <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend282" type="surname" value="Isaacs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend282" type="given" value="Tobias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-defend284" type="defendantName">
                     Rachael 
                     Isaacs  alias <rs id="t17400709-34-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend284 t17400709-34-alias-6"></join>Rachael Jacobs</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend284" type="surname" value="Isaacs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend284" type="given" value="Rachael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-defend284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400709-34-defloc173">St Catherine Creechurch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-34-defloc173" type="placeName" value="St Catherine Creechurch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400709-34-defloc173" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend282 t17400709-34-defloc173"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend284 t17400709-34-defloc173"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17400709-34-off174" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-off174" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-off174" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 8 Yards of Silver Netting for a Gown and Petticoat, val.20 l. a Gold Tissue Waistcoat, val.40 s. a Gold Repeating Watch, val.20 l. a Gold Equipage, val.30 l. a Gold Ring, a Pair of Silver Snuffers, a Silver Tea Kettle and Lamp,2 Pair of Silver Candlesticks , a Silver Pint Mug,5 Silver Spoons, a 12 Silver Handle Forks,6 Silver Tea Spoons, a Silver Tea-strainer, a Diamond Necklace and Ear-Rings and several other Things of great value, the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400709-34-victim286" type="victimName">
                           Moses 
                           Demattos 
                        <interp inst="t17400709-34-victim286" type="surname" value="Demattos"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-34-victim286" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400709-34-victim286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-off174 t17400709-34-victim286"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400709-34-cd175" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-off174 t17400709-34-cd175"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos. On the 16th of June, upon looking over my Trunk, I found my Silver, Gold, Jewels, Linnen, Laces,&amp;c. lost. I charged the Prisoner Rachael (who had been my <rs id="t17400709-34-deflabel176" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend284 t17400709-34-deflabel176"></join> 4 Years) with the Fact: She deny'd it, but after a long Examination, she delivered me my Jewels back again, and upon my asking her for the rest of the Things, she told me, they were all very safe, and I should have them again, in an Hour, provided I would let her go for them, and send no body with her. I was willing to have my Goods again, and desirous to know who was concerned with her, therefore I let her go; but I sent a Man to follow her, and to watch where she went. The Man return'd in Half an Hour, and told me she was gone to an Inn, in Leaden-hall-street; I went thither, but Rachael was gone from thence, and I heard no more of her till the 19th, and then I heard she was taken, and carried before Col. De Veil with the Goods; that he had committed her to Newgate, and desired me to wait upon him the next Morning, that I might see the Goods. Accordingly I went thither between 10 and 11 o'Clock, and found the other Prisoner Tobias Isaacs. He had carried a Ring of mine to a Goldsmith, to be stretch'd for him, to fit his Finger, and the Goldsmith gave me notice of it; and he, not being able to give any Account how he came by it, was committed to New Prison. The Monday following he was examined again, and would give no Account where he had it. These are the Goods. These Jewels, these 3 Gold Rings, this Diamond Necklace, this Gold Necklace, and Gold Medal, were deliver'd me by the Prisoner Rachael, and are Part of that I lost. They were in a Trunk, in my best Room, up one Pair of Stairs; and there was 2 Locks upon the Trunk, neither of which were broke. I suppose I left the Key of my Compting-House in the Door,(my Bunch of Keys being kept there) and I imagine , she took them out, and opened the Trunk with my own Keys. I saw the Goods in the Trunk between 2 and 3 Months before I missed them; and when I taxed her with taking them, she deny'd it with Earnestness for 2 Hours, but upon my promising to be a Friend to her, and that I would not hurt it, she confessed -* </p>
               <p>* The Prosecutor was not allowed to proceed; and another Witness afterwards offering to give an Account of what she had confessed to him, was likewise stopped; because a Confession obtained on a Promise of Friendship, or by false Insinuations (which was the latter Case) ought not to be given in Evidence against a Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-person287">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person287" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person287" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Ring I found amongst the rest of the Goods.</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos.'Tis mine, and has my Name in it. This Waistcoat is mine; this Silver Lamp, and all these Things are mine.</p>
               <p>Mr Rhodes. I found these Goods by a Search Warrant, granted by my Lord Mayor, and backed by Colonel De Veil, at a Lodging taken for the Prisoner Rachael, at Mr Latham's, by a few Woman, who sells Anchovies about the Streets. This Woman told me she believed the Goods were at this Lodging, and she shew'd me the House; but the Prisoner Rachael being gone out, we asked the Woman of the House, if any Goods had been brought there? She told us, that a Trunk had been brought there, the Night before; we seized it, and found all these Things in it. After this, we went with the Anchovy Woman in search of the Prisoner Rachael ; she carried us to Tower street, and there she called her out of a House to us, and I took her, and told her she was my Prisoner. She would not go with me till I shew'd her my Staff, and then she came along quietly, and we took her before the Justice, who examined her; and that Night she said, she knew nothing of the Robbery, but alledg'd, that the other Prisoner (Tobias Isaacs) brought the Goods to her: He was not with us at that Time?</p>
               <p>Prisoner Rachael, Ask my Master if he can swear I took them?</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos. I don't swear she took them: I swear she delivered me the Diamonds. The Prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174007090030"></xptr> ( Tobias ) is married to Rachael, and he used to come to her, till about 6 Months ago; but he frequently beat her so miserably, that I forbid him my House, and I have not seen him for 6 Months; tho' I have heard he has been there within that Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-person288">
                  Richard 
                  Latham 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person288" type="surname" value="Latham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person288" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know both the Prisoners. On Tuesday the 17th of last Month, a Jew Woman, who serves me with Anchovies and Pickles, brought the Prisoner Rachael to my House, and told me she was distressed for a Lodging, and desired my Wife to let her lie a Night or two at our House. She told us, the Prisoner had been lock'd up in a Room by her Husband, and that she had got through a Window, for fear of being murder'd by him. My Wife was sorry for her, and gave her leave to lie with my Mother; and the next Day, the Prisoner Tobias, and another Man, brought the Trunk to our House,- who that other Man was, I cannot tell. When the Constable came to my House; I happened to be at home: He said a Robbery had been committed, and I know there were several Parcels of Plate found in the Trunk, but I can't be particular to any one Thing, because I keep a Shop, and was out and in several Times. I believe I saw this Waistcoat taken out of it. I knew nothing of the Prisoner Rachael , before the Anchovy Woman brought her to our House, and after this, she fetch'd Tobias to her, and told me he was her Brother; she said, perhaps he could not come with her just then, therefore she desired me to give her a Direction in Writing how to find my House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-person289">
                  William 
                  Winne 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person289" type="surname" value="Winne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person289" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner Tobias brought this Ring to my Shop, to be stretched for him, and I knew it to be Mr Demattos's. I know nothing of the Woman Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-person290">
                  Jacob 
                  Isaacs 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person290" type="surname" value="Isaacs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person290" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Constable, and found the Goods at Latham's House; I know nothing else.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Tobias. Mr Demattos knows I was divorced from my Wife, and he sent to our Minister to know if it was a right Divorcement.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Rachael . The Goods were taken out of my Master's House, by the Woman that sells Anchovies, and she carried them to 
               <persName id="t17400709-34-person291">
                  Jacob 
                  Isaac 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person291" type="surname" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person291" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's House; and when my Master gave me leave to go and see for them, I went thither, and he told me they were carried to Mr Latham's .</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos. The Goods which Rachael herself delivered me back again, are worth about one hundred Pounds.</p>
               <p>- Lopez . I was the Person that Mr Demattos sent after Rachael, when she went to look after the Goods. I dodged her, to see if I could discover where she went, or find any of her Gang; and I saw the Anchovy Woman come to her first, and afterwards Jacob Isaacs: upon which I went back and gave Mr Demattos notice, but when we returned the Women were both gone.</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos. I have heard that the Anchovy Woman used to come to my House; and if I was to see her, I believe I should know her.</p>
               <p>One Witness for Rachael deposed that he had known her 20 or 22 Years; he never had had any Dealings with her, but took her to be an honest Woman. Two others deposed much to the same purpose.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400709-34-person292">
                  Phineas 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17400709-34-person292" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person292" type="given" value="Phineas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             knew her when she lived in Mr Salvadore's Family: he deposed, that she had lived there 3 Years very honestly.</p>
               <p>Two Jew Women deposed they had known her some Time, and never heard any Harm of her.</p>
               <p>Mr Salvadore deposed she had lived with him, at twice, near 6 Years, and that nothing was missing, during that Time.</p>
               <p>Mr Demattos. The Jewels were concealed in a Hair-Cap in the Trunk; she took them out, and gave them to me.</p>
               <p>Tobias <rs id="t17400709-34-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>. Rachael, <rs id="t17400709-34-verdict178" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-verdict178" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400709-34-verdict178" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, <rs id="t17400709-34-punish179" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17400709-34-punish179" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400709-34-defend284 t17400709-34-punish179"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>. The Prosecutor recommended her to the Court for Mercy
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
