<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-26">
               <interp inst="t17420428-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-26" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-26" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-26-off120-c190" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-defend245 t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-verdict124"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-26-off120-c191" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-defend247 t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-verdict124"></join>
         
               <p>30, 31. + 
               <persName id="t17420428-26-defend245" type="defendantName">
                  Richard 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend245" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend245" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-defend247" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Newton 
                  <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend247" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend247" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17420428-26-off120" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-off120" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-off120" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling House of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-26-victim249" type="victimName">
                           Nicholas 
                           Falcon 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-26-victim249" type="surname" value="Falcon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-26-victim249" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-26-victim249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-victim249"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , between Eleven and One in the Night, and stealing a Copper Saucepan, a Stew-pan, a Pottage Pot and Cover, a Brass Boiler, 2 large pewter Dishes, and 7 pewter Plates
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420428-26-cd121" type="crimeDate">March 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-cd121"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person250">
                  Nicholas 
                  Falcon 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person250" type="surname" value="Falcon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person250" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17420428-26-crimeloc122">Black-Swan-Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-26-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="Black-Swan-Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-26-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-crimeloc122"></join>, near <placeName id="t17420428-26-crimeloc123">London Wall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-26-crimeloc123" type="placeName" value="London Wall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-26-crimeloc123" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-off120 t17420428-26-crimeloc123"></join>. On the 30th of March I went to Bed about Ten o'Clock, and next Morning I found my House broke open, and the Goods gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What Part of your House was broken?</p>
               <p>Falcon. One of the Prisoners got over the Door-way, and unbolted the Yard Door, and let in the others; after which they took a Pane of Glass out of the Kitchen Window, and so got in, and took my Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your Kitchen Window open to the Street ?</p>
               <p>Falcon. No, it is backwards, but there are some Pales over the outer Door, about eight Feet high; they got over these, and so came into the Yard. I left the Kitchen Window safe when I went to Bed, (it was fasten'd with a Hasp such as usually are in Casements) but next Morning at 6 o'Clock, when I came down Stairs, I found it open. I had over Night providentially double lock'd my Kitchen Door, so that they could not get any farther; but the Shelves were clear'd of the Pewter, and upon examining a little Closet in the Kitchen, I miss'd the rest of the Goods mention'd in the Indictment. On the Sunday following, I received Information that the Evidence Veisey was taken, and by his Directions I found some of my Goods at the Places where he and his Companions had pawn'd them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person251">
                  John 
                  Veisey 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person251" type="surname" value="Veisey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Night this Robbery was committed; the two Prisoners and I met together at Mr. Bagley's in Hartsborn-court; he sells Gin, and we always used to meet there. Newton propos'd going to this Man's (Falcon's) House, to take the Pewter, we staid at the Gin-shop 'till toward Eleven or Twelve o'Clock, and then went to this House. There is a Door in the Alley with some Pales over it like a Fence: I help'd Newton over, and then he unbolted the Door and let us into the Yard. Then Newton broke some of the Panes of Glass with his Hand; they were large Panes of Glass set in Lead. Cooley thought Newton did not do it fast enough, so he push'd him away, and broke some of the Glass himself, and turn'd the Bolt of the Window back. Newton went in first, and Cooley follow'd him, and handed out the Goods to me: there were a small Copper Pot, and Cover, a large brass Pot, 2 Dishes, a Sauce-pan, a Stew-pan, and some Plates: Cooley and I did not know the House 'till Newton shew'd it to us, we brought the Things from thence, and put them into an empty House 'till Morning, and then I pawn'd a Copper Pot and one Dish at Mr. Trofeir's somewhere by Clerkenwell, in Peter-street; and the Stew-pan I pawn'd at one Mrs. Davis's up an Alley in Golden-lane. Cooley and I afterwards went to steal some Rabbits, and I being taken for that made this Information.</p>
               <p>Newton. Ask him over again.</p>
               <p>Veisey. We met together at Bagley's in Harisborn-court, where Newton ask'd us to go along with him, telling us he knew a House where we might get some Pewter. We went thither and I help'd Newton over the Fence, and he unbolted<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280018"></xptr> the Door and let us in. Then he broke some Panes in the Casement, but Cooley thinking he did not break them fast enough, did the rest himself and so open'd the Window. Newton went in first, Cooley follow'd him, and handed out the Things to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person252">
                  John 
                  Veisey 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person252" type="surname" value="Veisey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sen. The Evidence is my unfortunate Son. I was present when Newton was examin'd by the Justice, and the Evidence's Information was read over to him. When it was read that he got over the Prosecutor's Pales, open'd the Back door, and let in the other two, the Justice ask'd him whether it was not so? He said it was. Then it was read, - that Newton and Cooley broke the Window and open'd the Casement; and he said it was so. It was farther read that Newton and Cooley got in at the Window, and deliver'd out the Prosecutor's Goods to the Evidence, and being ask'd whether that was right? He said it was. He likewise confess'd that there was a great Brass Pot that held 3 or 4 Pails of Water, which he sold to one Cartet, for four Shillings, and he told us where Catrer liv'd, but I don't remember that. Cooley was not before the Justice at that Time so I did not hear his Confession.</p>
               <p>Newton. Ask him over again.</p>
               <p>[The Witness repeated his Evidence as above.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person253">
                  William 
                  Garnet 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person253" type="surname" value="Garnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person253" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I was before Justice Poulson when Newton was there, and Veisey's Information was read over to him. I took them both, and they acknowledged every Thing according to the Information of the Accomplice.</p>
               <p>Q. When the Information was read over, were both the Prisoners present?</p>
               <p>Garnet. No, one of them was taken on Sunday Morning, and the other afterwards. Veisey's Father was before the Justice, when the Information was read to Newton, but I don't remember seeing him when Cooley was there.</p>
               <p>Q. What Distance of Time was there between Newton and Cooley's being before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Garnet. I think I took Newton out of Bridewell on Sunday Morning, and on the Thursday or Friday following Cooley was taken.</p>
               <p>[Part of the Goods were here produc'd, and sworn to by the Prosecutor.]</p>
               <p>Newton. I have got a poor Mother and 2 or 3 Neighbours to appear for my honesty.</p>
               <p>Cooley. I was coming along and a Man laid hold of me and carried me to Bridewell, and said Veisey) had sworn House-breaking against me and Newton, but I am innocent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person254">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person254" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person254" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my Son. I always was a very poor Woman, and took an honest Care to get Bread; my Child did the same, when it was in his Power. I applied to Coleman-street Parish to put him Apprentice, or fit him for the Sea, but they would do nothing for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person255">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person255" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person255" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Newton 5 or 6 Years. He us'd the Markets, and has carried Fruit for me. I have trusted him with Money and Goods to the Value of 30 s at a Time, and don't know that I ever lost a Pin by him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person256">
                  James 
                  Rose 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person256" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person256" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 4 or 5 Years. I have trusted him to fetch and carry Goods for me, and never heard any Harm of him in the least.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person257">
                  Mary 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person257" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person257" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 7 Years: I am a Neighbour to him: He always was very willing to work in any Sort of Business, and I never knew nothing but that he was honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person258">
                  John 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person258" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Cooley 8 or 9 Years: I take him to be about 14 or 15 Years old. His own Father is dead, but he lives with his Mother, who has marry'd a second Husband. He is a Copper Smith, and works at Home. As to the Boy, I never heard any Harm of him, nor ever knew that he wrong'd any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Delacourt 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person259" type="surname" value="Delacourt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I knew Cooley before he could run alone: I live next Door to his Mother, and don't know that he ever was from her. She us'd to send him to School, but since she married a second Husband, he has been upon liking with his Father.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Chum 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person260" type="surname" value="Chum"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd next Door to the Prisoner, and I know nothing but that he took a very good Course. He us'd to clean the Brasses for his Father-in-law</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person261">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person261" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person261" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Cooley is my Son: He has had a good Education in reading and writing, and what I could afford to give him. He always staid within Doors, but sometimes he has been drawn away, and once I found him at a Place where the Evidence Veisey brought him to.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-26-person262">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pye 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person262" type="surname" value="Pye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person262" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Eleazar Gibbons, and 
               <persName id="t17420428-26-person263">
                  Matthew 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17420428-26-person263" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person263" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , likewise appear'd to Cooley's Character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17420428-26-verdict124" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-verdict124" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420428-26-punish125" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-26-punish125" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-defend245 t17420428-26-punish125"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-26-defend247 t17420428-26-punish125"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
