<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420603-3">
               <interp inst="t17420603-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-3" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-3" type="date" value="17420603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420603-3-off9-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-3-defend33 t17420603-3-off9 t17420603-3-verdict12"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-defend33" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Shad 
                  <interp inst="t17420603-3-defend33" type="surname" value="Shad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-defend33" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-defend33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17420603-3-off9" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-off9" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-off9" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the House of Enoch and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420603-3-victim35" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Stepple 
                        <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim35" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim35" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and stealing two Bags of Money, one of Gold and the other of Silver, to the Value of 190 Pounds
            </rs>, the <rs id="t17420603-3-cd10" type="crimeDate">7th of May</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-3-off9 t17420603-3-cd10"></join> last.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-victim37" type="victimName">
                     Enoch 
                     Stepple 
                  <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim37" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim37" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-victim37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . The 7th of May, at eleven o'Clock at Night, I went to Bed and left my Son (who is my Partner ) up, and about five in the Morning, he came up and told me, that the House was broke open, and we were robb'd; that the Drawer in the Bar was broke to Pieces, that the House was broken into up-one Pair of Stairs, that a Pane of Glass was taken out, and the Casement left open, and that the House-door was unlock'd and left open. My Lord, I miss'd the two Linnen Bags, one of Silver, and the other of Gold, in which there was upwards of 190 Pounds in Gold and Silver. My Lord, I did not suspect the Prisoner, who lived next Door to me, and was an <rs id="t17420603-3-deflabel11" type="occupation">Apprentice to a Barber and Perriwig-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-3-defend33 t17420603-3-deflabel11"></join>; but, my Lord, last Sunday
<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030003"></xptr> was Sen'night, I was in the Country as Hackney, and the Prisoner's Master came and told me, that he had taken the Person that had robb'd me, and had got the greatest Part of my Money. I came Home on Monday, and went to the Sun-Tavern, in Milk-Street, where the Prisoner was brought from the Compter, by the Constable. I ask'd the Prisoner which way he robb'd me. He said, that he clamber'd up the Out-side of the Bar, in the Court, and got up into the Coving of the first Floor, and that he drew up a large Sash Window, that open'd into the first Floor, and the Shutter being fast pin'd, he could not get in there; that then he went to the Casement that was on the Stair-case, and took out a Pane of Glass (a square Piece of Glass) and put his Hand in, and opened the Casement in the Inside. I ask'd him, whether he took the Pane of Glass out with a Knife, and he said no, he did it with his Nail: he said, that then he went into the first Floor, and came down Stairs, and open'd the Bar-door, and went into the Bar, and broke open the Drawer with a Chissel. I ask'd him, how he came by the Chissel, he said, he bought it for that purpose. I then ask'd him, where it was, and he said, that he had thrown it away: He then own'd that he took both Baggs of Money away, a Bag of Gold and a Bag of Silver. I ask'd him, what he did with them, he said, that he went into his Master's House, that the Door he had left upon a jar, and went up Stairs, and hid the Bag of Gold between two Stacks of Chimneys at the Top of his Master's Leads, and then went down upon the Leads of the Church, and hid the Bag of Silver in a Hole under the Roof; then I took the Bank Note that he had of 100 l and asked him, whether the Money that fetch'd that Bank Note was mine, and he said it was. My Lord, there was 18 l. that he had lodg'd in a young Man's Hands, at the other End of the Town, and he said, that that was also my Property, and the young Man's Master delivered the Money up to us. This be own'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17420603-3-person38">
                  George 
                  Championand 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person38" type="surname" value="Championand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person38" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             discharg'd the Person that he preseaded to be his Accomplice.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When you got up in the Morning, did not you ask my Master it I was at home ?</p>
               <p>E. Stepple. I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not find that I was at home at five o'Clock in the Morning, when you found your House was broke open?</p>
               <p>E. Stepple. I was a-bed at five.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person39">
                  John 
                  Stepple 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person39" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person39" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About half an Hour after eleven at Night, the 11th of May last, my Father seemed very sleepy, and I asked him, whether he would not go up to Bed, and he went up to Bed, my Mother was gone up before. About twelve o'Clock at Night, I told my Money, and put it into these two Bags, and lock'd the Drawer, and put the Key into my Pocket, the Company being all gone, I went all round the House, and put my Hand against this Casement that was broke open, and it was safe. The next Morning I call'd the Men up at five o'Clock, as I always do, and they went down Stairs, and in about five Minutes time, the Men came and told me, that the Door was broke open, and the Till was broke, and I came down and found it so, and I miss'd the 2 Baggs, one of Gold, and the other of Silver, there was in them, 195 Pounds, or thereabouts; there was 96 Guineas carried to the Bank, and 8 Guineas and half a Moidore, I found at an Aunts of this Lads in Black-Fryars, he told his Master that he had lodg'd them there. When I came down and found my House broke open, I saw upon the Table by the Bar, the Marks of his Feet, and the two bends of his Knees upon the Top of the Leads over the Bar. He endeavour'd to take out one Pane of Glass, but could not; he then took a Pane of Glass out over that, and then open'd the Casement. The Saturday Sen'night after, a Gentleman came to me about 9 at Night, and desired I would go and fetch a Constable, for he had got the Thief, and then we went into his Master's Shop, and took him out, and had him to the Nagg's-Head Tavern, and we had there the young Fellow that had got the 18 Pounds, that he (the Prisoner) had left in his Hands. Mr. Brigg's asked Shad, where he had the Money, and he said that he found it; but before that, he had told Noel Gregory, that he had made Wigs for it, and then Mr. Briggs took him into another Room with his Master and another Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Court. Was you there?</p>
               <p>J. Stepple. No. The Sunday Morning I went to him to the Compter, and told him, that I was sadly afraid, that he had impeached an innocent Person, and that I had very good Reason for it; that if a Person had been concerned with him in the Robbery, he would not have taken the Bag of Silver for his Share; and then he cried, and said, his Life laid in my Hands, and he then confess'd, that the Person that he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030004"></xptr> had ask'd him what he had done with the Bagg of Silver, he said, he had hid in under the Roof upon the Leads of the Church, Event the next Morning and took him one of the Compter, and got a Carpenter, and we went and took up a couple of Boards according to his (the Prisoners) Direction, and we found it, and he (the Prisoner) was with us when we found it.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he mention in what manner he got into the House ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person40">
                  John 
                  Stepple 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person40" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes Sir, at the Sun Tavern, on Monday, he laid, that he went to an Ivon-mongers, and bought a Chissel the Night before, and said that he got upon the Table underneath the Bar, and got up the Bar, and with his Nails he would the Lead of the Window, and came down, and broke the Drawer-open. I ask'd him what he had done with the Chissel; he said he had thrown it away, that he had taken two Baggs out, and that there was no more than 139 Pound in Gold.</p>
               <p>Court. What Time of Night did he say it was?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person41">
                  John 
                  Stepple 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person41" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person41" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He said it was pretty near 3 o'Clock; I ask'd him how long he was about it, and he said he was about a Quarter and half a Quarter of an Hour, from the Time of his going out of Bed, 'till the Time he got in; and he said he took up the Lad that laid with him, 3 Times in his Arms, and threw him down upon the Bed to try whether he would awake.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I would ask him whether I ever told him, that I took the Lad up 3 Times and threw him down again to see whether he would awake or not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person42">
                  John 
                  Stepple 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person42" type="surname" value="Stepple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He said he did to see whether he would awake before he went out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person43">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person43" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord the Prisoner at the Bar is my Apprentice, and last Saturday was 7 night he was taken up for robbing Mr. Stepple, and was taken to the Nagg's-Head Tavern. Soon after they sent for me, and we took him into a Room and otiarged him with robbing Mr. Stepple, and in a little time he confess'd.</p>
               <p>Court. What did he confess?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person44">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person44" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He confess'd that he and another, broke into Mr. Stepple's House.</p>
               <p>Court. Who was that other Person?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person45">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person45" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have forgot his Name.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he mention the Time?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person46">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person46" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He (the Prisoner) said it was between two and three o'Clock in the Morning, that he assisted him up the Bed, and that he took out two Baggs, that the Bagg (of Gold) that he (the Prisoner) had there, was 1130 l. in it, that in the Bagg of Silver, he did not know what was in it, for that, he said the other Person had I ask'd him where the 139 l. was, and then he (the Prisoner) put his Hand into his Pocket, and pull'd out a Key and gave it me, and told me, that if I would go up into the Garret, and open his Desk, and pull out the Drawer, that behind that Drawer was a private Drawer, and that there, he said I should find a Bank Note of 100 l. Accordingly I went and found it, and brought it back to the Tavern, and Shew'd it them, and he (the Prisoner ) said, that that 100 l. Bank-Note, was got with Mr. Stepple's Money, that he had put into the Bank the Monday before. There was 8 Guineas and half a Moidore left in a pair of Pumps, at an Aunts of his, in Black-Fryars, and I, and Mr. Stepple, went the Sunday following, and found it as he had told us.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire to know whether you did not ring me up that Morning (the Morning the Robbery was committed) and whether I did not come down as usual ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person47">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person47" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes you did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I not go to Bed between 10 and 11 o'Clock that Night?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-3-person48">
                  John 
                  Peisley 
               <interp inst="t17420603-3-person48" type="surname" value="Peisley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person48" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Wife said you did.</p>
               <p>Court. Prisoner, what have you to say in your Defence ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, as I was going towards Bucklers-Bury, I found a Bagg, in which was contained Gold and Silver to the amount of 140 l. or thereabouts, I carried the Gold and lodg'd it in Black-Fryars till the Monday following, and then I took a 100 l. and carried it to the Bank, and took a Bank-Note for it, I was not willing to make it known, because I did not know, but there might be some one or another, lay claim to it, and I might loose the Money by it; and my Lord, I found it in one Bagg only.</p>
               <p>E. Stepple. My Lord, the Bagg that the Silver was in, I can swear to it.</p>
               <p>Court. Prisone r, have you any Witnesses to call ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. Have you any thing more to say?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No Sir, I lie at the Mercy of the Court, and I hope your Lordship will consider my Youth.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030005"></xptr>E. Stepple. My Lord, as the Prisoner is a Young-Man, and this is his first Fact, I would recommend him to the Mercy of the Court.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17420603-3-verdict12" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-verdict12" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-verdict12" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               acquitted him of the Burglary, but found him guilty of the Robbery. 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420603-3-punish13" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-3-punish13" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-3-defend33 t17420603-3-punish13"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
