<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490906-66">
               <interp inst="t17490906-66" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-66" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-66" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-66" type="date" value="17490906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490906-66-off261-c258" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-66-defend383 t17490906-66-off261 t17490906-66-verdict264"></join>
         
               <p>558. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490906-66-defend383" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Graham 
                  <interp inst="t17490906-66-defend383" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-defend383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-defend383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17490906-66-off261" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-off261" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-off261" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, upon 
                     <persName id="t17490906-66-victim384" type="victimName">
                        Saven 
                        Nellson 
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-victim384" type="surname" value="Nellson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-66-victim384" type="given" value="Saven"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-66-victim384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-66-off261 t17490906-66-victim384"></join>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault , putting him in bodily fear and danger of his life , and taking from his person 3 s. and 1 penny, the monies of the said Saven
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-66-cd262" type="crimeDate">July 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-66-off261 t17490906-66-cd262"></join>.</p>
               <p>Saven Nellson. The 19th of July, between 11 and 12 o'clock at night, coming over <placeName id="t17490906-66-crimeloc263">Tower-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-66-crimeloc263" type="placeName" value="Tower-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-66-crimeloc263" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-66-off261 t17490906-66-crimeloc263"></join> , there came to me three other men, besides the prisoner at the bar, with drawn cutlasses in their hands; they said, if I spoke a word, they would cut me to pieces; while one stood on each side of me, the prisoner at the bar put his hand in my pocket and took my money; they perceiving the watchman coming, three of them ran away. I got hold of the prisoner, and call'd out watch, watch; the watchman came directly; I told him what had been done to me; we took the prisoner to the watch-house; in the morning he was carry'd before the justice, and committed to New Prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-66-person385">
                  William 
                  Ditchet 
               <interp inst="t17490906-66-person385" type="surname" value="Ditchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person385" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was constable of the night; the prosecutor brought the prisoner to me , and charg'd me with him, saying, he had robb'd him of half a crown and 7 pence, upon Tower-hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-66-person386">
                  Richard 
                  Leget 
               <interp inst="t17490906-66-person386" type="surname" value="Leget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person386" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish; I heard the prosecutor cry out watch, watch, July 19, between 11 and 12, I ran to his assistance, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174909060015"></xptr> he had the prisoner by the shoulder, and I took hold of him on the other side, and we took him to the watch-house; the prosecuter said there were three others just gone away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. About two days before this affair happen'd, I had my discharge from on board one of his majesty's vessels: I sold my ticket at the Half-way-house, between Greenwich and Woolwich, in order to enter on board any of his majesty's ships. I went and enter'd myself on board the Tyger that same day, and I saw 2 or 3 of my friends in St. Catherine's; I went to Towerhill , to the sign of the Hamburgh Arms, and was there till about 11 o'clock at night; then I went away to a house which I had used before, thinking from thence to go down to the ship, on the morrow morning; coming to this house, it was late; I knock'd at the door, they would not let me in; the while I was talking to them, from the window above, two men, one of them is 
               <persName id="t17490906-66-person387">
                  Wm.
                   Caveragh
               <interp inst="t17490906-66-person387" type="surname" value="Caveragh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person387" type="given" value="Wm."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and the other is Hazard, said who is here, a friend said I; before the door was opened, they said will they not let you in? said I, I do not know whether they will or no; these two men broke into the house, and made a disturbance, and immediately came the prosecutor; then they fled both of them; then this man seeing me in the house, said, I believe you are one of the men that robb'd me on Tower-hill; said I, you are mistaken, I was not in company with them men, any further than seeing them here.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Did you take him in a house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, my lord, I took him where they robb'd me; I was in no house at all.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-66-verdict264" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-verdict264" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490906-66-punish265" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-66-punish265" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-66-defend383 t17490906-66-punish265"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
