<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450710-18">
               <interp inst="t17450710-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-18" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450710-18" type="date" value="17450710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450710-18-off102-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-defend143 t17450710-18-off102 t17450710-18-verdict106"></join>
         
               <p>317. +
               
                  <persName id="t17450710-18-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Catharine 
                     Wilcox 
                  <interp inst="t17450710-18-defend143" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-defend143" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-defend143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            *, of <placeName id="t17450710-18-defloc101">St. Mary Whitechapel, in the County of Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450710-18-defloc101" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Whitechapel, in the County of Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450710-18-defloc101" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-defend143 t17450710-18-defloc101"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17450710-18-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing eight pounds ten shillings in money, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450710-18-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           White 
                        <interp inst="t17450710-18-victim145" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450710-18-victim145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450710-18-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-off102 t17450710-18-victim145"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450710-18-cd103" type="crimeDate">July 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-off102 t17450710-18-cd103"></join>.</p>
               <p>* This 
               <persName id="t17450710-18-person146">
                  Catharine 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person146" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person146" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             [aged sixty years or upwards] was tried in February sessions in the mayoralty of Sir 
               <persName id="t17450710-18-person147">
                  Robert 
                  Willimott 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person147" type="surname" value="Willimott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person147" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Knt. for privately stealing 11 s. from the person of 
               <persName id="t17450710-18-person148">
                  John 
                  Perthy 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person148" type="surname" value="Perthy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person148" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             [a young man] in some private conversation in an alley near Aldgate. See sessions paper, No. 3. Page 89, Trial 149.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-18-person149">
                  Thomas 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person149" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person149" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yesterday about three o'clock in the morning I was going along <placeName id="t17450710-18-crimeloc104">Gracechurch Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450710-18-crimeloc104" type="placeName" value="Gracechurch Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450710-18-crimeloc104" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-off102 t17450710-18-crimeloc104"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been at that time o'night?</p>
               <p>White. I had been drinking in Shoreditch with one Mr. Hope a brewer. The Prisoner and another woman hussled me, and took me hold by the middle, or much about that part. I had a handkerchief in my pocket, which I missed; missing my handkerchief I thought this woman had robbed me. I followed them into Bell Alley, [ Petticoat Lane] I think it is Bell Alley, it is by Whitechapel. Said I to this woman, when she was housed, mistress, pray give me my handkerchief, for I believe you have it, and I'll give you more than it is worth, because I would have it again. I offered them two shillings for it several times, and they denied the taking it. I asked them for it abundance of times, and thought they would have taken the money for the handkerchief, because it is not worth more. I came out and went into the house two or three times; I thought I would go into the house once more, so went in and asked them for it again: they said they could not do any thing till they had something to drink, so I put my hand in my pocket and gave them six pence to drink, thinking I should have got my handkerchief afterwards: then I offered them three shillings, and that would not do. I had three parcels of money in my pocket, and pulled out one parcel.</p>
               <p>Q. In what pocket was it?</p>
               <p>White. In my coat pocket. I pulled out a bag in which was 8 l. 10 s. all in silver, which I had taken that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you take it of?</p>
               <p>White. Of Mr. Berry, a bacon man in Goswell Street. The Prisoner at the bar seeing this dog went to the door, and locked the door with me in the room. Said I, you shall not make me a Prisoner; then I pressed to get out at the door, and while I was pressing I suppose she took the money out of my pocket, for the young woman who was there, [
               <persName id="t17450710-18-person150">
                  Hannah 
                  Cutherson 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person150" type="surname" value="Cutherson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person150" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] said, she [the prisoner] has got the money out of your pocket, see whether you miss any thing: then I put my hand into my pocket, and my money was gone; the prisoner had the money in her hand, and I took it from her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take it from her?</p>
               <p>White. In the same room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say for herself?</p>
               <p>White. I asked her what she did it for, but I don't believe she made me any answer; then the other woman said, tell your money, see that you have it all, so I put part of the money out of the bag upon the table, and the prisoner presently began<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174507100012"></xptr> to scramble, and she said she never saw so much money upon her table before.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did you tell of it?</p>
               <p>White. I told about two or three pounds out of the parcel, and then she would not let me be at quiet.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she do to you?</p>
               <p>White. She scrambled for the money, and I believe she took up some part of it: I told her if she meddled with me or my money, I would knock her down; then she began to curse and swear, and said she would have some, and she took some by violence: when I found I was in such had hands, I was willing to get my money up as well as I could; I told it afterwards at a publick house, and it wanted 8 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I know no more of his handkerchief or his money than your Lordship. Pray, honest man, had I your handkerchief or your money? you set down in the other woman's lap, I did not take your money.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you took a bag of money out of your pocket to take six pence out to give them, are you sure you put your money into your pocket again?</p>
               <p>White. Yes, as sure as I am of any thing in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. You say this was three o'clock in the morning. can you be sure what you did?</p>
               <p>White. Yes; I am very sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you lay your money down upon the ?</p>
               <p>White. That was after I had taken the money from her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-18-person151">
                  Hannah 
                  Cutherson 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person151" type="surname" value="Cutherson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person151" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I met Mr. White in Gracechurch Street; they talked together a little, and then she asked him if he would not go home with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give his consent to go home with her?</p>
               <p>Cutherson. I did not hear him say any thing, but they went along, and I went on too, sometimes before, and sometimes behind. As he was going along he complained that he had lost his handkerchief, and said, he loved justice and honesty. Then he went home with her into Bell Alley in Petticoat Lane; when he came into the house, he asked her for his handkerchief, and said, he hoped there was justice there; and that he missed his handkerchief in Gracechurch Street, and she said she knew nothing of his handkerchief, as she hoped to be saved: then he pulled a couple of shillings out of his pocket, and offered her for it, but she said she knew nothing of it. He went out at the door and came in again, and desired to have it, and said he would search us. I offered several times to be searched; then he said he would give three shillings for it, he valued it so much. He said he had twenty pound about him, and that he would as leave have lost that as the handkerchief: then he pulled out a bag of money, and said, here's a bag of money, and I have more in my breeches pockets both gold and silver; and he put the money into his pocket again; then the Prisoner went to the door and pushed it to, and asked him if he would give her something to drink; he said, yes, if she would let him have his handkerchief; but however, he would give her something to drink, and threw down six pence, and we had some gin and small beer, but he said he did not like any such liquor: then she locked the door, and he said he would not be locked in. I saw the bag in her hand, and I asked him if he had not lost something; he said he had lost his bag; he took hold of her hand, and took the bag out of her hand: I said you brazen face, how could you take the man's money out of his pocket?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take it out of his pocket?</p>
               <p>Cutherson. I did not see her take it, she said she would tell it for him; he said, you brazen face do you want to rob me again: then he pulled out his money again, and laid it upon the table to tell it, and she scrambled, and said, she had not seen so much money upon her table a great while; then she scrambled again, and scrambled some away from him, and he went to the alehouse and told the money over, and said he had lost 8 s. 6 d. and the Prisoner said, if she had known he had had that money he should never have brought it home.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Who had you your handkerchief from?</p>
               <p>White. I had it from you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Good Lord forgive me, I never had it; I never saw it till he put his money in it, and she was sitting in his lap. Sure he will not offer to swear any such thing.</p>
               <p>Cutherson. I never sat in his lap, and the man never offered to touch me; if I had thought she would have robbed him, I would have gone out of the house, and not have staid there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He took his money out of his pocket, and laid it upon the table, and sat upon my table an hour and an half.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was White there?</p>
               <p>Cutherson. I believe what with going backwards and forwards, and disputing, it was a couple of hours.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174507100013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-18-person152">
                  Mary 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person152" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person152" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 20 years, or more.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Brooks. I never heard a bad character of her - she <rs id="t17450710-18-deflabel105" type="occupation">winds Bengall silk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450710-18-defend143 t17450710-18-deflabel105"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450710-18-person153">
                  Ann 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17450710-18-person153" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person153" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about a quarter of a year, she comes to my house sometimes; but I have very little acquaintance or conversation with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Waters. I am nothing at all - I have nothing to do but to take care of my family - my husband is a diamond cutter. <rs id="t17450710-18-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450710-18-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
