<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420115-9">
               <interp inst="t17420115-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-9" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420115-9" type="date" value="17420115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420115-9-off41-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-defend86 t17420115-9-off41 t17420115-9-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>12. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-defend86" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17420115-9-defend86" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-defend86" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-defend86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420115-9-defloc40">St. Mildred in the Poultry</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-9-defloc40" type="placeName" value="St. Mildred in the Poultry"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-9-defloc40" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-defend86 t17420115-9-defloc40"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420115-9-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420115-9-victim88" type="victimName">
                           Susannah 
                           Nichols 
                        <interp inst="t17420115-9-victim88" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420115-9-victim88" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420115-9-victim88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-off41 t17420115-9-victim88"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain Street, putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from her a green Silk Purse, value 1 d. a Steel Seal, value 4 d. and 16 s. in Money
            </rs>. <rs id="t17420115-9-cd42" type="crimeDate">Jan. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-off41 t17420115-9-cd42"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person89">
                  Susannah 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person89" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person89" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person89" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was se'nnight, at a little after five in the Evening, I was coming from <placeName id="t17420115-9-crimeloc43">Newgate street towards the Poultry Compter</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-9-crimeloc43" type="placeName" value="Newgate street towards the Poultry Compter"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420115-9-crimeloc43" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-off41 t17420115-9-crimeloc43"></join> , and just as I came to the Apothecary's Door, the Prisoner came behind me, and held me fast down. I attempted to get from her into the Middle of the Highway, and some Fellows jostled me, and kept me close to her. Immediately I felt a Hand in my Pocket; I can't say I could tell whose it was, but she stuck so close to me, that I can't think it was any but her's</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any Thing?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. Yes: I lost a green silk Purse, with a Steel Seal in it, and about 16 s. in Silver, and perceiving my Purse go, I cry'd out Murder or three Times, and then the Prisoner loosed her Hold.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before that, can you take upon you to say, you had your Purse in your Pocket?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. About a Quarter of an Hour before I came from Newgate street: I had just received ten Shillings and put it into my Purse.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. How far did she walk that Night before this besel her?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. From the Place that is called Blowbladder street, which is about a Quarter of a Mile I believe.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Might you not have had the Money taken privately from you before you met with me?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols No, I felt it go at this Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoner is the Woman ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. Yes, it was not quite dark, but very Moon-light , and there was not a shop shut up.</p>
               <p>Q. As the Prisoner was behind you, how could you take Notice of her Face?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. With my struggling, I turn'd about with my Face to her's .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person90">
                  William 
                  Offley 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person90" type="surname" value="Offley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person90" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 4th, of January, about 6 in the Evening, I was going down the Poultry , and a little beyond the Compter I met the Prisoner and this Gentlewoman (Mrs. Nichols) as near together as it is possible for two Women to be, and both of them surrounded by a parcel of Men. I knowing Mrs. Nichols, and hearing her cry out Murder, I stepp'd up to her, but before I could get up to her, the Prisoner had made her way through the other part of the Mob. I can't say that I saw her run, but I think she went off in the usual Manner.</p>

               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoner is the Woman that you saw so near Mrs. Nichols?</p>
               <p>Offley. Yes, I am certain she is the Person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she complain of being robbed at that Time?</p>
               <p>Offley. Yes, about three Minutes after the Woman was gone, she stepped into the Entry at the Compter, and said she had been robb'd.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. You say there was a great Croud of People; were not a great many as near to the Gentlewoman as I?</p>
               <p>Offley. To the best of my Knowledge there was no Person so near Mrs. Nichols as the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person91">
                  John 
                  Garnal 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person91" type="surname" value="Garnal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday about the fourth of this Instant , about 6 o'Clock, I was coming from King Street, Cheapside, and when I came within a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174201150006"></xptr> few Yards of the Poultry, I saw six or seven Men hauling the Gentlewoman, and pushing her to and fro'. She cryed out, but I can't be certain what the Words were : I believe it was Murder , but I can't be certain. It being pretty near the Compter Passage; I apprehended they were taking her into the Compter , upon which I went up to them , and just as I came even with them, they all separated and left the Gentlewoman to herself . I then observed her clap her Hand to her Side, and thought I heard her say, her Watch! her Watch! Then the Prisoner crossed the Way on the other Side of the Poultry. She went an exceeding Pace, sometimes walked, and sometimes ran, so that I could not keep Pace with her without sometimes running myself , and upon her coming from them, and making such Haste , I believed her to be a Person concerned. When she came to the Corner of Walbrook , she turned down, and I believe might be a dozen Yards before me. I followed her to see where she went, and when I turn'd the Corner, I saw her take off her Cloak, and put it under her Arm, and run with full Speed. I then thought she certainly had the Watch about her, upon which I ran and grasp'd hold of her, and told her, she had stolen a Watch. It was just by the Poulterer's Shop that I first seized her, and a Man came out of the Shop to my Assistance, and took hold of her likewise. Immediately I heard two Blows behind me, and the Person that had got hold of the Prisoner's Arm reel'd a little on one Side . Soon afterwards I received a Blow myself on the Side of my Head, and turning about to see from whence it came, the Prisoner sprang out of my Arms . I pursued her, crying out Stop Thief! up Buckler's Bury, I overtook her again, and stopped her a second Time, and call'd for Assistance. Upon which, I heard the Person that followed her, strike about very smartly with his Stick, and I desired the Person , at whose Door I seized her, to let me bring her in, but he held the Door against me. I then took her into the House of one Mr. Bingham, a Silk-Dyer, and told her, she had stole a Watch, upon which, she was very willing to be searched, and turned a Purse and other Things out of her Pocket. She pretended that she was entirely innocent of the Matter , and that she was going to the Bottom of Walbrook to see a Friend who was going out of Town . After we had staid some Time at Mr. Bingham's, the Person was brought in that follow'd us, striking those that endeavoured to take the Prisoner, and we carried them both to the Watch-house, where the Man pull'd out a Purse and shook some Silver out of it into his Hand. They were been carried next Day before the Alderman at Guildhall , and ordered to be search'd; and the Woman then produc'd a green Purse, and the Man a light blue one , which I can take my Oath was not the same that he pull'd out at the Watch-house</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person92">
                  George 
                  Lesley 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person92" type="surname" value="Lesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person92" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was not present when the Fact was committed , but I was going from Walbrook towards Cheapside, and by the Poulterer's Shop, facing the Mantron-house, I saw this Man (Garnal ) holding that Woman at the Bar. He said , she had stole a Watch, and desired me to assist him. I was at a Loss whether I should stop or go past, and just as I came up to them , a Man rush'd from Cheapside, and struck me over the Head. I asked him, why he struck me ? and he said , she was his Wife, and he knew she was innocent . While he was repeating these Words, he redoubled his Blows, and struck me again , and likewise the Man that had hold of the Prisoner. She then ran with the Man that struck us, up Buckler's Bury, and so we pursued them, crying Stop Thief! The other People ran faster than I, so that I was a little distanc'd, and saw no more of them 'till I came to the upper End of Buckler's-Bury, and perceiving the Man using his Stick as smartly as before, I seized him; the Woman was taken by somebody else at the same Time, and when they came together they denied that they had ever seen each other before.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was the Prisoner to that Man when they ran off together?</p>
               <p>Lesley. They were so near that I can't fix any Distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they seem to be acquainted with each other?</p>
               <p>Lesley. The man told me she was his Wife, and he knew her to be innocent.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner in hearing then?</p>
               <p>Lesley. She was near enough to hear, and did not contradict it; but whether her struggling with this Man might not prevent her hearing it , I can't say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person93">
                  William 
                  Lambkin 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person93" type="surname" value="Lambkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person93" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the fourth of this Instant, I was standing at my Door in Buckler's-Bury , and heard a Cry of stop Thief; and seeing the Prisoner run very fast up the Street, I took hold of her. She struggled with me very much, and in the mean Time 
               <persName id="t17420115-9-person94">
                  James 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person94" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person94" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ran after her and struck me. In order to avoid the Blow, I let go the Prisoner, and pursued her again, and had not run above forty Yards, before<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174201150007"></xptr> she was taken by Garnal .</p>
               <p>Defence. I was going to a Master of a Ship at Wapping, and hearing them cry Stop Thief! I ran to hear the Noise, as you know Country People generally do. I had my Clock over my Arm, and this Man stopp'd me, and said, the Lady had lost her Watch. He got me into a House, and I was searched, and I had neither Gold nor Money, but half a Guinea and a Shilling in my Pocket .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person95">
                  Mary Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person95" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person95" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was seven-night, a little before Night, the Prisoner call'd at my House , and said, she was going down to Wapping, to enquire after some Country People, and desired me to go with her. She hurt her Foot going along, and we went Arm in Arm down the City; and just by the Poultry-Compter, (I think they call it ) a Croud of People came by, and shov'd me down, and so we parted.</p>
               <p>C. Did you hear any Out-cry in the Street then?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, but there was a whole Heap of People came along and parted us, and tumbled me down.</p>
               <p>C. When you fell down, what Distance was the Prisoner from you?</p>
               <p>Smith. I can't tell; she was shov'd away from me as I suppose.</p>
               <p>C. Why did not you ask for your Companion when you got up?</p>
               <p>Smith. Who should I ask among Strangers? I turn'd about to look for her, but could not see her.</p>
               <p>C Were you at any Time near the Poultry-Compter Door?</p>

               <p>Smith I think this was against the Church.</p>
               <p>C. Was there nothing said of the Loss of a Watch in your hearing?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go when you got up?</p>
               <p>Smith. I was going to my Mother's in East-Smithfield, and the Prisoner having some Business at Wapping, I was to go Part of the Way with her. I live in Shoe lane; my Husband is a Journeyman Brasier, and I have known the Prisoner about half a Year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person96">
                  Ann 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person96" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person96" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was a Chair-woman to me. I have known her about seven or eight Months. She has been in my House a Week together, and I always took her to be an honest pains-taking Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person97">
                  Margaret 
                  Downs 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person97" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person97" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 16 or 17 Years ; she was a Servant to one 
               <persName id="t17420115-9-person98">
                  John 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person98" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon Newcastle-Bridge . I recommended her to my Brother, and I should not have sent her there, if I had not heard that she bore a good Character .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person99">
                  John 
                  Swinton 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person99" type="surname" value="Swinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lodged at my House about 9 Months, and was recommended to me by the last Witness. I have entrusted her with every Thing in the House, and never knew her addicted to pilfering . The Night she was apprehended , she went from my House with a Design to go to Wapping to see a Relation that was going to Newcastle upon Tyne ; and I take her to be as honest a Woman as any in the Parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Swinton . At the Whittington and his Cat in Bloomsbury Market .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420115-9-person100">
                  Frances 
                  Gammon 
               <interp inst="t17420115-9-person100" type="surname" value="Gammon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person100" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-person100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner ever since the beginning of last Summer: She used to come down to my House in Wapping to enquire after Masters of Ships in Newcastle, who very often us'd to bring her little Presents . About a Fortnight ago, the 3d Day of this Month, was my Child's Birth-Day, who was three Years-old , and the next Day this young Woman (Smith) came to my House to wait for the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Littleton Westley . I have known her between 7 and 8 Months. I have employed her to wash for my Family, and never knew but that she bore a very good Character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420115-9-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420115-9-punish45" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420115-9-punish45" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420115-9-defend86 t17420115-9-punish45"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
