<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-24">
               <interp inst="t17400116-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-24" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-24" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-24-off122-c136" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-defend189 t17400116-24-off122 t17400116-24-verdict124"></join>
         
               <p>108. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-defend189" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Benbrook 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-24-defend189" type="surname" value="Benbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-defend189" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17400116-24-defloc120">St Ann's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-24-defloc120" type="placeName" value="St Ann's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-24-defloc120" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-defend189 t17400116-24-defloc120"></join> was indicted, for that he not having GOD before his Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17400116-24-cd121" type="crimeDate">19th of December</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-off122 t17400116-24-cd121"></join>, <rs id="t17400116-24-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-24-victim191" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Masters 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-24-victim191" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-24-victim191" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-24-victim191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-off122 t17400116-24-victim191"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an Assault, and with his Right-Hand, him the said Masters, in and upon the left Side of the Head did strike and beat, and with his Right-Hand, him the said Masters on and against a certain Stone Step, did cast and throw; giving the said Masters, as well by striking and beating, as by casting and throwing against the said Stone Step, a mortal Bruise and Contusion, of which he instantly died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time charged, by Virtue of the Coroner's Inquest, for the Murder of the said 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person192">
                  Samuel 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person192" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person192" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person193">
                  William 
                  Cheatham 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person193" type="surname" value="Cheatham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person193" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased came to work at my Master's, (Mr. White's in <placeName id="t17400116-24-crimeloc123">Tyburn-Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-24-crimeloc123" type="placeName" value="Tyburn-Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-24-crimeloc123" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-off122 t17400116-24-crimeloc123"></join>) and on the 19th of December, my Master having lent him 6 d. he asked me to go and spend three Halfpence with him. As we were going, the Prisoner met us, and asked the Deceased, if he was not a Rogue to go and work at another Place? The Deceased told the Prisoner he owed him Money, and the Prisoner said the Deceased had robbed him. What have I robbed you of, says the Deceased? I'll tell you said the Prisoner, and immediately he up with his Hand, and struck the Deceased a Blow, and he fell backward, with his Head against some Stone Steps, after which he never stirred. I told the Prisoner he had killed the Man; upon which he ran across the Road, but I followed him, and caught him by the Collar, telling him again, he had killed the Man. The Prisoner said, if I did not let him go, he would serve me in the same Manner: but I brought him back, and he took the Deceased by the Hand, and said he was alive. Upon the Mob's beginning to rise, the Prisoner got away again: I got one of our Men to assist me, and we pursued him to St Giles's. When we came up with the Prisoner, he struck at the Man, and told him he was not a proper Officer; so I ran to get a Constable, and after he had been to view the Deceased, he took charge of the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see me knock him down?</p>
               <p>Cheatbam. Yes: He gave him such a Blow on the left Side of the Head, that it might have been heard the Length of this Court. After which he bled very much out of his Nose and Ears.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. In what Manner did the Deceased fall?</p>
               <p>Cheatham. The Deceased stood with his Back against the Houses, and the Prisoner stood with his Face towards the Deceased, who fell with his Head upon the Stone Steps. - The Prisoner gave him but one Blow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person194">
                  Alexander 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person194" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person194" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at my Master White's when the Deceased and Cheatham went out together. In two Minutes Time he came back and said, Samuel (the Deceased) was killed, and the Man who killed him was gone down the Road. At Cheatham's Desire, I went down the Road, and passed the Place where the Deceased lay, without looking at him. When I came to the Sign of the Coach and Horses, I saw the Prisoner, and seized him. He made a Punch at me, and said I was not a proper Officer, - I should not hold him. But I held him, and told him he should find me Officer proper enough to do it.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person195">
                  Thomas 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person195" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person195" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. On the 21st of December, about two o'Clock, I was sent for to view the Deceased. I found a small Contusion on the left Temporal Muscle. In the Cranium, and between the Membranes of the Brain, and the Cerebellum, there was a large Quantity of coagulated Blood. Upon dividing the Membranes of the Brain, I found about two Ounces more, which I take to have been the immediate Cause of his Death. I am apt to think these Appearances were occasioned more by the Fall than by the Blow; and that the Blow could not have caused so violent a Concussion, as to have produced so much coagulated Blood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person196">
                  Thomas 
                  Makewell 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person196" type="surname" value="Makewell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person196" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. On Wednesday the 19th of December, Cheatham fetched me to the Coach and Horses, to take charge of a Man, who had killed another. I went thither and found the Prisoner; but before I would take charge of him, I went to see the deceased. I found him<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160015"></xptr> lying along, with his left Temple bloody. Then I went back to the Prisoner and said, - poor Man, I am sorry to take you into Custody, but I must bring you to Justice, - the Man is dead, - and so I carried him before Colonel De Veil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person197">
                  Alexander 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person197" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person197" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Not above half an Hour before this Accident happened, the Deceased listed up an Anvil upon the Block, of 2 Hundred Weight.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Deceased had robbed me of half a Guinea, and 3 s. and meeting him that Day in Tyburn Road, I told him it was very hard he should rob the Spittal, and use me ill; who had been so good a Friend to him. He said he would pay me at some Rate or other, and desired me not to hurt him. I told him I would not hurt him, but Justice should, and so I endeavoured to lay hold of him, we struggled together, and he struck me twice, and I believe I hit him a Blow in the Face; a Child of 2 Years old might have stood against it, but upon this Blow he slipped down, on the Paved-Stones, and fell with his Head against a Step. I thought the poor Man had been in a Fit; I am as innocent of designing to murder him, as the Child unborn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-24-person198">
                  Brian 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person198" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person198" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person199">
                  William 
                  Birt 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person199" type="surname" value="Birt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person200">
                  Francis 
                  Waeker 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person200" type="surname" value="Waeker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person200" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person201">
                  Thomas 
                  Cheney 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person201" type="surname" value="Cheney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person201" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person202">
                  Robert 
                  Sidney 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person202" type="surname" value="Sidney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person202" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400116-24-person203">
                  Francis 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17400116-24-person203" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person203" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner the Character of a quiet Man, not addicted to Cruelty; and some of them said, the Deceased was a wicked, poor Wretch. <rs id="t17400116-24-verdict124" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-verdict124" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-verdict124" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter only
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400116-24-punish125" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-punish125" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-24-punish125" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-24-defend189 t17400116-24-punish125"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
