<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400522-6">
               <interp inst="t17400522-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-6" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400522-6" type="date" value="17400522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-6-off39-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-defend72 t17400522-6-off39 t17400522-6-verdict42"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400522-6-off39-c59" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-defend74 t17400522-6-off39 t17400522-6-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>253, 254. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-6-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     West 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend72" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend72" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400522-6-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Armstrong 
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend74" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend74" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-defend74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17400522-6-defloc38">St Giles's Cripple-Gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-defloc38" type="placeName" value="St Giles's Cripple-Gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-defloc38" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-defend72 t17400522-6-defloc38"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-defend74 t17400522-6-defloc38"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17400522-6-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Tankard, val. 7l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400522-6-victim76" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Coster 
                        <interp inst="t17400522-6-victim76" type="surname" value="Coster"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-6-victim76" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400522-6-victim76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-off39 t17400522-6-victim76"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400522-6-cd40" type="crimeDate">May 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-off39 t17400522-6-cd40"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-6-person77">
                  William 
                  Coster 
               <interp inst="t17400522-6-person77" type="surname" value="Coster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person77" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a Silver Tankard last Friday. The 2 Prisoners came into my House, (the <placeName id="t17400522-6-crimeloc41">Sign of the Bell and Grenadier in Grub-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-crimeloc41" type="placeName" value="Sign of the Bell and Grenadier in Grub-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400522-6-crimeloc41" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-off39 t17400522-6-crimeloc41"></join> ) about 9 in the Morning, and called for a Tankard of Beer. They were served with the Beer, in a Tankard without a Lid; and after this, they sent for some Salmon, and then called for another Quart of Beer, which was carried to them in the Tankard which I lost. While they were drinking in the House, I had a Friend came to see me, and he said with me till 12 o'Clock; I then asked him to step into the Kitchen and dine with me. While we were at Dinner, we heard the Door open, and my Wife asked me, if the Women had paid their Reckoning? I told her yes. But have you taken care of the Tankard said she? upon this I stepp'd cut to look after it, and both Tankard and Women were gone. I saw it brought to them. They had it, and no one else; for my Friend and I were drinking at the same Table, and they shoved themselves into our Company, and said they would drink with us. Their Reckoning came to 8 d. which they paid before my Friend and I went into the Kitchen to Dinner; and while we were at Dinner I heard the Door open; upon which I stepped into the Room to look for the Tankard, and missing it, I went out of Doors after the Prisoner. West I took in a Minute, upon the Spot, but she had nothing upon her. However, I carried her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17400522-6-person78">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17400522-6-person78" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Guildhall, who committed her to Newgate; and just as I was carrying her thither, Mr Bennet a Goldsmith, came to Guildhall with the Tankard, and the other Prisoner, ( Armstrong, ) but Sir John Thompson being gone from the Hall, she was carried before my Lord Mayor, who committed her likewise. I saw the Tankard which Mr Bennet brought with him; 'tis mine, and 'tis mark'd W. C M. This is the same which the Prisoners had before them, and which I owned at Guildhall: about three Months ago, it cost me 8 l. 16 s. as near as I can remember; but it was upwards of 8 l. I am sure. I have never seen the Prisoners since they were committed 'till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-6-person79">
                  Joseph 
                  Reader 
               <interp inst="t17400522-6-person79" type="surname" value="Reader"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person79" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday the 16th of this Month, I went to Mr. Coster's to drink a Pint of Beer. The two Prisoners were drinking in the same Room, and sent for some Salmon, and asked us to eat some. About 12 o'Clock Mr Coster invited me to dine with him; and I went backwards with him into his Kitchen. While we were at Dinner, we heard the Door open, and the Prisoners being left with a Silver Tankard before them, Mrs Coster asked her Husband if he had taken Care of the Tankard, and told him the Creatures were gone. He went immediately from Table, and missing the Tankard, he ran out into the Street and took West. She was carried before Sir John Thompson, who committed her: and before we got away from Guildhall, the Gold-Smith brought Armstrong, and the Tankard, which was directly own'd by Mr Coster.</p>
               <p>Mr Bennet. The Prisoner, Armstrong, came last friday Morning to my Shop, and offered this Tankard to Sale. I asked her whether she sold it for herself, or for another Person? She told me it was her own. How long have you had it, said I? She said her Husband bought it about 4 years ago; but now she was necessitated to sell it. I desired to know what I must give her for it? She told me, she supposed, I could not give less than<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174005220008"></xptr> 5 s. an Ounce. Why you undervalue it, says I, - 'tis worth more: If I buy it, I will give more; but what is your Husband's Name? She said his Name was Armstrong. I had got the Handle of the Tankard in my Hand, and having look'd at it, I told her, there were no such Letters upon it. My Husband (said she) bought it at Second-hand, and there are not the Letters of his Name upon it. I bid her tell me what the Letters were, upon the Handle: She turn'd herself round, but could not recollect what they were. Then I asked if she knew any body hereabout? No. Can you send for People of Credit, who will satisfy me 'tis your own? If you can, you shall have it again. Why, says she, will you stop my Tankard? I told her I would. Then she began to make a Noise, upon which I told her, I would stop her and the Tankard too; and I sent my Servant for a Constable, and carried her and the Tankard to Guildhall, where I met with the Man who had lost it: He own'd it, and the sitting Alderman being gone, she was carried before the Lord-Mayor who committed her.</p>
               <p>West. I had been drinking with this Armstrong at the Prosecutor's House, and went home. The Prosecutor came after me, and took me in my own Yard.</p>
               <p>Coster. I pursu'd her, and took her in her own House, and there are but two Doors between the House where she lives and mine.</p>
               <p>West. I own I was drinking with her, but I know nothing of the Tankard.</p>
               <p>Armstrong. Yes; we had both been drinking plentifully; but I know nothing of the Tankard.</p>
               <p>Jury. How long was it after you miss'd the Tankard, before you took West?</p>
               <p>Coster. I took her in 2 Minutes after I had miss'd it; but I saw nothing of Armstrong, 'till she was brought to Guildhall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400522-6-person80">
                  Thomas 
                  Molding 
               <interp inst="t17400522-6-person80" type="surname" value="Molding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person80" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd Part of Mr Bennet's Evidence. West <rs id="t17400522-6-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>. Armstrong <rs id="t17400522-6-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400522-6-punish44" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400522-6-punish44" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400522-6-defend74 t17400522-6-punish44"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
