<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490906-11">
               <interp inst="t17490906-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-11" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490906-11" type="date" value="17490906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490906-11-off39-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-11-defend112 t17490906-11-off39 t17490906-11-verdict42"></join>
         
               <p>493. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490906-11-defend112" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Mooney 
                  <interp inst="t17490906-11-defend112" type="surname" value="Mooney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-defend112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-defend112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17490906-11-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490906-11-victim114" type="victimName">
                           Seymour 
                           Stocker 
                        <interp inst="t17490906-11-victim114" type="surname" value="Stocker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-11-victim114" type="given" value="Seymour"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490906-11-victim114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-11-off39 t17490906-11-victim114"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   the younger, did make an assault, putting him in bodily fear and danger of his life; 1 gold-watch, val. 10 l. 1 pair of silver shoe buckles, val. 10 s. did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-11-cd40" type="crimeDate">Aug. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-11-off39 t17490906-11-cd40"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-11-person115">
                  Seymour 
                  Stocker 
               <interp inst="t17490906-11-person115" type="surname" value="Stocker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person115" type="given" value="Seymour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was returning home from Stepney, near <placeName id="t17490906-11-crimeloc41">Ratcliff-cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-11-crimeloc41" type="placeName" value="Ratcliff-cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490906-11-crimeloc41" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-11-off39 t17490906-11-crimeloc41"></join>, Aug. 20, between the hours of 10 and 11 at night, a man met me and presented a pistol to my breast, and told me if I spoke a word he would shoot me, demanding my money and watch immediately; then there came up a second person, which I believe to be the prisoner at the bar, but I cannot swear that; this second person took my silver buckles out of my shoes; he took me by the collar, and trip'd up my heels, and laid upon me while the other robbed another person; it was the first person that took my money and watch; I have omitted mentioning the money in the indictment, because I know not the sum; after they had robb'd the other man, they brought him and laid him down by me, telling us they would shoot us if we offer'd to stir; then when they were at a distance we got up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-11-person116">
                  Seymour 
                  Stocker 
               <interp inst="t17490906-11-person116" type="surname" value="Stocker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person116" type="given" value="Seymour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , sen. I am father to the prosecuter ; on Saturday the 26th of August, a porter came to my house from the Crown and Magpy, which was the place I advertis'd the watch to be brought to; he told me a person had stopp'd the watch, &amp;c. I went as directed by the porter, to Mr. Keates, a pawnbroker in Chandos-street, there I describ'd the watch, and proved it to be the property of my son.</p>
               <p>Isabelia Keates. The woman that brought this watch to me , call'd herself Judith Wallice; the woman said, it was Capt. Bayley's; but having seen the advertisement, thought proper to stop it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490906-11-person117">
                  Judith 
                  Wallice 
               <interp inst="t17490906-11-person117" type="surname" value="Wallice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person117" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I carried this watch to Mrs. Keates's, I had it of the prisoner at the bar; the prisoner came to me that time, and ask'd me how I did, after my being blooded (I had been blooded the day before by Dr. Swinney,) who had two men with him at the time; I suppose the prisoner to be one of them; he ask'd me if I knew a pawnbroker ; I said yes, I did; he ask'd me if I knew ever a gentleman who wore a gold watch; I said, Capt. Bayley wore one; then he shew'd me this watch, and said it was the captain's, and desired me to go and pawn it for the captain; he wanted 20 guineas upon it, and if I could not get 20 I must get 15. and he said, he would give me and the pawnbroker half a guinea each. Before I went to the pawnbroker, I went with him to his room; there were 2 men he call'd ship-mates; we came all out together, and I went to the pawnbroker's; I told her I wanted 20 guineas on Capt. Bayley's watch;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174909060009"></xptr> she said it was not worth it; she stopp'd it: I went to the prisoner, and told him it was stopp'd; he seem'd angry and went away. Then I went to the prosecutor's father and gave him an account of the prisoner's person, and they took him: he was carried before the justice and committed.</p>
               <p>There were witnesses appear'd to prove he was ill in bed at the same time, but full of contradiction amongst themselves.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490906-11-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17490906-11-punish43" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490906-11-punish43" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490906-11-defend112 t17490906-11-punish43"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
