<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-7">
               <interp inst="t17460903-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-7" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-7" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-7-off25-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-7-defend84 t17460903-7-off25 t17460903-7-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>288. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-defend84" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     May 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-7-defend84" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-defend84" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-defend84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-7-off25" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-off25" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-off25" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 6 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-victim86" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Wilkins 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-7-victim86" type="surname" value="Wilkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-victim86" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-victim86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-7-off25 t17460903-7-victim86"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , the <rs id="t17460903-7-cd26" type="crimeDate">30th of August</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-7-off25 t17460903-7-cd26"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-7-person87">
                  James 
                  Wilkins 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person87" type="surname" value="Wilkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person87" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. The Prisoner at the Bar took from me two Half Crowns, a Shilling, and a Six-pence.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. I think on the 30th of August; last Saturday Night, between Eleven and Twelve, coming thro' Drury-Lane, a Woman of the Town pick'd me up.</p>
               <p>Q. What, the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. No, my Lord, the Woman of the Town is now in Bridewell. We went to the House and went up Stairs, and went to Bed. There were two Rooms on a Floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go to lie together?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. In Holford's-Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else lie in the Room with you?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. I undress'd myself, my Lord, so did the Girl too; we were in Bed about Half an Hour; I did not close my Eyes; the Girl got up and went down Stairs; whether she went down to the Necessary-House, or something I can't tell what: When the Girl went down Stairs the Candle was burning; the Prisoner took the Breeches from under my Head, and two Half Crowns In my Sight. My Lord, there was a Candle burning in the Room all the while. I would not have suffer'd her to rob me, but I was in Danger of my Life, for there was another Man that lay with her; I knew I was in a disorderly House. After the Girl that went down Stairs came up again, I said that Woman in the next Room has robb'd me; I got up, and saw a Man in Bed with her; she was only in her Smock when she came into the Room to my Bed-side, With that the Girl that lay with me slipt down again, and said that she would not lie under Danger for no such Whores, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she there; did you charge both these Women?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. She that lay with me was charged as a disorderly Woman, no other Offence.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the disorderly Man?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. The disorderly Man was along with the disorderly Woman; but he hopes he shall do so no more.</p>

               <p>Q. So you did not struggle?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. No, my Lord, I knew what Sort of Gang they were; I have heard it commonly said when I have been in Company with Parish Officers, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to such Places ?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. My Lord, I was to blame.</p>
               <p>Jury. My Lord, we believe he has been there before now.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she do?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. She took my Breeches from under my Head, and took out two Half Crowns, a Shilling and a Six-pence.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what Clothes had she on when she came in to take the Money?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030010"></xptr>Wilkins. She came in her Smock, my Lord, into the Room; had nothing but her Smock and her Cap upon her Head.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-person88">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person88" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person88" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Will you ask him any Question ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When he miss'd his Money I desired he would search me; I had but one single Farthing in the World.</p>
               <p>Court. (to Wilkins.) She ask'd you to search her Pockets.</p>
               <p>Wilkins. No, my Lord, she ask'd me no such Thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He (Wilkins) said, D - n your Eyes you B - s, I have lost my Money among such a Parcel of B - s; but he could not tell by whom.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-person89">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person89" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person89" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-7-person90">
                  William 
                  Ellison 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person90" type="surname" value="Ellison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person90" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Ellison. I was call'd to take Charge of the Woman; when I came up Stairs this Woman was in Bed; she shut the Door against me, but I push'd it open; the Prosecutor told me he had lost his Money; the Woman said, if he had lost Buckles, or any thing, he should look about the Bed; he said, I charge that Woman with robbing me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he charge any other Woman?</p>
               <p>Ellison. He charg'd the other Woman for being in Company with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body else in the House?</p>
               <p>Ellison. Not above, but there were two or three Women below.</p>
               <p>Cartwright. I am Beadle.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Cartwright. When the Woman was brought to the Watch-house, the Prosecutor charg'd that Woman, the Prisoner, with the Robbery, which he sent to Newgate, and the Woman that was a Bed with him to the Round-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-person91">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person91" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person91" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, this Gentleman have went to Bed along with another Woman; he got up between Twelve and One o'Clock, and made a great Noise; this Woman here run away; with that he said, I will have one or t'other of you; he d - d, and said, I will have you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-person92">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person92" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person92" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to Wilkins) what Money had you when you went in there?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. I believe I had fourteen Shillings; I spent all to two Half Crowns and a Shilling.</p>
               <p>Court. This Woman you say, that took your Money from you, had only her Shift on; did you over find the Money upon her?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. I did not stir 'till the other Girl came up; I never attack'd her; she made the best of her Way, after she got the Money; she never was search'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-7-person93">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person93" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person93" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-7-person94">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smallman 
               <interp inst="t17460903-7-person94" type="surname" value="Smallman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person94" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-person94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say in behalf of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Smallman. Please you, my Lord, I saw that Gentleman come in with two Women; my Mother keeps the House; they had been up Stairs a considerable Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner at the Bar one of the two?</p>
               <p>Smallman. I never saw her in his Company; they had drunk a pretty deal of Liquor; both the Women that were with him sought about the Money they had of him; the Woman that got the Day he took up with him; and stripe and went to Bed; when he had been in Bed about three Hours, he call'd; I came up to him; he said he was very dry; the Woman that was in Bed with him had got from him; when I came up to him, he went to pay me; he took his Breeches, and he had no Money; he said, bless me, have I spent all my Money; so I fetch'd him up some Water.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he charge the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Smallman. I never saw her in his Company. One of the Women that laid with him is committed as a disorderly Woman to Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner at the Bar in your House?</p>
               <p>Smallman. I never saw the Prisoner with him.</p>
               <p>The Court censur'd the Constable and Watchman for not taking up the Man as well as the Woman.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-7-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-7-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
