<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490411-32">
               <interp inst="t17490411-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-32" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490411"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490411-32" type="date" value="17490411"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490411-32-off147-c158" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-32-defend210 t17490411-32-off147 t17490411-32-verdict150"></join>
         
               <note type="special">[Note: this edition of the Proceedings was misdated on the original title page. The correct dates for this meeting of the court are MAY 11, 12 and 13, 1749.]</note>
               <p>350. 
               <persName id="t17490411-32-defend210" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17490411-32-defend210" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-defend210" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-defend210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17490411-32-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four China bowls, val. 5 s. one tea-chest, val. 5 s. one China plate, val. 2 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17490411-32-victim212" type="victimName">
                     Abraham 
                     Lardon 
                  <interp inst="t17490411-32-victim212" type="surname" value="Lardon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-victim212" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-victim212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-32-off147 t17490411-32-victim212"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17490411-32-cd148" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-32-off147 t17490411-32-cd148"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-32-person213">
                  Abraham 
                  Lardon 
               <interp inst="t17490411-32-person213" type="surname" value="Lardon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-person213" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My parlour was robb'd April 16: I live in <placeName id="t17490411-32-crimeloc149">Holborn, King's head-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490411-32-crimeloc149" type="placeName" value="Holborn, King's head-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490411-32-crimeloc149" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490411-32-off147 t17490411-32-crimeloc149"></join> , and I had more things than are mentioned in the indictment. By making some complaint I had been robb'd. there was a person came to me and told me she could help me to my China, saying Mr. Unwin, that honest man a thief catcher had it, and he lives at the Magpye-tavern without Aldgate. As soon as I went into his house , he said, What will you please to drink? said I, we come to search your house: said he, you have no occasion to search my house, I know what you are come upon; and said, I'll fetch you the China, which at first he said he bought; then went up and brought down four bowls, his wife the plate, and the prisoner the tea-chest, which he had kept by him almost three weeks ; which he said he design'd to have advertiz'd .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search the house ?</p>
               <p>Lardon. No , they brought them without giving me the trouble .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490411-32-person214">
                  Samuel 
                  Unwin 
               <interp inst="t17490411-32-person214" type="surname" value="Unwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-person214" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The prisoner at the bar brought this China into my house; I was not at home at the time ; it was desir'd to be set by . My servant took it and the other things: they never were offer'd to me upon sale upon any account whatsoever; I did not know they were in my house till the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. What time were they brought in the day before ?</p>
               <p>Unwin . In the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you suspect these things to be stolen ?</p>
               <p>Unwin . I did before they were chalanged, and stop'd them .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you inquire of the prisoner how she came by it ?</p>
               <p>Unwin. Yes, I did .</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she then?</p>
               <p>Unwin . In my house. I keep the Magpye-tavern without Aldgate ; she came to ask for them, and I said I would stop them 'till I knew how she came by them; she said they belong'd to her master and mistress, saying, they had sent them out by her . When these<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174904110014"></xptr> people came in they said they wanted some China and a tea-chest which I had stop'd, so we carried them into the kitchen, where the prosecutor was .</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner lay in your house?</p>
               <p>Unwin. Three nights .</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you take her up?</p>
               <p>Unwin . I let her lie two nights in my house out of charity , that was Wednesday and Thursday , on the Friday I stop'd her in order to know how she came by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath do not you see counsel for the prisoner in this prosecution ?</p>
               <p>Unwin . I did not think any harm in that; I do .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Counsel. My lord, I receiv'd a guinea from this witness to plead for the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>The prisoner <rs id="t17490411-32-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490411-32-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> and Unwin committed to Newgate, and the next time the Grand Jury came into court they brought the following presentment, which was read.</p>
               <p>12th of May, 1749 .</p>
               <p>We the Grand Jury for the city of London, do most humbly and unanimously present, that Samuel Unwin of the parish of St. Botolp, Aldgate , London, vintner, now and for the space of two months last past, has kept an ill-govern'd and disorderly house, call'd or known by the name of the Magpye-tavern , situate in the said parish without Aldgate, that for the sake of wicked lucre and gain, he, during all the time aforesaid has harboured and entertained, and still harbours and entertains divers rogues, thieves, vagabonds, and other loose and disorderly persons in his said house, as well by day as by night, and that the said house ought to be suppressed, it appearing to us that the said Unwin's farther continuance to keep the same, must greatly tend to the corruption of the morals of youth, to the great endangerment of the publick safety, and to the great terror and nusance of all his Majesty's liege subjects inhabiting thereabouts .</p>
               <p>Signed by the names of all the Gentlemen of the Grand Jury .</p>
            </div1>
