<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-8">
               <interp inst="t17400116-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-8" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-8" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-8-off44-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-8-defend96 t17400116-8-off44 t17400116-8-verdict48"></join>
         
               <p>89. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-8-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Fletcher 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-8-defend96" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-defend96" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-defend96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400116-8-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, Value 40 s. from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-8-victim98" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Banks 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-8-victim98" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-8-victim98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-8-victim98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-8-off44 t17400116-8-victim98"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-8-cd45" type="crimeDate">January 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-8-off44 t17400116-8-cd45"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. On the 7th of this Instant January at Night, I was going to the upper Part of Moorfields. When I came to Fore-Street, in my way thither, I saw it was half an Hour past 8. When I had passed thro' <placeName id="t17400116-8-crimeloc46">Moor gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-8-crimeloc46" type="placeName" value="Moor gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-8-crimeloc46" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-8-off44 t17400116-8-crimeloc46"></join>, I stopped to make Water. While I stood against the Wall, the Prisoner came up, and accosted me with such obscene Language, as I believe will be improper to mention in this Place, the Substance of it was, to ask me whether I would lie with her; and at the same Instant, she put one Hand under my Cloaths, and pulled them up to my Stomach, and with the other Hand, she forcibly took my Watch out of my Fob. As soon as ever I had put my Cloaths in order, I pursued her, and took her by the Crown Alehouse; she was carried in there, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160010"></xptr> was searched, but we could not find the Watch. 'Twas a Silver Watch, with a Coat of Arms, and a Motto on it; with a Key and Seal thereto. Mr Spearing assisted me, and the Prisoner was carried to the Counter, for I was positive she took it. I looked to see what a Clock it was, between the Castle Alehouse and the Globe Tavern, and when I stopped to make Water, and took up my Cloaths, the Chain of the Watch, struck against my Hand; after which there was neither Man, Woman, nor Child near me, 'till the Prisoner came up, and took it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Time o'Night was it when you saw your Watch?</p>
               <p>Mr. Banks. It was half an Hour past 8.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it not dark?</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. It was partly Moonlight, and something lighter, by Reason of the Snow, and there was the Light of the Lamps besides. I am positive the Prisoner is the Person who took my Watch. I felt her take it; she hurt me with one of her Hands in taking it; and I felt it slip away; but the Weather had made the Ground so slippery, that I could not run very fast after her; and when I pursued her, she walked faster than I could; else I had laid hold of her sooner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What was said to you by the Person that took your Watch, when she left you?</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. By the Prisoner's attempting to take my Watch, she made me drop one of my Gloves: So I bid her go along, and told her she had made me drop my Glove: upon which she very courteously stooped down to pick it up, and in so doing she took my Watch. I am subject to the Gravel, and could not make Water and lay hold of the Prisoner at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you tell me when I had given you your Glove, that you had lost your Watch?</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had I been in any Company after you lost your Watch?</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. No: She was never out of my Sight, 'till I took her. But I am informed that these Creatures have a very particular way of concealing such Things. She was searched by two Women, and it was not found.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How far distant, was the Place where I was searched, from the Place where you lost your Watch?</p>
               <p>Mr Banks. The one was at <placeName id="t17400116-8-crimeloc47">Little Moorgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-8-crimeloc47" type="placeName" value="Little Moorgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-8-crimeloc47" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-8-off44 t17400116-8-crimeloc47"></join>, and the other at Great Moorgate. When I laid hold of her, she was stooping down, and said she was tying her Garter. She did not stoop down till she saw me near her. When I charged her with the Fact, she called me base Man; but I am positive she took it out of my Fob-Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Last Monday was se'en-night about 2 o'Clock, a Gentlewoman called upon me at my Lodgings in Upper Moorfields, and told me Mrs Bragg had got a Child's Coat for me to make. I cleaned myself, and went with her to Mrs Bragg's in St. Thomas Apostles, about 3. I staid and drank Tea, and after that I staid to Supper, and we had Mutton Chops. At 8 o'Clock I came out to go Home, and Mrs Bragg came with me to Little Moorgate, where I stopped to tie up my Garter, and then the Prosecutor came up and told me he had lost his Watch, and carried me into the Alehouse. There was a Woman in the Bar, and 2 Women were with her, who carried me into a Room and searched me, but found nothing upon me. The Woman of the House, asked him, why he brought me in there? He told them he did not bring me in, but seeing me go in, he followed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-8-person99">
                  Amelia 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person99" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person99" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went that Night to the Crown Alehouse (Mr Hutton's) for a Pot of Beer, and heard a Woman crying in the little Room, Sir, you are not to beat me. I did not see the Gentleman beat hear, but I heard him say he had lost his Watch. Where did you lose it, says I? 'Tis lost in the House (said he) for ought I know, and I will make them find it. I did not hear any Thing of it's having been lost out of his Pocket, nor of the Woman's having been searched.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-8-person100">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadwater 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person100" type="surname" value="Broadwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person100" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner makes my Children's Coats, and I have employed her for my Friends; I know no Ill of her: She has always used me with Sincerity and Handsomness. I keep my Father's House, and he has a Place at Blackwell-Hall: I have known her 4 Years, and she gets her living this Way, and I am sure she follows her Business close, to get a Livelihood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-8-person101">
                  Mary 
                  Linton 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person101" type="surname" value="Linton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person101" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about 6 Years. I have laid her of 2 of her Children, one of them is about 2 Years old, and the other is almost 4. I believe she has good Business and keeps her Family as an honest Woman. Her general Character is, that she is a very honest Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-8-person102">
                  Mary 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person102" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person102" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-8-person103">
                  John 
                  Payd 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person103" type="surname" value="Payd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and - Crampton gave the Prisoner a good Character.</p>
               <p>- Bragg. On the Saturday before Twelfth-Day, Mrs Pain desired me to send the Prisoner to her about a Child's Coat. Accordingly I went to her, on Twelfth-Day, (the 7th of January) about 2 o'Clock, and told her Mrs Pain's Business. The Prisoner put on a clean Gown, and went with me to Mrs Pain's, and we staid there till 8 o'Clock; then we came out together, and I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160011"></xptr> left her at Little Moorgate, and kept strait on my self towards Whitechapple I have known her Years, and never heard her Character blasted in my Life.</p>
               <p>- Pain. The Prisoner was at my House the 7th of January, between 2 and 3 o'Clock, with Bragg, and they staid till about 8 o'Clock, I had desired Bragg to send her to me, to make a Coat. I have employed her, and have helped her to Customers, and was surprised when I heard of this Accident. They drank Tea with me, and eat a Mutton-Chop, and it being Twelsth-Night, I pressed them to stay longer.</p>
               <p>Mr Banks gave an Account of his having been offered 20 l. or a Watch that ran upon Diamonds, to stisle the Prosecution; and Mr 
               <persName id="t17400116-8-person104">
                  Caleb 
                  Rophey 
               <interp inst="t17400116-8-person104" type="surname" value="Rophey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person104" type="given" value="Caleb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed that he saw a Watch delivered into Mr Banks's Hands (not the Watch he lost) for this Purpose: but neither of them, could take upon them to say, these Proposals were made with the Prisoner's Privity or Consent. Mr Banks added, that he had heard the Prisoner had a bad Character, and said she was well known when she was committed; that he heard she had lately served a Countryman in the same Manner, and had been at the Old-Bailey before, for such an Offence. <rs id="t17400116-8-verdict48" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-8-verdict48" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
