<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401204-28">
               <interp inst="t17401204-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-28" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401204-28" type="date" value="17401204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401204-28-off156-c159" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-defend222 t17401204-28-off156 t17401204-28-verdict161"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401204-28-off159-c159" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-defend222 t17401204-28-off159 t17401204-28-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>38. 
               
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Ridout 
                  <interp inst="t17401204-28-defend222" type="surname" value="Ridout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-defend222" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401204-28-defloc154">St. John Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-28-defloc154" type="placeName" value="St. John Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-28-defloc154" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-defend222 t17401204-28-defloc154"></join>, <rs id="t17401204-28-deflabel155" type="occupation">Grocer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-defend222 t17401204-28-deflabel155"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17401204-28-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               that at a Sessions of Goal-Delivery , &amp;c. at Justice-Hall, in the Old-Bailey , on Thursday the 4th of Dec. before the Rt. Hon. Humphry Parsons, Esq; Mayor of the City of London, &amp;c. &amp;c. 
                     <persName id="t17401204-28-person223">
                        William 
                        Oliver 
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person223" type="surname" value="Oliver"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-28-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17401204-28-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   was by due Course of Law convicted for that on the 30th of Sept. 320 lb. wt. of Pepper, the Goods of the <rs id="t17401204-28-viclabel157" type="occupation">
                     
                        <persName id="t17401204-28-victim224" type="victimName">
                           united
                            Company of Merchants trading to the East Indies
                        <interp inst="t17401204-28-victim224" type="surname" value="Company of Merchants trading to the East Indies"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17401204-28-victim224" type="given" value="united"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17401204-28-victim224" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off156 t17401204-28-victim224"></join>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off159 t17401204-28-victim224"></join>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-victim224 t17401204-28-viclabel157"></join>,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174012040011"></xptr> did steal, &amp;c. and that afterwards on the <rs id="t17401204-28-cd158" type="crimeDate">30th of Sept</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off156 t17401204-28-cd158"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off159 t17401204-28-cd158"></join>. he the said Ridout, the said Pepper did receive and have, &amp;c. knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a 2d Time indicted for <rs id="t17401204-28-off159" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-off159" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-off159" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 160 lb. of Pepper, knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Councel for the Prosecution set forth, that the Crime with which the Prisoner stood charg'd, was of the most heinous Nature; that it is owing to such Persons that so many Enormities are daily committed; and unless there were People to receive Goods from Offenders, there would consequently be fewer, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The Record of Oliver's Conviction being read, the Witnesses were called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-person225">
                  Joseph 
                  Burges 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person225" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person225" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner very well.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you concern'd in this Hoy?</p>
               <p>Burges. Yes , I was Mate of her; we had a Loading of Pepper from an East-India Man, in Sept. last was twelve Months.</p>
               <p>Councel. Give an Account where you saw the Prisoner, and what passed between him and you?</p>
               <p>Burges. He came to us at <placeName id="t17401204-28-crimeloc160">Botolph Wharf</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-28-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Botolph Wharf"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401204-28-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off156 t17401204-28-crimeloc160"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401204-28-off159 t17401204-28-crimeloc160"></join>, and beckon'd me on Shore; when I came to him, he asked me what Craft we? I told him Pepper, he then asked me if he could Trade with me? I said I did not know till I saw what Officers would be put on Board us. He asked me how we got into the Hold? I told him we had Keys, but I had no Bags to put any Thing in; he said if I would go Home with him, he would give me Bags; I accordingly did, and he gave me two Bags, which we filled with the Company's Pepper . After we had filled them, we put them into the Boat, and carried them in at the Prisoner's Back Door, at Wapping New-Stairs, and he paid us for them.</p>
               <p>Councel. What Time of Night was it that you carry'd the Pepper to his House?</p>
               <p>Burges. It was between 9 and 10 at Night, and quite dark.</p>
               <p>Councel. Can you tell the Quantity?</p>
               <p>Burges. Each Bag contained 112 lb. but the Prisoner struck off some for Dirt and Tare.</p>
               <p>Councel. Who took the Pepper from you out of the Boat?</p>
               <p>Burges. Mr. Ridout himself was at the Door, he receiv'd it from us, and paid us 10 l. for it. After he had weigh'd it, he put the Pepper into a Tub, and gave me one of the Bags again to get some more; and the next Night we got 130 lb. Wt.</p>
               <p>Councel. Who was this 10 l. paid to?</p>
               <p>Burges. Clowes took his own and his Partner Greenwood's Shares ; I took mine, and Oliver his, we had 50 s. piece .</p>
               <p>Councel. Was there any Bill of Parcels made?</p>
               <p>Burges. No, I never saw any.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did Ridout pay you the Money himself?</p>
               <p>Burges. Yes, and he was in the Room when we divided it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Q. You say you told me, that you had the Keys of the Hold; where was it?</p>
               <p>Burges. It was ashore on the Key; and there was no body but us two present; it was the same Night as we came up, and we took the Pepper directly.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Who put the Pepper into the Bags?</p>
               <p>Burges. Greenwood and I; the Master of the Vessel, and the other Officer haul'd it into the Cabbin.</p>
               <p>Councel How much was allowed for Dirt and Tare?</p>
               <p>Burges. Twelve Pounds.</p>
               <p>Councel. Where was the Pepper weigh'd?</p>
               <p>Burges. It was weigh'd in his Warehouse, where his great Scales hang.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did any of his Servants assist him in weighing it?</p>
               <p>Burges. No, there was none of the Family present but himself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q You speak of a Back-Door; is it not a common passage to carry in all Goods that come by Water?</p>
               <p>Burges. I can't tell; I know they do carry in Goods there, and they call it a Back-Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q Is it not a common place?</p>
               <p>Burges . I never carry'd Goods in at any other Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. On your Oath, did you never declare to any body that this Pepper was run?</p>
               <p>Burges. No, I never said so in my Life.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was you in the Service of the Company then?</p>
               <p>Burges. Yes, we had our Loading from one of their Ships, and this Pepper was taken out of our Hold at Botolph Wharf, where we lay sometimes 2 or 3 Days before any body come to touch our Goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-person226">
                  Samuel 
                  Clowes 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person226" type="surname" value="Clowes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person226" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the latter End of Sept. in the Year 39, I was boarded on the Thomas and 
               <persName id="t17401204-28-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Hoy 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person227" type="surname" value="Hoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which was loaden with Bags of Pepper. About 10 at Night, Burges open'd the Hold Doors, and fill'd 2 Bags; they were carried to Ridout's House . I did not see him fill the Bags; but there was no body but him and Greenwood below; they were put into the Boat, and I and Oliver walked down by Land to Ridout's, where I saw him pay 10 l. and I suppose on Account of the Pepper. The Money was equally divided amongst us , and the Prisoner said he should be very proud of such another Freight.</p>
               <p>Councel. Who was present at that Time?</p>
               <p>Clowes. There were Burges, Oliver, and myself.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you hear any Discourse about the Price?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174012040012"></xptr>Clowes. No; the Pepper had been weigh'd, and carry'd away before I got there; but I saw the Prisoner pay the Money, and I believe he was present at the Division of it.</p>
               <p>Councel. Were any of his Apprentices or Servants present?</p>
               <p>Clowes. No, I saw none, - in my Opinion it seem'd to be a private Transaction.</p>
               <p>Councel. Was there any Receipt given for this Money?</p>
               <p>Clowes. No, not that I saw.</p>
               <p>Councel . Did you drink any Thing at the Prisoner's House?</p>
               <p>Clowes. Yes, we had some Punch, but we paid for it ourselves.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did not you pretend that this Pepper was a Perquisite ?</p>
               <p>Clowes. No, I never said so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. You say that Burges put the Pepper into the Boat; who went with him?</p>
               <p>Clowes. There was no body but Burges and Robinson in the Boat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Who paid for the Punch?</p>
               <p>Clowes. Mr. Ridout sells Liquors; we treated him with the Punch, and paid for it among our selves.</p>
               <p>Councel. How many Bags were open'd, to take out this Pepper?</p>
               <p>Clowes. I can't tell; - I was walking on Deck with Oliver at that Time.</p>
               <p>Burges. About 18 or 20 were opened; we took about 8 or 10 lb. out of each Bag, and sew'd them up again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-person228">
                  Matthew 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person228" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person228" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went in the Boat with the Pepper.</p>
               <p>Councel. Where did you carry it?</p>
               <p>Robinson. To the Prisoner's House, at Wapping-new Stairs.</p>
               <p>Councel. What Time of Night was it?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I can't exactly tell the Hour; but it was dark.</p>
               <p>Councel. When you came to the Prisoner's House, who took the Pepper out of the Boat?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Burges took it out of the Boat, and carried it in at the Back-door.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you go into the House with Burges?</p>
               <p>Robinson. Yes; I went in, and the Prisoner gave me a Dram, and sent me about my Business, to take Care of the Boat.</p>
               <p>Councel. I would ask you whether there were any People at Work on the Keys?</p>
               <p>Robinson. No, when we carried the Pepper away, the Porters had done Work on the Keys.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Who paid you for your Boat?</p>
               <p>Robinson. It was not my Boat; - that belong'd to the Hoy.</p>
               <p>Councel. We shall now shew, that Greenwood is not to be found, although the Strictest Enquiry has been made after him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Foster. I am one of the Inspectors of the River; and it is my Business to see that the Tidesmen do their Duty. I find by the Register, that these 2 Men Clowes and Greenwood were at this Time boarded as Watchmen, on the Thomas and 
               <persName id="t17401204-28-person229">
                  Mary 
                  Hoy 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person229" type="surname" value="Hoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person229" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Councel. Please to give an Account what Enquiry has been made after Greenwood?</p>
               <p>Mr. Foster. Since the Discovery of the Hoy's being robb'd, the strictest Search has been made after Greenwood, but to no purpose; and he has absconded from his Duty ever since, although he has given Security for the Performance of it. This Warrant in my Hand is against him - I received it from Sir 
               <persName id="t17401204-28-person230">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person230" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            
               </p>
               <p>The Warrant was read.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier Sworn.</p>
               <p>Councel. What was the Price of Pepper in Sept. Sale, 1739.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. In that Sale, the Company's Pepper sold from 10 d 78ths, to 11 d. farthing the Average was above 11. They allow the Buyer 6 l. 10 s. Discount, and likewise the home Consumption Duty, which is about 4 d. per lb. so that in the whole Bag it might come to a Groat less than 12 d. per lb.</p>
               <p>Councel. What was it worth at that Time, every Duty paid?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier . The nearest Computation that can be made, is 14 d. farthing, it was worth so much at that Time, Duty paid .</p>
               <p>Councel. Suppose a Man had come to you, and offer'd you Pepper at 12 d. per lb. what should you have thought of it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. If Pepper had been offer'd me at 13 d. per lb. I should not have thought it honestly come by.</p>
               <p>Councel. Is there a large profit on this Pepper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. In the Wholesale Way, there is not a half-penny per lb I believe all the Year round.</p>
               <p>Councel. How much is generally allowed for the Tare of each Bag ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. The Company allow 15 lb. for the Tare of a Bag of 112 lb. for a Bag of 100 lb. 12 lb. Tare is too much.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Suppose the Pepper had been damaged, or put into foul Bags, what then?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. Damaged Pepper will not bear the price of good to be sure; but putting it out of one Bag into another will not hurt it, provided it does not come to any Wet, and the Pepper be found at first.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Is there not a great deal of Waste and Dirt in this Pepper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Gambier. In the last Sale, 5400 Bags of Pepper were sold, and out of those, there were 116 Bags of Dust; but these Bags of Dust do not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174012040013"></xptr> weigh so much as Bags of Pepper, although they are of the same Size</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17401204-28-person231">
                  Robert 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person231" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person231" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Scarborough Pepper in 39, after it had been sitted sold for about 11 d. Farthing to 3 8ths per lb. and I believe it might amount to about 14 d, Farthing Duty paid.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-person232">
                  Mark 
                  Hudson 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person232" type="surname" value="Hudson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person232" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Torin sold Pepper after the Company's Sale in Sept. was 12 Months , for 11 d. per lb. and the Buyer paid the Duty, but we never buy any but for Exportation.</p>
               <p>It was here urg'd on the Part of the Defendant, that Oliver in Point of Law could not be deem'd a Principal; but that in Order to have brought the Defendant to Trial, Burges and Robinson, who were principally concern'd in stealing these Goods, should first have been convicted, &amp;c. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Defence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had known Burges some Years, and believ'd him to be a very honest Man; I have bought China Bowls and Handkerchiefs of him, and when I bought this Pepper, I thought it might be run, but could not think it was stolen; if I had, I never should have given 1 s. per lb. for it. My Servants will make it appear, that I bought it full of Dust; they brought it to the fore part of the Shop to clean, and I sold it again for 13 d. Half-penny per lb.</p>
               <p>- The Prisoner's Sister. I remember there was some Pepper brought in at the Back Door, about 8 or 9 at Night; the next Day it was carry'd into the publick Shop, and clean'd; - there were a vast many Stones and Dirt in it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Did it look like a private Transaction?</p>
               <p>The Witness. No; I saw one Bag weigh'd, and it was emptied into some Casks in the Shop, which stood next the Street; - the Shop was not shut up, neither fore Door, nor back Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Is not this Door a common Passage for Goods?</p>
               <p>The Witness. Yes; all the Goods we ship off, or receive by Water come to this Door.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you see Burges bring these Bags?</p>
               <p>The Witness. No: I can't say who brought them.</p>
               <p>Councel. Does your Brother use to receive Goods in at this Door, at 9 o'Clock at Night?</p>
               <p>The Witness. Yes; according to the Time of the Tide.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you know whose Bags those were which were brought to your House, - are they your Brother's?</p>
               <p>The Witness. I can't say they are; I saw no Mark on them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401204-28-person233">
                  Alice 
                  Obermore 
               <interp inst="t17401204-28-person233" type="surname" value="Obermore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person233" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Servant to the Prisoner at the Time when this Pepper was brought. I can't say what Time it was; but it was brought in at the back Door, - as publickly as other Goods, and the next Day it was carry'd into the Shop and clean'd for Sale.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you see it weigh'd?</p>
               <p>Obermore. Yes, but I can't tell the Weight of it - I did not take much Notice of it.</p>
               <p>Councel. Where was it weigh'd?</p>
               <p>Obermore. In the same Place with all the large Goods.</p>
               <p>Councel. There was some Punch carry'd in, where was that?</p>
               <p>Obermore. It was in a Room joining to the publick Shop, and after the Money was paid.</p>
               <p>Councel. How much Money was there paid?</p>
               <p>Obermore. I can't tell how much, but I saw it paid down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Was this done in a private Manner?</p>
               <p>Obermore. No, it seem'd to be as publick as all the rest of his Dealings.</p>
               <p>Councel. Did you see Burges and Oliver there?</p>
               <p>Obermore. Yes, but I can't remember that I saw Clowes.</p>
               <p>Councel. Who divided the Money?</p>
               <p>Obermore. I can't tell, - I was in and out, and did not take much Notice.</p>
               <p>Councel. How many Persons partook of the Punch?</p>
               <p>Obermore. I can't say, - I remember only Burges and Oliver.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you remember your Master's giving a Dram to any Body?</p>
               <p>Obermore. The Lad came in, and I believe my Master did ask him to drink a Dram, and Oliver sent him about his Business.</p>
               <p>Councel. Do you know how much your Master was to give for the Pepper?</p>
               <p>Obermore. A Shilling a Pound, I believe.</p>
               <p>Councel. I would ask you, whether there is not a fore Shop, a back Shop, and a Room between?</p>
               <p>Obermore. Yes, there is a Door to keep the Air out, but it was wide open.</p>
               <p>Councel. Where do the Casks stand which this Pepper was emptied into, in the fore Shop or the back Shop?</p>
               <p>Obermore. In the fore Shop, just by the Door.</p>
               <p>Councel. Where was it weigh'd?</p>
               <p>Obermore. In the back Shop?</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q. Are there any other great Scales beside those in the back Shop?</p>
               <p>Obermore. No, none that will weigh 100 wt. of Goods.</p>
               <p>Councel. Were any of your Master's Servants present at the weighing of the Goods?</p>
               <p>Obermore. No, he had no Apprentice, nor Journeyman at that Time; he used to serve in the Shop himself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174012040014"></xptr>The Prisoner's Sister again. I used to serve when my Brother was out , and used to sell this Pepper for 14 or 15 d. per lb. and by the Ounce for five Farthings, after it was clean'd .</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. I bought Pepper of the Company in September was Twelve-months, from 10 d 78ths , to 11 d. 1 8th per lb. 6 and a half per Cent. Discount; which reduces the price to 10 d. Farthing; the Duty is near a Groat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Q, Suppose you should buy Pepper unclean'd, would you give 1 s. per lb. for it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. I never buy any unclean'd.</p>
               <p>Councel. What would you say, it a Person brought you Pepper for 12 d per lb.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. It might not be worth the Money .</p>
               <p>Councel. I speak Sir, of that Pepper in Sept. Sale, 39, what should you think if it was offer'd you for 1 s per lb.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. I would not have bought it at all, for I should have thought it had been run, or -</p>
               <p>Councel. Or what?</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. Or otherwise come by.</p>
               <p>Councel. This Pepper was weigh'd; could the Prisoner be a Judge whether it was worth 15 d. or 12 d. per lb.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marlow. Yes, I think so. I have known the Prisoner a great many Years; he always bore the Character of a fair Dealer, therefore I don't think he would buy Goods knowing them to be stolen.</p>


               <p>Mr. Shippey. I have known the Prisoner 5 or 6 Years; and he always bore the Character of an honest fair Dealer.</p>
               <p>Mr. SHERIFF Marshall. I have known him a great many Years; he always behav'd as an honest Man, and I never heard his Character call'd in Question.</p>
               <p>Mr Roberts, Mr. Camden, Mr. White, Mr. Neaves, Mr. Burnet, Mr. Pool, Mrs. Ridout, Mr. Earle, Mr. Clarke, Mr. Windsor , Mr. Priestly, the Rev. Mr. Wilson, and Mr. Hudson, gave the Prisoner the Character of a very honest Man, and did not believe that he would buy Goods, knowing them to be stolen</p>
               <p>The Jury withdrew, and after a short Stay, return'd and brought the Prisoner in <rs id="t17401204-28-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Not Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was likewise <rs id="t17401204-28-verdict162" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401204-28-verdict162" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted on the second Indictment
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
