<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-11">
               <interp inst="t17400903-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-11" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-11" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-11-off72-c98" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-11-defend114 t17400903-11-off72 t17400903-11-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>375. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-11-defend114" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Kittison 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-11-defend114" type="surname" value="Kittison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-defend114" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-defend114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400903-11-defloc71">St. Giles's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-11-defloc71" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-11-defloc71" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-11-defend114 t17400903-11-defloc71"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-11-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing a pair of Bath-metal Shoe-Buckles, a Pair of Bath-metal Knee Buckles, a Hat, and a Pair of Leather Shoes
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17400903-11-victim115" type="victimName">
                  John 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17400903-11-victim115" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-victim115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-victim115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-11-off72 t17400903-11-victim115"></join>
                  </persName>
             . <rs id="t17400903-11-cd73" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-11-off72 t17400903-11-cd73"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Lambert. On the 28th of July last, I went out to a Club Feast , and happened to get a a little in Liquor, and so I came home late. When I came to my Door, instead of going into the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030011"></xptr> house, I sat down at the Door, and fell fast a-sleep. When I waked I found my Shoes were taken off my Feet, my Shoe-Buckles, Knee-Buckles, and my Hat were taken away too. The next Day I gave notice to the Shops, where such Things are bought, to stop them, if they came to be sold. The Shoes being a very remarkable pair of Shoes, - such a Pair, as I am sure, are not in London again, - they were brought the next day, to be sold at the next Shop, - next Door to where I live; but I don't know the Person's Name they were offered to. So I having given an Account in the Morning, that if such a remarkable Pair of Shoes should be offered to sale, they must stop them. I had notice that they were stopp'd, and I am positive they are the same which were taken off my Feet, while I was a-sleep at the Door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-11-person116">
                  John 
                  Fern 
               <interp inst="t17400903-11-person116" type="surname" value="Fern"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-person116" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner at the Bar came to sell these Pumps, (now under my arm) and this Man ( Lambert ) having given me Information of them the Day before, I stopped them , being a very particular Pair, - double channell'd, block heel'd, and stitch'd.</p>
               <p>Lambert . I have seen the Shoes several times, and they are mine.</p>
               <p>Fern. I keep 2 Cellars, and deal in the second-hand-way; I sell second-hand Boots and Shoes, and Lambert after he had lost his Shoes, went through our whole Trade, to give notice of them; and I swear the Prisoner offered to sell them to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I never saw the Prosecutor, or this Man, with my Eyes before.</p>
               <p>Fern. You was the Woman that offered them to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I went to sell them for another Woman, and so he stopped me.</p>
               <p>Fern. I asked her what she must have for them? She said she must have 18 d. Whose are they says I? Why says she, to tell you the Truth, I did a Man a Favour for them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing of the matter; I never saw that Witness in my Life. <rs id="t17400903-11-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-11-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
