<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-26">
               <interp inst="t17470429-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-26" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-26" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-26-off108-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-26-defend217 t17470429-26-off108 t17470429-26-verdict111"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-26-off108-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-26-defend219 t17470429-26-off108 t17470429-26-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>204, 205. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-defend217" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Masterman 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend217" type="surname" value="Masterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend217" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-defend219" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Phillips 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend219" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend219" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-defend219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17470429-26-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 50 Pounds Weight of Tallow, value 10 s. and twenty Pounds Weight of Cotton, value 30 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-victim221" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Greenhill 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-26-victim221" type="surname" value="Greenhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-victim221" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-victim221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-26-off108 t17470429-26-victim221"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470429-26-cd109" type="crimeDate">April 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-26-off108 t17470429-26-cd109"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person222">
                  William 
                  Greenhill 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person222" type="surname" value="Greenhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. In Newport-Market .</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Trade ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. A <rs id="t17470429-26-viclabel110" type="occupation">Tallowchandler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-26-victim221 t17470429-26-viclabel110"></join> .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I was called up about two o'Clock the 4th of April , there was 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person223">
                  Edward 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person223" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person223" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             stopped at my Door, with a Basket of Tallow he had taken out of my House .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him?</p>
               <p>Greenhill . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Court. It was dark then .</p>
               <p>Greenhill. Yes very dark.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be up?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I was called up, and I found him at my Shop Door with a Basket of Tallow .</p>
               <p>Q. How much might there be?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I believe about 50 Pounds, value 10 s. when I came down, he was at the Door, and he came into the Shop, and fell down upon his Knees , and begged I would excuse him, for it was the very first Time that he had done any thing of that Kind; I kept him in the Shop, and before he went to the Watch-house, he confessed he had taken such a Basket full before.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of your Tallow?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. The Basket of Tallow that he had taken last , is at the Constable's, the other is disposed of.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did he confess ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I suppose about the same Quantity .</p>
               <p>Q. Have you missed Tallow before ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill No, my Lord, I have not missed it</p>
               <p>Q. Could you lose such a Parcel , and not miss it?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of the other Prisoner, Masterman ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. Phillips told me that it was by the Instigation and Persuation of Masterman that he did this? and that he had never known my Shop had it not been for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Masterman?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He was at work in my Cellar .</p>
               <p>Q. Have you no other Evidence against Masterman but what this Man said?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I know nothing but what this Man said.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing else taken away?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. A Bag of Cotton.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that at the same Time?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. No, my Lord, that was some Time before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it, or did he confess it ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. Phillips told me, that Masterman had carried Cotton away, and he told me where he had carried it. I believe it to be of the Value of thirty Shillings.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you miss any Cotton?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I did think one Time I did miss it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person224">
                  Edward 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person224" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person224" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confess any thing himself of this Cotton ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He did not confess that he was concerned in carrying this Cotton away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever your Cotton again ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I hear the Constable has that Parcel of Cotton.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know it when you see it ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290019"></xptr>Greenhill. No, my Lord, I cannot swear to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing more? Did Masterman confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did Masterman work with you?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. The best Part of the Winter ; he worked with me as a Journeyman .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Masterman. Ask Mr Greenhill if I had any Concern with the Tallow, and as for the Cotton I bought it of one Lawson. I never carried an Ounce of Goods out of his House in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person225">
                  Thomas 
                  Greenhill 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person225" type="surname" value="Greenhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person225" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What Kin are you to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person226">
                  William 
                  Greenhill 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person226" type="surname" value="Greenhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. His Nephew, Sir; on the 4th of April, at two o'Clock in the Morning, I looked down through the Grate as they were at work , when I looked down, the first I saw was 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person227">
                  Edward 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person227" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person227" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             walking a cross the Cellar after Masterman , with a Basket on his Shoulder; presently there was a Couple of Shutters put up, 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person228">
                  James 
                  Masterman 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person228" type="surname" value="Masterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person228" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ordered the Boy to put up a Couple of Shutters; the Boy is got away, is not taken , and by putting up the Shutters, I could not look down .</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after that?</p>
               <p>Greenhill After that, in about five Minutes, they were coming up the Ladder into the Shop, I steps to the other Side of the Way thinking they would come presently, I heard the Door open , and I saw 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person229">
                  Edward 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person229" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person229" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             come out with a Basket of Tallow on his Back.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body with him?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. My Lord, I saw no-body , I stepped up to him, and catched him by the Collar, and asked him whether he was going with that; he replied, For God in Heaven's Sake, it was the first Time; after that, he confessed he had been there once before, and he was to have come the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he take before?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He had about half an Hundred, and fourteen Pounds, as he told me.</p>
               <p>Q. What had he done with it?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He said he had made it into a few Candles to maintain his Family ; he had a large Family he said .</p>
               <p>Court . You did not see 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person230">
                  James 
                  Masterman 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person230" type="surname" value="Masterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person230" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do any thing ?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. I cannot say that I saw him touch the Basket .</p>
               <p>Court to Phillips, the Prisoner. What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Phillips. When he took the Basket of Tallow, I told him I bought it of Mr Greenhill's Apprentice .</p>
               <p>Q. to Greenhill. Did he tell you that he bought this Tallow of the Apprentice?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He said he bought it of James and the Apprentice, he said he gave 15 s. for this Parcel, and 15 for the last Parcel.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he say that he paid that Money to.</p>
               <p>Greenhill. He said he paid the Apprentice for the first Parcel, and the other to James.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the Apprentice?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. My Lord, the Money was hid, it was put in between the Checks of a Press and a Box in the Workhouse .</p>
               <p>Q. Who shewed you where the Money was?</p>
               <p>Greenhill. The Apprentice, he took it out, and this is the 15 s. for the last Parcel, and he said they had spent the Money for the other Parcel.</p>
               <p>Court to Phillips. Would you ask the Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Phillips. My Lord, he took the Money from the Apprentice, and the Apprentice had an Opportunity for two or three Hours in order to escape, to make Examples of us.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to buy it of such Persons ? And how came you to fetch it away at that Time?</p>
               <p>Phillips. My Lor d, he told me I might come for it at any Time when it suited me.</p>
               <p>Thomas Lloyd I am a Tallow-chandler, I live the other Side of the Water, at the Old Barge-House; 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person231">
                  James 
                  Masterman 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person231" type="surname" value="Masterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person231" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought a Bag of Cotton to my House , I was not at Home.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought it?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person232">
                  James 
                  Masterman 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person232" type="surname" value="Masterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person232" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             he waited at a publick House till I came Home; it was about a Month ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was it?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. There was upwards of twenty Pounds of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give for it?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I did not buy it of him, my Lord; he asked me to buy it, or if I could tell him any body that would buy it; he told me it came from his Master Greenhill's in Newport-market .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he pretend he had any Authority from his Master?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. He told me he was to have Part of the Money for selling of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who did buy it?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. He appointed me to come in three Days for an Answer; before the Time was expired, he was taken up; the Cotton was left at my House with a Design to call in three or four Days to see if I would buy it, or knew any body that would buy it; it was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290020"></xptr> about two Days after he had been with me, that he was taken, then he confessed the Cotton . The Cotton was taken by Mr Greenhill and his Servants from my House.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the Cotton ?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. The Constable 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person233">
                  Hopkins
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person233" type="given" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Masterman. My Lord, please to ask the Evidence whether I told him where I got that Cotton; I told him I bought it of one Lawson.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lloyd. Did or did he not tell you he bought it of Lawson?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. No, my Lord, he did not.</p>
               <p>Masterman. I can prove the Delivery of the Cotton, the Man I bought it of is gone out of Town.</p>
               <p>Court to Masterman. What have you to say in your Defence? Who do you call?</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person234">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person234" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person234" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What are you?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I am a Publican, I know the Porter that brought a Bag to my House, and left it at my House for some Time; it was a Month or five Weeks ago. This Prisoner at the Bar came to the Porter, and paid him for bringing of it, and gave him a Pint of Beer for his Trouble .</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was this Cotton brought?</p>
               <p>Taylor. About eleven o'Clock in the Day-time; the Prisoner always behaved very well, I have heard an extraordinary good Character of him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person235">
                  Samuel 
                  Hutton 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person235" type="surname" value="Hutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person235" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What do you know of this Man?</p>
               <p>Hutton. I have known him seven Years, and never heard any thing of him but Honesty.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hutton. I am a Weaver by Trade.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person236">
                  Patrick 
                  Mumford 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person236" type="surname" value="Mumford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person236" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What is your Business?</p>
               <p>Mumford. A Victualler.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known this Man?</p>
               <p>Mumford. He used to come to our House several Times to see his Acquaintance , I never heard any thing of him but what was very good, before this happened; how true it is, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-person237">
                  Andrew 
                  Ferguson 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person237" type="surname" value="Ferguson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person237" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Tallow-chandler, I have known the Prisoner, Masterman, three or four Years, he has worked for me, and lodged in my House, and has brought Candles of me , and paid me honestly for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person238">
                  Edward 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person238" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person238" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Ferguson. No, no farther than that I have seen the Man .</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person239">
                  William 
                  Sheron 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person239" type="surname" value="Sheron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person239" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . What are you?</p>
               <p>Sheron . I am a Peruke-maker .</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Man?</p>

               <p>Sheron . I have known him about two Years, he has a very good Character, and his Relations give him as good a Character as I have heard of any Man .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-person240">
                  Andrew 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person240" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person240" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Taylor, I have known the Prisoner about a Year, I never heard any thing ill of the Prisoner in my Life before this.</p>
               <p>Archibald Brown I am a Sea faring Man, I knew him before he served his Time out, and since, and never heard any thing ill of him .</p>

               <p>Masterman. I expected Mr Allen of Wapping , and some others besides, to my Character.</p>
               <p>Court to Phillips. Have you any body to call?</p>
               <p>Phillips. I rely upon one of the Evidences for my Character, that has known me some Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-26-person241">
                  Thomas 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person241" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person241" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner, Phillips, ever since he went an Apprentice.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character has he?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I never heard any Ill of him in my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470429-26-person242">
                  Frances 
                  Thomson 
               <interp inst="t17470429-26-person242" type="surname" value="Thomson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person242" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What are you?</p>
               <p>Thomson. My Father is a Smith, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known this young Man?</p>
               <p>Thomson A Year and a half, and I know him to be a very honest Man, as far as ever I saw.</p>
               <p>There was no legal Evidence against Masterman , with respect to the Tallow, and the only thing that affected Phillips, was his taking away the Tallow, though that was set forth to him by the Court as a very wrong thing; but then the Prosecution appeared to them to be wrong too, because they should have indicted the Apprentice for selling his Master's Goods that he had no Right to, and the Prisoner should have been indicted for receiving stolen Goods, since the Fact is verified by the Money being produced.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17470429-26-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-26-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> .</p>
               <p>[The Prisoners were admonished by the Court how they acted such a wicked Part again ; for one to see his Master's Goods embezzled and sold, and the other to buy them in such a Manner ]</p>
            </div1>
