<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480706-41">
               <interp inst="t17480706-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-41" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-41" type="date" value="17480706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480706-41-off190-c280" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-41-defend359 t17480706-41-off190 t17480706-41-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>363. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-defend359" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lancaster 
                  <interp inst="t17480706-41-defend359" type="surname" value="Lancaster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-defend359" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-defend359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17480706-41-off190" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-off190" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-off190" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a pair of sheets, value 8 s. two handkerchiefs, value 4s. three half guineas, and fifty shillings in silver, &amp;c. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480706-41-victim361" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17480706-41-victim361" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-41-victim361" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-41-victim361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-41-off190 t17480706-41-victim361"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480706-41-cd191" type="crimeDate">June 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-41-off190 t17480706-41-cd191"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person362">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person362" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person362" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lodged in my house about a fortnight before this happened, and gave me the slip, and went away. I went out that day about ten in the morning, and came home about four in the afternoon, and found the doors open, my boxes open, and rummaged, and my things gone; but one of my neighbours telling me they saw a couple of men lift another man over the pales, who by description was the Prisoner, I took him up the next morning, and had him before Justice Tall; and the corner of the handkerchief, that the things were tied up in, was hanging out of his pocket, I said that was my handkerchief, he said he had had that handkerchief several years.</p>
               <p>[The constable produced the handkerchief, which he took from the Prisoner, and said the Prisoner had six shillings and sixpence in his pocket.]</p>
               <p>Smith. This is my handkerchief, and the handkerchief that the Prisoner had. I know it by the mark, it is marked with an M.</p>
               <p>The Constable. The Prosecutor said, the Prisoner told him he had no money, and desired him to give him three halfpence for a pint of beer; he said he had bought a new pair of breeches, and had spent a good deal of money that day.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not know the money, did you?</p>
               <p>Smith. No; there were no marked pieces. He was asked how he came by the money, and he said he borrowed about half a guinea of two masters, and the Justice was so good as to let him send for his masters, but they said they did not let him have any, and that was the reason the Justice committed him; and going along, the Prisoner said, it was well for the Prosecutor that he did not come home while he was in the house, for if he had, he should have done him a mischief.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Prosecutor is a very hard-mouthed man. I desire to know, whether I told him I had no money?</p>
               <p>Smith. You did tell me you had no money, and asked me for a pint of beer, and I gave you a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person363">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Kingston 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person363" type="surname" value="Kingston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person363" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Thompson's-Rents, by London-Wall; and on the day Mr. Smith was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060028"></xptr> robbed (as high as I can guess) I heard the Prisoner desire two men to lift him over the pales, and I saw him sit upon the pales.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his face?</p>
               <p>Kingston. I had a fight of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it?</p>
               <p>Kingston. About two o'clock in the afternoon; I did not trouble myself any further, for I did not think he was going to rob the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he sit upon the pales?</p>
               <p>Kingston. Not long, and then I heard him jump into the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Kingston. Not that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he the man that came over the pales?</p>
               <p>Kingston. To the best of my knowledge, he is the man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see me there?</p>
               <p>Kingston. To the best of my knowledge, you are the man that sat upon the pales.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what clothes the man had on that was lifted over the pales?</p>
               <p>Kingston. He had a brown coat like Mr. Smith's, and a brown linen apron, and he was of a brown complexion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person364">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Atkinson 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person364" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person364" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Thompson's Rents, overagainst Mr. Smith's, I was coming along about the middle of the day, when Mr. Smith's house was robbed, and I saw two sailor like men lifting another over the pales, and I thought it was somebody belonging to Mr. Smith, therefore I did not much observe it, and the two men said, Folk will say we come to rob the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the person?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. I cannot say that I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what clothes he had on?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. He had a brown coat, and a brown linen apron.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade was the Prisoner bred to?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. He said he was bred a <rs id="t17480706-41-deflabel192" type="occupation">weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-41-defend359 t17480706-41-deflabel192"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the Prisoner a brown coat on when you met with him?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, and a linen apron.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Pray, madam, do you know me?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see me there, madam?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. I saw two men lift another man over the pales in a brown coat, with a linen apron, but I did not observe the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person365">
                  William 
                  Gitters 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person365" type="surname" value="Gitters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person365" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know this handkerchief to be the Prosecutor's, because the Prosecutor lent it me several times; for I lodged at his house, and the constable said this is the handkerchief he took from the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long have you had that handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Smith. About four years, and this is my handkerchief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person366">
                  Ann 
                  Morse 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person366" type="surname" value="Morse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person366" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met with the Prisoner about six week ago, about four o'clock in the afternoon, and he told me he was going to buy a shirt, and asked me to go with him; and in Rag Fair there was a woman standing with a handkerchief in her hand, with a mark very much like an M, and the Prisoner bought it, and I verily believe this is the handkerchief he bought.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person367">
                  James 
                  Grant 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person367" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Smith's house before the robbery was committed, and he said he had taken some things out of pawn, and was not worth five shillings in the world. I have used Mr. Smith's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What house does Mr. Smith keep?</p>
               <p>Grant. He sells a dram.</p>
               <p>Q. What business are you?</p>
               <p>Grant. I am a journeyman cheesemonger; I lived with Mr. Humphry Wright, in Whitechapel, five years, all but seven weeks, and served be hind his counter</p>
               <p>Q. to Smith. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Smith. My business is to get in small debts; ask him whether I did not get in a debt for him?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes, he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person368">
                  Charles 
                  Dormer 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person368" type="surname" value="Dormer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person368" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lived with me as an apprentice; he is a weaver, and has been out of his time about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave?</p>
               <p>Dormer. As other lads do.</p>
               <p>Q. You seem to hesitate; did he behave well?</p>
               <p>Dormer. I never knew any thing against him.</p>
               <p>Smith. This witness said he had the Prisoner twice before a Justice.</p>
               <p>Dormer. Yes, but this was not for a felony, it was for neglect of his business, as boys will do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person369">
                  James 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person369" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person369" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner eight or nine years, and lived next door to where he served his time; I never knew but he minded his business, and he is a very sober honest fellow. I could bring a great many people to his character; he kept my son company, and has gone to church several times with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person370">
                  James 
                  Dormer 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person370" type="surname" value="Dormer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person370" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner six years, and never knew of any dishonesty by him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-41-person371">
                  Peter 
                  Dormer 
               <interp inst="t17480706-41-person371" type="surname" value="Dormer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person371" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner nine years; he was apprentice to my brother, and I never heard any thing amiss of him in my life; he was worked for several eminent velvet weavers.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174807060029"></xptr>Q. to Mrs. Atkinson. What is Mr. Smith's character?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. I live by him, and never heard any thing against him; he is as civil a neighbour as any in the world.</p>
               <p>Isabella Oliver. Mr. Smith is a very civil neighbour, and a man of a very honest character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-41-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-41-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
