<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480907-54">
               <interp inst="t17480907-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-54" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480907-54" type="date" value="17480907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480907-54-off287-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-defend448 t17480907-54-off287 t17480907-54-verdict292"></join>
         
               <p>445. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17480907-54-defend448" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-defend448" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-defend448" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-defend448" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of the parish of <placeName id="t17480907-54-defloc286">St. Botolph Bishopsgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-defloc286" type="placeName" value="St. Botolph Bishopsgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-defloc286" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-defend448 t17480907-54-defloc286"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480907-54-off287" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-off287" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-off287" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17480907-54-victim449" type="victimName">
                        Benjamin 
                        Thrumpton 
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-victim449" type="surname" value="Thrumpton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-54-victim449" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-54-victim449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-off287 t17480907-54-victim449"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the king's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a silk purse , value 2 d. sixteen guineas, and fourteen shillings in silver, the property of the said 
                     <persName id="t17480907-54-person450">
                        Benjamin 
                        Thrumpton 
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person450" type="surname" value="Thrumpton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-54-person450" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480907-54-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17480907-54-cd288" type="crimeDate">June 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-off287 t17480907-54-cd288"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-54-person451">
                  Benjamin 
                  Thrumpton 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person451" type="surname" value="Thrumpton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person451" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The prisoner robbed me of sixteen guineas, and fourteen shillings in silver, in a silk purse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the night, or day?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. It was between 10 and 11 at night.</p>
               <p>Q. You must describe how the robbery was committed.</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. On the 20th of June I was coming down <placeName id="t17480907-54-crimeloc289">Houndsditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-crimeloc289" type="placeName" value="Houndsditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-crimeloc289" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-off287 t17480907-54-crimeloc289"></join> with my wife, and the prisoner and a man came along together, and pushed against us: I had my wife by the arm, and after they had passed us, they turned about, and rushed against me again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. No; and I went along till I came near <placeName id="t17480907-54-crimeloc290">Bishopsgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-crimeloc290" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480907-54-crimeloc290" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-off287 t17480907-54-crimeloc290"></join>, within two doors of Houndsditch, just by a pastry-cook's shop. Then the prisoner at the bar, and the man that rushed against me, knocked me in the face , and my wife in the face, and I thought they had no good intention; and then he came behind me, and gave me a blow on the side of the head with his fist , and knocked me down, and then put his knee at the pit of my stomach, and search'd it; there were 3 keys there, and he left them in it; and the prisoner came to the left pocket of my breeches , and pinched me by the throat, and almost throtled me; then she quitted my left pocket, and came to my right pocket, and took out my purse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the silver along with the gold?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. Yes; and when she had got the money, I saw no more of her .</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the man?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. He gave me several blows on the side of my head, that the blood gush'd out at my mouth and nose ; and I thought I should have been murder'd, as well as lose my money; and then they made off toward, Bishopsgate. Some people ask'd me what was the matter; and I said, a man had knocked me down, and a woman had robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. There were about six people; and they said they thought it was a quarrel, and that the man was gone towards Bishopsgate .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing to the people more?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I only said I had been robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your wife knocked down?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . She was taken from me by another man, and carried down Houndsditch .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . I had a warrant for her the 28th of June .</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you did not take her up sooner?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. Because I could not find out her name before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take her up?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. At a house where she was a servant .</p>
               <p>Q. What house was that?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . The Eagle and child in St. Martin's Le Grand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I had seen her several times before.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her before?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I had seen her several times in Bishopsgate-street .</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you her name?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. Several people up and down.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are those several people ?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. Her comrades in Bishopsgate-street: they are loose people of the town.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I am a <rs id="t17480907-54-viclabel291" type="occupation">cutler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480907-54-victim449 t17480907-54-viclabel291"></join> by trade , and belong now to Billingsgate , in the fish business, and meeting business: I live in Spittle-fields .</p>
               <p>Mrs. Thrumpton. I had been at Twickenham, and after I came off the water I met my husband at Billingsgate , and we met with the prisoner and a man, and they jostled against us.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. Just by Bishopsgate; and when he came to the cook's shop he knocked my husband down ; and he had a pretty large bundle under his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174809070029"></xptr> arm, and I took the bundle from him, and threw it into the pastry-cook's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you go in there?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. A little man in grey took me round the waist , and pulled me down Houndsditch; and he hit me a slap on the face, and run away .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out all this time ?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . I called out, Watch!</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body else but the watch?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . No; only the watch .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do then?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I looked about for my husband , and found him in the crowd .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing to the people at the pastry-cook's shop?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton. I told the gentlewoman of the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know your husband was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Thrumpton . Because he told me he was robb'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-54-person452">
                  Charles 
                  Wellings 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person452" type="surname" value="Wellings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person452" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was in an office on the 22d of June, at the time this thing was done; there was a warrant granted against Mrs. Davis the prisoner , and I saw 
               <persName id="t17480907-54-person453">
                  Mary 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person453" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person453" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person453" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and one Mrs. Alexander, coming out of the Duke William's-head at Hoxton, opposite to the alms-houses.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade are you?</p>
               <p>Wellings. I am a weaver. Said I, Mary, how came you to be here? for I knew she could not afford to spend much money. And she said, did not you hear of my Find?</p>
               <p>Q. What Find?</p>
               <p>Wellings. She said there were two men upon the ground, and she thought she heard some half-pence fall; and that she got a candle, picked them up, and gave them to Mr. Thrumpton, the undermost man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she know him?</p>
               <p>Wellings She said she gave the half-pence to the undermost, and then she said she kick'd something before her , and took up a purse; and she said to one 
               <persName id="t17480907-54-person454">
                  William 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person454" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person454" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , that it was a blue silk purse, and that there were 16 guineas , and 14 shillings in silver, in the purse ; and she said she put it into her bosom, and went to her lodging in Widegate-alley; and her landlord seeing her a little in liquor, said, if she would give it to him, he would give it her again in the morning : and she said, in the morning he gave her 11 guineas, and kept 5 guineas and the silver .</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with the purse?</p>
               <p>Wellings. The landlord gave her the purse with the 11 guineas, and I said, Moll, if the half-pence were the man's, the purse must be his. Why did not you give him the purse? And she said, what was better than a Find? And I said to her, you know there is a warrant against you; why don't you surrender yourself? And she said, she would not. And I said, I would take her. Then a trembling, and said, For God's sake don't take me. And afterwards she said, I was out of my office, and had no business with her. I saw, every one was an officer to take a thief; but there, two men, I was frightened, and let her go against and about a week afterwards. I met with her against then we went and took her, at the Eagle and in St. Martin's Le Grand. I went to Mr. Thrumpton, and said, you must come now, for the is in hold; and he went into the room where the prisoner was, and there were several other women in the room; and he said to the prisoner, you are the person that took my money .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-54-person455">
                  Jane 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person455" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person455" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person455" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live by Devonshire-square in Bishopsgate street; the prisoner has sent me a subpoena to come and swear for her, and I knew nothing of the quarrel at all; and I would not take a false oath for the world.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She was at the counter three times with me.</p>
               <p>Taylor. I was at the counter but once, and I heard the prisoner say she found 16 guineas and 14 shillings; that is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480907-54-person456">
                  John 
                  Rowley 
               <interp inst="t17480907-54-person456" type="surname" value="Rowley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person456" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchmaker, and live at London-wall; I have known the prisoner 5 or 6 years , and she is as honest a creature as ever I knew in my life; and sometimes I have the value of ten pounds in goods; and she came constantly to her work, and I never miss'd the value of a pin's point, tho' it was in her power to wrong me; and she has work'd for me 4 or 5 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she use to be given to tipling?</p>
               <p>Rowley. No; she is a very sober woman.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480907-54-verdict292" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480907-54-verdict292" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
