<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420714-23">
               <interp inst="t17420714-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-23" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-23" type="date" value="17420714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-23-off109-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-defend197 t17420714-23-off109 t17420714-23-verdict112"></join>
         
               <p>26. 
               <persName id="t17420714-23-defend197" type="defendantName">
                  Ann, the <rs id="t17420714-23-deflabel108" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-defend197 t17420714-23-deflabel108"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17420714-23-person198">
                        James 
                        Glass 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person198" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-23-person198" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-23-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17420714-23-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-defend197 t17420714-23-alias-6"></join>Ann Cox</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-defend197" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-defend197" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Widow, was indicted, for that she, together with a Man unknown, did <rs id="t17420714-23-off109" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-off109" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-off109" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               feloniously assault 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420714-23-victim200" type="victimName">
                           Catherine 
                           Glass 
                        <interp inst="t17420714-23-victim200" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-23-victim200" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-23-victim200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-off109 t17420714-23-victim200"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17420714-23-viclabel110" type="occupation">Spinster, about the Age of 12 Years</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-victim200 t17420714-23-viclabel110"></join>, and that the said Man unknown, did feloniously ravish her, the said Catherine, and that the said Ann was present, aiding and assisting the said Man to commit the said Rape
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420714-23-cd111" type="crimeDate">Feb. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-23-off109 t17420714-23-cd111"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person201">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person201" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person201" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being produced to give Evidence, was asked, how old she was?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person202">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person202" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person202" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was 12 Years of Age last Sunday.</p>
               <p>[Being then interrogated concerning the Nature of an Oath, and giving a satisfactory Answer, was sworn.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person203">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person203" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person203" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This 
               <persName id="t17420714-23-person204">
                  Ann 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person204" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person204" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my Mother-in-law, in December last, her own Son Webly Cox lay with me, at the Gravel-Pits at Woolwich, near Plumbtree-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consent to his lying with you?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person205">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person205" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person205" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did this 
               <persName id="t17420714-23-person206">
                  Ann 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person206" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person206" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person207">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person207" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person207" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She made a Man lie with me, - one Thomas, a Carpenter, - in the Month of November, she stood over me with a Case-knife in her Hand whilst the Man lay with me. - This was in a Cellar in Grosvenor's-Mews. - She said, she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140011"></xptr> would cut my Throat from Ear to Ear if I told my Father, that the Man ever lay either with her or me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she do any thing at that Time that Thomas the Carpenter lay with you?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person208">
                  Catherine 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person208" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person208" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She stood over me with a Case-knife, and threaten'd to cut my Throat from Ear to Ear, if I did not let him lie with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you resist Thomas the Carpenter?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lie with you?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he enter your Body at all?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it by Night, or by Day?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. It was in the Middle of the Night.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first complain of this Injury you received?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. I never complained of it till after I had been in the Workhouse 2 Months.</p>
               <p>Q. Who persuaded you to complain of it then?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. My Godmother threaten'd to send me to Bridewell, if I would not tell the Truth, and my Mother-in-law order'd me, if I was with Child, to lay it to my Brother-in-law, which I could not do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what is become of Thomas the Carpenter?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. I heard he was here Yesterday, I did not see him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not your Father in the House all the while.</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not he in the House at the Time that you speak of this being done?</p>
               <p>Cath. Glass. He was in the House that Night, he came for a clean Shirt, and went back again to Woolwich.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person209">
                  Sarah 
                  Triphook 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person209" type="surname" value="Triphook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person209" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Child's Godmother. I went to see the Girl after she had been in the Workhouse about two Months; I said, what do you come in here for? She said, for the Dropsy; she was pass'd from St. George's Workhouse, to Marybone; I said, I did not think it was a Dropsy, and took her to Dr Ross, he offer'd to take her as an Out-patient, I said, that would be of no Service to the Girl, because she had no Friends: I told him she had confessed what had happened, and he stripp'd her stark naked, and examined her, and then he was of Opinion that she was with Child: This Woman at the Bar fetched her from Greenwich, and carried her to a Cellar in Grosvenor's Mews, the Child told me, Thomas the Carpenter was at the Head of the Bed with the Prisoner at the Bar, and she was at the Feet. She said, she stood over her with a Case-knife, while Thomas the Carpenter had to do with her, and that the Prisoner should say, if you do not let him lie with you, or tell your Father, or any Body else, she would cut her Throat from Ear to Ear; and said, that Thomas the Carpenter did lie with her. The Prisoner came to me in Tyburn-Road, the Saturday Night before she was taken up, and said, if I could get the Girl out of the Workhouse, she could make her confess who the Father of the Child is, and she knew the Father to be worth Money.</p>
               <p>[The Jury desired the Matron of the Workhouse might be called, to know if the Child had over varied in her Account of this Matter ]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person210">
                  Ann 
                  Ramsey 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person210" type="surname" value="Ramsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person210" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Matron of the Workhouse; I found this out first, and asked her, whether she had had any Dealings with Man or Boy, for I did not take her Disorder to be a Dropsy; this was about 2 Months after she came into the Workhouse, she said, no; she had not: Hussey, said I, you must have had to do with some Body, for it is not a Dropsy, and you must confess it to me, or the Overseers will send you to Bridewell; then she confess'd it, and that it was by her Mother-in-law's Son, that he lay with her several Times, and once in Bed with her Mother-in-law; she would not confess any thing to me, concerning Thomas the Carpenter, but only the Boy Webly Cox; she did not confess this till April. She always gave the same Account, and did not vary in it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Jer. Longbottom. This Girl's Father lodged in my House at Greenwich, he was a Matross, I never saw any harm by the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-23-person211">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pyle 
               <interp inst="t17420714-23-person211" type="surname" value="Pyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person211" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 4 or 5 Years, and never knew any ill of her; as to the Girl, she was given to lying.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Woman can swear my Husband was at home in Bed with me that Night.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Pyle. I know he was, but I cannot tell the Day of the Month.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I thought the Child look big, and I said to her, Hussey, what have you been doing, you are with Child; she denied it, I got some Neighbours to search her, and they thought she was not with Child. <rs id="t17420714-23-verdict112" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-23-verdict112" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
