<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-14">
               <interp inst="t17400416-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-14" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-14" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-14-off79-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-defend116 t17400416-14-off79 t17400416-14-verdict82"></join>
         
               <p>204. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-14-defend116" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hetherington 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-14-defend116" type="surname" value="Hetherington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-defend116" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-defend116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400416-14-defloc78">St. Luke's Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-14-defloc78" type="placeName" value="St. Luke's Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-14-defloc78" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-defend116 t17400416-14-defloc78"></join> . was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-14-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a leather Bag, val. 1 d. a Pair of Silver Buttons val . 3 d. 2 Thirty-six Shilling-Pieces, a Moidore , 22 Guineas, 3 Half-Guineas, and 7 Shillings and 6 d. in Money, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-14-victim118" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Crimes 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-14-victim118" type="surname" value="Crimes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-14-victim118" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-14-victim118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-off79 t17400416-14-victim118"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17400416-14-person119">
                        Edward 
                        Dudley 
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-person119" type="surname" value="Dudley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-14-person119" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-14-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs> , <rs id="t17400416-14-cd80" type="crimeDate">March 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-off79 t17400416-14-cd80"></join>.</p>
               <p>Richard Crimes . I lost 30 l. out of a Chest in Edward Dudley's House, It was in a Leather Pocket, in a Chest, which was locked, and I kept the Key of it: I took particular Notice, that it was there the 10th of Feb. last. On the 19th of March I was at Work at Stratford , and Mr Dudley came thither to me, and asked me what Money I had in my Chest at his House, telling me he found it broke open. I informed him, I had 30 l. there, and mentioned what Pieces of Money there were. 22 Guineas, 3 Half Guineas, 2 Thirty-six Shilling Pieces, one Moidore, and 7 s. and 6 d. in Silver. Upon receiving this News from Mr Dudley, I came directly to London, and found my Chest broke open, and all my Money gone. Mr Dudley suspected the Prisoner, because he was his <rs id="t17400416-14-deflabel81" type="occupation">Apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-defend116 t17400416-14-deflabel81"></join>, and was run away. - I don't know the Prisoner's Age.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am between 14 and 15.</p>
               <p>Crimes. The Prisoner being run away from his Master's House, somebody informed him, that he had been seen with Money upon him; this gave Mr Dudley a Suspicion of him, and he searched after him, took him, and got him committed to New-Prison before I came to Town. While he was there in Goal, I went to him, and examined what he had done with the Money. He told me, he forced open the Chest with a File, and took the Money; and the Remainder, which was unspent, he had given his Master. He gave me an Account, that he went out with the Money into Moorfields, and got into Company with some Boys who were tossing up there; that he carried some of the Boys to an Alehouse , where they had some Beef-stakes drest, and a young Woman with them. One of the large Pieces of Money, (he said,) he had given to a great Boy to get changed for him, and the Boy brought him 21 Shillings for it; and 20 Shillings or upwards, he had spent himself. I asked him how he had made away with so much</p>
               <p>Money? He told me, he had bought Shoes, and Handkerchiefs for several of the Boys, and one Handkerchief, which he had bought for himself, his Master found upon him. In this Manner he said he had spent 20 Shillings. The rest of the Money, that was missing, the great Boy had cheated him of; for he had given him the Bag to hold for him at the Alehouse, while he went out; and when he returned, he told him he was sure he had opened it, because it was not tied up in the same Manner, as it was when he left it in his Hands: Upon which the great Boy denied it, and ran away immediately. The Prisoner was taken before he had squandered all the Money away; and Mr Dudley returned me 24 l. and upwards.</p>
               <p>Edward Dudley. The Prisoner was my Apprentice, and having ran away from my Service, I happened to see him as I was going with a Friend into the City, and I laid hold of him. I had not any Suspicion of his having taken this Money then; but my Friend, observing him to drop some upon the Ground, told me of it, and I searched him, and took 6 Pence and 6 Pence Halfpenny out of one Pocket, and 2 l. 17 s. 6 d. and a Handkerchif out of another of his Pockets. Upon this I went to get Advice how to secure the Money, and in the mean Time he got away. When I came Home I found Mr. Crimes's Chest broke open; and when the Prisoner was taken the second Time, he owned he broke it open with a File, and had taken away all the Money. Nineteen Guineas, a Moidore, a Half-Guinea, and a Pair of Buttons, he delivered me at that Time, which he owned was part of the Money he had taken out of the Chest. The Prisoner's Father says he is 15 Years old this Month: He has been bound to me between 8 and 9 Months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-14-person120">
                  John 
                  Lashley 
               <interp inst="t17400416-14-person120" type="surname" value="Lashley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-person120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw the Money taken from the Boy; there were 19 Guineas, a Moidore, and Half a Guinea. I heard him own he broke open the Chest with a Piece of a File, and then took out the Money.</p>
               <p>The Jury found the Prisoner <rs id="t17400416-14-verdict82" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-verdict82" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-14-punish83" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-14-punish83" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-14-defend116 t17400416-14-punish83"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
