<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470116-44">
               <interp inst="t17470116-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-44" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470116-44" type="date" value="17470116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-44-off180-c403" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-44-defend499 t17470116-44-off180 t17470116-44-verdict183"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470116-44-off181-c404" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-44-defend501 t17470116-44-off181 t17470116-44-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>122. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-44-defend499" type="defendantName">
                     Deborah 
                     Herod 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend499" type="surname" value="Herod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend499" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend499" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-44-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Piece of Silver, with the Coat of Arms of the Cook's Company, value 8 s.
            </rs> And.</p>
               <p>123. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470116-44-defend501" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Pulling 
                  <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend501" type="surname" value="Pulling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend501" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-defend501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470116-44-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               feloniously receiving the same , knowing it to be stolen
            </rs>. <rs id="t17470116-44-cd182" type="crimeDate">January 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-44-off180 t17470116-44-cd182"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470116-44-off181 t17470116-44-cd182"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470116-44-person502">
                  John 
                  Burding 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person502" type="surname" value="Burding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person502" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Do you know either of the Prisoners at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Burding. Please ye, my Lord, I was abroad at Work: I am Beadle of the Worshipful Company of Cooks.</p>
               <p>Q. What Do you know of the Fact?</p>
               <p>Burding. While I was at Work at Tower-hill, 
               <persName id="t17470116-44-person503">
                  Deborah 
                  Herod 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person503" type="surname" value="Herod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person503" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person503" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , she came to see my Daughter the third of this Instant; she came to see my Daughter, and desired her to go out.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your daughter live?</p>
               <p>Burding. She lives with me, and takes Care of the Beadle's Apartment in the Hall; she sent my Daughter out to see a poor Woman in her Coffin, and then took the Silver off from my Staff: she confessed before the Alderman, that she did take this off the Staff, and pawn it, this Piece of Silver with the Cook's Arms. Q. Who did the Staff belong too?</p>
               <p>Burding. 
               <persName id="t17470116-44-victim504" type="victimName">
                  The
                   Company of Cooks
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-victim504" type="surname" value="Company of Cooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-victim504" type="given" value="The"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-victim504" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Sir .</p>
               <p>Q. What did she do with it?</p>
               <p>Burding . She pawned it, she could not be easy till she let me know where it was.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she make this Confession to you?</p>
               <p>Burding . We took her on Saturday, and then she confessed it; and on Sunday we went to demand it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Promises made to her to induce her to confess it?</p>
               <p>Burding No, my Daughter told her if she did, not confess it, her Father would be turned out of the Place; then she confessed it</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she pawn it?</p>
               <p>Burding. To one Mr Broadstreet in Blue Anchor-Alley, in Whitecross Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find it there?</p>
               <p>Burding . Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it pawned for?</p>
               <p>Burding . Nine Shillings , Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pay any thing for it to the Pawnbroker ?</p>
               <p>Burding . No, they delivered it to me without any Money.</p>
               <p>Court. You say nothing at all against 
               <persName id="t17470116-44-person505">
                  James 
                  Pulling 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person505" type="surname" value="Pulling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person505" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Burding. He confessed that she went for his Sister and she said it was her Brother's Badge; she was with him; he said himself that she was his Sister-in-law, and that it was his Brother's Ticket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-44-person506">
                  Ann 
                  Burding 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person506" type="surname" value="Burding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person506" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person506" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . While I was gone out, the Prisoner took this Thing away, she confessed it herself.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was she at your House?</p>
               <p>Burding. In the Afternoon; she pawned it, Sir .</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17470116-44-person507">
                  James 
                  Pulling 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person507" type="surname" value="Pulling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person507" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before the Magistrate ?</p>
               <p>Burding. Yes, but I was not there .</p>
               <p>Q. to Dudley Broadstreet. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Broadstreet . In Blue Anchor-Alley, White-cross-street .</p>
               <p>Q. What Business do you follow ?</p>
               <p>Broadstreet. I live upon my Fortune, I lend Money too.</p>
               <p>Court. You lend Money upon Pawns?</p>
               <p>Broadstreet. The third or fourth of this Month Pulling and that Woman comes in at six o'Clock Night into my House on Sunday Night.</p>
               <p>Court. You do not follow your Business on Sunday?</p>
               <p>Broadstreet . I will tell you how it was, Pulling was a Tenant of mine, and I could not see him on a Sunday; Sir, said he, I am poor, and you are very severe; says he, it is my Brother's Badge, and he said this Woman was his Sister-in-Law, which I find since is not; he told me for five Pounds it could not be left any Time, but it must be released in two or three Days following; they did not come, and began to be uneasy how he came by it. On the Sunday following three Persons at Night came to enquire for this Pulling , I told them I believed that he was not at Home, but I desired to know their Business ; I was very inquisitive to know their Business; I can tell you this, if it is a Piece of Plate, I have such a thing in my Custody for 9 s. they said, Sir, that is the very thing we want, it belongs to a Man that is will lose his Place if he has it not; I said there<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174701160037"></xptr> was 9 s. upon it, but if I was satisfied of the Truth of what they told me, I would let them have it; accordingly this Man, Burding , brought his Staff, and it fitted, and my Wife delivered it to them. This is all I know of the Affair, I gave 2 s. upon it , and set off 7 s. I have known Pulling six Years, I never knew that he was charged with a Felony, or any thing of that Kind; I have known him to keep two or three People at work, and he has lately been reduced.</p>
               <p>Q. to Greville Jepsey . What are you?</p>
               <p>Jepsey . I am a Silver-smith, I saw the Woman, the Prisoner, last Saturday was Fortnight, that was the first Time, I saw her, and that was in the Prosecutor's Room; on the Wednesday following I heard that she h ad stolen this Plate from the Cooks Company, she confessed to me that she stole this Plate belonging to the Cooks Company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470116-44-person508">
                  Ann 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17470116-44-person508" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person508" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-person508" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the Woman till I heard her confess it, that she had taken it off the Staff.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the Man say any thing?</p>
               <p>Morgan. I heard him say he pawned it for her, that he carried it to Mr Broadstreet to pawn.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Arms of the Cooks Company?</p>
               <p>Morgan. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470116-44-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470116-44-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>What made well for the Prisoners was, there was none in Court could take upon them to swear what were the Cooks Arms.</p>
            </div1>
