<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-2">
               <interp inst="t17400227-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-2" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-2" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-2-off6-c32" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend35 t17400227-2-off6 t17400227-2-verdict11"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-2-off6-c33" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend37 t17400227-2-off6 t17400227-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>149,150. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-2-defend35" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Whitney  alias <rs id="t17400227-2-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend35 t17400227-2-alias-1"></join>Dribray</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend35" type="surname" value="Whitney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend35" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend35" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-2-defend37" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                      Nash  alias <rs id="t17400227-2-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend37 t17400227-2-alias-2"></join>Goulding</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend37" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend37" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-defend37" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17400227-2-off6" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-off6" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-off6" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-2-victim39" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Stacey 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-2-victim39" type="surname" value="Stacey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-2-victim39" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-2-victim39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-off6 t17400227-2-victim39"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the Dwelling-House of 
                     <persName id="t17400227-2-person40">
                        William 
                        Needham 
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person40" type="surname" value="Needham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-2-person40" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him, a Moidore, a Thirty-six Shilling-piece, and 30 Guineas
            </rs>. <rs id="t17400227-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">Nov. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-off6 t17400227-2-cd7"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Stacey. On the 20th of November I was going towards Temple-Bar, and the Prisoners followed me, and asked me to give them a Quartern of Brandy, or Gin. I did not value such a little Matter, so I followed them into Needham's House, at the <placeName id="t17400227-2-crimeloc8">Rose by Temple-Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-2-crimeloc8" type="placeName" value="Rose by Temple-Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-2-crimeloc8" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-off6 t17400227-2-crimeloc8"></join>, and there we had 3 Quarterns of Gin. Then they came round me, and began to be sweet upon me, but I said, - stand off, I want nothing with you, nor will I be concerned with you, on any Account. Whitney said, 'tis very hard with us, Sir, and I hope you'll give us something. And a small Matter I did give them; - I believe it was 2 Six-pences, and I paid for what we had had in the House, and was going away. But getting off my Chair, both of them took hold of me by Force of Arms, and held me so, that I could not help myself. I was a little in Liquor, but not much. I knew very well what I did, and I stood upon my Feet for some Time before they got me down; but at last they did get me down, and I cried Murder! Help, for God's Sake! Whitney told me, if I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270003"></xptr> cried out, she would cut my Throat. They gagged me; and my Mouth was so full of Blood, that I could not speak; and Blood likewise gushed out of my Nose. Then they took from me all my Money; 30 Guineas, and upwards, a Moidore, and a Thirty-six Shilling-Piece. Upon my crying out, Assistance came, and the Door was got open; and then the Landlady of the House and the Drawer came in, and saw me in this Condition. They were both bound over by Colonel 
               <persName id="t17400227-2-person41">
                  De 
                  Veil 
               <interp inst="t17400227-2-person41" type="surname" value="Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person41" type="given" value="De"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person41" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to appear here, but they are hired I believe to keep out of the Way. I take them to be Parties concerned. When the Prisoners were taken, we found 25 Guineas in Nash's Bosom, and one in her Hair; and they both cried, and said they had no more, but I lost a great deal more. The Moidore, the Thirty-six Shilling-Piece, and all the rest of the Money was gone. After this, there was a Man in the House pretended to be my Assistant, and to right me; and he said, - You brazen faced Sluts, I'll see you tied up; so we went to see for a Constable, but there was none to be got, and the Man of the House rescu'd the Prisoners away, since which, he is not to be found. The Prisoners were taken some Time afterwards before Colonel De Veil , upon another Account, and he knowing them, I was sent for, and bound over to prosecute them. I never saw the Prisoners, (to my Knowledge) before I took them to Needham's House that Night, - 'twas about 7 or 8 o'Clock. I had nothing to do with them, - I did no Harm with them, only gave them a little Gin; and 'tis no Crime to do that.</p>
               <p>Whitney. Was any Thing found upon me?</p>
               <p>Mr Stacey. No, I believe not; but she was a Party concerned: her Hand was in my Pocket, as well as Nash's. They both attacked me; one of them throtled me, and the other robbed me.</p>
               <p>Whitney. Was not you in Needham's House before I came in?</p>
               <p>Mr Stacey. No; I was not, I followed you in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-2-person42">
                  Sarah 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17400227-2-person42" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person42" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person42" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have a Sister, (one Murphin) who keeps a Stall at Temple-Bar, and she sent for me that Night, to come and open Oysters for her. As I was going thither, I met her Husband going into the Ship Tavern with Oysters. He told me his Wife was at the 
               <persName id="t17400227-2-person43">
                  Rose 
                  Alehouse 
               <interp inst="t17400227-2-person43" type="surname" value="Alehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person43" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , eating Salt-Fish and Potatoes. I went thither, and as I was cutting a Potatoe, I heard a Man cry, - Lord help me, I am going to be murdered. Speedily he cried out again, - Murder! Murder ! Lord help me! Lord, says I, don't you hear somebody cry out Murder! Phoo, Phoo, says one, 'tis nothing at all. But I took the Candle, and run into one Room, but there was no body there. Then I went to another Room, (a back Room) and found there was a Chair, or something, set against the Door, but I push'd it open, and saw Mr Stacey upon the Ground, the Blood running out of his Nose; and Whitney had her Right-Hand in his Left Pocket, dragging out his Money, and Nash held him down with her Right-Hand on his Throat. I told them they would certainly kill the Man, and ran directly to Mr Bird the Fishmonger, and informed him, that a Man was likely to be kill'd at the Rose. He bid me get a Constable, and accordingly I gave Two-pence to two Boys to get one, but there was none to be found. When I got back again to the Rose, I met Nash coming out of the Door, and opposing her passing by me, she flew upon me, but I struck her down to the Ground with my Hand; then she got up, and made at me again, and Whitney coming up, I defended myself, till Mr Stacey came to my Assistance, and struck at them, and so we took them. From Nash there were 25 Guineas and a half taken; and tho' they were stripped naked to their shifts, we could find no more. Nash call'd for all the Vengeance of God to seize her, if she had any more, but I unpinn'd her Cap, and found another Guinea in her Hair. The Gentleman said, He still miss'd 6 or 7 Guineas, and upon my asking what they had done with them, Whitney said, - You Bitch, I will swear a Robbery against you, for my Hood and Cloak, which she herself had hid by the Fire-side. Nash would have made herself an Evidence that Night, and declared that Whitney gave her all the Money.</p>
               <p>Whitney. Are you sure you saw my Hand in his Pocket?</p>
               <p>Scot. Yes. I saw her Right-Hand in his Left Pocket, and was afraid to assist the Gentleman, tho' I saw her pulling out his Money.</p>
               <p>Nash. Did she see me pull any Money from the Gentleman?</p>
               <p>Scot. No. Whitney took his Money, while Nash held him down by the Throat, till he was perfectly spent. Afterwards I saw Nash pull the Money out of her Bosom, and lay it down on the Table. I never saw the Prosecutor before that Night in my Life.</p>
               <p>Whitney. I was going that Night to see the Entertainment, at the Old House , and thinking it too soon. I went to the Rose-Alehouse at Temple-Bar, and sent for Mrs wood in Sheer-Lane, to go with me. When I went into the House, the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174002270004"></xptr> Gentleman was there, and asked me to drink with him. I refus'd at first, but after some little Perswasion, I drank with him; and then he wanted to be rude with me, and he pull'd me about, and tore Hales's Cloak almost off her Back, so I did not care to stay with him, he hall'd us about so. About a Fortnight ago, I was set upon by a Man and three Women, and went to Colonel De Veil for a Warrant against them, and then this Gentleman and the Woman (Scot) was sent for to prosecute me.</p>
               <p>Nash . When we went into the House the Gentleman offered to treat us, and called for a Glass of Wine, and said, If we would drink with him, he would give us what we should require.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stacey . We went into the House all together; I was not there before them, nor had we a Drop of Wine, for they did not sell Wine; - 'tis an Alehouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-2-person44">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gale 
               <interp inst="t17400227-2-person44" type="surname" value="Gale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person44" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-person44" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I wind Silk for my Living; I have known Nash ever since she was a little Girl: she is a <rs id="t17400227-2-deflabel9" type="occupation">Gloveress</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend37 t17400227-2-deflabel9"></join>, and, as far as I know, work'd hard for her Maintenance. I never knew any Harm of her in my Life.</p>
               <p>Another Witness had known Nash about five Years, and gave much the same Account.</p>
               <p>Whitney's Father. Whitney is my unfortunate Daughter, to my Sorrow. She was marry'd, I believe, to one Whitney, a Wheeler by Trade, who is now living, as far as I know. I have seen my Daughter now and then of late Years, but she hath not been very conversant with me. She told me she employed herself in <rs id="t17400227-2-deflabel10" type="occupation">Mantua-making</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend35 t17400227-2-deflabel10"></join>, and she has work'd for my Wife. I had no Suspicion of her following ill Courses, till I heard she was in the Gatehouse. I know a little of Nash; her Husband sold Pictures, but he is now gone to Sea. I knew nothing but what she was just and honest.</p>
               <p>The Jury found both the Prisoners <rs id="t17400227-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400227-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend35 t17400227-2-punish12"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17400227-2-punish13" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-punish13" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-2-punish13" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-2-defend37 t17400227-2-punish13"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death -respited for pregnancy. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
