<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-49">
               <interp inst="t17430114-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-49" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-49" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-49-off237-c485" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-49-defend578 t17430114-49-off237 t17430114-49-verdict240"></join>
         
               <p>128. + 
               <persName id="t17430114-49-defend578" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-defend578" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-defend578" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-defend578" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-49-off237" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-off237" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-off237" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the Dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17430114-49-person579">
                        James 
                        Jeffs 
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person579" type="surname" value="Jeffs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-49-person579" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-49-person579" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , about the Hour of 12 in the Night , and stealing from thence 7 Pewter Dishes, 3 Soop-Plates, 28 Pewter Plates
            </rs>, &amp;c. the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-victim581" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Jeffs 
                  <interp inst="t17430114-49-victim581" type="surname" value="Jeffs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-victim581" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-victim581" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-49-off237 t17430114-49-victim581"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17430114-49-cd238" type="crimeDate">December 10. 1741</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-49-off237 t17430114-49-cd238"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person582">
                  James 
                  Jeffs 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person582" type="surname" value="Jeffs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person582" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person582" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have a Country-House at <placeName id="t17430114-49-crimeloc239">Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-49-crimeloc239" type="placeName" value="Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-49-crimeloc239" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-49-off237 t17430114-49-crimeloc239"></join>; I left it the Beginning of Dec. last, I locked the Kitchen-Door when I came from it, and put a Padlock upon it, and when I went there, on the 16th or 17th , I found the Padlock off, the Brick-work was broke into a Foot and an half, and the Post of the Door, where the Staples go in, was cut like an Half-Moon, and the Door was cut in the same Manner, that they might come easy to push the Lock back; I found all the Pewter and Goods gone out of the Kitchen, except a large Copper: I advertised these Goods, in order to come to the Knowledge of them, and I did not expect to hear any thing of them, till somebody came to be tried for a Robbery; but last Tuesday two Men, one whose Name is Hambleton, came to my House in Town, and said if I would come to Justice Wroth's, I might see a Basket of Brass and Pewter, and the Justice desired I would see if any of them were mine, and I found my Cullender, one of my Soop Plates, and the Winder of the Jack.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person583">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person583" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person583" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person583" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About a Fortnight before last Christmas was 12 Months, the Prisoner said to me, That House looks as if there was something in it, and we agreed to rob it, and at 12 at Night cut the Door and Door-post with a Knife, and we brought a great many Things out of the House, put them into a Bag, and carried them as far as the Long Field, and put them into a Pond, and fetched them the next Morning , before it was light; he took away his Part, and I took away mine. - I never carried any thing to the Prisoner's House ; I have seen the Cullender in Smith's House, in Old street .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person584">
                  William 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person584" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person584" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person584" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Recruiting-Serjeant; the last Witness enlisted with me in Col. Wolf's Regiment of Marines last Thursday, and continued with me to the 10th of Jan. and then he brought another young Man, in order to enlist him: There was a Fire made for them up Stairs at our House (I keep a Publick House, the 
               <persName id="t17430114-49-person585">
                  George 
                  Alehouse 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person585" type="surname" value="Alehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person585" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Windmill-Hill) they broke open a Cupboard there, and I found 4 Guineas and some Silver upon the Witness, so I carried him before Justice Wroth, in order to bring him to Justice, and he desired to speak to the Justice, and acknowledged that he and the Prisoner had broke open a Gentleman's House at Hampstead, and made himself an Evidence, I went with a Search-Warrant to search the Prisoner's House, and found the Cullender which is produced in Court, the Jack-Winder, and a Padlock Key in the Chest where we found the Soop-Plate, the Cullender was in a Cupboard upon an high Shelf.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person586">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person586" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person586" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person586" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is the Key of the Prisoner's Stable where he keeps his Horse; these are all Picklock Keys (there were 5 in the Bunch) I do not know whether these were made use of at Mr Jeffs's; they never were in my Custody .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person587">
                  Anne 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person587" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person587" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person587" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 1st of Nov . the Witness, Smith , came to the Prisoner's House and brought a green Bag on his Shoulder, and desired him to let<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140040"></xptr> him leave it till he called for it; there was in the Bag a Pewter Cullender, the Handle of a Jack, 2 little Dishes or Plates - it was a Cullender much of the Size of this, I cannot swear to it - I was Servant to Mr Geare, the Corner of Dover-Street, I have been come from thence four Months; I lived with one Watkinson, a Stocking-Shop in the Strand. - I am the Prisoner's Wife's Sister.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person588">
                  Martha 
                  Boot 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person588" type="surname" value="Boot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person588" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person588" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In November last I was at the Prisoner's House a washing, Mr Smith was not at home; 
               <persName id="t17430114-49-person589">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person589" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person589" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             comes in with a green Bag upon his Shoulder, and desired Mrs Smith to let him leave it. She asked him what was in it; he said, something that his Mother had left him. Mrs Smith opened the Bag, and there was a Pewter Cullender, a Handle of a Jack, two small Dishes, or Plates, I cannot tell which, some Knives and Forks, I cannot tell how many. - I live at Richard Green's in Swan-Alley, in Old-Street; I am a Buckle-Maker, and work for Richard Green; I can swear to that Cullender, but I do not know the Mark: I lived with Mr Young in Old-Str eet.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-49-person590">
                  Henry 
                  Hooper 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person590" type="surname" value="Hooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person590" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person590" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17430114-49-person591">
                  William 
                  Burridge 
               <interp inst="t17430114-49-person591" type="surname" value="Burridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person591" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-person591" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and - Bates, gave the Prisoner an honest Character.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. And please you, my Lord, if the Troop had not been gone to Flanders , I should have had all the Officers of the Troop to have appeared to my Character. <rs id="t17430114-49-verdict240" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-49-verdict240" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
