<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430629-47">
               <interp inst="t17430629-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-47" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430629"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430629-47" type="date" value="17430629"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430629-47-off262-c345" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-defend456 t17430629-47-off262 t17430629-47-verdict266"></join>
         
               <p>343. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430629-47-defend456" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Berreau 
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-defend456" type="surname" value="Berreau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-defend456" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-defend456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17430629-47-defloc261">St George in Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-defloc261" type="placeName" value="St George in Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-defloc261" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-defend456 t17430629-47-defloc261"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17430629-47-off262" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-off262" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-off262" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430629-47-victim458" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Shortland 
                        <interp inst="t17430629-47-victim458" type="surname" value="Shortland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-47-victim458" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-47-victim458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-off262 t17430629-47-victim458"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a Linnen Apron, val. 2 s. 6 d. a Straw Hat, val. 2 s. 6 d. and a Piece of Copper Money, called an Half-penny; the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17430629-47-person459">
                        Ann 
                        Shortland 
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person459" type="surname" value="Shortland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-47-person459" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430629-47-person459" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17430629-47-cd263" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-off262 t17430629-47-cd263"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430629-47-person460">
                  Ann 
                  Shortland 
               <interp inst="t17430629-47-person460" type="surname" value="Shortland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person460" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person460" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 1st of this Instant, as I was coming by the <placeName id="t17430629-47-crimeloc264">Hole in the Wall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-crimeloc264" type="placeName" value="Hole in the Wall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-crimeloc264" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-off262 t17430629-47-crimeloc264"></join>, in a little Street turning up to <placeName id="t17430629-47-crimeloc265">Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-crimeloc265" type="placeName" value="Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430629-47-crimeloc265" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430629-47-off262 t17430629-47-crimeloc265"></join>; the Prisoner took my Apron off my Sides, and a Half-penny out of my Pocket; and, in the mean Time, two Hussies, who were along with her, took my Hat; while she was taking off my Apron the two young Women took my Hat, and made off; then the Prisoner beat me over the Face, and assaulted me very much: I did not know but she intended to murder me; I cried out Murder, and this Man, (Mullins) came to my Assistance - I am a Chairwoman, and lodge at a Publick-House in Carnaby-Market, and was going to Barnard's-Inn in Holbourn, to try to get a Day's Work.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be up so soon as 4 o'Clock to try to get work? That was not a proper Time to go to look for Work.</p>
               <p>Shortland. Because I was in Hopes of getting some - I was alone.</p>
               <p>Jury. She says, she lives in Carnaby-Market, that was not the Way to come into Holbourn: Did you ever see the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Shortland. I never sat Eyes on her in my Life before; there was a Man who looked out of Window came to my Assistance, without Shoes and Stockings; and she was taken with the Apron upon her; she damned me, and sinked me, and said, she would have my Apron; this is the Apron she took off my Sides.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430629-47-person461">
                  Jasper 
                  Mullins 
               <interp inst="t17430629-47-person461" type="surname" value="Mullins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person461" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to hear a Noise of crying out stop Thief, and Watchman, or Constable, so I looked out of Window, and saw four Women together; the Prisoner got hold of the last Witness, and beat her, and said, she would have some Money of her; she said, she had no more than an Half-penny; then the Prisoner turned her Pocket inside out; and when she found she had no more Money; says she, I will have your Apron; then she got hold of her, and with both her Hands tore it from her Body; the other two Women were then at some Distance; says she, to the Prisoner, Do not use me ill, I am a poor Woman; and she gave the Woman a Blow over the Face, and then made off; she cried out stop Thief; I was in my bare Shirt (I am ashamed to speak it before your Lordship) and followed her without shoes, Stockings, Breeches, or Slippers; and when I came to her, said I, Why were you so villainous as to take the poor Woman's Apron; deliver it: Said she, what's that to you, you Son of a B - h, G - d - n you to Hell - this was in Little Russel street; there was a Bricklayer coming by, I begged of him to help me, but he went his Way, and never stopped; I told her I would follow her all that blessed Day, till she was taken; I followed her up Duke-street into Great Russel street, and then came to the House of the Beadle of our Parish, and he had just happened to open his Shop; said I, You see that Woman, take her up in my Name, for I am quite tired; he asked me what he must charge her with, said I, with stealing a Woman's check'd Apron, and he went directly after her and secured her.</p>
               <p>Mrs Brotherton. I heard a Noise, in a Place which we call the Hole in the Wall, fronting the Market; I got out of Bed, and looked out of the Window, and saw the Prisoner, the Prosecutrix, and two more Women together; the Prisoner stopped the Prosecutrix, just by the Door where I live, and she said, she would have her Money; she said, she had none; the Prisoner pulled her Pocket clear out, and turned it, and finding she had no Money, she cursed and swore, and untied her Apron, and said, she would have that; she begged and prayed, for Christ's Sake, that she would not take her Apron; says she, Do not take my Apron away, for I am going to a Gentleman's House, and cannot do without it: I said at first, what are you going to rob the Woman; and told her, I would call the Constable, who lived at next Door; she said, he might be d - d, and I too; she took away her Apron, and swore violently, and run away; the last Witness pursued her without Stockings, Shoes, or Breeches.</p>
               <p>- Burgess. I am Beadle, and a Wheelwright by Trade; the Prisoner at the Bar came running by my Door in a great Hurry, swearing, and making a Noise; I stepped out of the Door, and looking after her, I saw 
               <persName id="t17430629-47-person462">
                  Jasper 
                  Mullins 
               <interp inst="t17430629-47-person462" type="surname" value="Mullins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person462" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             running after her, without Shoes, Stockings, or Breeches; he calls out to me, Mr Burgess, stop that Woman, for she has committed a Robbery; said I to her. I want to speak with you; she turned back her Head, and I ran after her to the End of our Street, and told her she must come back; she had this Apron upon her (the Apron was sworn to by the Prosecutrix ) the Prosecutrix came crying, and said, You barbarous Woman how could you be so cruel, as to rob<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174306290027"></xptr> me, and beat me in this Manner; and, she said, she had lost a Hat; 
               <persName id="t17430629-47-person463">
                  Jasper 
                  Mullins 
               <interp inst="t17430629-47-person463" type="surname" value="Mullins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person463" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went from me, and I did not see him again for some Time afterwards; I charged my Son to take care of this Woman till Mullins came back again; and when he came back, he said, he had been following the other two Women, but could not find them.</p>
               <p>Jury to Mrs Brotherton. When you looked out of Window, and saw the four Women together, did not they look as if they were Arm in Arm?</p>
               <p>Brotherton, when they found that she would not consent to give them her Money, they took her Apron from her by Force; and the other two Women held her, while the Prisoner did it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That Man and that Woman only do it for the Sake of the Reward, 'tis for that they want to take away my Life.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mullins. You say, the Prisoner turned the Prosecutor's Pocket inside out; what did the Prisoner say then?</p>
               <p>Mullins. She took hold of her Apron, and tore it from her; I saw it plain enough all the while.</p>
               <p>Q. The Prosecutrix seems to be a pretty lusty Woman, did not she struggle with her?</p>
               <p>Mullins. She did struggle with her, I believe, as much as she could; but the Prisoner gave her several Blows; and at last, gave her a Blow upon her Arm, and then took her Apron.</p>
               <p>Jury. Were the two Women near at that Time?</p>
               <p>Mullins. They were not near her Body. <rs id="t17430629-47-verdict266" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430629-47-verdict266" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
