<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400416-36">
               <interp inst="t17400416-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-36" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400416-36" type="date" value="17400416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400416-36-off212-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-defend290 t17400416-36-off212 t17400416-36-verdict216"></join>
         
               <p>229. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400416-36-defend290" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Moore 
                  <interp inst="t17400416-36-defend290" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-defend290" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-defend290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400416-36-defloc211">Harmansworth</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-36-defloc211" type="placeName" value="Harmansworth"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-36-defloc211" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-defend290 t17400416-36-defloc211"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400416-36-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400416-36-victim292" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Freeman 
                        <interp inst="t17400416-36-victim292" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-36-victim292" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400416-36-victim292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-off212 t17400416-36-victim292"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17400416-36-viclabel213" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-victim292 t17400416-36-viclabel213"></join>; on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him a Guinea, and 6 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-36-cd214" type="crimeDate">Mar. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-off212 t17400416-36-cd214"></join>.</p>
               <p>John Way . On the seventh of March, as my Master (Mr Freeman) was coming to Town, two Men passed by the Coach on Horseback; I looked after them, and seeing them turn their Horses, I told Austin they were Highwaymen; and just as we got upon the Heath, the Prisoner rode up to the hind Wheel of the Coach, and cry'd - Stop Coachman. Then he presented his Pistol into the Coach, and bid my Master deliver his Money. I am sure the Prisoner is the Man; I remembered his Face as soon as ever I saw him in New-Prison. There were my Master and his Lady, and two Maid-Servants in the Coach; and he swore he would shoot them, if they did not deliver their Money: Upon which I saw my Master hold out his Hand, and give him something, which the Prisoner put into his own Pocket. The first Money that was given him, he put into his Right-hand Pocket, and the next into his Left; but I could not see what Money it was, and when he had got what he could, he bid the Coachman drive on. There was another Man in Company with him, but he did not come up to the Coach; he stopped Austin.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I am in such Misery I cannot discourse. He said I was the Man (in New-Prison) before he well saw my Face; and the Reason my Arm was so cut was, because my Name was Moore, and therefore they apprehended I was the Man.</p>
               <p>Way. When he robbed the Coach he had a brown dark-coloured Coat on, a Wig over his Hair, and his Hair was pulled down on each Side of his Face. He presented a short Pistol into the Coach, but I can't swear this is the Pistol, nor to what Money was given him, but I am sure he is the Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-36-person293">
                  Dorothy 
                  Biggs 
               <interp inst="t17400416-36-person293" type="surname" value="Biggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-person293" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . As we were coming over Hounslow-Heath, on the seventh of March, between four and five in the Afternoon, the Prisoner came up to the Coach, and presenting a Pistol, he demanded my Master's Money and Watch. I saw my Master give him Gold and Silver. I am sure the Prisoner is the Man. He had a dirty Wig upon his Hair, and his Hair was pulled over his Face. After he had my Master's Money, he demanded mine, but my Master telling him I was only a Servant, he went off in a Hurry.</p>
               <p>Mr Freeman. As I was coming over <placeName id="t17400416-36-crimeloc215">Hounslow-Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-36-crimeloc215" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400416-36-crimeloc215" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-off212 t17400416-36-crimeloc215"></join>, the seventh of March, the Prisoner rode up to the Coach, and bid the Coachman stop. I am sure he is the Man: he swore bitterly, and demanded my Money and Watch. I gave him 10 or 12 Shillings, and a Guinea, - I can't tell how much exactly. After this he demanded the Servants Money; I told him they were but Servants, and then he demanded my Wife's Money, and she gave him 6 or 7 Shillings. When he had got what Money he could, he demanded my Watch, and felt for it himself. I told him, I had none about me; and as he had got both Gold and Silver, he was pretty well off: Upon this he rode away; I am sure he is the Man; his Face is very remarkable, and I saw his black Hair under his Wig.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400416-36-person294">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17400416-36-person294" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-person294" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the Prisoner on Sunday the ninth of March: I first went to his House,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174004160031"></xptr>(the Sign of the Jolly Sailor at Ratcliffe) with a young Man; but the Prisoner not being up, we waited till he came down, and then I bid the young Man go out to call the rest of our Assistants. While he was gone, I desired the Prisoner to drink with me, but he immediately went out, and we lost him. Upon this we went out to take a Turn, and returned again to the Prisoner's House, which we searched, and found a Hanger, some Powder, and two or three Wigs. We had not been a Quarter of an Hour in the House (this last Time) before a Man came in, and asked if Mr Moore was at home? I took him on one Side, and asked him if he knew Moore? He said, yes. I told him I had a Warrant against him, and that he was a Highwayman, and if he would tell us where he was, it might be of Service both to him and the Publick. He told us he was then at a Publick-house, the Waterman's-Arms; and hearing this I ran away thither, and forgot my Hanger; but the young Man who was with me, happened to have taken the Hanger with him, which we found in the House. We found the Prisoner at the Waterman's-Arms, with a Pint of Beer before him, and I immediately laid my Hands on his Shoulder, and said, I take you up for the Highway. He clapp'd his Hand in his Pocket, and I judged what he was going to do, so I called out to the young Man who was with me, - Cut away! He did so, and we got the Prisoner out of the Box, where he sat, and cut him, and laid him upon his Back. Then he said, he would surrender; and I took out of his Hand this Pistol ready cock'd, and loaded with five Slugs; and one of the Slugs was of the same Sort with those taken from Hide. (See the preceeding Trial.) This Pistol I took out of his Hand, and this I found in his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They chopp'd my Hand off, before I saw them.</p>
               <p>Harris. We had Information that he had a Brace of Pistols about him: but we took him, and carried him back to his own House, and sent for a Surgeon, to sow up his Arm. We were forced to use Violence to him, because he was so desperate; and upon searching him again at his own House, we found a Knife 15 Inches long upon him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He took my wearing Cloaths out of the House, and all my Money from me.</p>
               <p>Harris. I took 39 s. and 6 d. from him; but I was wounded in the Contest, and have lost the Use of my Thumb. I could not work for a Fortnight, and have expended the Money, in paying my own Surgeon. My Thumb was almost cut off. - I have not the Money at present; I am a poor Man, and have not the Money at present. - I can't give him any of his Money now, for I have not a Farthing about me; and I have been out of Business a long Time.</p>
               <p>The Court reprimanded Harris for seizing and detaining the Prisoner's Money, and ordered him to restore it. <rs id="t17400416-36-verdict216" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-verdict216" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400416-36-punish217" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400416-36-punish217" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400416-36-defend290 t17400416-36-punish217"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
