<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-1">
               <interp inst="t17470225-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-1" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-1" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-1-off2-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-1-defend29 t17470225-1-off2 t17470225-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>128. +
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Perfect 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Perfect"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-defend29" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-defend29" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, and the Indictment sets forth, that on the <rs id="t17470225-1-cd1" type="crimeDate">27th of January</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-1-off2 t17470225-1-cd1"></join>, <rs id="t17470225-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               being big with a certain Male Child, in the <placeName id="t17470225-1-crimeloc3">Parish of Holy Trinity</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="Parish of Holy Trinity"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-1-off2 t17470225-1-crimeloc3"></join>; and she not having the Fear of God before her Eyes, and being moved by the Instigation of the Devil, on the said Male Bastard Child, did feloniously and wilfully make an Assault, and in a certain quilted Petticoat did, with both her Hands, wrap or hide, then and there feloniously, wilfully did suffocate and strangle
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-1-person30">
                  Mary 
                  Millet 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person30" type="surname" value="Millet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person30" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person30" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What is it you know in Relation to this Charge of 
               <persName id="t17470225-1-person31">
                  Hannah 
                  Perfect 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person31" type="surname" value="Perfect"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person31" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's murdering her Bastard Child?</p>
               <p>Millet. I don't know the Child was born alive.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an Account of what you know in Relation to this Child; What Employment do you follow?</p>
               <p>Millet. I am Servant in the same House where the Prisoner lived.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Prisoner in that House?</p>
               <p>Millet. She was <rs id="t17470225-1-deflabel4" type="occupation">Kitchen Girl</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-1-defend29 t17470225-1-deflabel4"></join>, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her being with Child?</p>
               <p>Millet. Nothing at all, Sir; we did not know that she was with Child.</p>
               <p>Q. What is it you know in Relation to this Matter?</p>
               <p>Millet. I don't know any thing relating to the Murder.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know at any Time, or when she was with Child?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What is it you know of a Child being wrapped up in a Petticoat?</p>
               <p>Millet. I know I went up Stairs a little before Nine; I don't know the Day of the Month, it was of a Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago was it? In what Month Mrs Millet?</p>
               <p>Millet. It was about a Month ago last Tuesday, I went up Stairs in the Room where she lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she been ill before that, or kept her Bed?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, when I went up to her, I asked her what was the Matter, and she said nothing at all to me; and I was very much surprized and came down Stairs, and went and fetched the Midwife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any thing that made you to think a Midwife was necessary?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that?</p>
               <p>Millet. I thought by what I did see, there must be a Child.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you this Thought by what you observed upon the Prisoner, or by what you observed in Relation of any Linnen or Bed?</p>
               <p>Millet. By what I observed on the Bed, and in the Room too.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250003"></xptr>Court. Well, you went to call the Midwife, and did she come?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, the Midwife came and found the Child.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that Child found in?</p>
               <p>Millet. It was laid in an old Petticoat under the Head of the Bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the Midwife took out the Child?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the Midwife here?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her Name?</p>
               <p>Millet. 
               <persName id="t17470225-1-person32">
                  Mary 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person32" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person32" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person32" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner confined up Stairs before that Day?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was this ?</p>
               <p>Millet. It was about Nine o'Clock at Night.</p>

               <p>Q. Whose Servants were you and the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Millet. Mr Smith's that keeps the Dog-Tavern on Garlick Hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing further?</p>
               <p>Millet. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you saw nothing but Marks of Blood upon the Linnen and Floor, did you?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the Child whether there were any Marks of Violence?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-1-person33">
                  Mary 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person33" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person33" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person33" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the next and only Witness besides, but being a Quaker she would not take an Oath, therefore was not admitted as an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-1-person34">
                  Mary 
                  Millet 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person34" type="surname" value="Millet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person34" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person34" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the former Witness. Was you present while 
               <persName id="t17470225-1-person35">
                  Mary 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17470225-1-person35" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person35" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-person35" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             examined this Child? Did you and she examine the Child together ?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you form any Kind of Judgment whether this Child had been alive?</p>
               <p>Millet Really, Sir, I cannot tell that indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. At that Time what was the best of your Judgment, whether the Child was born alive or dead.</p>
               <p>Millet. To the best of my Judgment the Child might have been born alive, but for want of proper Assistance to be sure the Child could not live long.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you cannot take it upon you to say whether the Child was or was not born alive.</p>
               <p>Millet. I can't indeed, Sir</p>
               <p>Court. You don't know she was with Child, or this was the Child she was delivered of? nor you don't know whether she was actually delivered of any Child ?</p>
               <p>Millet. Sir, I cannot say, I was not in the Room with her.</p>
               <p>Court. Nor you can't certainly say by these Marks you saw, that she was delivered of a Child?</p>
               <p>Millet. I could not be sure, but I thought it must be so by what I did see.</p>
               <p>Court. You did not discover this Child at the Head of the Bed till the Midwife came, did you?</p>
               <p>Millet. I was in a great Fright, and I did not look for it.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Condition was the Prisoner, was she in her Senses?</p>
               <p>Millet. I think she was not in her right Senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Behaviour at that Time that induced you to think she was crazy?</p>
               <p>Millet. I think the Nature of a Woman, except she was out of her Senses, would not make away or destroy her own.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you talk to her at that Time?</p>
               <p>Millet. She talked to no Body, nor gave no Body any Answer.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time might it be between your going up first, and the coming of the Midwife ?</p>
               <p>Millet. About five or six Minutes to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been up Stairs before you went up Stairs after her?</p>
               <p>Millet. About an Hour and an Half, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Conversation with her afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, Sir, only asked her how she could do so, but she made me no Answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you construe by her Behaviour that she was stupified; that she was in her Senses, or was not?</p>
               <p>Millet. I believe she was stupified.</p>
               <p>Court. You believe she had not the Government of her Understanding ?</p>
               <p>Millet. No, I believe she had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she a sensible Woman at other Times?</p>
               <p>Millet. She is a very sensible young Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any Conversation with her since that Time?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes; and she said her Child came dead into the World.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she since talked sensibly?</p>
               <p>Millet. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think from the Condition she was in at that Time she was sensible what came upon her? Had she drank any thing that Day?</p>
               <p>Millet. Nothing at all, any farther than common drink.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her Behaviour in general ?</p>
               <p>Millet. She always behaved like a very sober, honest Girl; I never heard her speak an ill Word in my Life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
