<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17461205-6">
               <interp inst="t17461205-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461205-6" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461205-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17461205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17461205-6" type="date" value="17461205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17461205-6-off21-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461205-6-defend105 t17461205-6-off21 t17461205-6-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>8. + 
               <persName id="t17461205-6-defend105" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-defend105" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-defend105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17461205-6-off21" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-off21" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-off21" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one Silver Tankard, value 8 l. the Goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17461205-6-victim107" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Francis 
                        <interp inst="t17461205-6-victim107" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461205-6-victim107" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17461205-6-victim107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461205-6-off21 t17461205-6-victim107"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , out of the Dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said 
               <persName id="t17461205-6-person108">
                  Henry 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person108" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person108" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17461205-6-crimeloc22">Bow-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17461205-6-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Bow-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17461205-6-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461205-6-off21 t17461205-6-crimeloc22"></join>, the <rs id="t17461205-6-cd23" type="crimeDate">14th of November</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461205-6-off21 t17461205-6-cd23"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461205-6-person109">
                  Henry 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person109" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person109" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the Bar came into my House this Day three Weeks, about nine o'Clock at Night, and he pushed himself into the Bar with Mr Rigby, otherwise I should not have admitted him into the Bar, on the Account of his mean Appearance. After he had been there a little while, Mr Rigby said he must go Home, and left a Shilling to pay the Reckoning: about a Quarter of an Hour afterwards, the Prisoner bid the Gentlemen good Night in the Bar, and took me by the Hand, and bid me good<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174612050008"></xptr> Night; as he was going not knowing the Stairs, he fell down the Cellar Stairs, I went down to him, and found the Tankard upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him take the Tankard?</p>
               <p>Francis. No, my Lord; but there was some Gentlemen see me take it from him; he concealed it in his Hand.</p>
               <p>Court. He could not conceal it, when he tumbled headlong?</p>
               <p>Francis. He had it in his Hand when I was under the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before, that you had seen the Tankard?</p>
               <p>Francis. My Lord, we had several Tankards in the Bar, several drinking there. He was upon his Backside, sitting upon the Stairs when I took him.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoner. Will you ask the Witness any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I was very fuddled.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461205-6-person110">
                  John 
                  Rigby 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person110" type="surname" value="Rigby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner at the Bar made a great Noise at my Door, the 14th Day of November at Night. I live the very next Door to this Gentleman, the Witness. My Boy heard some-body make a Noise at the Door; he went down and opened the Door, and the Prisoner asked if Mr Rigby was at Home, the Boy answered yes; he said, call him down then, then my Boy called me down, as I was coming down Stairs, the Prisoner said, Is not your Name Mr Rigby, says he, I am come to be taken Measure of by you for a Suit of Cloaths; I said, where do you lodge? he said, I lodge at the next Door, meaning the Prosecutor's House; I said, have you got the Cloth to make the Cloaths? he said no, but he should have it by nine o'Clock in the Morning; I said it would be Time enough to measure him then, but he would not let me rest till I had done it; he said he would send the Cloth to that Gentleman's at the Tavern, at nine o'Clock in the Morning, but he would not let me rest till I had measured him, and then he would not let me rest unless I would take a Tankard of Beer with him at the next Door, so I went into the Gentleman's House, and would have sat down in the Kitchen, but he would not sit there, but forced himself into the Bar; so the Gentlemen were talking about foreign Coin, &amp;c. and he talked with them while we were drinking the Tankard of Beer. I thought it long, it was my Bed-time, and I would go home. I left him in the Bar with the four Gentlemen; about half an Hour after I was gone to Bed, either this Gentleman came himself, or sent some of his Servants to my Door, and said I had brought a Man there that stole his Tankard. True, I did go in with the Man, but he said he lodged there. I never saw him before he knocked at the Door. I imagined that my Neighbour had sent me a Customer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461205-6-person111">
                  Elias 
                  Falmoth 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person111" type="surname" value="Falmoth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person111" type="given" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the House drinking, and saw Mr Francis take the Tankard from under the Prisoner's Coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17461205-6-person112">
                  Philip 
                  Scriwen 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person112" type="surname" value="Scriwen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person112" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Peruke-maker, my Lord, the Prisoner came into my Shop, my Servant called me up (I was below Stairs); the Prisoner said he wanted to bespeak a Wig of me. I looked at the Man, and I did not think he was a Person that wanted a Wig. He said he belonged to a Privateer, that he was just come home, and he was going to receive 70 l. behind the Exchange; but seeing the Man so shabby, and I thought a little in Liquor, I did not regard what he said, but wanted to get rid of him, and looked to see that he should not take any Thing from me. At last he says, I will speak with you; he said, it is a sad Thing for a Man to be in Distress; I said it was impossible that he should be in Distress, that was going to receive so much Money so soon. He desired me to lend him a Couple of Shillings; he pressed me very much, but I let him have nothing. I asked him his Name, and he gave me his Name in Writing, that it was Captain 
               <persName id="t17461205-6-person113">
                  James 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17461205-6-person113" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person113" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>To the Prisoner. What do you say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I have several People to speak for me, that I could send to, but I did not know my Trial would come on. - The only Defence the Prisoner made, was, that he was very much in Liquor.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17461205-6-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-verdict24" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty, value 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17461205-6-punish25" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17461205-6-punish25" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17461205-6-defend105 t17461205-6-punish25"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
