<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411204-4">
               <interp inst="t17411204-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-4" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-4" type="date" value="17411204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-4-off15-c46" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend52 t17411204-4-off15 t17411204-4-verdict17"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-4-off15-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend55 t17411204-4-off15 t17411204-4-verdict17"></join>
         
               <p>5, 6. 
               <persName id="t17411204-4-defend52" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Warner 
                   alias <rs id="t17411204-4-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend52 t17411204-4-alias-2"></join>Goody Warner</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend52" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17411204-4-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend55" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of <placeName id="t17411204-4-defloc14">St. James's Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-4-defloc14" type="placeName" value="St. James's Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-4-defloc14" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend52 t17411204-4-defloc14"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend55 t17411204-4-defloc14"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17411204-4-off15" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-off15" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-off15" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411204-4-victim57" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Blackburn 
                        <interp inst="t17411204-4-victim57" type="surname" value="Blackburn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-4-victim57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-4-victim57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-off15 t17411204-4-victim57"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, &amp;c and taking a Silver Watch, value 4 l. 2 Iron Keys, value 2 d. a Quart Glass Bottle filled with Brandy, value 1 s. and a Copper Pocket Piece, value 1 d. and 5 s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17411204-4-cd16" type="crimeDate">Nov 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-off15 t17411204-4-cd16"></join>. </p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's Desire the Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Wm Blackburn. On Sunday Morning the first of last Month, a little before one o'Clock, I was going up towards Islington, and very near Sadler's Wells back Gate, he in the blue grey Coat and red Waistcoat (Warner) came up to me with a Hanger in his Hand .</p>
               <p>Pris. Warner. He swore before the Justice, that I had the Pistol.</p>
               <p>Blackburn. Another came up , whom I take to be the other Prisoner, with a Horse Pistol in his Hand, and they damn'd me , and bid me deliver my Money. I dropped my Watch in the Grass , thinking to save it, and I had a Bottle of Brandy on my left Side, and Warner took it out of my Pocket, and the other took 5 s and two Box Keys. Warner happen'd to see my Watch lie in the Field , and he said , D - n me Jack , here, I have got his Watch! come along Jack! and then I saw them go along the Field together, and presently I saw a Man lying at length, and heard him cry O Dear! Upon that one of them said, he had a good Mind to turn again and shoot him through the Head, and the other said, he deserved his Brains blown out, and they would do it. I passed them, and went up to 'Squire Edward's Brewhouse, at the Woolpack, for some of their Men to come and see what was the Matter with the Man, and while I was there the Man himself ( 
               <persName id="t17411204-4-person58">
                  Charles 
                  Shippey 
               <interp inst="t17411204-4-person58" type="surname" value="Shippey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person58" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) came up.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a Night was this?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. A Star light Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish the Persons?</p>
               <p>Blackburn Yes, very well.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Warner. How came you to take us up?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I described their Persons, and on the Tuesday following they were taken on Suspicion of House-breaking, and sent to the Gate-house, where we saw them. - They were both taken up on the Tuesday, and Warner only was sent to the Gatehouse, and we saw him there the next Day.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Employment?</p>
               <p>Blackburn, I am Servant to Mr. Forcer , and</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040004"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>have lived with him three Years, and the Night this happened, I had been at Goodman's-Fields to a Benefit there.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the Persons dressed that robbed you:</p>
               <p>Blackburn . Warner was in the same Dress as he is in now, but Newman was not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Newman. The Almanack will convince these People that it was a dark Night. Here is a Frock, and he swore I had not a Frock on. This is a Frock.</p>
               <p>Q. What, that which you had on then?</p>
               <p>Newman. Yes my Lord; he saw me in Goal in this Frock. Ask him whether it was not a dark Night?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. It was between twelve and one in the Morning, and Star-light.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-4-person59">
                  Charles 
                  Shippey 
               <interp inst="t17411204-4-person59" type="surname" value="Shippey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person59" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two Prisoners met me, and knock'd me down, and after I had recovered myself, I walk'd to Mr. Edwards's Brewhouse, and there I saw Blackburn. He said, he had been robb'd, and I told him, I believed they had broke my Skull, but I would go back and see for my Meat and Potatoes. After they had robbed me, Warner said, here comes another, and I turned my Head as quick as he spoke, and saw Mr. Blackburn in his white Apron, and he told me, he had lost his Watch, and five Shillings, a Half penny, a Pocket-piece, and a Quart of Brandy.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that after they had robbed you?</p>
               <p>Shippey . Not two Minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in the same Place?</p>
               <p>Shippey . I believe it was ten or twelve Yards distant .</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in the Place where Blackburn was robbed ?</p>
               <p>Shippey . Yes, they ran from me to him. Warner ran first, and as he was going along, I took him a Drive to knock him down, and I hurt my Hand in two Places. He had a Horse-Pistol in his Hand, and when I took him that Blow, Newman knock'd me down again; I can't tell with what, for I lay senseless.</p>
               <p>Q. Where they the Persons that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Shippey . Yes, Warner came up to me, and ran his Pistol to my Breast: I said, Friend, I have nothing about me worth your taking. He put his Hand into one Pocket and found nothing, but in my other Pocket, I had three Shillings, which he took from me, and I believe he would not have taken my Meat, if I had not struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before Blackburn was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Shippey. Yes, as soon as he had taken the three Shillings out of my Pocket, he said, here comes another, and I turned my Head , and saw a Man in a white Apron; so I took him a Knock, and thought I would have another when Blackburn came up, imagining he might take my Part; but they knocked me down, and immediately went up to him, and the last Words I heard them say, were, D - his B - d, I have a good Mind to go back and shoot him through the Brains, for he deserves it. It was a Star-light Night, and the Watch were going Twelve when we came through Wood's Close.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them afterwards?</p>
               <p>Shippey. Warner was sent to the Gatehouse, and Newman to Bridewell, and there I saw them the Wednesday following.</p>
               <p>Newman. Please to see whether it was a Starlight Night.</p>
               <p>Shippey. It was a Star-light Night.</p>
               <p>Warner. Did it Rain?</p>
               <p>Shippey. No.</p>
               <p>Warner. I hope you will look into it, and see whether it did or no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-4-person60">
                  Charles 
                  Revington 
               <interp inst="t17411204-4-person60" type="surname" value="Revington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person60" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know no more than that I have seen the two Prisoners together Day and Night. - I am a Marshal's Court Officer.</p>
               <p>Warner. He is a Thief-taker .</p>
               <p>Revington. Mr. Blackburn was at our House, and left Word that he wanted to speak with me, and when I saw him, he informed me he had been robbed by a Man in a blue grey Coat, and another in a brown Frock. Afterwards hearing that these Men were taken, I desired him to go and look at them, and I went with him and Shippey , and they were positive to the Men. I have seen them frequently in the Street passing and repassing in the Night-time.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business had you up in the Night-time?</p>
               <p>Revington . I have attacked some of their Kind before.</p>
               <p>Jury . Was there a mix'd Company when Blackburn picked them out at the Gatehouse ?</p>
               <p>Revington. I was not directly in, because Warner threw a Pipe at me, and swore he would do me a Mischief, but there were several Prisoners about.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body shew the Man to Blackburn?</p>
               <p>Revington. No, he challenged him himself.</p>
               <p>Q. To Blackburn. Did any Body point out Warner to you?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. No, I just look'd at him, and he said D - n your Eyes, you Rogue, what do you look at me for? I saw Newman in Tothillfields Bridewell; Revington was with me , and I found him out myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040005"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-4-person61">
                  Thomas 
                  Blackburn 
               <interp inst="t17411204-4-person61" type="surname" value="Blackburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person61" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Shoemaker by Trade, and have kept the Coach and Horses in Hog-Lane , St. Giles's, a Quarter of a Year at Christmas. I have known Newman two Years and something better. He is a Bricklayer by Trade, and lived in the same House with me in Newport Market: that was two Years ago, and I have not been much in his Company since then, but I never knew any Harm of the Man. I used to make Shoes for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Warner?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-4-person62">
                  Thomas 
                  Blackburn 
               <interp inst="t17411204-4-person62" type="surname" value="Blackburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, they were at my House together the Sunday Morning this was sworn to be done. I took Notice of it, because he said it was the first of October, and they were at my House then.</p>
               <p>C. That happens to be a Month before the Robbery.</p>
               <p>Warner. My Witnesses will not be here till To-morrow.</p>
               <p>Newman. Examine whether it was a Star-light Morning or no. I have no Money, and therefore can't get any Body else to appear for me. </p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17411204-4-verdict17" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-verdict17" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17411204-4-punish18" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-4-punish18" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend52 t17411204-4-punish18"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-4-defend55 t17411204-4-punish18"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
