<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-31">
               <interp inst="t17470225-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-31" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-31" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-31-off132-c296" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-31-defend366 t17470225-31-off132 t17470225-31-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>166. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-defend366" type="defendantName">
                     Lucy 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-31-defend366" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-defend366" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-defend366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-31-off132" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-off132" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-off132" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               feloniously receiving of 
                     <persName id="t17470225-31-person367">
                        Edward 
                        Corp 
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person367" type="surname" value="Corp"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-31-person367" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-31-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , thirty five Pounds Weight of Wood called Fustick, which Goods stole by the said 
                     <persName id="t17470225-31-person368">
                        Edward 
                        Corp 
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person368" type="surname" value="Corp"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-31-person368" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470225-31-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, he has been already convicted for. <rs id="t17470225-31-cd133" type="crimeDate">November 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-31-off132 t17470225-31-cd133"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person369">
                  George 
                  Hardwell 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person369" type="surname" value="Hardwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person369" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to the Prisoner, I don't know her, but as to the Fustick, I detected Corp with it, and he told me that he had sold it to this Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search the Prisoner's House, or did you find this Fustick in her House? What do you know of your own Knowledge?</p>
               <p>Hardwell. Of my own Knowledge I detected the Man in stealing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he steal it?</p>
               <p>Hardwell. He stole it the 14th of November; between eight and nine o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Woman?</p>
               <p>Hardwell. I asked him what he was to do with it, and he told me he was to sell it to Mrs Walker; I asked him how he knew he could sell it there, he said he sold things to her before.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250038"></xptr>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-31-person370">
                  Robert 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person370" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person370" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know of the Prisoner's having any Fustick stole by Edward Corp?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I was Constable for the Night, when the Wood was stole off from Wiggins's Key, he said he sold it for three Half-pence, and I had a Warrant in my House to search the Prisoner's House, which I did, and found it there; I had a Warrant from my Lord-Mayor, to search that Woman's House, upon Corp's being brought before him: I found the Wood in her Room; she was not at Home; I never saw her since, till I saw her yesterday. Corp told me that he had three half pence for it; he would have given it me; I told him he was a poor unhappy Creature, I would not have his Money.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you find upon searching her House?</p>
               <p>Lucas. This is the 
               <persName id="t17470225-31-person371">
                  Wood 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person371" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person371" type="given" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             found in the Grate in the Chimney; (The Stick of Wood was produced in Court) 'tis Fustick used by the Dyers.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in an upper or lower Floor?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person372">
                  Lucas 
                  It 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person372" type="surname" value="It"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person372" type="given" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was upon the Ground Floor, I saw none but a little Girl; I demanded the Wood that was bought of a poor Fellow.</p>
               <p>Court. You don't know how she came by this?</p>
               <p>Lucas. No otherwise but what Corp told me; and I found it by his Description, it was a crooked Piece of Wood.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you afterwards any Conversation with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I never saw her before yesterday, and asked her how she came to be such an unhappy Woman as to bring herself into such a Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person373">
                  William 
                  Skarf 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person373" type="surname" value="Skarf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person373" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I caught Corp with the Wood, and he told me where he was going to sell it; I told him I was sure she would not buy it, for I says she was tried in May Sessions for such a thing; he said she would, for she had bought many a Piece of him; so I went with him to the Door, and he showed the Door, and went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Skarf. I saw Mrs Walker and her Daughter, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by?</p>
               <p>Skarf. I was looking on all the Time.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she offer him?</p>
               <p>Skarf. First a Penny, at last she gave him three half pence for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ask him any Questions?</p>
               <p>Skarf. Not any, for I was at the Door, and I saw and heard all that past, for I did not believe that she would buy it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her give him the three half-pence ?</p>
               <p>Skarf. Yes, my Lord, he brought it out in his Hand, and carried it down to the Keys in his Hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that Fustick worth?</p>
               <p>Skarf. Mr. Lucas can tell you, I cannot tell?</p>
               <p>Q. to Lucas. Do you know the Value of that Fustick that is produced in Court?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I asked the Opinion of two Brokers, and it was valued between three and four Shillings, 'tis between 30 and 40 Pounds Weight.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoner You have heard what the Witnesses have sworn; you are charged with receiving these things knowing them to be stolen.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, this poor Fellow used to bring Hoop-sticks, and I used to give him a Penny or Two-pence. There was a House a pulling down a little from us, and he brought it from thence. I am innocent: I am as innocent as your precious Heart within you; if it is any otherwise, it is Ignorance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person374">
                  Thomas 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person374" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person374" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her seven or eight Years; I never heard that she was guilty of any such Crime: She keeps a Cook's Shop in Harp lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general Character?</p>
               <p>Proctor. Her general Character is, that she is a poor honest industrious Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person375">
                  Samuel 
                  Luck 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person375" type="surname" value="Luck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person375" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her six or seven Years; and she kept a Cook's Shop in another Place. I happened to lodge there when this Bit of Wood was brought in: When the Man brought it, she went to turn it out of Doors. I said, I would not give a Farthing for it; it was heavy Stuff: The Man asked her to buy a Bit of Wood to burn.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she do ?</p>
               <p>Luck. She refused it, and said it was not fit to burn</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Name of the Man?</p>
               <p>Luck. No, I never saw him before: He was an undersized Man: She let him have Three half pence for it, and it was laid in the Room by the Fire-side, in order to burn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person376">
                  Mary 
                  Cutler 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person376" type="surname" value="Cutler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person376" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 14 Years; I have been Servant to her about 10 Years, of and on; and she always paid me for what I did</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-31-person377">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person377" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person377" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Clark. Yes, my Lord, very well; and she knows me: I am one of the King's Constables for the Custom-house and I know the Prisoner to be a Dealer in all Manner of Goods: I have taken Goods out of her House, but I know nothing of this Fact.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general Character?</p>
               <p>Clark. A reputed Buyer of Sugar, Tobacco, Rice, Camels Hair. I never indeed took any of that.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250039"></xptr>- Clark to the Prisoner. Did not I make you go out of your House in Bear-lane ? I have often cautioned you of these Things</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-31-person378">
                  William 
                  Skarf 
               <interp inst="t17470225-31-person378" type="surname" value="Skarf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person378" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I have known her nine or ten Years: I know she was reckoned a Buyer of several Sorts of Goods.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-31-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-31-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[The Prisoner being an old Offender, had a very narrow Escape from being sent abroad in her old Age]</p>
            </div1>
