<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470715-20">
               <interp inst="t17470715-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-20" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470715-20" type="date" value="17470715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470715-20-off86-c156" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-20-defend190 t17470715-20-off86 t17470715-20-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>290. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470715-20-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     Lewis 
                     Lawrence 
                  <interp inst="t17470715-20-defend190" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-defend190" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470715-20-off86" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-off86" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-off86" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing three Prints, one Carpet, and seven Cups and Saucers
            </rs> , the Good of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470715-20-victim192" type="victimName">
                     Abraham 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17470715-20-victim192" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-victim192" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-20-off86 t17470715-20-victim192"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470715-20-cd87" type="crimeDate">May the 7th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470715-20-off86 t17470715-20-cd87"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174707150013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-20-person193">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17470715-20-person193" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-person193" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we lost a Carpet, seven Cups and Saucers, and three Prints; all lost the 7th Day of May. There was the Print of the Duke of Cumberland , another of Mr Handel, the other of Mr Hebden. I lost these Things that Night the Fire was at our House . I have nothing to say against the Prisoner, but I found the Goods in his Apartment the 13th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is his Apartment?</p>
               <p>Brown. In Prince's-street, Cavendish square .</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to his Apartment.</p>
               <p>Brown . Because I had a Servant that went into the same House to lodge, and she told me she saw our Carpet upon his Floor; so I got a Search-Warrant, and found the Things there. The Carpet was on the Ground, two of the Prints were on the Chest of Drawers. The Cups and Saucers were set out in the Closet.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Seal . I saw the Carpet in his Lodgings. I can't say directly the Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you live with Mr Abraham Brown?</p>
               <p>Seal. Yes, Sir, I liv'd there almost two Years. I saw the Carpet through the Door, and I told my Mistress of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other Thing?</p>
               <p>Seal. No, Sir, not till they had a Justice's Warrant, then I saw the Prints and the other Things. My Mistress ask'd Mrs Laurence , how she came by the Things? And she did not know any Thing of them. When we came before the Justice he said, he went out of Town, and he desired his Wife to inquire about the Things, and deliver them. Part of one of the Frames was left in my Master's House.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any Thing before the Justice, how he came by those Things?</p>
               <p>Seal. He said a Person brought them. Mrs Laurence was before the Justice first; and when he came home and heard where she was gone he went before the Justice; so the Justice took him and discharg'd his Wife.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Now is your Time to make your Defence.</p>
               <p>Laurence. I was at my Lord Harcourt's to dress a Dinner, and stay'd late that Night the Fire was; as I was coming Home a Gentleman's Servant came to my Door; for God's sake, says he, a Fire is at our House, take these Things, and I'll call To-morow . I says, do you know me? My Name is Laurence .</p>
               <p>Q. to Col. 
               <persName id="t17470715-20-person194">
                  Talbot
               <interp inst="t17470715-20-person194" type="given" value="Talbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-person194" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Talbot . I have known the Prisoner at the Bar for several Years. I know not only his Character in general to be as honest, industrious Man as ever liv'd, but have known him and his Family, and entrusted him in my House, and Relations, these twenty Years. I know he is a Man of much Probity and Honestly I know him to be a Man of that Character, that there are very few of that Probity, and take that Care of their Children, as he does of his.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470715-20-person195">
                  Thomas 
                  Crosdell 
               <interp inst="t17470715-20-person195" type="surname" value="Crosdell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-person195" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about sixteen Years; he liv'd with my Lord Archer. At that Time he had an extraordinary good Character, and his Wife too. This Charge against the Prisoner came within the Limits of the Act of Grace; but the Prisoner chose to have it try'd to clear up his Character, and he had a very good one. He was honourably <rs id="t17470715-20-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470715-20-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
