<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-24">
               <interp inst="t17421208-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-24" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-24" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-24-off133-c183" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-24-defend229 t17421208-24-off133 t17421208-24-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>26. + 
               <persName id="t17421208-24-defend229" type="defendantName">
                  David 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-defend229" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-defend229" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-defend229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17421208-24-defloc132">St Paul, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-24-defloc132" type="placeName" value="St Paul, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-24-defloc132" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-24-defend229 t17421208-24-defloc132"></join> , was indicted <rs id="t17421208-24-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               for assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-24-victim231" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Squire 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim231" type="surname" value="Squire"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim231" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from her one Mother of Pearl Snuff-box, with a Silver Rim and Hinge, Value 7 s. a Pocket-Book, Value 2 d. and one Silk Handkerchief, Value 1 s. and two Shillings and a Penny in Money, the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-24-victim233" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Squire 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim233" type="surname" value="Squire"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim233" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-24-victim233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17421208-24-cd134" type="crimeDate">October 15th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-24-off133 t17421208-24-cd134"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-24-person234">
                  Mary 
                  Squire 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-person234" type="surname" value="Squire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person234" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of October in the Evening, between the Hours of Nine and Ten, I was going down <placeName id="t17421208-24-crimeloc135">Tavistock-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-24-crimeloc135" type="placeName" value="Tavistock-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-24-crimeloc135" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-24-off133 t17421208-24-crimeloc135"></join>, and was very much frightened with this Fellow's (the Prisoner at the Bar) standing against a Wall, so that I did not know which Way to go; but I went down the Street and turned the Corner, and three or four Doors beyond the Salutation Alehouse, I saw him again: I found a Touch at my Pocket, and presently I was knock'd down, and my Pocket tore from me, my Knees were very much cut and bruised with the Fall; the Person that knocked me down, came behind me, for I saw him over my Shoulder; he was a Soldier, I took particular Notice of him. - It was a darkish Night; but by the Light of the Salutation, I could see him very plain. - I was very much<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080016"></xptr> afraid of him, seeing him standing with his Back against a dead still so that I took particular Notice, and had a full View of him; I am very positive the Prisoner is the Man. Mr Rock apprehended the Prisoner in a Minute or two after I cried out, Stop Thief, Stop Thief, Soldier, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he taken while he was in Sight, or was he got out of your Sight?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-24-person235">
                  Mary 
                  Squire 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-person235" type="surname" value="Squire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person235" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I cannot say but he was got out of my Sight: I heard my Pocket was found a Quarter of an Hour after he was taken; there was a Man said, he would help me to my Pocket again for a Guinea . - I never had my Pocket or any of my Things again; - there was in it a Snuff-Box, a Pocket-Book , and 2 s. 1 d. in Money .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She says now, there was 2 s. 1 d. in her Pocket; and she said before the Justice, there was but one Shilling; she swore before the Justice, that I was the Man, because I had got a red Coat on; and she said there, that she could not be certain to my Face, for she only saw my Back.</p>
               <p>Squire . He was the Person, upon the Oath that I have taken; I viewed his Face by the Light at the Salutation , or I would not have swore so positively to him; for I have a greater Regard to Life .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was it a Moon light Night, or a dark Night?</p>
               <p>Squire. It was dark, but the Light came against the Wall.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am innocent of the Fact, I am sure.</p>
               <p>Mr. Huggins . I am one of the Constables of Covent Garden Parish; I took Charge of the Prisoner at the Bar, on the 15th of October, and searched him, to see if I could find any Fire-Arms, or any Thing that might endanger us in carrying him before a Magistrate; but I could not find any, or any Thing that Mrs Squire had charged him with; but there was another Pocket dropped from between his Coat and Waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I told him I found the Pocket, for it does not belong to she.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-24-person236">
                  John 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-person236" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman in Charles-Street; on the 15th of October, between Nine and Ten, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief; I stood still a little while to hear where it was: I perceived it was in Tavistock Street; then I heard a Cry of Stop Thief, Soldier, Thief, &amp;c. I seized him, - he fell into my Hands with a great deal of Easiness; he made no Opposition. but said, he would submit to me; and as there was no Watchman came immediately to me, I desired some Gentlemen to help me to hold him, and I held him, by their Assistance, till Mrs Squire came up; she said, she had been robbed, and that she was very positive that the Prisoner was the Man ; I bid her look in his Face, and see if he was the Man; she said, she was positive he was the Man that robbed her; Mr Huggins the Constable, searched him; but the Prisoner did not give any Account how he came by the Pocket that was found upon him: - He said he would submit, these were his very Words . Mrs Squire was very faint when she came up, and was very confident that he was the Man; there was one Mrs Langley's Pocket found in the Place where he robbed Mrs Squire</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Do you say you were the Man that stopped me?</p>
               <p>Rawlinson. Yes; I do.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Man says he stopped me; were there two Men that stopped me?</p>
               <p>Rawlinson. I stopped him, and then he was with out any Hat and running. - he did not resist</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had no Occasion to resist, if I was not guilty of the Fact, and I am sure I am innocent of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-24-person237">
                  William 
                  Rock 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-person237" type="surname" value="Rock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of October, between Nine and Ten in the Evening, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief; I perceived a Man running, and was waiting for him; I stood looking on both Sides of the Way, for I could hear the Tread as he came along; when he came pretty near me, I caught hold of his Coat; the Cry was Stop Thief, Stop Soldier, there was no Body pursued him, and no Body but he and I in the Street, as I could see: He slipped out of my Hand, and the Watchman coming along, got hold of him; when the Watchman had hold of him, I went to the Prosecutrix, and brought her to the Prison . - I was the first Person that laid hold of him. - it was neither Dark nor Light; it was a Starlight Night. - I found out the Woman that owned this Pocket, which was found upon him, by advertising it; but she is since absconded.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. One of the Evidence says, there was a great Mob in the Street, and the other says, there was no Body in the Street.</p>
               <p>Rock. When you came to the upper End of the the Street, there were five or six People; but that was the second Time of my coming up with you, for you got away from me the first.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw him before in my Life: Did I make any Resistance?</p>
               <p>Rock. He slipped away, and got about ten or a dozen Yards from me; I had hold of him but slightly by the Coat, - he had no Hat on, - the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080017"></xptr> Street was very quiet till after the Cry of Stop Thief, and then there were some People got together.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner in his Defence, said, On Friday Night I was in Liquor, and quarrelled with a Man, and in that Quarrel I lost my Hat; coming along the Street, I heard a Cry of Stop Thief, and I said, where, where? and in running along, I met that Man, and he took me hold by the Collar, and let me go again; and presently this Watchman took hold of me; then I said to him, keep me if you will , for I have done nothing, for I knew myself innocent; then they searched me, and said, here is a Pocket. Ask them, whether I did not bid you shew it to the Woman, and said, if she had a Right to it, I would suffer Death; and the Woman still insisting upon it, that it was a Soldier who robbed her , and because there was ne'er another Soldier in the Street, it must be me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-24-person238">
                  James 
                  Massey 
               <interp inst="t17421208-24-person238" type="surname" value="Massey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person238" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . [Call'd by the Prisoner.] I believe I can contradict what has been said in Court, for I was the Person that took him. - I serve one Mr Swinney , belonging to the Custom-House: I was going to my Master's Duty about ten Minutes after Nine, in the Evening on the 15th of October, I heard some People cry out stop Thief, and I cry'd out stop Thief: There was a Woman before me, and she jump'd up upon a Door-way, and the Prisoner came running along, and ran against me; and as the Gentleman, the Prisoner at the Bar, came running against me, he hit his Foot against a Stone, and fell down about five Yards from me: Then I cry'd out, who calls stop Thief? but no body answered. I called out again, who calls stop Thief? still no body answered. This Person, the Prisoner at the Bar, lay still, and did not offer to stir: I said, if he offered to stir a Foot further I would knock him down; for as there was a Cry of stop Thief, I believed he was the Thief. He put his Hands in this Manner in his Bosom, and did not offer to move. I called out again, who calls stop Thief? and no Answer was made; presently there came up three People: I asked what's the Matter; they cry'd out stop Thief , and so did I; then the Prisoner came running against me; I took hold of him, believing he might be the Thief. Damn you says he, let me go: He was gone about four or five Yards from me, then they cry'd out stop Thief, Soldier: Then said I, do not let him go: Then some body took hold of him before I did the second Time; then I called out for a Watchman, and desired him to come and take Charge of him; he refus'd it: There came a Man running up, and asked where he was? Said I, do not hurry your self, for here he is safe: Then there came a Man with a Napkin Cap tied about his Head, and said, I believe that is the Man. I said again to the Watchman, now will you take Charge of him; which he refused, then said I, damn him. let him go; but when Mrs Squire came up, she said, that is the Man that knock'd me down, and took my Pocket from me. Now said I to the Watchman, will you take Charge of him, and then he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she give any Reason why he should's the Person?</p>
               <p>Massey . No: but when she said he was the Person , I said, if he went any further I would knock him down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You see, my Lord, they do it for the Sake of the Reward, for one Witness contradicts another. <rs id="t17421208-24-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17421208-24-punish137" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-24-punish137" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-24-defend229 t17421208-24-punish137"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
