<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-53">
               <interp inst="t17430907-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-53" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-53" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-53-off272-c432" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-53-defend526 t17430907-53-off272 t17430907-53-verdict276"></join>
         
               <p>429. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430907-53-defend526" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Cotes 
                  <interp inst="t17430907-53-defend526" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-defend526" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-defend526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted (toge ther with 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person527">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Prothero 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person527" type="surname" value="Prothero"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person527" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken ) for <rs id="t17430907-53-off272" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-off272" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-off272" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               feloniously and traiterously forging, coining, and counterfeiting, six Pieces of false and seigned Money, to the Likeness of good and lawful Money called Half-Crowns, &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17430907-53-cd273" type="crimeDate">July 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-53-off272 t17430907-53-cd273"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-53-person528">
                  Thomas 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person528" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person528" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person528" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Turnwheel to Mr King, Pewterer in <placeName id="t17430907-53-crimeloc274">Gracechurch-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-53-crimeloc274" type="placeName" value="Gracechurch-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-53-crimeloc274" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-53-off272 t17430907-53-crimeloc274"></join>, when this Fact was committed, the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person529">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Prothero 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person529" type="surname" value="Prothero"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person529" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person529" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were his <rs id="t17430907-53-deflabel275" type="occupation">Apprentices</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-53-defend526 t17430907-53-deflabel275"></join>. - I saw Marmaduke beat out two Pieces of Lead flat and smooth with a Hammer upon an Anvil (Cotes was by at the same Time) he nail'd one of them to a Piece of Board, and turned a round Hole in it, - he said it was to cast a Seal for a Watch; he turned it to the Bigness of a Half-Crown and hollowed it, and then fixed a Half-Crown upon it. After he had done that Piece he nailed the other Piece on, then he hollowed it to the same Circumference, and half the Thickness; so these two Pieces of Lead were one Mould; after he had done that, he held the Hollow of each Piece over the Candle and blacked it with the Smoak; then he put the two Pieces of Lead together, and put a Half-Crown between them, and laid it upon an Anvil; (he made the Impression before he smoaked it with the Candle) and gave it a Stroke or two with a Sledge-Hammer, and then there was the Impression of a Half-Crown on each Side of the Mould; then he took some of the Metal that my Master makes his best Pewter of, put it into a Ladle, melted it, and poured it into the Mould, and it came out in the Shape of an Half-Crown; then he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070034"></xptr> said to 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person530">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person530" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person530" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person530" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , this will serve well enough to give to the Whores, if we have an Opportunity.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prisoner make him any Answer?</p>
               <p>Gray. I do not remember, that he did; Marmaduke, made three or four at that Time, and filed the Edges to make them smooth, I did not see the Mould again for a Fortnight; when he destroyed that, and in the like Manner made a Mould for a 36 s. Piece; he did not use that Mould, that I know of; he had a Sort of Metal, what it was I cannot tell, but to look at it, it was like a Piece of Glass, he put that into the Ladle, and held it till it was red hot, but it would not melt; 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person531">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person531" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person531" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person531" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             then said, You can do nothing at that, Duke, I would have you let it alone, and do no more about it, he laid it by at that Time; the next Day, or the Day after, he melts some Lead, and pours it into two Parcels as before. beats them out flat, and nails one of them to the Block, and makes a Hole in it, as he did before; after he had made one, he bid 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person532">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person532" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person532" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person532" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do the other; 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person533">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person533" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person533" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person533" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             tried, but could not do it so well as he - he asked 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person534">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person534" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person534" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person534" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to make the other half Mould; Cotes said, Make an End of it yourself, for I will do no more about it; Prothero made an End of it himself, and did it to his own Liking; after it was done, and he had made the Impression, he held it over my Master's Pit of Metal, to melt the Edges off, because he thought it was too broad - he held the Mould over that Mettle to melt the outside Edges off; and doing that, he made it so hot, that it all run in, and he lost his Mould: 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person535">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person535" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person535" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person535" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, you have spoilt my Master's Pot of Metal, and that he could not cast the Basons; which made a great Confusion between them two at that Time; and no more was then done: The Saturday following, my Master went to his Country-Seat at Camberwell; in the Afternoon, Marmaduke came down into the Cellar, and made another Mould for Half-Crowns, as he did the first; he made the Impression, and finished it by himself; after he had done it, he melted down some of my Master's Metal, and poured it into the Mould, and it came out in the Shape of a Half-Crown.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there cast at that Time?</p>
               <p>Gray. There were eight or ten cast.</p>
               <p>Q. Who cast them all, Marmaduke, or the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Gray. Sometimes one cast, and sometimes the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that the Prisoner cast any?</p>
               <p>Gray. I saw him cast some.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by casting?</p>
               <p>Gray. I mean the pouring the Metal into the Mould - sometimes they came out with Holes in them, and then they threw them into the Pot again.</p>
               <p>Q. Who threw them in again?</p>
               <p>Gray. Cotes threw some in.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell, who cast them that were cast whole?</p>
               <p>Gray. I cannot tell whether Cotes cast any that came out whole.</p>
               <p>Q. Did 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person536">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person536" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person536" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person536" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             cast any that were cast perfect?</p>
               <p>Gray. I cannot say that he did, I would not say it for the World - After they were cast they filed the curside Edges off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Marmaduke or Cotes do it?</p>
               <p>Gray. I saw Cotes and Duke do that; after that they left off at that Time, and on the Monday Morning, when I came to work, they seemed sorry for what they had done; and said, they would do so no more; the Wednesday after that, we were casting Plates and Easons again; and 
               <persName id="t17430907-53-person537">
                  William 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17430907-53-person537" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person537" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-person537" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the two Moulds, that which was for the 36 s. Pieces, and that which cast the Half-Crowns, and melted them down in my Master's Iron Ladle, and threw them under my Master's Pit; and said, that there never should be any such thing done more while he staid; - the Prisoner was taken up the next Day, - Duke was run away; he went away on the Wednesday; when Cotes melted the Moulds down, he had some of the bad Pieces by him, that they had made, and he put them into the Pit, and melted them.</p>
               <p>Q. What made Duke run away?</p>
               <p>Gray. I believe it was upon the Account of something that Mr Stevens had heard, and he charged him with it, and he run away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what they did with these eight or ten that they cast?</p>
               <p>Gray. I heard them say, they had put some off with Whores - I heard them both say so.</p>
               <p>The Court, in Compassion to the Prisoner, Considering the little Share he had in this Affair, and his immediate Repentance, recommended it to the Gentlemen concerned for the Crown not to proceed any farther: And no other Evidence was offered, whereupon the Prisoner was <rs id="t17430907-53-verdict276" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-53-verdict276" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
