<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17441017-9">
               <interp inst="t17441017-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-9" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17441017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17441017-9" type="date" value="17441017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17441017-9-off56-c106" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-defend130 t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-verdict63"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174410170010"></xptr>441.+ 
               
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-defend130" type="defendantName">
                     Clement 
                     Haggett 
                  <interp inst="t17441017-9-defend130" type="surname" value="Haggett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-defend130" type="given" value="Clement"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-defend130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             * was indicted for the <rs id="t17441017-9-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17441017-9-victim132" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Wackett 
                        <interp inst="t17441017-9-victim132" type="surname" value="Wackett"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441017-9-victim132" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17441017-9-victim132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-victim132"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him with a sword made of Iron and Steel of the value of 12 d. a wound upon the left side of the belly, above the navel, of the breadth of one inch, and the depth of four inches, on the <rs id="t17441017-9-cd57" type="crimeDate">15th day of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-cd57"></join> last, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17441017-9-crimeloc58">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc58" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc58" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-crimeloc58"></join>, of which he languished till the 21st day of the same month, and in the Parish of Pancras died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>* His right Name is Hackett.</p>
               <p>He was a second time charged by virtue of the Coroner's Inquisition for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person133">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person133" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person133" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a public house, the <placeName id="t17441017-9-crimeloc59">sign of the Plough</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc59" type="placeName" value="sign of the Plough"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc59" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-crimeloc59"></join>, in <placeName id="t17441017-9-crimeloc60">St. Martin's Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc60" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17441017-9-crimeloc60" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-off56 t17441017-9-crimeloc60"></join>. On the 15th of September in the evening, <rs id="t17441017-9-viclabel61" type="occupation">Serjeant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-victim132 t17441017-9-viclabel61"></join> Wackett (the deceas'd) came in, and while he was there the Prisoner came in, and when he was going away, one Lloyd said, Why will you go? I will strike you down if you won't stay. There were some words arose between the two <rs id="t17441017-9-deflabel62" type="occupation">Serjeant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-defend130 t17441017-9-deflabel62"></join>s, about the duty of a soldier; and the deceased began to be angry, and the Prisoner said, Don't be angry, I'll ask pardon, what would you have me do?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any talk about the Prisoner's borrowing half a crown of the deceased?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did not hear any thing of the half crown; a little while after they all went away together; about a quarter of an hour after that, the Prisoner and the deceased came in again; and the Prisoner said, Mr. Jones let us have a Quartern of Brandy; the deceased said, I will have no Brandy, let us have Rum; but they had neither, they had a Tankard of Beer, and sat down by the fire together. I thought the dispute was all made up, but on a sudden, I heard my wife cry out, Oh Lord, there will be murder. I saw a sword drawn in the Prisoner's hand, and clapped my hand upon his wrist, and then the deceased cried out, He has stabbed me. I saw blood on the inside of his waistcoat, and upon his shirt. I went to Mr. Hewitt the Surgeon, and when he came in the deceased was sitting in a chair, (I did not know then that the Prisoner was wounded) and the deceased said to Mr. Hewitt, Dress my comrade first.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Prisoner wounded ?</p>
               <p>Jones. He was wounded in the back very much.</p>
               <p>Q. What, with a sword ?</p>
               <p>Jones. I believe it was with a hanger .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blows given ?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did not see any .</p>
               <p>Q. When your wife said there would be murder, was the sword, or the hanger drawn ?</p>
               <p>Jones. They were both drawn then .</p>
               <p>Pris. Council. You say both the sword and hanger were drawn; did you think yourself time enough to have prevented the mischief?</p>
               <p>Jones. I thought I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were in the room then?</p>
               <p>Jones. There were 
               <persName id="t17441017-9-person134">
                  John 
                  Barney 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person134" type="surname" value="Barney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person134" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17441017-9-person135">
                  Thomas 
                  Holden 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person135" type="surname" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person135" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my wife, and 
               <persName id="t17441017-9-person136">
                  Richard 
                  Godson 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person136" type="surname" value="Godson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person136" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my servant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person137">
                  Thomas 
                  Holden 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person137" type="surname" value="Holden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person137" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of September in the evening, I was at Mr. Jones's smoking a pipe with Mr. Barney. Serjeant Wackett was there, and had 2 or 3 pints of been before the Prisoner came in. When the Prisoner came in he said he was very glad to see the deceased, and they seemed very glad to see one another. The Prisoner was for going away several times, but one Lloyd said he should not go, and said, Clem sit down. (the Prisoner was very much suddled when he came in) After that the Prisoner and the deceased had some discourse about a Corporal's, or a Private Man's duty, or some misdemeanors in the regiment. The deceased said, let it all drop, we'll have it decided by the Captain, on the parade to-morrow. Some time after the Prisoner said to the deceased, Sam lend me half a crown; the deceased said, Poh! Poh! you don't want money; the Prisoner said, I do want money, lend me half a crown. The deceased put his hand in his pocket and threw half a crown down. Then the Prisoner said to the deceased, Do you know God? The deceased said, I hope I do. The Prisoner said, God pay you, or God will pay you, and then they all three went out of the house together. This was about 11 o'clock. It was not long before they came in again, then the Prisoner asked for some brandy or rum, the deceased said he would drink no drams, if they had any thing, they would have a tankard of beer, which they had. Mr. Jones and I were playing a game at draughts. The Prisoner and deceased were in a box by themselves; presently I heard Mrs. Jones cry out, There will be murder. I looked and saw a small sword in the Prisoner's hand drawn; the deceased turned himself round and said, The villain has stabbed me; then the deceased turned about and gave the Prisoner a cut in the back.</p>
               <p>Q. When you turned about first, after you heard the deceased say, the villain has stabbed me, was his hanger drawn, or had he it by his side?</p>
               <p>Holden. He had it by his side - When the deceased first cried out, he had it by his side; and I saw him draw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner stab the deceased?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174410170011"></xptr>Holden. I did not see it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see first?</p>
               <p>Holden. The first thing I saw was the small sword drawn in the Prisoner's hand I would not hurt any one, I would speak the truth, and no more than the truth God knows.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person138">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person138" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person138" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called again .</p>
               <p>Pris. Council. You hear this man says the deceased was stabbed, before the hanger was drawn, was it so or not?</p>
               <p>Jones. The cut on the Prisoner's back was given before the deceased clapped his hand upon his belly, and said, The villain has stabbed me.</p>
               <p>Pris. Council. Will you take upon you to say the deceased's hanger was drawn then, and he made no use of it afterwards?</p>
               <p>Jones. His hanger was drawn, when he said he was stabbed.</p>
               <p>Q. to Holden. Did you hear any challenge given?</p>
               <p>Holden. I did not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hewitt, (Surgeon.) I was sent for to the deceased, he had a wound between the third and fourth ribs, which penetrated into the Cavity of the belly.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that wound the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Hewitt. I opened the body, and I found a vast quantity of bloody matter in the belly, which came from the wound, which was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Pris. Council. Can you give any opinion as to the nature of the wound, how it was given, or in what position the deceased was?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . It appears to me, that as the deceased was a right handed man, that the wound could not be given when he was upon his guard. - The wound was on the left side of the belly. Upon opening the body, I examined the Spleen and Kidney , and I can't say positively, whether the Spleen , or the Kidney was wounded; but I think the Spleen was wounded.</p>
               <p>Pris. Council. Supposing two men had stood directly facing one another, quarrelling; do you think they could have given such a wound as that?</p>
               <p>Hewitt. Indeed, I believe not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the Prisoner any wound?</p>
               <p>Hewitt. The Prisoner had a wound back .</p>
               <p>Q. Was that a cut or a stab?</p>
               <p>Hewitt. I took it to be a stab, from the nature of the wound, for it had first penetrated, and then turned round; to the best of my remembran deceased said it was a stab. - I was sent for that night, about a quarter of an hour after the accident happened.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the deceased live afterwards?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . From the Saturday evening, to the Friday se'nnight following. He desired I would attend him, and so did his colonel. As to the Prisoner, he was left to the care of the Surgeon of the Regiment.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased tell you the occasion of it?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He told me he and his comrade had some words about a private man's doing his duty, but had agreed in the end, and were very good friends. But returning again to drink something , they received the dispute. The deceased was for bringing it before the colonel, and that exasperated the Prisoner, and he challenged him, and upon his challenging him, the deceased said, Then turn out .</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased in great danger from the first?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He was in extream danger, and I thought there was occasion to call in more Surgeons , I mentioned the Surgeon General, but the Colonel said he was satisfied with me; however I took that Gentleman with me for my further satisfaction with relation to the wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased desire you to dress the Prisoner's wound first?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He desired me to take care of his comrade , for he had a value for him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the deceased say, with relation to any complaint of the Prisoner's behaviour or usage?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He said the Prisoner stabbed him first.</p>
               <p>Q. What before his hanger was drawn?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He did not say any thing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any complaint of any foul practice , or proceeding, or did he say it was a fair quarrel?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . He did not say much of that to me, but I think , if any thing, he complained of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say the Prisoner had murdered him?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . I don't know that he said any thing of that .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person139">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Moreton 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person139" type="surname" value="Moreton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person139" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the deceased all the time of his illness, and he always said the villain had stabbed him, and about two hours before he died, he desired that God would provide for his family, for Mr. Haggett had murdered him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person140">
                  Charles 
                  Nicholson 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person140" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person140" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (a soldier.) I was with him about two hours before he died, and he begged that God Almighty would provide for his distressed family, for he did not think he should live that night out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person141">
                  Jane 
                  Wackett 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person141" type="surname" value="Wackett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person141" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband declared that the Prisoner stabbed him before he drew his hanger, and he declared that before the Surgeon on the Monday following.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174410170012"></xptr>Mr. Hewitt called again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the deceased say the Prisoner stabbed him before he drew his hanger?</p>
               <p>Hewitt . I don't particularly remember that he said the Prisoner stabbed him before he drew his hanger. - I don't remember his mentioning the hanger, but he said the Prisoner stabbed him first.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. When the Prisoner, the deceased, and Lloyd came into our house the second time, the Prisoner called for a quartern of brandy or rum, and the deceased said if he drank any thing he would have beer. As I was dressing some stakes the deceased said, By G - d the Colonel shall decide this affair between you and I to morrow morning; and in a minute the deceased got up and pushed by between the table and me, but I did not apprehend any thing of mischief, and I heard the words, D - n you draw, or I'll cut you. - I don't know who said the words, and I saw the deceased's hanger drawn and his arm extended.</p>
               <p>Q. Were either of them got out of the box, when the word draw was spoke.</p>
               <p>Jones. The deceased was just got out to the end of the box.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Council. It has been asserted that the deceased said, The villain has killed me; was you so near that you must have heard it if he had said so?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, I was so near, that I must have heard it, but I did not hear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person142">
                  Richard 
                  Godson 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person142" type="surname" value="Godson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person142" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the deceased say, You villain draw or I'll cut you.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any weapon then?</p>
               <p>Godson . Yes, I saw him hold up his hanger drawn then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17441017-9-person143">
                  John 
                  Burney 
               <interp inst="t17441017-9-person143" type="surname" value="Burney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the words, D - n you draw or I'll cut you.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any complaint of being stabbed?</p>
               <p>Burney. Yes, the deceased said, The villain has stabbed me; that was after the words, D - n you draw or I'll cut you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Council. Was the stab given in the box or out of the box?</p>
               <p>Burney. I believe it was by the side of the box. <rs id="t17441017-9-verdict63" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-verdict63" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-verdict63" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17441017-9-punish64" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-punish64" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17441017-9-punish64" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17441017-9-defend130 t17441017-9-punish64"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
