<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-1">
               <interp inst="t17460903-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-1" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-1" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-1-off1-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-1-defend29 t17460903-1-off1 "></join>
         
               <p>282. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     Barney 
                     Linsey 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Linsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-defend29" type="given" value="Barney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-defend29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460903-1-victim31" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Dunn 
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-victim31" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-victim31" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-victim31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17460903-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-victim32" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-1-off1 t17460903-1-victim32"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , putting them in bodily Fear, and robbing the said 
                     <persName id="t17460903-1-person33">
                        William 
                        Dunn 
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person33" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-person33" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   of a Watch, and Ambler of a Coat, Breeches
            </rs>, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17460903-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">29th of June</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-1-off1 t17460903-1-cd2"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. (to Ambler) What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ambler. On Sunday the 29th of June, as I was coming from Hamstead, between Nine and Ten o'Clock at Night. I was set upon by seven Men. in the second Close on this Side <placeName id="t17460903-1-crimeloc3">Figg-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="Figg-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-1-off1 t17460903-1-crimeloc3"></join>; after they had pass'd me they all turn'd short and gave me several Blows (with Bludgeons ) on my Body, Head and other Parts; I made Resistance, but when they had master'd me they led me to the Ditch; in the Scuffle I lost my Hat and Wig.</p>
               <p>Q. When they had got you into the Ditch, what did they take from you?</p>
               <p>Ambler. My Cloth Coat, a Cambrick Stock, a Silver Buckle, &amp;c. They robb'd Mr. Dunn at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that in your Sight?</p>
               <p>Ambler. Yes. They robb'd Mr. Dunn of his Watch; then they turn'd to me again and took my Breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they?</p>
               <p>Ambler. Black Leather Breeches. They took my shoes and also Mr. Dunn's Shoes; then they went away; but soon return'd again and took my Shirt from my Back; they had taken my Stock the first Time. On Friday the 4th of July I saw, in the Advertiser, the Advertisement of a Watch; that was stopp'd by Justice Dennis's Clarke; by the Description I knew it was Mr. Dunn's Watch; the Watch was found upon Parkison, a Soldier, who was then committed to Prison. I went to New-Prison to this Soldier, and I charg'd him with the Robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not see the Watch then?</p>
               <p>Ambler. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What Robbery did you charge him with?</p>
               <p>Ambler. With robbing me the Sunday before; but he said he was not in the Robbery; I ask'd him then how he came by the Watch; he said he had it from 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person34">
                  Barney 
                  Linsey 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person34" type="surname" value="Linsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person34" type="given" value="Barney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it that you saw the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ambler. At Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person35">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person35" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person35" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you saw him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person36">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person36" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person36" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030003"></xptr>Ambler. I can't directly say, but I think about a Fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the Prisoner is the Man?</p>
               <p>Ambler. He is the Man.</p>
               <p>Court. Now inform us what you heard him say concerning this Robbery ?</p>
               <p>Ambler. He said he was concern'd in the Robbery, and that he gave me Water to drink out of the Brim of his Hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you Water given you?</p>
               <p>Ambler. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was the Man, or one of the Men?</p>
               <p>Ambler. That he was one of the Men; he also said there was one of them swore he would destroy me, and that he was the Man that prevented him from giving the Blow; and another of them desir'd him to murder me, saying, that it was better I should die than they.</p>
               <p>Court. Then he positively declar'd that one of the Men would have murder'd you and he prevented it.</p>
               <p>Ambler. Yes. And he told me the Name of the Person who wore my Coat was Ryly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention whether Ryly was in the Robbery?</p>
               <p>Ambler. Yes, Sir; and that one Mathews was in the Robbery also.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person37">
                  William 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person37" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person37" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Dunn. No Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any Thing to lay to the Prisoner's Charge with respect to the Robbery committed on Sunday the 29th of June?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I was robb'd then with Mr. Ambler.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night?</p>
               <p>Dunn. Between the Hours of Nine and Ten.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it?</p>
               <p>Dunn. In the Foot-Path between Mother Red-Cap's and Southampton-Row.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I think there were nine in Company: Mr. Ambler was attack'd first; I might be about ten Yards behind; I hasten'd up to Mr. Ambler and found a Party of them attacking him.</p>
               <p>Q. What had they in their Hands?</p>
               <p>Dunn. They had Scymeters and Sticks; I heard one of them call it a Scymeter. I hasten'd up to him, then another Party of them enclos'd me: Ambler defended himself as long as he could; he had a Cane in his Hand, and they had a great deal of Difficulty to get it from him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them rob him of any Thing?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I saw them take off his Coat; nothing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they go away then?</p>
               <p>Dunn. No, Sir. After they had rifled him they went about ten Yards distant, then they came back again and took his Breeches and Shoes from him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person38">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person38" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person38" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when the Prisoner was there?</p>
               <p>Dunn. Yes. And he desir'd to speak to Sir Thomas privately; so Sir Thomas went with him into a private Room. Sir Thomas told me the Man wanted to turn Evidence; I said to Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person39">
                  Thomas 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person39" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person39" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             should be glad to ask him some particular Questions touching the Robbery; so I traced him thro' the whole Robbery, and he told me all the particular Circumstances of it, who they first attack'd and what they took.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Promise made to the Man of a Pardon in cafe he would confess.</p>
               <p>Dunn. None at all, he offer'd himself voluntarily; he said he gave me Water out of the Ditch in his Hat.</p>
               <p>Q. But what did he say about the Robbery?</p>
               <p>Did he confess that he was one of the Persons?</p>
               <p>Dunn. He said he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you the Person that had Water given you?</p>
               <p>Dunn. Both of us had Water. I lost a Snuff-Box and Tweezer-Cafe; I ask'd him if he knew where they were, if they had pawn'd them I would redeem them; he told me they buried them in the Ground, and the next Morning a Party of them went to fetch them, and he knew nothing more of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Mr. Dunn, what Robbery did he own he committed?</p>
               <p>Dunn. He said he was one that robb'd us.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Thing said before Sir Thomas about Mr. Ambler's Coat?</p>
               <p>Dunn. He said that one Ryly had it.</p>
               <p>Q. by the Prisoner) Mr. Dunn, was it I that robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I don't say you did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Those two Gentlemen gave me Liquor, and made me to drunk that I don't know what I said; Mr. Ambler, did not you give me Sixpence, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Ambler. I did; I went on Sunday Morning and gave him Sixpence; I said if he made good his Confession he should not want a Sunday's Dinner while he was in Prison.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030004"></xptr>Prisoner. Mr. Ambler promised that he would get my Pardon.</p>
               <p>Ambler. I might say I would be a favourable Prosecutor if he would make Discoveries, &amp;c. but none of the Persons he nam'd could be found.</p>
               <p>Q. (to John Sergeant) What are you?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. I am a Butcher by Trade; I was one of the Persons that took him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take him, and upon what Occasion.</p>
               <p>Sergeant. Upon Parkison's Confession, the Soldier.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take him?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. In King-Street, Bloomsbury.</p>
               <p>Q. After you had taken him what did you do with him?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. We brought him to the Publick-House opposite the Place.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing of this Robbery ?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. He own'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-1-person40">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-1-person40" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person40" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that he had robb'd Mr. Ambler and Mr. Dunn.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any Promise of Pardon for being an Evidence.</p>
               <p>Sergeant. None that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober at that Time?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. He seem'd as sober as I am, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time did you take him before Sir Thomas?</p>
               <p>Sergeant. About Ten o'Clock in the Forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. (to the Prisoner.) What have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, I know nothing about it; he is a Thief-catcher, and will say any thing on account of the Money.</p>
               <p>Sergeant. You are the first Thief that I ever caught.</p>
               <p>Q.(to the Prisoner.) Have you any Witnesses?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have no Witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-1-punish4" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-1-punish4" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-1-defend29 t17460903-1-punish4"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
