<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440223-17">
               <interp inst="t17440223-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-17" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-17" type="date" value="17440223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-17-off98-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-defend125 t17440223-17-off98 t17440223-17-verdict101"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-17-off98-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-defend127 t17440223-17-off98 t17440223-17-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>+ 156, 157. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-defend125" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Petty 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend125" type="surname" value="Petty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend125" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Edmund 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend127" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend127" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-defend127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17440223-17-defloc97">St. Clement Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-defloc97" type="placeName" value="St. Clement Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-defloc97" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-defend125 t17440223-17-defloc97"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-defend127 t17440223-17-defloc97"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440223-17-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440223-17-victim129" type="victimName">
                           Humphrey 
                           Nightingale 
                        <interp inst="t17440223-17-victim129" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-17-victim129" type="given" value="Humphrey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-17-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-off98 t17440223-17-victim129"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him twenty three bottles of Hungary water, value 12 s. and a silk handkerchief, value 1 s. the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17440223-17-person130">
                        Humphrey 
                        Nightingale 
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person130" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-17-person130" type="given" value="Humphrey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440223-17-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17440223-17-cd99" type="crimeDate">Dec. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-off98 t17440223-17-cd99"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-person131">
                  Humphrey 
                  Nightingale 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person131" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person131" type="given" value="Humphrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of Dec. last, about six o'clock at night, I was stopped and robbed by the two persons at the bar, at the end of <placeName id="t17440223-17-crimeloc100">Wych-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-crimeloc100" type="placeName" value="Wych-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-17-crimeloc100" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-17-off98 t17440223-17-crimeloc100"></join>, of twenty three bottles of Hungary water, tied up in a silk handkerchief. Petty seized me by the collar with one hand, and the parcel with the other, and said, D - n you, give me your parcel. I said, I would not; he said, D - n me, he would have it; and I don't know but I might say, d - n him again; then Smith came and said, D - n you, we will have it; he held a stick of an uncommon size over my head, and repeated many oaths, which put me in fear, and I did deliver it. Petty had hold of the parcel all the while; as they were going off, I cried out help! I recovered myself a little, and got Smith by the collar; and finding myself a little stronger than him, I got him into a Butcher's shop, that was pretty near, and desired somebody to get a Constable; Petty got from me, but I secured Smith, and carried him before a Justice, and I said, he was one of the two men that robbed me, and he denied the taking the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they make any excuse in the butcher's shop, when you charged them with it?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. They did not say any thing, they made no excuse.</p>
               <p>Council. Had you your goods again.</p>


               <p>Nightingale. My brother has them, he took them from the Justice's.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first met the Prisoners, upon your oath, did not they tell you what they were? Did not they tell you they were Excise Officers?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. Upon my oath, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first hear that they were Excisemen?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. It was before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not they say so to you in the street?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. No, upon my oath, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not they say, they were Excise-men, or belonged to the Excise-Office, and desired to see your parcel?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. No, nor did they give me the least reason to think they were Officers of the Excise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not they produce their deputations before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. Not that I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been then?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. I had been at Mr. Pelleret's in Lime-street, and had bought some Hungary water; and going home, I called upon Mr. Sandys, a dealer in tea, on Ludgate-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Are not you a dealer in tea?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. Yes, I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Then did not you know the Prisoners?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. I never saw them before that time in my life to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, you were in a Butcher's shop with the Prisoners; don't you know the Butcher's name?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230011"></xptr>Nightingale. I do not know it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then I will put you in mind of it; his name is 
               <persName id="t17440223-17-person132">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person132" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did not they ask you to see what was in your handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they ask you for your money, or any thing else besides your handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. No, nothing else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-person133">
                  Miles 
                  Nightingale 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person133" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person133" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This bundle was taken from the Prisoners before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Who carried it into the Butcher's shop?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. Petty did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-person134">
                  Samuel 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person134" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person134" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of Dec. I was coming down Wych-street; there was a crowd at a Butcher's shop, I enquired what was the matter, and they told me, a gentleman was robbed. I went in and said to Mr. Nightingale, Are you the gentleman that was robbed? and he said, Yes. I went for a Constable, and he charged the Constable with Smith.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Petty?</p>
               <p>Lee. He pretended to go for a Constable, but did not return again. Another Excise-Officer (as I was informed) said before the Justice, that he believed he could light of this Petty, and said, he would step out and see for him; he went out and returned again in about a quarter of an hour, and brought Petty along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they any deputations?</p>
               <p>Lee. They pretended to snew some deputation before the Justice.</p>
               <p>The Justice's Clerk. Smith said he was an Excise-Officer, and that he seized the parcel as run goods - Petty denied the taking of the goods - They offered to produce deputations; I cannot say they did produce any.</p>
               <p>Lee. The Justice said, that the Prisoners swore directly contrary to one another.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say?</p>
               <p>Lee. I can't tell justly.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how can you say they differed in their accounts? Tell us the sum of what they said?</p>
               <p>Lee. I cannot very well remember what was said.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Petty deny the fact before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Lee. No, to the best of my remembrance he never did deny it. [The Justice was of opinion, when they were before him, that it was not a robbery; and directed the Prosecutor to prefer a bill at Hicks's-Hall for an assault.]</p>
               <p>The PRISONERS DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-person135">
                  Thomas 
                  Unwin 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person135" type="surname" value="Unwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person135" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to my brother, who is an Attorney. On the 19th of December, as I was going along the back-side of St. Clement's, Mr Nightingale came by, with a bundle under his arm; the two Prisoners came up to him, and said, they suspected that he had got some run-goods, and desired to see what he had in his bundle.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Nightingale say?</p>
               <p>Unwin. He said, If you molest me, I will swear a robbery against you; they took the bundle away, and they all went into a Butcher's shop by the Angel, the back-side of St. Clement's.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed in the shop afterwards?</p>
               <p>Unwin. I did not go in; I only saw the two Prisoners and the Prosecutor go in together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Prosecutor, Nightingale, demand to see their deputations?</p>
               <p>Unwin. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they tell him they were Excise-Officers?</p>
               <p>Unwin. They told him, they were Excise-Officers.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Council. I never heard any thing of this before.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Nor I neither.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-17-person136">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17440223-17-person136" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person136" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 19th of Dec. in the evening, the two Prisoners and Mr. Nightingale came together into my shop; Mr. Nightingale had a handkerchief in his hand - I cannot say but Mr. Smith might have hold of it with one hand; and Nightingale put it upon the window himself. Mr. Smith said, they were Excise-Officers, and had been at Ludgate-Hill to see after some run tea; Nightingale was for sending for a Constable; and Smith bid Petty go and fetch a Constable; and Petty went for a Constable, but did not bring any.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Nightingale close to him when he said they were Excise-Officers?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Nightingale was as near as I; he might have heard, for my wife and I heard.</p>
               <p>The Justice declared, that when the Prisoners were before him, they prosessed themselves to be Officers of the Excise, and showed their deputations.</p>
               <p>A worthy Alderman of this City said, he has known Petty about ten years, and always took him to be a very honest young man; and from the knowledge he has had of him, believes him to be incapable of committing a dishonest or an unjust act.</p>
               <p>Justice Engier said, he has known Petty eight or ten years, believes him to be as honest a man as any in England, and that he would not do such a thing for the world.</p>
               <p>There was one person called to the character of Smith, who has known him from three or four years of age, and says he has a very honest, just, fair character. <rs id="t17440223-17-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-17-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230012"></xptr>The Court granted the Prisoners a copy of their indictment.</p>
            </div1>
