<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460117-40">
               <interp inst="t17460117-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-40" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460117-40" type="date" value="17460117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460117-40-off158-c451" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-40-defend521 t17460117-40-off158 t17460117-40-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>79. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-defend521" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Sockwell 
                  <interp inst="t17460117-40-defend521" type="surname" value="Sockwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-defend521" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-defend521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17460117-40-defloc157">Penitent-Street , Ratcliff-Highway</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460117-40-defloc157" type="placeName" value="Penitent-Street , Ratcliff-Highway"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460117-40-defloc157" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460117-40-defend521 t17460117-40-defloc157"></join>, stands indicted for unlawfully and willfully <rs id="t17460117-40-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="religiousOffences"></interp>
               exercising Part of the Office and Function of a Popish Priest, against a Statute made and provided in that Case, in the Reign of King 
                     <persName id="t17460117-40-person522">
                        William 
                        III 
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person522" type="surname" value="III"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460117-40-person522" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460117-40-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . to prevent the Growth and Spread of Popery
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person523">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person523" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person523" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person524">
                  Edward 
                  Addison 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person524" type="surname" value="Addison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person524" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Pray what have you seen the Prisoner at the Bar do at any Time?</p>
               <p>Addison. I have seen him act with Crucifixes. It was done in Ratcliff-Highway in a Room of his own House in Penitent-Street. I have never seen him act any Thing abroad any where. I have seen a Parcel of People come in of a Sunday Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you? What was you formerly?</p>
               <p>Addison. I was a Protestant from my Cradle.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you fix the Time when you saw this.</p>
               <p>Addison. It was about two Years ago, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Now tell me what you have seen him do, when these People came to his House?</p>
               <p>Addison. There has been a Bason of Water, and as they came in, they dipp'd their Hands in this Water, and after that I have seen them kneel down, and they have taken Beads out of their Pockets, and there was a Parcel of Images, and they seem'd to me to be made of Wax. Their Beads hung upon their Arms.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Addison. I have seen them reckon their Beads.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the Images placed?</p>
               <p>Addison. Upon a pretty long Table he had.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of those Images.</p>
               <p>Addison. I believe there were about seven, and I believe they were made of Wax.</p>
               <p>Q. When this Preparation was made, what did you observe of this Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Addison. I have seen him walk backwards and forwards with a Crucifix in his Hand. He read in an unknown Tongue, that I could not understand a Word that he spoke. It seem'd to me as if it was all Latin.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hold the Crucifix in his Hand?</p>
               <p>Addison. In his Hand, please you my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. You don't understand Latin yourself?</p>
               <p>Addison. No, my Lord. Then they all kneel'd down and went to Prayer.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Language did he read Prayers.</p>
               <p>Addison. In an unknown Tongue.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he kneel down as well as the People?</p>
               <p>Addison. Yes. My Lord. From the Posture they were in, I judg'd it was Prayer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hold the Crucifix in his Hand when he read Prayers ?</p>
               <p>Addison. He held it down, please you my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any other Persons to hold a Crucifix in their Hands.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174601170028"></xptr>Addison. No. Only that Man, the Prisoner, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray did you know any of this Congregation?</p>
               <p>Addison. Yes. There were three that lodg'd in the same House; a Man and his Wife and a single Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. I want to know how you knew these People?</p>
               <p>Addison. I lodg'd in the House, please you my Lord. He wanted to turn my Wife and I to his Way of Thinking, from a Protestant to a Roman; And told me that was the best Way to save my Soul and go to Heaven. And told me, that if I continu'd in the Protestant Way, I should be d - n'd to Eternity: But if I would be of his Opinion I should have the Holy Ghost come down upon me, and I should be as wide awak'd as could be, and that the Holy Ghost should breathe three Times in my Mouth, and rest for the Space of a Minute or two, and then the same again; and I should be in a great Agony of Pain, my Lord: And the Prisoner said, he acted in Lincoln's-Inn-Chapel, when the Priests have been taken ill, and at Spitalfields, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he say this to you?</p>
               <p>Addison. At the same Time, please you my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing farther?</p>
               <p>Addison. He told me, he acted at several Places in the Country; while he went in the Way of buying of Hair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he acquaint you what he was doing when he was in his Room?</p>
               <p>Addison. He told me, he was brought up a Romish Priest ever since he was 10 Years of Age.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing more?</p>
               <p>Addison. There was a Male Child brought in to be christen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What, the same Day?</p>
               <p>Addison. No. Of another Day, please you my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>Addison. I take it to be Sunday following, to the best of my Memory.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the Male Child was brought in to be christen'd, what did he do?</p>
               <p>Addison. He took the Child into his Arms naked, and there was a little Gallypot that stood upon the Table, and he cross'd the Child several Times, and said some Expressions in an unknown Tongue.</p>
               <p>Q. What was there in the Gallypot.</p>
               <p>Addison. Whether it was Water or Oil I cannot sell.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did it stand?</p>
               <p>Addison. The Gallypot stood upon the Table.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any Sponsors there, or any Thing of that Kind?</p>
               <p>Addison. No, my Lord. Then they kneel'd down and went to Prayer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe no Godfathers, nor nothing of that?</p>
               <p>Addison. No, my Lord. But they continu'd in their Way of Praying, about 13 or 14 Minutes, to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray did you give him any Reason to imagine that he would convert you?</p>
               <p>Addison. Yes, an't please you my Lord. I told him I would consider of it. No further Satisf action I ever gave him. But as I was brought up a Protestant, I design'd to die in it. When he got up from Prayer, he said a few Words in an unknown Tongue. And the Women that were there, curtsy'd to him, and one of the Men on going away gave him a Crown or half a Crown, I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing farther?</p>
               <p>Addison. Nothing more about that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person525">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person525" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person525" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) Will you ask him any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, he has not spoken one Word of Truth, in what he has declar'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person526">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person526" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person526" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Addison) You was present at this Christning, and present there before the People begun. How many were there?</p>
               <p>Addison. Thirteen or fourteen.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Child brought in naked?</p>
               <p>Addison. Brought in in Flannel; And was given to him naked. He held it upon his Right Arm and put his Finger in the little Gallypot.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any of the Persons that were present there?</p>
               <p>Addison. No.</p>
               <p>Q. So you don't know whether they were Romans or not?</p>
               <p>Addison. That I cannot say or swear.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any other Witnesses?</p>
               <p>Addison. My Wife, the Witness, is dead and buried.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was bred an Irishman; served my Time at Newcastle upon Tyne. After I came up to London, I follow'd my Business, and kept four or five Journeymen; but met with many Losses. When I took in the Prosecutor, I took him in upon Charity : His Wife was an aged Woman. He pretended to go into Business as a Painter, and I never receiv'd but 18 d. of him. When he went away, I took Pity on him, and I gave him a little Gin. At the other Lodgings they went to, I heard his Wife died for Want Please you, my Lord, I got<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174601170029"></xptr> a Lodger of mine to help him to carry a Linnen Bundle of Rags and Things they had to carry, and I said, Mr. Addison I hope you will make me Amends when it is in your Power. Upon this, I went once or twice to the other Lodgings. He had not got into Business, and there was no Relief from me. My Lord, the Time he absconded from the other Lodgings, he took something more than he should have done, but I cannot testify it: His Landlord is here, he can: But one Time I met him in Rag-Fair, I said, Mr. Addison, I hear you have got into Business, and he and went away from me. I never saw him since, which is near a Year and a half ago; but last Friday was a Month he came down to my House, and went to a Friend of mine; he told my Friend he was come to pay me my Money, which was 3l. 10s. Upon this, my Friend sent his Boy with him to my House; he told my Wife a fine Story, that he had married a Wife, and that he had got 300l. with her, and he would make me a Recompence to the last Halfpenny: My Wife desired him to stay longer; but he desired I might come up to him to the Sign of the Boat; so I sent my Wife to this House, and they sent to the Place where he order'd them, and he came to my Wife, and she call'd for a Pint of Beer, and she would have him drink. She said, I have brought you a Receipt; says he, I never pay Money to a Wife. So when he came himself, he told me he would go and fetch my Money; I went out of Doors to make Water; he brought three Men and seiz'd me, and would not let my Wife nor any Person know where they were going; and they carried me before Justice Burdus. Says the Justice, he has sworn so hard against you, that I must commit you. I will commit you to New-Prison, that is the easiest Place I can commit you to.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person527">
                  James 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person527" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person527" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person528">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person528" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person528" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner) What do you call 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person529">
                  James 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person529" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person529" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person529" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to prove?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. To prove my Business.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person530">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person530" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person530" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Griffith) Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Griffith. I have seen him when he has come to Addison, in order to get the Money that he owed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard any Conversation between Addison and the Prisoner about his Debt?</p>

               <p>Griffith. This Addison lodg'd in my House, but he was in such Circumstances at that Time that he had nothing to help himself, and I got his Wife buried for him. And after she died, I gave him a clean Pair of Sheets, and he staid some Time afterwards, and kept the Key for a Time, and when he deliver'd me the Key one of the Sheets was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. You know nothing of the Prisoner but as he came to enquire after Addison?</p>
               <p>Griffith. No, my Lord, nothing else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person531">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person531" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person531" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person532">
                  Andrew 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person532" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person532" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person532" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know any Thing of the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Yes, my Lord, I have had Dealings with him for many Years.</p>
               <p>Q. In what Way?</p>

               <p>Lambert. In the Hair-selling. He has been in that Way for many Years, and in a very mean Manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing of his being a Popish Priest?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I really believe that he is not.</p>
               <p>Q. You think he has Wrong done him?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Yes. And this is one Reason; I take him not to be qualified for that Office, let him be of what Church he will.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing farther?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I know nothing of his Principles of Religion. 'Tis so far from it, that I never heard him talk about Religion. I cannot think but if he was one of the Romish Church, they would have made better Provision for him, for no Man ever lived in a meaner Manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person533">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person533" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person533" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person534">
                  Joseph 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person534" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person534" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person534" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cole. About ten Years.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his Business?</p>
               <p>Cole. He dealt in Hair, I have bought a great deal of him in my Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any Thing of his being a Popish Priest?</p>
               <p>Cole. No, my Lord, I never heard nor knew of any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. I would only ask you whether you are a Protestant or a 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person535">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person535" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person535" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person535" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Cole. I am a Protestant, I assure you, my Lord; I am upon my Oath, I would not appear for him if I knew that he was not a Well-wisher to the present Government.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person536">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person536" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person536" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person537">
                  William 
                  Bannister 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person537" type="surname" value="Bannister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person537" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person537" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What Religion do you profels ?</p>
               <p>Bannister. I am a Protestant.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bannister. About 23 Years. I was a Servant with him about 22 Years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he at any Time endeavour to convert you to the Popish Faith? Did you ever see any Thing of his officiating as a Priest in any Degree? Did he use to have a Congregation come to his House?</p>
               <p>Bannister. No, my Lord, and I have seen him drunk and sober, and I have never seen any such Thing.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174601170030"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person538">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person538" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person538" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person539">
                  Mary 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person539" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person539" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person539" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Webb. I have known him about two Years and an half. I lodg'd in his House.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his Business?</p>
               <p>Webb. Preparing of Hair for Wigs.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you observ'd any Congregation to resort to his House? Have you observ'd any Images in the House?</p>
               <p>Webb. No. Nor Beads, and I have been all about the House.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Webb. A Protestant. Neither I nor my Husband ever heard the Prisoner talk about Religion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person540">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person540" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person540" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person541">
                  Robert 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person541" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person541" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person541" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) How long have you known the Prisoner? What has been his Manner of Dealing?</p>
               <p>Gibson. Hair-curling, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you, a Protestant or a 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person542">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person542" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person542" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person542" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Gibson. A Protestant, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. You lodg'd at his House, did you?</p>
               <p>Gibson. Yes. About half a Year.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any Congregation at his House on a Sunday?</p>
               <p>Gibson. Never, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever attempt to convert you to the Popish Religion?</p>
               <p>Gibson. No, my Lord. I never heard him say a Word about Religion.</p>
               <p>( to 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person543">
                  William 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person543" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person543" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person543" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bear. Thirteen Years, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Bear. A Protestant.</p>
               <p>Q. What hath been his Manner of Dealing?</p>
               <p>Bear. In Hair, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been pretty conversant in his Family? Have you ever seen him officiate as a 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person544">
                  Roman Catholick 
                  Priest 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person544" type="surname" value="Priest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person544" type="given" value="Roman Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person544" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? Or seen any Images or Crucifixes in his House?</p>
               <p>Bear. I have been all over his House and never saw any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he endeavour to convert you to the 
               <persName id="t17460117-40-person545">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person545" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person545" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Faith?</p>
               <p>Bear. No, my Lord. I never heard him talk of Religion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person546">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person546" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person546" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Addison, the Prosecutor) When did you first give Information of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Addison. About a Month ago. I never gave any Information against him before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460117-40-person547">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460117-40-person547" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-person547" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Clement North) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>North. About 10 Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a Protestant or a Papist?</p>
               <p>North. A Protestant.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been pretty conversant with his Family?</p>
               <p>North. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him officiate as a Romish Priest? Ever see any Crucifixes or Images? Did he ever make an Attempt to convert you to the Roman Catholick Faith?</p>
               <p>North. I never heard him speak of any Thing of Religion in my Life.</p>
               <p>After his Lordship had summ'd up the particular Evidences, he concluded thus; Gentlemen, you are to consider whether the Prisoner at the Bar be guilty of this Fact or not: The Punishment is a very severe one, 'tis perpetual Imprisonment without Bail or Mainprise. Before you convict the Prisoner of this, you ought to have full Evidence, and consider how this Fact appears. Addison, the Prosecutor, had known of these Things for a considerable Time: Makes no Discovery of it, 'till the Proclamation is publish'd, of 100l. Reward, which is dated the 6th of November, 1745, at St. James's. In the next Place, Gentlemen, you'll observe, the Man by his Appearance, does not seem to be a Man of Learning at all: It appears he has got his Livelihood, and a very mean one too, by dealing in Hair. A Number of Protestants have had Dealings with him. Some of them have lodg'd in his House: They swear, they never saw any Appearance of his performing Mass or having any Images, nor of making any Attempts to convert them: And Persons of that Character are very apt to make Converts. Tho' 'tis true, where they endeavour to make Converts they ought to be punish'd; yet, Gentlemen, before they are punish'd, there must Satisfaction be given to the Country, that they are guilty. In the present Case, it does appear, there is a Demand the Prisoner has on the Prosecutor: It is a considerable Circumstance in this Cafe, whether the Reward of 100l. is not to pay this poor Man the Prisoner, as appears by the Prosecutor's needy Circumstances. <rs id="t17460117-40-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460117-40-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
