<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410405-21">
               <interp inst="t17410405-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-21" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410405-21" type="date" value="17410405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410405-21-off91-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-defend152 t17410405-21-off91 t17410405-21-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>22. *
               
                  <persName id="t17410405-21-defend152" type="defendantName">
                     Timothy 
                     Burn , alias <rs id="t17410405-21-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-defend152 t17410405-21-alias-1"></join>Teddy Brian</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-defend152" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-defend152" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-defend152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             of <placeName id="t17410405-21-defloc90">St. Paul Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-21-defloc90" type="placeName" value="St. Paul Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-21-defloc90" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-defend152 t17410405-21-defloc90"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17410405-21-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410405-21-victim154" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Patten 
                        <interp inst="t17410405-21-victim154" type="surname" value="Patten"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-21-victim154" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-21-victim154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-off91 t17410405-21-victim154"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17410405-21-viclabel92" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-victim154 t17410405-21-viclabel92"></join>; on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Cane with a Gold Head, Value 5 l. 5 s. the Property of the said 
                     <persName id="t17410405-21-person155">
                        David 
                        Patten 
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person155" type="surname" value="Patten"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-21-person155" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410405-21-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17410405-21-cd93" type="crimeDate">November 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-off91 t17410405-21-cd93"></join>.</p>
               <p>* The Prisoner was convicted last Sessions of stealing Goods Value 15 s. of 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person156">
                  Edward 
                  Thorne 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person156" type="surname" value="Thorne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person156" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and received Sentence of Transportation.</p>
               <p>Mr. Patten. On the 4th of November 1739, between 6 and 7 at Night, I was coming into <placeName id="t17410405-21-crimeloc94">Bow-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-21-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="Bow-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410405-21-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410405-21-off91 t17410405-21-crimeloc94"></join>, and as I came under the Arch at the Bottom of Earl's Court, I received a Blow on the left of my Head which sunk me on my Knee: I endeavoured to rise, and to throw up my Hands to defend myself, and as I rose I received several other Blows which sunk me to the Ground again. I attempted to get up a 2d Time, and I then received a Blow with something very heavy, which cut me to the Scull: Upon that I made a Sort of a Sweep with my Cane, and immediately it was snatched from me. I then endeavoured to draw my Sword, but my Right-hand was so disabled by warding off the Blows, that I could not draw it. I saw one or two Men run up the Court, and I got into Bow-Street and told some Chairmen of what had happened; they pursued them, and could not overtake<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174104050007"></xptr> any of them, but brought me back my Hat which was not carried off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-21-person157">
                  James 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person157" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person157" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 4th of November 1739, the Prisoner who goes by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person158">
                  Teddy 
                  Brian 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person158" type="surname" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person158" type="given" value="Teddy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , * John Lincham who is executed, 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person159">
                  Henry 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person159" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person159" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and a hump backed little Boy who goes by the Name of John of Gaunt went out from Mrs. Lambert's in Parcer's Lane, between 5 and 6 o'Clock in the Evening. We went round Covent-Garden 'till we came to Earl's Court, and saw that Gentleman (Mr. Patten) at the end of the Court. The Prisoner made a blow at his Head, with a Bludgeon which he concealed under the Lining of his Coat, the Gentleman made a Defence with his Cane, and whether he fell by a Blow or a Slip, I can't tell, but the Prisoner snatched the Cane out of his Hand, and on the Gentleman's attempting to draw his Sword, he came to us who were standing on the other Side of the Way. After this, we all went to Lambert's, and on her telling us the Cane was not Gold, but only washed over, we sold it her for 7 s. and shared the Money between us.</p>
               <p>* See Sessions Block 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person160">
                  N. 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person160" type="given" value="N."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person160" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2, 1740, pag. 76.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What Sort of a Night was it?</p>
               <p>Thompson. It was a light Night, besides there was a Lamp at the Corner of the Court, and I am certain Mr. Patten is the Gentleman that was robbed.</p>
               <p>Mr. Patten. It was light enough, but the Moon was under a Cloud; - it was a large Archand I being in the Shade, could not distinguish the Persons who attacked me.</p>
               <p>Thompson. There is a Lamp which strikes directly into the Arch, besides I can't be mistaken in the Prisoner, for all of us except John of Gaunt lodged at Lambert's, and the Prisoner and I lay together in the same Bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If I am the Man, let him tell what particular Marks I have.</p>
               <p>Thompson. About the Time that this Thing was done, he had a Sore on his Lip, and he used to scrape Lint off his Hat and put on it. When I went to see the Prisoner in Newgate, all the Transports were brought into the Hall, and I picked him out of them.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-21-person161">
                  James 
                  Macdonnel 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person161" type="surname" value="Macdonnel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person161" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about 5 Years; he lived with his Uncle 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person162">
                  Patrick 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person162" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person162" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in May-Street, Ireland. I am an Irishman and I have not been above 5 Months in England, and did not know that the Prisoner was come to London 'till I heard of his Consinement.</p>
               <p>Jury. How often have you seen him within these twelve Months?</p>
               <p>Macdonnel . I saw him just before I came from Ireland. On the 6th of November come 2 Years, I saw him in Ireland at his Step-Father's Burial. He was in Ireland last November, and the November before that: - I can't rightly tell the Month that I came here, but I have not been quite 5 Months in this Town yet.</p>
               <p>C. How long before you left Ireland, did you see the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Macdonnel. About a Week before I came away, no, I did not see him a Week before I came away, but I used to see him every Day.</p>
               <p>C. How long before you came away did you see him there?</p>
               <p>Macdonnel. I have not seen him in Ireland these 6 Months. I can't tell the settled Time that I saw him, but I know he was at his Step-Father's Burial November was twelve Months.</p>
               <p>C. Did you ever hear him called by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person163">
                  Teddy 
                  Brian 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person163" type="surname" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person163" type="given" value="Teddy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Macdonnel. No, I remember that his Name was 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person164">
                  Timothy 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person164" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person164" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was working in a Place, and saw him in Ireland every Week of the Time that I was in it. - I had not seen him there for some Time before I came away, but I know that I left him there, because I came away before him.</p>
               <p>Jury. What Reason have you to say that you left him in Ireland?</p>
               <p>Macdonnel. It was - I am sure I have been here 5 Months. I can't rightly tell when I last saw him there, but I saw him there 3 Years, 2 Years, and a Year ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-21-person165">
                  Ann 
                  Twisten 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person165" type="surname" value="Twisten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person165" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Castle-Street , near the Seven Dials. I came from May-Street, about 5 Months ago; I lived at 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person166">
                  Patrick 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person166" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person166" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, the Prisoner's Uncle, and never saw him away from thence. The last Witness, Macdonnel, and I both came over from Ireland in the same Ship, and when I came away, I left him (the Prisoner) there. While I lived there I saw the Prisoner every Day, especially every Sunday. I knew him to be a very honest Man there, and never heard him called by any other Name, but that of 
               <persName id="t17410405-21-person167">
                  Timothy 
                  Burn 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person167" type="surname" value="Burn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person167" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410405-21-person168">
                  Patrick 
                  Ivory 
               <interp inst="t17410405-21-person168" type="surname" value="Ivory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person168" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I worked a matter of 14 or 15 Years with his Father, and never knew him by any other Name than Burn. I have been here 6 Years, and the very first Night the Prisoner came to London, I saw him; his Shoes were full of Country Dirt, and he could not stir out of his Bed he was so tired: - He has not been here a Quarter of a Year, and the Night he came to England he was with me.</p>
               <p>Jury. We desire Thompson may be asked, what was done with the Cane?</p>
               <p>Thompson. The Prisoner himself brought it into Lambert's House; she persuaded us it was not Gold, and Lincham sold it to her for 7 s. and Smith, Lincham , the Prisoner and I had Eighteen Pence a Piece, and John of Gaunt a Shilling.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174104050008"></xptr>The Jury withdrew to consider of their Verdict, and after a short Time returned and found the Prisoner <rs id="t17410405-21-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410405-21-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
