<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430223-26">
               <interp inst="t17430223-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-26" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430223-26" type="date" value="17430223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430223-26-off135-c260" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-defend310 t17430223-26-off135 t17430223-26-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230022"></xptr>162. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-defend310" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Waite 
                  <interp inst="t17430223-26-defend310" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-defend310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-defend310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17430223-26-defloc133">London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430223-26-defloc133" type="placeName" value="London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430223-26-defloc133" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-defend310 t17430223-26-defloc133"></join>, <rs id="t17430223-26-deflabel134" type="occupation">Gentleman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-defend310 t17430223-26-deflabel134"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17430223-26-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17430223-26-cd136" type="crimeDate">10th Day of May, in the 14th Year of his Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-off135 t17430223-26-cd136"></join>, with Force and Arms, at London, that is to say, in the <placeName id="t17430223-26-crimeloc137">Parish of St Christopher's, in the Ward of Broad street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-crimeloc137" type="placeName" value="Parish of St Christopher's, in the Ward of Broad street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-crimeloc137" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-off135 t17430223-26-crimeloc137"></join>, in a certain Dwelling-House there situate; wherein Zerubbabel Crouch, and divers other Persons, to the Jurors unknown, did then and there dwell and inhabit, did feloniously steal, take and carry away, one Bond, commonly called an East-India-Bond, No. A. 2336, sealed with the common Seal of the United Company of Merchants of England, trading to the East-Indies, thereunto affixed, bearing Date the 27th Day of June, 1737, in and by which said Bond, the said United Company of Merchants of England, trading to the East-Indies, did acknowledge to have received of 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-person311">
                        William 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person311" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person311" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 100 l. which the said Company promised to repay to the said 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-person312">
                        William 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person312" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person312" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , his Executors, Administrators, or Assigns, (by Indorsement thereon) for the true Payment whereof, the said Company did find themselves and their Successors in the penal Sum of 200l. One other Bond. No. A. 2337, in the like Sum, sealed, &amp;c. as before. One other Bond, No. A. 2740, in the like Sum, sealed, &amp;c. One other Bond, No. 9671, sealed, &amp;c. One other Bond, No. 20311, sealed, &amp;c. in and by which said last mentioned Bond, the said United Company of Merchants of England, trading to the East-Indies, did acknowledge to have received of 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-person313">
                        William 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person313" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person313" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   the Sum of 100l. which the said Company promised to repay to the said 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-person314">
                        William 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person314" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person314" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , his Executors, Administrators, or Assigns, (by Indorsement thereon) with Interest for the same, from the 31st Day of March, then next ensuing, after the Rate of three Pounds for 100l. for a Year, at the East-India-House, in Leadenhall street, London, on six Months Notice to be given by the Company in the London-Gazette, or on six Months Notice to be given by the said 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-person315">
                        William 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person315" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person315" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , his Executors, Administrators, or Assigns to the Company's Accomptant, in Writing, at the East-India-House aforesaid. One other Bond, No. 23335, sealed, &amp;c.
That each of the aforesaid Bonds, at the Time of the committing the Felony, was of the Value of 100l. and are laid to be the Property of the 
                     <persName id="t17430223-26-victim316" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17430223-26-viclabel138" type="occupation">Governor and Company of the Bank of England</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-victim316 t17430223-26-viclabel138"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17430223-26-victim316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430223-26-off135 t17430223-26-victim316"></join>
                     </persName>
                  ; against the Form of the Statute
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>2. He was likewise charged in the same Indictment in the same Manner as before, but with this Distinction only, the Bonds are laid to be the Property of a Person unknown; and the Sum of 100 l upon each of the six said last mentioned Bonds was then due and unsatisfied to the said Person, to the Jurors unknown, against the Form of the Statute.</p>
               <p>3. He was further charged, for that he, on the 10th Day of May, in the 14th Year of his Majesty's Reign, in the Parish of St Christopher's, in the Ward of Broad-street, in a certain Dwelling House therein situate, wherein Zerubbabel Crouch, and divers other Persons did then and there inhabit, did feloniously take and carry away, one Bond, No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person317">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person317" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person317" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2336, sealed, &amp;c. which said Bond, at the Time of committing the Felony, was of the Value of 100 l. and the Property of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, and that the Sum of 100l. was due and unsatisfied to the Proprietors thereof; against the Form of the Statutes, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>4. He was also charged in the same Indictment, in the same Manner as in the last Count, for stealing the said Bond, No. 2336, but with this Distinction only, that Bond is laid to be the Property of a Person unknown, against the Form of the Statutes, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>To this Indictment the Prisoner having pleaded, Not Guilty, he then said, My Lord, I am brought here on a Trial for my Life; I am now in Iron; I hope, as I am an Englishman, I have a Right to the Privilege which the Law allows, and hope your Lordship will order my Irons to be taken off.</p>
               <p>Court. When you come upon your Trial we will take Notice of it, but we have nothing to do with it till then.</p>
               <p>When the Trial came on his Irons were ordered to be taken off.</p>
               <p>Before the Jury were sworn it was asked, on the Part of the Prisoner, whether any of them were Proprietors of the Bank, or Indorsers of Bank Bills of Exchange, because if they were they could not, by Reason of their Interest, be upon the Jury, but none of 'em being so, they were accordingly sworn.</p>
               <p>Waite. My Lord, I beg there may be a profound Silence, for I have caught Cold since I have been in Prison, and cannot hear well at this Distance.</p>
               <p>The Council for the King * opened the Indictment, by acquainting the Court and the Jury, that the Prosecutors, who are the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, had brought before them the Prisoner at the Bar, to take his Trial for stealing a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230023"></xptr> great Number of East-India Bonds, the Property of the Bank; That till the Statute of the second Year of his present Majesty, the stealing of Bonds, &amp;c. was not made Felony; for such Securities for Money not being frequent in ancient Times, the common Law had not made a proper Provision to punish People for stealing them; but as these are now become a valuable Part of our Property, the Legislature had thought proper to make the stealing of East-India Bonus, and other public Securities, Felony, as the stealing of Goods or Money is at Common Law; That they hoped to be able to lay the Case before them, in such a Manner, as would bring it Home to the Prisoner, that he was the Stealer of these Bonds within the Meaning of that Law; and took Notice, that the Occasion of these Bonds coming to be placed in the Bank of England, was upon the Deficiency of some of the Masters in the High Court of Chancery, who were possessed of valuable Effects of the Suitors; whereupon, by an Act, in the Twelfth of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person318">
                  George
                   I. Cap
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person318" type="surname" value="I. Cap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person318" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . xxxii. it is directed, That all these Securities should be sent to the Bank of England, and that they, on giving Receipts for them, make themselves answerable for them, whatever becomes of them afterwards: When they are in their Possession, it is at the Peril of the Bank of England if they are lost, and therefore they are laid to be the Property of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England; and as these Bonds were lost, they had been forced to buy others, and replace them; and that therefore there could be no Doubt; but that these Bonds were the Property of the Bank of England; but that if there should be any Difficulty arise upon that, in Point of Law, they are likewise laid to be the Property of Persons unknown. That when any Bonds are brought in, the Person who receives them, gives an Account to the Directors in waiting, and they are deposited in a Chest, in the Committee-Room, and afterwards put into the Valut, in the securest Manner that can be; and it is uncertain to whom these belong, till the Matter depending between the Litigants in the Court of Chancery is determined; and these Securities are never taken out but for the Purpose of receiving the Interest, or delivering them back by Order of the Court of Chancery.</p>
               <p>* The Council for the Prosecution were Sir 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person319">
                  John 
                  Strange 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person319" type="surname" value="Strange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person319" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr Bootle and Mr Purchas. Of Council with the Prisoner, Serjeant Wynne, Serjeant Agar, Serjeant Kettleby, and Serjeant Hayward.</p>
               <p>They then stated the Circumstances relating to these six Bonds with which the Prisoner was charged, and to which only their Evidence would be consined : That in 1736, there being then a great Number of East-India Bonds in the Custody of the Bank; and the East-India Company resolving to reduce the Interest, that made it necessary to apply to the Court of Chancery, to have the taken out and exchanged for the Company's new Bonds; and that some of these Bonds would appear to be some of those Bonds which were thus brought to the Bank upon such Exchange; that as soon as they were brought there, they were carried to the Account of the particular Persons to whom they belonged, and the Prisoner himself gave Receipts for them, which should be produced: That on the 21st of April, the Court of Chancery, in the Cause of Broome and Broome, (that Cause being then at an End) ordered seventeen Bonds which were in the Bank to be delivered out; they went to the Bank to receive these Bonds, and seventeen Bonds were delivered them, by the Prisoner at the Bar; but those not being the same identical Bonds which were described in the Cause, but of different Numbers, upon this there was an Application made to the Bank, to get the right Bonds; and the Directors desired Mr Waite to look them out accordingly. Nobody thought there was any Thing unfair in it, but that he had taken the seventeen uppermost Bonds without any particular Reason; this occasioned an Enquiry, and the Prisoner said he would look into it, and set it right; but no Body suspecting him, he took an Opportunity of getting away; and though there were frequent Advertisements, with great Rewards for the apprehending him, there was nothing heard of him till he was taken in Ireland, about two or three Months ago. That Mr Waite going away in this Manner, occasioned a farther Enquiry: He had a little Desk at the Bank, wherein they imagined there might be some Bonds; this Desk was ordered to be broke open, and there were two Bonds in it, which were a little before brought in by Order of the Court of Chancery.</p>
               <p>That as these Bonds were taken away, the Bank had endeavoured to trace them, in order to know how they had been disposed of, and by whom; and were able to prove that the Prisoner at the Bar carried six of them to a Broker, said they were his own; that the Broker sold them for him, and that the Money was paid into his own Hands; and from thence they hoped it would appear, that the Bonds were stolen by him, and that he applied the Money to his own Use; that there would be a little Difference as to the Evidence, with Respect to some of the Bonds: These Six, being all the Bonds they could trace, it would be proper to state upon what Account they were brought into the Bank. As to No. A 2336, and No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person320">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person320" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person320" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2337, these were brought in, in the Cause of Draper and Pit, before the Time, that the Occasion of exchanging with the East-India Company arose, and were Part of those new Bonds which were to be replaced in that Cause. There<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230024"></xptr> were Thirty-six Bonds for 3600 l. from No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person321">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person321" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person321" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2306, to No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person322">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person322" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person322" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2341, both inclusive, and the Prisoner gave a Receipt for these Bonds, dated July 23, 1737; which says, they are received for the Governor and Company of the Bank of England.</p>
               <p>Then there is No. 2740, brought in, in the Cause of Boswell and Smiter; this Bond was delivered into the Hands of the Prisoner at the Bar, and he gave the like sort of a Receipt for this, as he did for the other two: Then these three No. 9671, 20311, 23335, were brought in by Order of the Court of Chancery, in the Cause of Wheeler and Harvey, (there were twenty in all) these were brought to the Bank, when the Prisoner happened not to be there, and were delivered to another Cashier, but upon the Prisoner's Return, as he was the Person that principally managed this A ffair, they were delivered to him; and these are three of those Bonds which they should prove were sold by the Order, and on the Account of the Prisoner at the Bar, and if so, there would remain no Doubt at all, that the Charge was brought home to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>That considering the Nature of the Case as it stands together, his disposing of these Bonds clandestinely, without any Sort of Authority, without communicating it to any Person belonging to the Bank, or concerned for the Bank; clandestinely conveying away these Bonds, delivering them into Mr Willoughby's Hand, as his own, directing him to sell and dispose of them, receiving the Money for them, and converting it to his own Use; these Bonds being taken out of a great Number which were under his Care; his not carrying away the whole Number, but separating of them, and converting them into Money for his own Use, in Fraud of the Bank, in Fraud of the Suitors, (if they had not Reparation made them by the Bank) and in Fraud to all Mankind; putting the Money into his Pocket and running away with it: If considering it in this Light, and under these Circumstances, this should not be allowed to be a felonious taking, what upon Earth could be said to be a felonious taking: What is the Difference between this and going to the Coffers of the Bank and taking out so much Money? the Bank are equal Sufferers, for they are to make this good: If he had got by this iniquitous Way 5000 l. it is the same as if he had gone to their Coffers and taken 500 l. out of them: That always, in these Cases, of great Weight; that the Jury are to enquire whether the Prisoner sled for it or no; the Law had a good Intention in that, for flying is an Institution of Guilt. That the Indictment is laid for stealing these Bonds out of a Dwelling-House, which takes from the Prisoner the Benefit of the Clergy; and the Bank is the Dwelling-House, where the Accomptant-General used to live with his Family, and if any Doubt were made of that they were prepared to make it appear in Point of Law, to be a Dwelling-House; and it is not laid, in the Indictment, to be the Dwelling-House of any particular Person, but properly and cautiously laid to be a Dwelling-House, wherein Zerubbabel Crouch, and divers other Persons to the Jurors unknown, did then and there inhabit; and this was done to prevent any Inconvenience that might arise from laying it as the Dwelling-House of a Body corporate. In like Manner, as in the Case of Bambridge, Warden of the Fleet, that Prison was laid to be a Dwelling-House, wherein A. B. and divers other Persons, to the Jurors unknown, did inhabit.</p>
               <p>(
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person323">
                  Gabriel 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person323" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person323" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.)</p>
               <p>Counc. Look out Draper against Pit, the 15th of July, 1730.</p>
               <p>Martin. I examined this at the Register-Office, it is a true Copy, At the Rolls the 15th Day of July, 1730, &amp;c. [This was an Order of the Court, for the positing in the Bank two East-India Bonds in this Cause.</p>
               <p>Mr Martin then produced the Order for taking out the old East-India Bonds, and exchanging them for new ones, dated the 10th of July, 1741.</p>
               <p>Mr Pyle. I belong to the Report-Office, in the Court of Chancery, these are what were filed there, the 23d of July, 1737, that is the Original filed in the Office.</p>
               <p>Mr Waite's Receipt produced.</p>
               <p>Mr Race. I do believe, the Name of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person324">
                  John 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person324" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person324" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to be the Prisoner's Hand-Writing. - The Receipt was read. - Signed 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person325">
                  John 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person325" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person325" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , London, July 23d. 1737. Received of the East-India Company, Thirty six new East-India Bonds, No. and Dates following, for l. 3600, No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person326">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person326" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person326" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2306, to 2341. both inclusive, dated the 27th of June, 1737. Interest due from the 31st of March last, exchanged for Bonds of the like Value, which Bonds are placed to the Account of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person327">
                  Mark 
                  Thurston 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person327" type="surname" value="Thurston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person327" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esquire, Accomptant-General of the Court of Chancery, in the Cause of Draper against Pit, for the Governor and Company of the Bank of England.</p>
               <p>Counc. This proves No. 2336, and 2337.</p>
               <p>Another Exhibit the 9th of December, 1740, Boswell and Smiter.</p>
               <p>Mr Martin. This is a true Copy.</p>
               <p>The Order was read, importing that 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person328">
                  John 
                  Bosanquet 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person328" type="surname" value="Bosanquet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person328" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person329">
                  Henry 
                  Gambier 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person329" type="surname" value="Gambier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person329" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were to deposit three East India Bonds in the Bank.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230025"></xptr>Mr Pole, of the Report Office, produced another Receipt of Mr Waite's.</p>
               <p>Mr Race. The Name 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person330">
                  John 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person330" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person330" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I believe, to be Mr Waite's Hand-Writing. - The Receipt road. - Signed 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person331">
                  John 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person331" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person331" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , London, December 22, 1740. Received of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person332">
                  John 
                  Bosanquet 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person332" type="surname" value="Bosanquet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person333">
                  Henry 
                  Gambier 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person333" type="surname" value="Gambier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person333" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , pursuant to an Order of the 9th of December, the three following Bonds; No. 2738, No. 2739, No. 2740. dated the 1st of July, 1737, for 100l. each, on which Bonds the Interest is due from the 31st of March, 1738, and which Bonds are placed to the Account of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person334">
                  Mark 
                  Thurston 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person334" type="surname" value="Thurston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person334" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esquire, Accomptant General, to the Court of Chancery, in the Cause of Boswell against Smiter, for the Governor and Company of the Bank of England.</p>
               <p>Pris Counc. to Mr Gambier. Are you a Proprietor of Bank-Stock?</p>
               <p>Gambier. No.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. If he was, that is no Objection: Here is a Receipt of Mr Waite's read for 3 Bonds, delivered into the Bank, the 22d of December, 1740. Do you know any Thing of placing these Bonds there?</p>
               <p>Gambier. I was not at the Bank, Mr Bosanquet went himself; I was a Trustee - My Name was made Use of, but Mr Bosanquet did transact it. - These 3 Bonds, No. 2738, 2739, and 2740, were placed in the Bank.</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. The Gentlemen of the other Side have mentioned 3 Bonds to you, whose Property were they?</p>
               <p>Gambier. They were in Dispute between Mrs Guiguer, Smiter, and Boswell; they were deposited in the Bank by Order of Doctors-Commons, where a Will was contested. - They never were in my Possession. - It was the Will of Mrs 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person335">
                  Eunice 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person335" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person335" type="given" value="Eunice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that was contested: This will was never proved; I believe the Matter was made up.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. 'Tis a special Property; a Carrier has a special Property and may bring an Action of Trover.</p>
               <p>Court. They do not open it, that the Bank of England have an absolute Property in these Bonds, but they have a special Property as they are answerable for them; and they are answerable to those who are the absolute Proprietors of them, who are the Suitors in the Court of Chancery.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. In the Cause of Wheeler and Harvey, Mr Martin proved an Order, dated March 18 1740, to deposit in the Bank 20 East-India Bonds, for 100l. each, to be placed to the Credit of this Cause (among which, were the Numbers 9671, 20311, and 23335) ordering, that the Interest be paid to the Plantiff, 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person336">
                  Charles 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person336" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person336" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>As to these 3 Bonds we have not the same Receipt for them as we have for the others; for Mr Waite was not there when they were brought, but they came into his Hands immediately.</p>
               <p>( Mr Collyer sworn.)</p>
               <p>Q. What Office were you in, in the Bank, in April 1741?</p>
               <p>Mr Collyer. I was then one of the Cashiers.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any Thing of any Bond being brought into the Bank when Mr Waite was not in the Office ?</p>
               <p>Collyer. I cannot say that I do. (The Receipt was shewn to him ) I own this to be my Hand writing, it was brought to me by Mr Standish, who was an entering Clerk.</p>
               <p>Mr Standish. I received these Bonds in Mr Waite's Absence and entered them, Mr Collyer sign'd the Receipt, [The Act of Parliament directs the Receipt should be signed by a Cashier] and when Mr Waite came back I delivered them into his Hands - It might be 2 or 3 Hours after I received them - I gave them to Mr Waite and he locked them up in his Desk - it was his own Desk; we have each of us a Desk to lock up every Thing we have in Trust - No Body had the Key of that Desk but himself. - These Bonds should regularly have been carried down into a Vault. The Directors have the Keys of the Vault; Mr Waite had only the Keys of a particular Chest. - I never went down with the Directors, and do not know whether one, two, or three go down.</p>
               <p>Mr Collyer's Receipt read, signed 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person337">
                  James 
                  Collyer 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person337" type="surname" value="Collyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person337" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , dated April 7, 1741, wherein he acknowledged to have received of the Defendant, 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person338">
                  Jacob 
                  Harvey 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person338" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person338" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , by an Order of the 18th of March last, 20 East-India Bonds, in the Cause of Wheeler and Harvey. Among which, were No. 9671, No. 2311, and No. 33335.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person339">
                  John 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person339" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person339" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr Standish, I desire to know whether or not, when you delivered those 20 Bonds to me, you saw me lock them up in my Desk?</p>
               <p>Standish. I saw you put them in, and the Key turn; I think that is locking them up.</p>
               <p>Waite You might see me put them in, and not see me lock them up.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. Having proved the Bonds to come into his Care, we shall now proceed to prove his Disposal of them.</p>
               <p>( 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person340">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person340" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person340" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.)</p>
               <p>King's Counc. Mr Willoughby, do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person341">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person341" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person341" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 7 or 8 Years; I have done Business for him as a Broker.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230026"></xptr>Counc. Look into any Minute or Memorandum you have, and see whether you ever received any East-India Bonds from him; what the Numbers were; what Directions he gave you, and what you did with them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person342">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person342" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person342" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of April 1741, he gave me six India Bonds to sell, Letter 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person343">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person343" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person343" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2336, Letter A 2337, Letter 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person344">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person344" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person344" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2740, No. 9671, No. 20311, No. 23335.</p>
               <p>Counc. What were you to do with them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person345">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person345" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person345" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was to sell them - for himself - and I did dispose of them accordingly - they carried a Premium of 4 l. 11 s. - 628 l. 12 s. and 7 d. was the neat Produce of them. - I delivered the Money to Mr Waite the same Day.</p>
               <p>Coun. Whose Bonds did you understand them to be?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person346">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person346" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person346" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . His own Bonds; we always suppose them to be the Property of the Person that brings them.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Name were they made out in?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person347">
                  Richard 
                  Willoughby 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person347" type="surname" value="Willoughby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person347" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They were made out in the Name of Webb, that is the Name they are all made out in. - I cannot say that I know the Dates of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430223-26-person348">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person348" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person348" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Officer of the East-India Company. - I am the Person in whose Name the Bonds are made out, and do indorse them - These are India Bonds - this is my Endorsement - they have all my Name on the Back - there are no other Bonds of the same Numbers and Dates.</p>
               <p>Counc. At the Time of making out these Bonds, were they all made payable to you?</p>
               <p>Webb. Yes, they were all made out in my Name, and I endorsed them.</p>
               <p>Counc. They are, by Act of Parliament, transferable by Endorsement.</p>
               <p>The Bonds were produced and read, viz.</p>
               <p>No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person349">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person349" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person349" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2336, - Dated June 27, 1737.</p>
               <p>No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person350">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person350" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person350" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2337. - Dated June 27, 1737.</p>
               <p>[No. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person351">
                  A. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person351" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person351" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            2740. - was not produced.]</p>
               <p>No. 9671. - Dated October 25, 1736.</p>
               <p>No. 20311. - Dated February 18, 1736.</p>
               <p>No. 23335. - Dated March 17, 1736. with the Seal off.</p>
               <p>Q. How came that Bond to be cancelled?</p>
               <p>Mr. Robins. It is a satisfied Bond - it was exchanged for another - it was brought in to be exchanged October 31, 1741, by Mr. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person352">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Newnhman 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person352" type="surname" value="Newnhman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person352" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>(Mr Standish called again.)</p>
               <p>Counc. Did any Body live in the Bank at the Time Mr. Waite went away?</p>
               <p>Standish. Yes; Zerubbabel Crouch, the Accomptant General of the Bank, lived there - he lay there himself, and his Wife and Maid-Servant. - Mr. 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person353">
                  Robert 
                  Sayer 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person353" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person353" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Clerk in the Bank, lived there at the same Time. - The Porter and his Wife have an Apartment there. - I am positive Mr. Crouch was alive when Mr Waite went away.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. There is another Thing we are ready to prove, that as the Bank is obliged to make good these Bonds, that they have bought others and replaced them.</p>
               <p>The Order of the Court of Chancery of the 10th of July 1741, was read; whereby the Bonds deficient in the Cause of Draper against Pit, Boswell against Smiter, &amp;c. to the Amount of 133 were ordered to be replaced by the Bank.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pyle, an Officer of the Report-Office, produced the Certificates, whereby it appeared that the Bank had replaced them.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. My Lord, as to Matters of Fact, I am under very great Restrictions, and that is the Misfortune of the Prisoner. He is only assisted, if Matter of Law arise in this Case, and then we are only at Liberty to speak for him, as to that. I submit it upon the Prosecutors own Evidence, whether upon the Circumstances they have proved, he is guilty of the Crime laid to his Charge. I shall not endeavour to state any Thing contrary to the Facts; and considering the Evidence in the strongest Sense, the single Question is, whether this Taking of his does amount to a felonious Taking or not. I will not dispute that the Bank has a special Property, and may bring an Action of Trover, and lay an Indictment for it: And I would not have this forgot, and I believe the Witnesses will not deny it, that as the Prisoner is a Proprietor in the Bank, he may have a special Interest in this Corporation; these Bonds may be the Property of the Bank, but the Question is, whether he, as a Proprietor of Bank-Stock, has not a Right with the rest of the Company; and whether a Man, even in that Respect, can be indicted for stealing Goods in which he has a Property; that will be one Thing to be considered in this Man's Defence, and I could even submit it upon the Circumstances of that single Point, whether this does amount to a felonious Taking.</p>
               <p>I will not state the whole Facts, because I know I am not allowed to do it, and therefore I will state it upon their own Evidence; and I beg leave to say, that the Prisoner has been entrusted with these Bonds, that he has had these<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230027"></xptr> Bonds delivered to him, and has given Receipts for them in his own Name; therefore I submit it, whether, under these Circumstances, he ought to be indicted for a felonious Taking of these very Bonds which were so delivered to him, tho' I do not doubt but he did dispose of them against his Trust, this Man being under Misfortunes at that Time, tho' they were not publickly known; but I apprehend the disposing of them will never make him guilty of Felony, unless the taking them was Felony.</p>
               <p>Court. We shall leave that to the Jury, whether it was with a felonious Intent that he took them away.</p>
               <p>2d Counc. I submit it to your Lordship, whether they have gone far enough in a Case of this Nature. They have laid the Bonds as the Property of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, and have described the Money to be due to the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, and unsatisfied to them; and as to the second Count, they say, if we have not been right in laying them to be the Property of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, we have laid them to be the Property of a Person unknown; and not any one of the Witnesses they have produced has shown, that the Governor or Company of the Bank of England, have any Right to this Money at all; and according to the laying of this Count in the Indictment, they should have shewn the Money to be due to the Governor and Company of the Bank of England; or according to the second Count, that the Bonds were the Property of a Person unknown. I must submit it to your Lordship, that they have failed in proving either Count, so as to affect the Prisoner; for if, as they have proved the Governor and Company of the Bank had a Property, then these Bonds were not the Property of Persons unknown; and if the Governor and Company of the Bank could not receive the Money for them (being a Deposit only) then the Money cannot be due to them, as is set out in the Indictment.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. You mistake it, in the third Count it is, was due and unsatisfied to the several Proprietors thereof; in the fourth Count it is laid to be the Property of a Person unknown, and remains due and unsatisfied to the said Person unknown. Mr Serjeant Wynne says right, that it will maintain an Action of Trover, or support an Indictment; the Bank were answerable, and we have proved they were answerable.</p>
               <p>2d King's Counc. Take this one Way or the other, it incontestably hits him: First, they are laid to be the Property of the Bank of England; secondly, the Property of a Person unknown. Now take it upon the first, it cannot be disputed but that the Bank has a special Property: In the Case of a Bailment of Goods and Pledges, the special Property is in the Bail, in whom the Property is placed. Wilbraham and Snow, 2 Saunders 47. A Carrier can bring an Action. They must either be the Property of those who were originally entitled to them, or the Property of other Persons: One of the Witnesses says, there was a Dispute between the Parties who had the Property in the Bonds, and this shows them plainly to be the Property of Persons unknown.</p>
               <p>(Part of the Indictment read)</p>
               <p>'' Was the Property of the Governor and Company '' of the Bank of England, and was then due '' and unsatisfied to the Proprietors thereof.''</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. Mr Bootle says, if they do not belong to the one they do to the other, that is very true; but they have fixed the Property in the Bank of England, and therefore their being the Property of a Person unknown, is quite out of the Case; therefore they must make it out that the Governor and Company of the Bank of England may receive the Money: It will be admitted that they had a special Property, so far as to have the Custody of the Bonds, but not such a Property as to receive the Money, or that the Money was due and owing to them. They have laid this Money to be the Money of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England; they might safely have said the Money was unsatisfied, but it was not the Money of the Bank of England. The Gentlemen of the other Side say, that the Bank has made it good; but I apprehend what the Bank has done, was upon a Time subsequent to the Fact, and this should have been at the Time of the taking away, therefore I think this does not support the Indictment. Then, as to the second Count, it says the Property of a Person unknown.</p>
               <p>King's Counc. It says each of the Bonds is the Property of a Person unknown.</p>
               <p>Court. I think this is the Description of the Bonds; it says the Bonds were the Property of the Bank of England, and that the Bonds were then due and unsatisfied to the Bank, and the Proprietors thereof.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. It is due and owing to the Proprietors thereof.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is entitled to receive the Money due upon these Bonds; may not the Person who has the Custody and Possession of them receive it?</p>
               <p>King's Counc. They are endorsed to the Bank.</p>
               <p>Court. If you will but look at them, you will see they are endorsed Blank.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230028"></xptr>Pris. Counc. Whoever had the lawful Possession of these Bonds, cannot be guilty of Felony.</p>
               <p>Court. I may have the lawful Possession of a Thing, and yet be guilty of Felony.</p>
               <p>King's Council (to the Prisoner's Council.) If you will argue the Point of Law, go on, or else examine your Witnesses.</p>
               <p>Pris. Couns. We want to examine your's.</p>
               <p>Mr. Collyer called.</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. Give an Account to my Lord and the Jury, when these Bonds were delivered to Mr Waite, which were brought to the Bank in his Absence?</p>
               <p>Collyer. I can give no Account of it at all, till I turn to the Receipt. I believe they were delivered to him that Day. This is my Hand-writing; the Bonds were delivered to the Prisoner, the 7th of April, 1741. - They were the Bonds in the Cause of Wheeler against Harvey. These are Part of those twenty Bonds.</p>
               <p>Pris. Council to Standish. Don't you know that Mr. Waite is a Proprietor of Bank-Stock.</p>
               <p>Standish. I believe he has been possessed of Bank-Stock - I cannot swear whether he is now or not. *</p>
               <p>* The Prisoner had been possessed of 1000 l. Bank-Stock, which he transferred as Part of his Security; but this did not appear in Evidence.</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. We cannot get at the Bank Books to prove this.</p>
               <p>King's Counc . He has no Bank-Stock. The Prisoner's two Receipts are dated, one on the 23d of July, 1737, the other, on the 22d of December, 1740, and the other Bonds, for which Collyer gave a Receipt, came to his Hand the 7th of April 1741, and they were sold the 27th of the same Month by his Order; and therefore I submit it to your Lordship whether this was a felonious taking or not.</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. My Lord, before the Act of Parliament of the second of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person354">
                  George 
                  II 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person354" type="surname" value="II"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person354" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . c. 25, the stealing and carrying away Bonds and other Securities (or Choses in Action, as they were then called) could not be Felony; but by that Act of Parliament it is made Felony. As it is agreed that the making this Felony, is founded on this Act of Parliament, I desire it may be read, and then I will submit it to your Lordship, that this is not a felonious taking, as the Circumstances will be made out.</p>
               <p>The Clause read.</p>
               <p>'' And be it further enacted, by the Authority aforesaid, That if any Person or Persons, after the said 29th of June, shall steal, or take by Robbery, any Exchequer Orders, &amp;c. East-India-Bonds, &amp;c. being the Property of any other Person or Persons, or of any Corporation, notwithstanding any of the said Particulars are termed, in Law, a Chose in Action, it shall be deemed and construed to be Felony, of the same Nature, and in the same Degree, and with or without the Benefit of Clergy, in the same Manner as it would have been if the Offender had stolen, or taken by Robbery, any other Goods of like Value with the Monies due on such Orders, &amp;c.''</p>
               <p>Pris. Counc. My Lord, I shall trouble your Lordship with a Word or two upon this Head; and I believe, upon the Circumstances of the Case, this will not appear to be a felonious taking; the Words have been read to your Lordship, that such Persons who shall steal or take, by Robbery, any Bonds, Orders, &amp;c. shall be guilty of Felony, as if such Offender had stole Money or Goods: It was admitted, on the other Side, that this was not Felony by the Common Law; (the stealing of Bonds, Warrants, &amp;c.) and he was pleased to give a very good Reason for it, that these Securities were not so common, or numerous as they are now; and therefore the Case of Property being very much altered, there was a Necessity of altering the Law, and, I believe, the Act of Parliament takes Notice of it fully: It is not a declaratory Act of Parliament, but introductive of a new Law, and the Question is, whether they have offered your Lordship any Evidence to bring this Case within the present Act of Parliament: By this Act of Parliament, it must be an actual stealing or taking by Robbery: What Evidence has been offered to your Lordship, to shew that there has been any stealing, or taking by Robbery? they are Terms extremely well understood in Point of Law; if they are taken by the Person who has the Possession, (that is a right Possession) if it is by the Privity or Consent of the Owner, or by an actual Delivery to the Person, by him or his Order, that cannot make it to be a felonious taking; the Intention of the Statute is only to make Choses in Action, and which are Part of a Man's Property secure; that seems to be the Intention of the last Act of Parliament, that the taking of these should be punished in the same Degree and Manner, as if a Person had taken Goods or Money to the same Value. But the Law makes no Difference in these, it intends no Alteration at all, either in the Nature of the Crime, or the Consequences of it. My Lord, I take the Thing to be pretty clear, that where a Thing is delivered to a Person;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230029"></xptr> where it is entrusted with him, and put into his Possession and Custody, I think that cannot be Felony; though the Party does unhappily abuse his Trust, that will not make it Felony, it will not alter the Original Trust so as to make it Felony; and I believe there are many Authorities which may be mentioned to prove this, 1 Hale 667. The Gentlemen say, it is very clear that he sold them, and converted the Produce to his own Use: It was urged that the strongest Argument of his Guilt was, his flying and running away with the Money; an honest Man is sometimes forced to go out of the Way for Debt; but this does not infer the Crime of Felony; and I will suppose, for Argument Sake, that the Prisoner has converted this Money to his own Use, and, if so, it is certainly a Misdemeanor, and a Breach of Trust, for which he must be answerable another Way: Aand in Answer to such a general Argument as was made Use of in the out-set; I must say, that any Man that designs a Felony does not use to give Receipts, but he gave Receipts under his own Hand to shew the Delivery of these Things, and his receiving them: And, as I have mentioned Possession in general, I may further add, where a Man is intrusted with Goods, and has the Possession of them, for a particular Purpose, that Man cannot be guilty of Felony. Hawkins 89.</p>
               <p>If a Man has Possession of any Goods, by Delivery, he cannot commit a Felony; as with Respect to the Case of a Carrier that goes away with Goods which were put into his Hands to deliver to another. Hale's Abrigdment 61. Hist. Pleas of the Crown, 506. Hawkins 89.</p>
               <p>If the Carrier goes away with these Goods, carries them to a wrong Place, by which they are lost, or sells them, it has been determined over and over again, that this is not Felony. One of the Gentlemen made use of an Expression, that the Prisoner separated the Bonds, that he had Possession of them, and took them out of a greater Number; that he embezzled them and applied them to his own Use. I do allow there is a Distinction in this, for if a Carrier breaks open a Pack, or a Chest, or a Trunk, and sells Part of the Goods, the Carrier then may be said to be guilty of Felony. If a Man delivers or lends an Horse to another, and he rides away with it, this Person is not guilty of Felony: This is a common Case in all the Books, and I rely strongly upon it. I have known the Case tried here. Suppose a Man comes to an Inn-keeper under Pretence of chaffering for a Horse, and when he has got upon his Back, rides away with it; this is not Felony. 1 Hale 504. But there is a Distinction in the Statute, where a Servant takes a Horse, without the Leave of his Master, and rides away with it, that is Felony by the Statute of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person355">
                  Henry 
                  VIII 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person355" type="surname" value="VIII"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person355" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>I might trouble your Lordship with a great many more Cases, but I will leave it upon this; here are a great many Bonds delivered to and entrusted with an Officer of the Bank, and he sells them, &amp;c. I submit it to your Lordship, that from the Authority of the Officer, it is not a felonious taking. I am not contending that a Man is not answerable another Way; but the Question is, whether the Law will support a Prosecution for a Felony. As to Mr Waite's being guilty of a Misapplication of the Money, to be sure he is, but that such Misapplication does not amount to a Felony; I am confirmed in it, by an Act of Parliament made very lately, to prevent Accidents of this Kind for the future; and I believe, the Gentlemen will find no Retrospection in the Act; it is the Act of the 15th Year of his present Majesty c. 15, p. 538. This Act of Parliament says, '' If any Officer, or Servant of the said Company, (meaning the Bank of England) being intrusted with any Note, Bill, Dividend - Warrant, Bond, Deed, or any Security, &amp;c. Money, or other Effects, belonging to the said Company, or having any Bill, Dividend-Warrant, Bond, Deed, or any Security, or Effects of any other Person or Persons, lodged or deposited with the said Company, or with him, as an Officer or Servant of the said Company, shall secrete, embezzle, or run away with any such Note, Bill, Dividend Warrant, Bond, Deed, Security, Money, or Effects, or any Part of them, every Officer or Servant so offending, and being thereof convicted in due Form of Law, shall be deemed guilty of Felony, and shall suffer Death as a Felon, without Benefit of Clergy.'' I apprehend this Clause shews the Sense of this Body, the Sense of the honourable Persons who advised them in this Case, and the Sense of the Legislature, that this was not Felony before; for they will find that this is not a declaratory Act, (there being no declaratory Words,) but is plainly introductive of a new Law. I am far from thinking that such a wise Body, as the Legislature is, would make a vain, or a needless Act; for if this was Felony before, what Occasion was there to make it Felony? I hope this Act of Parliament, which is a publick one, will not be looked upon as a nugatory Act, but have its full Weight in Favour of the Prisoner, and that a Jury of Englishmen will regard it as such.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230030"></xptr>2d Coun. The Question is, Whether this is a Breach of Trust, or a Felony? I shall not dispute with the Gentlemen of the other Side, but that there is a special Property in the Bank, and the Gentlemen might have brought an Action against the Prisoner, and may yet do it; and I hope if they can have a Remedy in a Civil Way they will never succeed in a criminal one. I apprehend the taking of these Bonds is no Felony at all; but if it is so, it is a Felony by the Act of Parliament of the 15th of his present Majesty; It is said, If this is not Felony, what is Felony? The Case of a Carrier has been mentioned, but I apprehend that is not applicable to the present Case. A Carrier had Goods delivered to him to carry to a particular Place, he carried them and delivered them at that particular Place, and then takes them away, that I agree is Felony; for when he had delivered them at that particular Place, his Trust determined, he had divested himself of that Property he had in them, and when he took them away, then the Felony commenced, then was the unjust taking, for there must be an unjust taking to make it stealing: But it is not thus in the present Case, for as the Bonds always remained with the Prisoner, the Question will be, Whether he can be guilty of stealing these Bonds from himself, and I apprehend no Man can be guilty of stealing from himself what he has in his Possession. My Lord, it is said, by the Council for the King, that there was a special Property in these Bonds in the Bank of England, but in Respect to this, I would mention the Act of Parliament of the 12th of George I. for by that Act the Bank is only entitled to the Receipt of the Interest, the Money was not due to them, but the Suitors, and therefore the taking cannot be Felony in this Case. In the Act of Parliament of his present Majesty, it is indeed declared, If any Person belonging to the Bank does secrete, or embezzle any Thing belonging to them, that Person shall be guilty of Felony: But this Act of Parliament was made after this Offence was committed, and therefore does not reach the Crime this Man is charged with; and therefore, I hope, upon the Circumstances of the Case, this Man does not appear to have acted any otherwise than in Breach of his Trust.</p>
               <p>3d Council observed, among other Things, that if the Prisoner had been intrusted with these Securities, without giving any Receipt for them, there might have been a Difference in the Case; but here Mr. Waite had 'em by a Sort of a Contract, for she gave a Receipt for them, which proves he came not by them tortiously, or that he robbed the Bank of them; for having them thus in his Custody, he made himself a Trustee to the Company, and was answerable for the Value of them; and the Bank is not destitute of a Remedy in this Case, inasmuch as they take Security of their Officers, and I submit it to the Court, that the Act of Parliament of the 15th of 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person356">
                  George 
                  II 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person356" type="surname" value="II"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person356" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . was not a declaratory Act, or explanatory of any other Act of Parliament, but a new Law, and that the Offence charged upon the Prisoner was not Felony by any former Law.</p>
               <p>4th Counc. My Lord, I will leave the Facts as they now stand, and not trouble the Court with any thing in Relation to the Nature of the Evidence, but consine myself merely to Matters of Law, and make a Parallel between this and other adjudged Cases, from Time to Time, and show that there's no Reason to distinguish this from any of those Cases. Before the Statute-Law, stealing a meer Chose in Active, could not be Felony; therefore it was thought necessary to make the Breach of that great Trust, which is reposed in the People of the Bank, Felony, because if they thought themselves at Liberty to play Tricks of this Kind, and not be punished for them, it would be of the last Consequence to the Publick. The Words of that Act of Parliament are plain enough to me to show that this Offence is not in any former Act: For the Act says, '' If any Person shall steal or take by Robbery;'' stealing is a transferring the Possession, and that privately from a Person; taking by Robbery, implies a Force, for there cannot be a Robbery without an actual Force; there cannot be a Robbery in this Case, if it is any Thing it must be a stealing. Could he take these Things without the Consent of the Persons who put them into his Hand? Has not he a Property? Had the Governor and Company embezzled these Things, Could they be guilty of Felony? No, they could not, but they are liable to make Satisfaction to the Suitors in Chancery: What Right is there to distinguish Persons? They have entrusted him as their Servant; he is as much entrusted by them, as the Court of Chancery entrusted the Bank; and he, by his Receipt, is liable and answerable. Put the case, that the Bank had a Mind to make a little Use of a Parcel of inconsiderable Papers for a little Time, though I do not suppose they would. What would have been the Consequence, it would not be Felony?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230031"></xptr>King's Counc. They cannot commit a Felony, for they are a Corporation.</p>
               <p>4th Counc. I know a Body-Corporate cannot commit a Felony, but each of them separately may be guilty of Felony. Now I beg leave to consider how it may be distinguished in Point of Law, for Waite had a special Property in these Bonds. If I lend my Watch, or my Horse to a Person, and he goes to Market and sells them, this is not Felony, this supposes a Contract, and gives the Party a Remedy at common Law; besides they have Security for his good Behaviour; all the Officers of the Bank gave Security, and as to the Property there should be a Distinction made in this Respect, for there may be a Property for a particular Purpose; and when a Person has Possession of a Thing lawfully, there an Action of Trover only lies against the Person. If a Carrier is robbed, he may maintain a Prosecution, because he has a special Property for a particular Purpose. A Man that comes legally by a Thing, cannot rob himself; for if he had a Right to the Possession, he must have stole them from himself, he could not have stole them from any Body else. Then as to the late Act of Parliament, my Lord, for what End and Purpose could this Act of Parliament be made, if it was not the Sense of the Legislature, that the stealing of these Securities was not Felony before; but the Reason, as I apprehend, was, and in Point of Law, must be taken to be so, that the stealing of Choses in Action, was not Felony before. Suppose he forgot or mislaid a Bond, and could not find it, must he be indicted for a Felony. I very well remember a remarkable Case *, (that went out of this Court upon a special Verdict, whether the stealing of Chancery-Records, taking them out of the Office, and taking the Stamps off, and selling them, was Felony; but the Court of King's Bench gave their Opinion upon it, that it was not Felony, and the Party was acquitted, and it was the Voice of the whole Court, that it was not Felony. But this new Act being made, plainly shows that Mr Waite is not guilty of Felony, as it was not Felony before this Act. But should we be so unfortunate as not to satisfy the Court and the Jury, that this is not Felony, then I should be glad if the Court would be pleased to indulge us in such a Manner, that the Facts may be stated, in order that the several Points may be more fully argued; and that we may have Time to lay Reasons before the Judges, which, in this material Case, ought to be very maturely considered, and that it may not be left to a Jury, to determine Quo animo he took them.</p>
               <p>* In the Mayoralty of Mr Alderman Perry. See the Trial, January Sessions, No. 124.</p>
               <p>Serj. Agar. It is, my Lord, admitted by us all, that the Bank had so far a special Property in the Bonds, as to receive the Interest, but not otherwise.</p>
               <p>King's Council. My Lord, I beg a few Words by Way of Reply, in Behalf of the Prosecution; but before I argue the Points of Law, it will be proper to see upon what Ground we stand, in Point of Evidence. By the Act of Parliament, these Bonds are to be carried to the Bank, to be received by the Governor and Company of the Bank of England, and Receipts are to be given for them; and the Act of Parliament makes the Bank of England expressly liable for the same. According to the Evidence, these Bonds were carried from the Court of Chancery to the Bank, and as the Bank have proper Servants for every Branch of their Business, the Prisoner at the Bar was the proper Person to receive these Bonds from the Accomptant-General of the Court of Chancery; and I do lay this as a Foundation, that as soon as they are delivered into the Bank of England, they are that Minute in the Possession of the Bank; let them remove that Corner-Stone if they can, they are in the Possession of them, whether they are under their own Lock and Key, or the Lock and Key of their Servant, for it is their Possession in Point of Law: The Gentlemen would insinuate, that these Bonds are not to be considered as delivered into the Possession of the Bank, but into the Possession of Mr Waite, for Mr Waite has given Receipts for them, and made himself answerable for them; but they have omitted the most material Part, that he receives them for, and subscribes the Receipt for the Governor and Company of the Bank of England; his Receipt is not such a Receipt as will entitle the Suitors to call upon him for the Money, not such a Receipt as will entitle him to it; for though this Man's Name is to the Receipt, it is in Point of Law the Receipt of the Governor and Company of the Bank of England. If a Servant gives a Receipt, and says, for my Master such an one, Is not this, in Point of Law, the Receipt of the Master? Because this Money is received by the Servant, is it not the Receipt of the Master? It is as much mine as it I had signed it. They would turn us round, and tell us we are to bring an Action, and make this a Breach of Trust:</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230032"></xptr>I should be glad to know whose Trust it is that he has broke: Would they say he has broke his Trust with the Court of Chancery, they cannot say he has broke his Trust with them. - They have brought it out, but not as a Point of Law, that a Man cannot steal from himself; no more he can abstractedly, but he may commit a Felony of what he has in his own Possession; and I will make it out very plain from the first Case put by Mr Serjeant Wynne, Hale 506, in the Case of a Carrier, says, that if a Man delivers Goods to a Carrier, to carry to Dover, and he carried them away, 'tis no Felony. But if a Carrier, after he has carried Goods to the Place appointed, secretly takes them away again, Animo Surandi, in such Case the Possession which he received from the Owner being determined, his second taking, is in all Respects, the same as if he was a Stranger. I will put a middle Case: If a Carrier, in his Journey between London and York, will unpack Goods, and take any thing out of a Case, Box, or Pack, that will be a felonious Taking; for he had no Authority at all to separate these Goods, his Authority was to receive the Bundle entire, and to deliver it entire at such a Place. Let us compare the Cases: here are twenty Bonds delivered at one Time into the Hand of this Man, and three of these are taken by him for his own Use, he is in the same Case with the Carrier who takes part of the Goods out of a Parcel, and does not deliver them to the Party they are for, but disposes of them, and applies the Money to his own Use; the Question is, whether this is not Evidence to a Jury of a felonious Taking.</p>
               <p>The next Case they mention, is that of lending a Horse; that if a Man lends a Horse to another, and he rides away with it, it is not Felony. And they have put a Case which they cannot make out, that if a Man goes to an Inn to hire a Horse, and gets upon his Back and rides away with it, that is not Felony; but I believe they cannot make a Book-Case of it; that it is not Felony, for in that Case the Horse is not lent to him, and therefore it must be a Felony. I would not have them run away with this as a Point, but I hope there are no Horse-stealers here, for this is too dangerous a Doctrine to be delivered in this Place. - But the Gentlemen, they say, as to what has been done by Mr Waite, that is not such a Stealing, as comes within the Meaning of the Law; but as I have proved that those Bonds are in the Possession of the Bank of England, as soon as they are delivered to him, those Persons who make away with them are liable to be punished for a Felony. There is a Difference between having the Care of Goods, and the legal Possession of them; for when a Man has no more than the Care of Goods, the Possession is all the while, in the Judgment of the Law, in the Master. I will venture to lay it down as a Rule, that that Sort of a Servant may be guilty of Felony in taking those Goods to his own Use. Serjeant Hawkins, in his Pleas of the Crown, p. 90. says it has been received as Law, that those who have the bare Charge of Goods may be guilty of Felony; that is, when they are entrusted with a Parcel of Goods, the taking out part of them is Felony; and one who has the bare Charge of Goods, or the special Use of Goods, and not the Possession, that is a legal Possession, he may be guilty of Felony. The first Case he puts, is the Case of a Gentleman's Butler; every Gentleman, I believe, does not lock up his own Plate, or keep it in his own Custody, and when a Butler is hired, there is nothing more known, than that an Account of the Plate is taken in Writing and delivered to the Butler, and the Plate is delivered into his Care, he has the cleaning of it, and is the proper Person to take Care of it; and he has it by that Delivery, if I may so say, intrusted into his Hand; it is a determined Point, that by being in my House (in Point of Law) it is in my Possession, and if my Butler will take a Piece of my Plate and sell it and put the Money into his Pocket, he is Guilty of Felony. 1 Hale, 506.</p>
               <p>Dyer, fol. 5. It is determined there, that if a Butler disposes of a Piece of my Plate, he is Guilty of Felony, and must suffer Death, if it is to the Value of 40 s. - Now as to this Sort of Bonds, I find they remain in the Custody of the Person who has the Care of them, till the Directors go down to put them into the Vault, and then he that had the Care of them, goes down to the proper Place to lock them up, in the Sight of the Directors: This is not like a Case where Goods are delivered to a Man to keep in his Custody, I take the Case of the Butler to be stronger than the present Case, for there he has the Plate by the express Act of the Master delivered to him; and when he goes away, the Plate is counted over and delivered back.</p>
               <p>The next Case is that of a Shepherd, who is employed by a Farmer to take Care of his Sheep. There was a Notion that the Shepherd was so entrusted with the Sheep, that if he run away with them, he could not be prosecuted for a Felony. See Hawkins, and Hale's Pleas of the Crown, 506. A Shepherd, by disposing of one Sheep is guilty of Felony; for he has only the Care of them; he is not generally entrusted with them, the Law distinguishes<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230033"></xptr> between having Possession of a thing, and only having the Care of it.</p>
               <p>There is another Case put of a Servant who has the Key of an Appartment delivered to him, that he may be Guilty of Felony, if he takes any Thing out of it; for tho' he has the Key of the Chamber, the Goods are still in the Possession of the true Owner.</p>
               <p>Then there is another Case put; if a Man goes into a Tavern as a Guest, and has a Piece of Plate set before him, not with standing he has Possession of this by my Delivery; if he walks off with it, he must walk to Tyburn, or else be carried thither; for it is only delivered to him to use, it is not a Delivery of Possession.</p>
               <p>There is another Case put by my Lord Hale, fol. 506, if an Apprentice embezzles his Master's Goods or Money, out of his Shop, it is there determined to be Felony; if I go abroad, and leave my Shop of Goods in the actual Possession of my Servant or Journeyman, to dispose of while I am gone, and he makes away with any Part of it, it is Felony; for not with standing his Possession, the legal Possession is in me; and there is a Rule in Law, which I will put the Gentlemen in Mind of, that tho' there may be a Sort of a mixed Possession, the Law always supposes the true Possession to be in him who is the Master, and he is judged to be really in Possession. And since they are praying Aid of this Act of Parliament which makes this Felony, which was not Felony before, and that as the Act does not make Use of any declaratory Words; they conclude, that Persons who committed such Facts before, were not Guilty of Felony - I do agree, that there are no Recitals of other Acts, and no retrospect Words, and therefore they conclude, this Act must only be designed as a Punishment for Facts committed, subsequent to the making of this Act; and the Gentlemen would insinuate, that this Man was in the entire Possession of these Bonds, and that by disposing of these Bonds he has made a Breach of that Trust which they had reposed in him: If, I say to a Person, Sir, take Care of these Bonds for me, till I come to Town, and he misapplies these Bonds, that is a Breach of Trust. Now the Act says, any Officer being entrusted, &amp;c. But this Man had not that Sort of Trust, and the Act would have been very improperly made, to have had declaratory Words in that Instance. It is very well known, we have a Number of Statutes, which are made to put an End to Differences which were quite unnecessary: And, I will put the Gentlemen in Mind of a Statute, which they hear of almost every Session at the Old Bailey, that is, the Statute of Stabbing; does any Body consider that as a New Law? And, I will submit it to your Lordship, whether there is any Doubt, but that that Act runs as this does. (Be it enacted.) There was one Thing more said, by the Gentlemen of the other Side, if this is a doubtful Case, if there are any Difficulties in Point of Law in relation to it, in Favour of Life, say the Gentlemen, we hope the Court will not hastily determine a Point of this Consequence.</p>
               <p>My Lord, I am very ready, where the Court has any reasonable Doubt, to refer any thing of this Nature; but I cannot see, how they can make a Special Verdict of it, for there must be Facts found by the Jury; and if the Jury say, he did take them with a felonious Intent, there cannot be a Special Verdict, if they say he did not take them with a felonious Intent, there is an End of the Case; I cannot see how it can be any otherwise, than by the Direction of the Court to the Jury. I am sure, in the Case of a Man's Life, I would not strain any Point of Law, and, I am sure, my Clients would not desire it; but when you come to consider the Case of the Butler as having the Plate, and the Case of the Shepherd as having the Sheep in their Custody only for Care: These Cases seem to be such Authorities, that we have Reason to expect, your Lordship's Direction to the Jury after summing up of the Evidence, that this is Felony in Point of Law.</p>
               <p>2d King's Counc. My Lord, I hope to be admitted to speak a few Words on the same Side; and as those four Gentlemen have so elaborately handled this Point, I would willingly make some Observations upon the Case; and I think, according to the Argument of those Gentlemen, the whole Question amounts to this, Whether as Mr Waite had those Bonds delivered to him, by the Court of Chancery, and did not come by them by any fraudulent Means, this can be any more than a Breach of Trust, and that to make this Felony will be going beyond what bath ever been known to be adjudged Felony, and they have stated several Cases to shew that this cannot be Felony; and now, my Lord, to turn to that which I think has been inconteleably proved, I submit it to your Lordship, Whether upon the whole Scope of the Evidence, the Case does not appear to be this and no otherwise, that these Bonds were legally, properly, and in Point of Fact in the Possession of the Bank, and that Mr Waite, though he was the Hand that received them. though he was the Hand that went to receive the Interest upon them, was still acting only under that Possession, in like Manner as every Person, who has the Care of Things, which are in the Possession of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230034"></xptr> another, may be said to act; that he gave Receipts for these it is true; But who was it for? why, for the Bank of England, and from these Receipts the Possession is fixed directly and absolutely in the Bank : The Law charges the Bank just the same as if they were actually kept in the Hands of the Directors of the Bank; and the Bank has in Fact, and it is nothing but what is founded upon the Principles of Equity and Justice, made good the Loss, which has arisen by this, to the Proprietors; therefore considering this in every Light, it cannot be taken any otherwise than that this is the Possession of the Bank. How is Mr Waite then to be considered ? Why merely as a Servant who only has the Care of them; and it was from this that he had an Opportunity of disposing of them; Then, my Lord, this being laid down, supposing I am right in that, the only Question that does arise upon on this is, Que animo, did this Man take these Bonds ? he took them, gave them to a Broker as his Bonds; he sells them for him, gave him the Money, and he put it into his Pocket, Quo animo, was this done? I shall allude to the Case, put by Sir 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person357">
                  John 
                  Strange 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person357" type="surname" value="Strange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Case of the Butler, which is Law; my Lord Hale, in his Pleas of the Crown, treats on this Question; I would not misrepresent the Words, I think they are these, '' He that hath the Care of another's Goods hath not the Possession of them, and therefore may, by his felonious embezzling of them be guilty of Felony; as the Buttler, that hath Charge of the Master's Plate; the Shepherd, that hath Charge of the Master's Sheep. 3 Hen. 7. 126. 21 H 7. 15. a. Co. Pl. C. p. 108.</p>
               <p>The like Law for him, that takes a Piece of Plate set before him to drink in a Tavern, &amp;c. for he hath only a Liberty to use, not a Possession by Delivery. 13 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person358">
                  E. 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person358" type="given" value="E."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person358" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            4.9.''</p>
               <p>And my Lord Hale, so great a Man, lays it down positively as referring to these Authorities: I would consider how this Case stands before your Lordship, with Respect to the Prisoner: If a Butler, by embezzling his Master's Plate, be guilty of Felony, (the Plate that he has the Charge of) how does Mr Waite stand? Had he any more than the Charge of these Bonds? If any one of the Bonds reach him, it is the same Thing as if the whole Number were proved upon him: Consider what his Possession was; it was only their being in his Hand to convey them to the proper Repository, and when they had Occasion to receive the Interest, or the like, he is the Hand to whom these are committed to do this, or that Act relating to them, and I do not apprehend that they are any otherwise under his Care than only for this particular Purpose. A Shepherd cannot be said to have the Superintendency of the Flock, but he has a Sort of a Care of it, and if he runs away with any Part of it he will be guilty of Felony. Where does this differ from the present Case, either in one Thing or the other? Dalton c. 155. It is likewise taken Notice of by my Lord Hale, with respect to an Apprentice, that if he embezzle his Master's Goods out of his Shop it is Felony: Why may it not be as well said, that an Apprentice, by having the Key of the Door belonging to the Shop, has Possession of the Goods to dispose of them as he shall think fit ? This is only a Trust reported in him for the Profit of his Master; Where is the Difference between this Case and the Case of Mr Waite ? My Lord, I beg Leave to mention another Case in my Lord Dyer, Fol. 5. That if a Master delivers to a Servant 20 s. in Silver to change into Gold; or Leather to make Shoes, and he runs away with the Gold or the Shoes, it is Felony. I will take this for Argument Sake, that Mr Waite had Possession by the Delivery; I do not take it as a Fact but only argumentatively; Suppose these Bonds were incontestably delivered to Mr Waite, and in the Possession of him, and he sells these Bonds and runs away with the Money, where is the Difference between this Case and the Case my Lord Dyer makes use of: Suppose a Servant has 20 s. in Silver deliver'd him, by the Hand of the Master for a particular Purpose, (so were these Bonds delivered to Mr Waite for a particular Purpose, not to sell or dispose of) and the Servant, instead of turning the 20 s. of Silver into Gold, and delivering it back to the Master, he runs away with the Gold; Where is the Difference between this Case and that of Mr Waite? I will take it for Argument-Sake, that he had this Possession for the Bank; but if he sells these, and puts the Money into his Pocket, it is Felony: Where is the Difference between this and the Leather made into Shoes? The Leather was delivered for that very End and no other: But if he runs away with the Shoes, he is guilty of Felony. They have been pleased to say, that it was with the Consent of the Bank that this Man had these Bonds; the Bank consented that he should have the Care and Management of them, to receive the Interest, and exchange them, as there should be Occasion; But was it the Consent of the Bank for him to sell them? For though he had in the first Instance acquired the Possession of them, and had them in his Power; yet if that is consined to a particular End and Purpose, and he goes beyond that, there is no Consent in the Bank for any other Purpose. The Gentlemen took<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174302230035"></xptr> Notice that I had some Allusion to this Case, when I said, that where a Person has Goods delivered him for a particular Purpose, as a Carrier or Waggoner, who has Goods delivered him to carry, and he breaks open the Bales, and takes out part of these Goods, (though the whole were delivered him by the Hand of the Owner) that is Felony. They took Notice, that in my opening, I did allude to this Fact, so I did, I do not deny it. Here were a great Number of Bonds delivered to this Man, he did not dispose of them all, but some of them. Consider what Difference the Law makes in this: If a Parcel of Goods is delivered to a Person, and he sells part of them, he is guilty of Felony. I do not apprehend, but that the Circumstances make a considerable Difference, and the Matter rests upon the Application, and it is reduceable to this, Quo animo, With what Mind did this Man do this? Whether he did it with a Design to put the Money into his own Pocket, and if he did, it is the same as if he had gone to the Coffers and took out the Money, and put it into his Pocket. And then they refer to another Act of Parliament, made very lately, and say, that is a very plain Parliamentary Declaration, that no Servant of the Bank, before that Act of Parliament, could be guilty of Felony for stealing Notes or Bonds, &amp;c. and that if it was Felony before, there would have been no Occasion for this Act of Parliament. By a Statute of the 1st of Queen Anne, it is enacted, that whoever steals Goods or Chattels to the Value of forty Shillings, in any Dwelling-House, is guilty of Felony without Benefit of Clergy; before this Law, it was (as I think may farm it ) a Clergy Felony; but this Act which they mention, 15 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person359">
                  George 
                  II 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person359" type="surname" value="II"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person359" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , makes the stealing Bonds, Orders, &amp;c. Felony, whether in a Dwelling-House House or not. It makes Choses in Action stand upon the same Footing as Money or Goods did by other Acts; and though there was a Provision made against this before, yet it was such a Provision, that if any Person of the Bank stole any Bonds, &amp;c. and it was not in a Dwelling-House, he and the Benefit of the Clergy. However if this can be put in such a Manner as to be serviceable to the Prisoner, God forbid I should be against it. It has sometimes happened, that upon an insufficient Finding, the Prisoner has got off Scot-free, because the Court could give no Judgment upon it. My Lord, all that is to go before the Jury is Quo animo, did this Man take these Bonds, whether it was with a felonious Intent, or was it a Breach of Trust. The Law makes this Distinction, whether it was a Breach of Trust, or a felonious Taking. The Court cannot determine this, it is a Fact, and this lies before me Jury. I only mention this that we may not go into any Mistake, so far as that this Man shall not have Justice done him, either to acquit him or to convict him. I am not for having him convicted, if the Law does not convict him; God forbid I should desire this if the Law deems him innocent.</p>
               <p>Court. (to Mr Collyer ) Is there Security given to the Bank? Collyer. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Is it for any accidental Occurence, or Misfortune, that may happen; or is it for Fidelity?</p>
               <p>Collyer. It is in general for Fidelity.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Counc. It is a general Security.</p>
               <p>The Court was of Opinion, that it was not Felony, before the late Act of Parliament, 15 
               <persName id="t17430223-26-person360">
                  George 
                  II 
               <interp inst="t17430223-26-person360" type="surname" value="II"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person360" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but offered a Special Verdict, if the King's Council desired it: They expressed themselves satisfied with the Opinion of the Court, whereupon the Jury were directed to find the Prisoner <rs id="t17430223-26-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430223-26-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               not guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[The Court was moved for leave to charge the Prisoner with a Civil Action, which was granted, and he was accordingly charged, at the Suit of the Bank, with a Debt of 13300 l.]</p>
            </div1>
