<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411014-24">
               <interp inst="t17411014-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-24" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411014-24" type="date" value="17411014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411014-24-off128-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-defend203 t17411014-24-off128 t17411014-24-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140013"></xptr>29. 
               
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-defend203" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Woolford 
                  <interp inst="t17411014-24-defend203" type="surname" value="Woolford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-defend203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-defend203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17411014-24-crimeloc127">St. Bride's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-24-crimeloc127" type="placeName" value="St. Bride's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411014-24-crimeloc127" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-off128 t17411014-24-crimeloc127"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17411014-24-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for that he, not having God before his eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17411014-24-cd129" type="crimeDate">2 d of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-off128 t17411014-24-cd129"></join>, on 
                     <persName id="t17411014-24-victim204" type="victimName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17411014-24-person205" type="victimName">
                              John 
                              Piper 
                           <interp inst="t17411014-24-person205" type="surname" value="Piper"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17411014-24-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17411014-24-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-off128 t17411014-24-person205"></join>
                        </persName>
                        , alias <rs id="t17411014-24-alias-3" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-victim204 t17411014-24-alias-3"></join>Haddock</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-24-victim204" type="surname" value="Piper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-24-victim204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411014-24-victim204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-off128 t17411014-24-victim204"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , feloniously, wilfully . and of his malice aforethought, did make an assault, and with a certain knife , on the pit of the stomach of him the said Piper, feloniously, &amp;c. did strike and thrust, giving him a mortal wound, of which he instantly died .
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>He was a second time charged by virtue of the coroners inquest for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person206">
                  Sarah 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person206" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person206" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 2d of Sept. I was at breakfast at my shop in the Fleet-market, and saw the prisoner and the deceased run by my window. Hearing the prisoner say, D - n you, you son of a B - I will have my ends of you. I ran from my breakfast, and saw the prisoner hold his knife in his hand, on this side of him . I ran directly out of my shop, and I saw the prisoner take the knife from the side of his clothes, and stab it into the deceased, just into his heart.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a knife was it?</p>
               <p>Austin . It was a small bladed knife with a point to it; - this is the knife: it is a sort of a case knife ground down , sharp on each side, and a point to it. The prisoner gave the blow with great force , and took the knife out again himself. I believe, as near as I can guess, it went in about an inch and an half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased bleed much?</p>
               <p>Austin . He bled the space of three minutes after he was stabb'd, and died immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner seem to intend this?</p>
               <p>Austin . Yes, to be sure, because he did it wilfully and with good force. I never saw the prisoner or the deceased before this happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person207">
                  Mary 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person207" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person207" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All that I can say about it is, that on the 2d of Sept. I was coming from my mistress's door, and saw the deceased running after the prisoner; - it was just by the Wheatsheas in the Fleet-market. The deceased said, You rogue, why do you cut me? I did not hear the prisoner make any answer, but the deceased had a stick in his hand, and offered to strike at the prisoner with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before the stab, or afterwards?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. After the deceased had said, You rogue, why do you cut me? he up with his hand directly, and before he could give a blow, the prisoner stabb'd him. I know nothing either of the prisoner or the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether the deceased was cut when he said, why do you cut me?</p>
               <p>Wheeler . I did not see that he was cut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person208">
                  Thomas 
                  Round 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person208" type="surname" value="Round"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person208" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was sitting at my stall in the Fleet-market, and hearing a noise , I rose up and went to the stone arch, and saw the prisoner with its knife in his hand. I looked at the deceased, and observed that his hand was all bloody. I spoke to the prisoner and said, you rogue, what do you do with that knife? you have cut the man's hand! Immediately I turned my eye to the deceased, and saw him leaning forward with the wound in his breast, and an effusion of blood coming from him, as much as if a sheep or a lamb had been killed . I then turned to the prisoner , and said, you rogue , you villain, you have killed the man! Upon that, he drew back to a coffin maker's shop, and I came up to him, and bid him lay down his knife. Another person coming up, took hold of him, and he shoved the knife behind him and dropped it down the coffin maker's cellar , from whence it was taken and delivered to the church-warden.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner behave when you took hold of him?</p>
               <p>Round . All he had to say was, why did he strike me? - I had no other answer from him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person209">
                  Francis 
                  Betterson 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person209" type="surname" value="Betterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person209" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Hearing a noise at the back part of our shop, I went to see what was the matter, and saw the prisoner go on a pretty bandsomish pace, and the deceased followed him with a stick in his hand. I ran after them, and when I got half way down the market, the deceased struck the prisoner with his stick. There ensued a sort of a skirmish between them, and just as I came up, the prisoner stabb'd him with a knife into the pit of the stomach . He bled pretty much on the ground, and died in a quarter of an hour, without speaking, as I heard.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the deceased was pursuing the prisoner!</p>
               <p>Betterson . Yes, and the boys cried, Now Jack! Now Jack! and that aggravated him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the deceased struck the prisoner was the stab given?</p>
               <p>Betterson . The deceased's hand was up a second time, to strike the prisoner, as I thought, and then the stab was given. I never saw the prisoner before that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person210">
                  Henry 
                  Snagdon 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person210" type="surname" value="Snagdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person210" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was at breakfast on the 2d of Sept. and a message was brought to me that a man was killed in the Fleet-market. I went down, and saw the deceased lying on his back, and I did not perceive any life in him. His name was 
               <persName id="t17411014-24-person211">
                  John 
                  Haddock 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person211" type="surname" value="Haddock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Round. He used to go by the name of Piper, but his true name was Haddock.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person212">
                  Simon 
                  Snowd 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person212" type="surname" value="Snowd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person212" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Surgeon. On the 3d of the month aforesaid, I was sent for to open the body of the deceased on the coroner's inquest. I found in the sternum a small wound, which penetrated into the breast. I found it necessary to open it, and when I had opened the breast, I found the cavity of the belly filled with blood; and on examination of what we call the viscera, I found a wound in the heart of about an inch and an half, and it was impossible he should live above two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174110140014"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17411014-24-person213">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17411014-24-person213" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person213" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner lie on his back, just against the Fleet-prison for about a minute: he turned himself short round, and got up, and pulled a knife out of his pocket. It seemed to have a paper upon it, and when he had untied it, he looked towards Fleet-street, and seeing no body there, he clapp'd himself against a bulk, and rested himself in this manner. He held his knife by the side of his clothes, and the deceased came down with a design to take the knife from him. Accordingly he took the prisoner by the elbow, but missing his hold, the prisoner turned round, and cut him on the finger, and he bled violently. This was about three quarters after 8 in the morning, and in about 5 minutes I heard that the man was murder'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He struck me first, and I did it in my own defence. <rs id="t17411014-24-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-verdict130" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17411014-24-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411014-24-punish131" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411014-24-defend203 t17411014-24-punish131"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
