<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400116-46">
               <interp inst="t17400116-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-46" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400116-46" type="date" value="17400116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-46-off216-c253" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-defend357 t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-verdict220"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400116-46-off216-c254" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-defend359 t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-verdict220"></join>
         
               <p>133, 134. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-defend357" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Snowd 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend357" type="surname" value="Snowd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend357" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-defend359" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Wells 
                  <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend359" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend359" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-defend359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17400116-46-off216" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-off216" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-off216" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400116-46-victim361" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Hull 
                        <interp inst="t17400116-46-victim361" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-46-victim361" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400116-46-victim361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-victim361"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400116-46-crimeloc217">Heston</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-crimeloc217" type="placeName" value="Heston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-crimeloc217" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-crimeloc217"></join>, putting him in Fear, &amp;c. and taking from him 7s. in Money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-46-cd218" type="crimeDate">December 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-cd218"></join>.</p>
               <p>The Witnesses at the Prisoners Request were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hull. On the 19th of December, I was coming over <placeName id="t17400116-46-crimeloc219">Hounslow-Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-46-crimeloc219" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400116-46-crimeloc219" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-off216 t17400116-46-crimeloc219"></join>, in the Hillendon Stage-Coach, between 2 and 3 in the Afternoon, and 2 Men came up to the Coach and robbed us. They asked us for our Money, and took 7 Shillings from me. The Henley Stage-Coach was robbed just before us, but what they took from thence I can't tell. I can't swear to the Prisoners, because they had Paper-Masks on their Faces; but 2 Gentlemen's Servants being hunting on the Heath, I sent them after the Men who had robbed us, and the 2 Prisoners were taken, and they say, they are the same Men.</p>
               <p>Snowd. What Sort of Cloaths had the Men on who robbed you?</p>
               <p>Hull. One had a white Coat on, and the other a brown one. Snowd (I take it) was in the white Coat, and Wells in the brown. I kept them in Sight about 10 Minutes, and sent these Men after them; but I did not keep them in View till they were taken; most part of the Time I did, and saw that one of them was on a brown Horse, and the other on a grey Gelding. There were other Coaches behind us, 4 (I believe) in all, and I saw them go to them. The Reading and Henley Coaches were robbed at the same Time. - This is the first Time I have seen the Prisoners since the Robbery was committed, for after we were robbed, we went on, in the Coach; therefore I can't swear to them; and that's all I have to say.</p>
               <p>Snowd. Then I presume he knows neither of us, but by Hearsay. He knows not which is Snowd, nor which is Wells. In the next Place<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160030"></xptr> he says, he saw us rob the first Coach. I would ask him if there were any others in the Coach with him, when he was robbed?</p>
               <p>Hull. Yes, 2 Gentlemen, and 2 Gentlewomen. They did not rob the 2 Women, but they robbed the other 2 Men.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Were the Men who robbed you, in Sight, when the Gentleman's Servants came up to you?</p>
               <p>Hull. Yes; they were then both in Sight, and I told them I had been robbed by those two Men.</p>
               <p>Snowd. Did you see the Huntsman when you was in the Coach?</p>
               <p>Hull. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. What Part of the Coach did you fit in?</p>
               <p>Hull. I sat on the Left-Hand Side; with my Back to the Horses: I was coming to Town, and there was one Coach before us, and another behind. I did not see them rob the first Coach, but I put myself out of the Coach, and saw them rob the other Coaches.</p>
               <p>Snowd. And were the 2 Persons, who robbed the other Coaches, pursued immediately?</p>
               <p>Hull. Yes, they were pursued directly. I only speak to the Gentleman's Servant who rode away for Arms, and then he pursued them directly: He was not gone above 10 Minutes for Arms.</p>
               <p>Wells. But in those 10 Minutes, did not you lose Sight of the Men?</p>
               <p>Hull. Yes, a little; but not much.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. Did you describe the 2 Men to the Gentleman's Servants?</p>
               <p>Hull. They were in Sight of them, and saw 'em themselves.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person362">
                  John 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person362" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person362" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday, December 19. I was going to my Master Bulstrode's, (I am his Servant) over Hounslow-Heath, - He lives at Hounslow, - and as I was going to his House, I saw 2 Men ride by me into Colibrook Road, and to a Place called Butcher's Grove. The one was on a grey horse, the other on a brown.</p>
               <p>Snowd. What Distance were the 2 Men from you, when you saw this?</p>
               <p>Harding. About 200 Yards from me, when I saw them first: after which they went into the Road, and stopped a Coach; I can't tell whether it was the Bath, Bristol, or the Reading Coach; but I knew the Man who drove it, his Name is 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person363">
                  William 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person363" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person363" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The second Coach they stopped, was the Heuley Coach. They stopped one Coach first, then they went to the second, which was the Henley Stage Coach, and stopped that. After this, they rode away from the Coaches, some Distance out of the Road, and went forwards. I went on likewise; but the Passengers in the Coaches halloo'd to me, and beckon'd to me, to come to them. When I came up, 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person364">
                  Robert 
                  Hull 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person364" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person364" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             looked out of the Henley Coach, and said he had been robb'd of his Money, by two Men, and desired me to pursue them, and take them. I said, It signifies nothing to pursue Men, and have no Arms; but they told me, if I would ride away, and get Arms, they would stand still, and tell me when I came back which Way the Men went. While I was talking to them, I saw the 2 Men ride up to a third Coach, and stop it. Upon this I rode to my Master's House, (which was then within Sight) and a Servant being in the Yard, I desired him to bring me a Gun, which hung up loaded over the Kitchen-Chimney. The Man brought me the Gun, and took my Master's Mare, and a Blunderbufs, and came along with me. He was the first Man who came up with the Coaches, for I did not stop; I had so much Sight of the 2 Men when they did the Fact, that I thought I should know them and their Horses, when I saw them again. But the People in the Coach told my Fellow-Servant, they were gone round a Hedge call'd the Bavers, and that they were about a Quarter of a Mile before. There were at this Time four Stage-Coaches, and one of Mr Paris's together, but I went on, without asking any Questions, because I had seen the Men, and I knew the Horses so well, that I could be positive to them, (if I should see them again) without any Direction. So I rode round the Bavers, and a Shepherd told me, the Men were just gone before me. He thought (I suppose) they had done some Mischief by seeing us ride hard with Guns. When I was got out upon the Heath, beyond the Bavers, I found I was beyond the Prisoners, therefore I turn'd back again, and met some Servants of my Lord Berkeley's, who told me the Men were gone down a Nine-pin Alley, and over the Stile. When I came to the Stile, I could perceive the Track of their Horses over the Stile, into Harlendon Field; so I rode along the Outside of the Field, which joins to my Lord Berkeley's Park, and came to the Park, where there is a Pannel in the Pales, which may be listed up; but that being lock'd, and the Gate likewise, the Prisoners were obliged to take the Foot-path to Harlendon, and go over a Stile, by Mr Bright's Dog-kennel. When we came to Harlendon, we enquired if any Body had seen 2 Men ride that Way, one on a grey, the other on a brown Horse? and at Dawley Lodge a Man told us, they were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160031"></xptr> just before us, and were at Dawley Park, belonging to the 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person365">
                  Lord 
                  Bolingbroke 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person365" type="surname" value="Bolingbroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person365" type="given" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : So we pursued them down the Lane, and were told by a Man, who was driving a Farmer's Cart, that they were just before us. We went on till we came to Hillendon; and at a Smith's Shop, we saw the 2 Prisoners stand at the Heads of their Horses, to have a Shoe put on, and Cloths were thrown over the Horses Backs. I got up first, and knowing the Men and Horses, I turned from the Shop into a hollow Way, 'till my Companion came up. Then we got off our Horses, and while we were dismounting, the Prisoners whipp'd out at the Smith's Back-door: I cry'd out, - '' Gentlemen, if you offer to go '' away, I'll shoot you: - You have robb'd '' such and such Coaches.'' Upon this they turn'd back, and came through the Smith's Shop again, and would have got into the Smith's House, but we went up to them with our Gun and Blunderbuss, and told them, If they did not surrender, or if they offer'd to shoot, we would let fly at them. Wells immediately surrender'd to my Fellow-Servant; but Snowd ran away, and got through a little Wicket, into a Garden: But as he was getting over the Garden-Pales, into a Field, I up with my long Gun, and said I would shoot him as he ran. He turn'd and begg'd I would not shoot him, and so he surrender'd. After which we had them both into the House, and carry'd them into the Kitchen, where great Numbers of People (near Fourscore) came into see them; so we had them into a private Room while their Horses were shod; and my Horse had likewife thrown off 2 Shoes in the Pursuit. While we were in this Room, I gave them the Liberty to go before what Magistrate they pleased: They chose to go before my Master ('Squire Bulstrode) at Hounslow, and Snowd said, he with'd he had thrown away his Pistol; for I had taken it from him. This is the Pistol, and this is the Ball that was in it; it was charged with Powder and Ball. My Fellow-Servant took a Pistol from Wells, and discharg'd it against a Brick-Wall, and the Impression the Ball made remains there now, if nobody has destroy'd it. As they chose to go before my Master, we put them on their own Horses, and carry'd them thither, and in my Master's Yard we charged a Constable with them, and they were examin'd by my Master; but as to any Confession they made, I know nothing of it. While we had them in the private Room, one of them said, in the Hearing of the other, - '' He wish'd we had shot them, for he was sure '' they should be hang'd.'' But I don't remember which of them it was said this, nor what Reply the other made to it. They both cry'd very much.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. From the Observation you made, can you take on you to swear we are the Men who robbed the Henley Coach?</p>
               <p>Harding. 'Tis hard swearing to their Faces, but I can swear to the Horses, and the Cloaths the Men had on. The Persons we took had the same Cloaths on, which the Men had who robbed the Coach: and I am positive to the Horses.</p>
               <p>Prisoners. At 200 Yards distance, can you take on you to swear to Horses, and Cloaths?</p>
               <p>Harding. Yes: for they did not ride fast, they walked their Horses, when they first went before me. And at the same Time when the third Coach was robbed, I was a great deal nearer them.</p>
               <p>Wills. Did not I live in the Neighbourhood, and did not you know it was me, when I rode by you?</p>
               <p>Harding. I believe he did live in the Neighbourhood; but I can't say, I knew it to be him, at that Time. These are the Cloaths they had on when they were taken. This is the Coat that Wells wore, and by the same Token here's the same Handkerchief in the Pocket, which I lent him at the Smith's House, to wipe his Eyes. This is the Coat which was upon Snowd.</p>
               <p>Hull. These are the same Cloaths the Men had on, who robbed me.</p>
               <p>Harding. I can't say the Men were in sight when I came up the second Time to the Coaches. I can't tell whether they were or not. The People said, - there go the Men, and they turned round an Elbow of a Hedge. I never stopped to ask the People in the Coach any Questions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person366">
                  Richard 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person366" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person366" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of December, John Harding came home to Mr Bulstrode's, and told me two Men were robbing the Coaches upon the Heath. He said, he had seen them rob two, and they were stopping another when he came away; so he desired me to get him a Gun, for they were but badly mounted, and he believed he could take them. A Servant in the Yard ran in, and brought him a Gun, and me a Blunderbuss, and we went on directly about one fourth of a Mile on the Heath to the Coaches which had been robbed, and which stood still waiting for us. The People (in the Coaches) called out to us, and said, - There are the Men, and they are going round the Bavers. The Coachman upon the Box could see them, but I could not, because of the Bushes upon the Heath. We followed them round the Bavers, and before we had gone a quarter of a Mile round the Hedge, a Man who was picking Turneps told us, the Men<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160032"></xptr> were just gone before us. So we went on into Colebrook-Road, and some Drovers informed us, they had just then met them. Presently after this we met a Grasier, who was going after his Cattle, and he told us he met the Men, in the Water at Cranford-Bridge, and that we might overtake them before they got on the next Heath. But when we got upon the Heath we saw a Stage Coach, and the Coachman telling us he had not seen any such Persons in that Road, Harding was about to take one Way, and I another, to see if they had not taken to the Grounds, but meeting with my Lord Berkeley's Servants, they directed us after them, over a Nine Pin Ground, to a Foot-path, which goes to my Lord Berkeley's House. When we came to the common Field, we tracked them along the Path, but could not see them. A Woman being in the Field, we enquired of her, if she had not seen two such Men? She told us yes, and that they had been trying to get into my Lord's Park, but could not, so they were gone over the Field toward Harlendon. I followed them according to the Woman's Directions down the Field, and found the Gate fastened, and that they had jumped their Horses over a Stile. I jumped my Mare over, and as soon as I came to Harlendon, a Man told me, they were just gone before me. I rode on to Cranford Lane, and thence to Lord Bolingbroke's Lane; and at the Sign of the Woolpack in the Lane, Harding enquired after them again. The Man of the House said, he had not seen any such Persons, but another Man, who was looking out of a Window in the House, told us, he saw them go by about a quarter of an Hour before. Upon this we rode up the Lane as fast as we could, and in the middle of the Lane, a Man who was driving a Cart, told us, he had met them at the Top of the Lane: and before we got out of the Lane, another Man informed us he met them going upon Hillendon Heath. When we got out of the Lane upon the Common, Harding took the Uxbridge Road and I the London Road, but meeting a Coach with Attendants who told me there were no such Persons in that Road, I turned and rode for Hillendon; and by the Gravel-pits I was told the Men were just before me; so I went on, and at Hillendon, at a Smith's Shop, I saw the two Prisoners standing at their Horses Heads: Upon which I rode up to an open Place, and jumped off my Mare, and the two Prisoners ran away to a Gate that goes to an Orchard, but I cocked my Gun, and said, if they would not surrender, I would shoot them. Wells turned round and begged I would not shoot him, and he surrendered; but Snowd ran thro' the Gateway. After Wells had told me, he would surrender, while he was coming toward me, he put his Hand into his Pocket; I thought he might be feeling for a Pistol, so I told him, if he pulled out any Arms, I would shoot him; and he drawing nearer, with his Hand still in his Pocket, I clapped hold of his Wrist, and having pulled his Hand out, I felt in the Pocket myself, and there I found this Pistol; upon which I turned my Hand behind me, and discharged it against the Wall. This Paper of Gunpowder, I found in his other Pocket. I can't tell what the Pistol was charged with, but the People of the House said, I had beat a Piece of Brick out of the Wall. When Harding had took Snowd, we carried them both into the Kitchen, but such Numbers of People came in, that they desired they might be taken into a private Room, for they said, they were known there, and were not willing all the Country should see them. I think it was Snowd said this; he told us likewise that he went to School at Uxbridge. In the private Room, they both cried very much, and Snowd asked Wells for his Handkerchief, to wipe his Eyes, but Wells was using it himself, so Harding lent him one, and 'twas in the Coat Pocket now. Snowd wept, and and said, in the hearing of Wells, that he knew he must die. Wells answered, he did not value dying, for he had rather die, than live and starve, but for the Disgrace. We told them, we hoped they would not die; for as they were young Men, and this their first Fact, they might get off, and must not do so any more. They both said, they wished they had thrown their Pistols away. I have seen the Cloaths which have been produced in Court, and I am sure Snowd wore the white Coat, and Wells the brown.</p>
               <p>Snowd. I ask him whether he's sure it was I, who said, I am sure we shall die?</p>
               <p>Ball. Yes: he said so when he asked Wells to lend him his Handkerchief. I had some little Knowledge of Wells before, but not any Acquaintance with him; I never knew any Thing ill of him, before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person367">
                  William 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person367" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person367" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I pursued them, for the Good of my King and Country, as well as Harding and Ball, and went after the Prisoners, when the 2 Witnesses went first on the Pursuit; but I was upon a Coach-Horse, so I could not follow them over Ditch, and over Hedge, as they did; therefore I quitted my Horse at Cranford-Bridge, and followed them to the Place where they were taken. I did not see them before they were taken, but I followed them by the People's Directions, and heard Snowd say, 'tis a very unfortunate Thing, that we are<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174001160033"></xptr> taken, and I with we had thrown away our Pistols. Yes, said Wells, so it is; and I wish we had. This was at the Blacksmith's Arms, a Smith's Shop at Hillendon.</p>
               <p>Snowd. I absolutely deny I was on the Heath that Day: and that's the first thing I have to say. In the next Place, I humbly presume none of them have sworn that we are the very Men who robbed the Coaches, and that they have spoken but circumstantially. There were no Masks found on us, and I absolutely deny the Fact. As to Harding's swearing I went over a Stile, - I had been very ill; and had not had a Stool for 5 Days before, and having taken something to open my Body, I went out of the Way to ease myself in a Hog-sty. Then as to the circumstance of the Pistols, I never rode without them. I had a 20 l. Bank Bill, and 3 l. in Money about me, and was then going to sup at Mr Sergeant's, at Uxbridge: and the Pistol Wells had, was a Pistol which has belonged to his Family several Years: and very good People travel the country with Pistols. And I might say I wished I had thrown my Pistol away, because of the Scandal; for to be sure it would put an innocent Man into an Agony, to have such a charge upon him. But then there is a great Variation in the Evidence: for Hull swears that 2 Men came up to the Coach, and that he sent 2 Men to pursue them directly. Ball was at Home; and Hull swears they were both there. Harding went Home to Mr. Bulstrode's for Arms, and brought Ball with him; how then could they pursue us directly.</p>
               <p>Harding. I was in Sight of my Master's House when the People in the coach told me they were robbed, and they stood still till Ball and I came back from thence.</p>
               <p>Snowd. As to the white Coat, there are very few People who do not wear white Dussel Coats.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person368">
                  Peter 
                  Hardcastle 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person368" type="surname" value="Hardcastle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person368" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Day before the Prisoners were apprehended, Wells hired a Horse of me to go to Rumford. He hired it on the Tuesday, and on the Wednesday Morning he had it, which was the Day he was taken. I had seen him once before that Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person369">
                  Benjamin 
                  Dove 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person369" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person369" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Wells hired 2 Horses to go to Rumford, but I can't tell the particular Day. One was a brown bay Horse, with a bald Face, which he hired of Mr Hardcastle. I heard of the Robbery, but I can't swear it was on that Day. He had a brown coat on at that Time, but I can't swear this is the same.</p>
               <p>Hardcastle. Wells was in a brown Coat when he hired my Horse, but I can't swear this is the same.</p>
               <p>Snowd. Wells hired the Horses to go to Rumford, and desired me to take a ride with him; but I desired him to ride another Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person370">
                  Edward 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person370" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person370" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person371">
                  William 
                  Wingfield 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person371" type="surname" value="Wingfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person371" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person372">
                  William 
                  Deane 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person372" type="surname" value="Deane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person372" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person373">
                  William 
                  Passingham 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person373" type="surname" value="Passingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person373" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person374">
                  Benjamin 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person374" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person374" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , John Darvson, 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person375">
                  David 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person375" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person375" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person376">
                  Lancelot 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person376" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person376" type="given" value="Lancelot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person377">
                  Henry 
                  Pemberton 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person377" type="surname" value="Pemberton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person377" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person378">
                  Robert 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person378" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person378" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person379">
                  John 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person379" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person380">
                  Richard 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person380" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person380" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spoke to Well's Character. Many of them had known him from a Child, and said he had been well educated; that he was a well behaved Man, and had served part of his Time with Mr Roberts, an Apothecary, and they did not believe he would be guilty of such a Crime.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400116-46-person381">
                  Cornelius 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person381" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person381" type="given" value="Cornelius"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person382">
                  Thomas 
                  Thompkins 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person382" type="surname" value="Thompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person382" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person383">
                  John 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person383" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person384">
                  James 
                  Base 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person384" type="surname" value="Base"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person384" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person385">
                  Thomas 
                  Dent 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person385" type="surname" value="Dent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person385" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person386">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Rayner 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person386" type="surname" value="Rayner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person386" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person386" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person387">
                  Peter 
                  Stanton 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person387" type="surname" value="Stanton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person387" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17400116-46-person388">
                  Whiston 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17400116-46-person388" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person388" type="given" value="Whiston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had known Snowd a different Number of Years; they said he was brought up as a Surgeon by his Father, and they never heard of his having behaved ill. Some of the Witnesses having entrusted him, they found him honest, and said they should be under no Apprchen sion of being wrong'd, tho' they should trust him again. Both <rs id="t17400116-46-verdict220" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-verdict220" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17400116-46-punish221" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400116-46-punish221" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-defend357 t17400116-46-punish221"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400116-46-defend359 t17400116-46-punish221"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
