<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410116-15">
               <interp inst="t17410116-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-15" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410116-15" type="date" value="17410116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410116-15-off70-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend115 t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-verdict76"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410116-15-off70-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend117 t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-verdict76"></join>
         
               <p>15, 16. * 
               
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Young , alias <rs id="t17410116-15-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend115 t17410116-15-alias-2"></join>Jenny Diver</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend115" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend115" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Davis  , alias <rs id="t17410116-15-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend117 t17410116-15-alias-3"></join>Catherine the <rs id="t17410116-15-deflabel69" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend117 t17410116-15-deflabel69"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17410116-15-person118">
                              Henry 
                              Huggins 
                           <interp inst="t17410116-15-person118" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17410116-15-person118" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17410116-15-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend117" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend117" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-defend117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , were indicted for <rs id="t17410116-15-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410116-15-victim120" type="victimName">
                           Judith 
                           Gardner 
                        <interp inst="t17410116-15-victim120" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-15-victim120" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410116-15-victim120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-victim120"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting her in Fear, and taking from her 12 s. in Money , the Money of the said Judith
            </rs>, in the Parish of <placeName id="t17410116-15-crimeloc71">St. Mary Woolchurch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc71" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Woolchurch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc71" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-crimeloc71"></join> , <rs id="t17410116-15-cd72" type="crimeDate">Jan. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-cd72"></join>.</p>
               <p>* Jenny Diver, was sentenc'd for Transportation, by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17410116-15-person121">
                  Jane 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person121" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person121" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in April Sessions, 1758. See her Tryal, No. 4, 2. 74.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person122">
                  Judith 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person122" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person122" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday Night, between 6 and 7 o'Clock, I was coming out of <placeName id="t17410116-15-crimeloc73">Sherbourne-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc73" type="placeName" value="Sherbourne-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc73" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-crimeloc73"></join> , and had 13 s. and an Half-penny in my Pocket; the last House I came from was the Black-Bull Alehouse. There were some Boards laid over a wet Place at the Corner of the <placeName id="t17410116-15-crimeloc74">Mansion House</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc74" type="placeName" value="Mansion House"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410116-15-crimeloc74" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-off70 t17410116-15-crimeloc74"></join>, and a Man laid hold of my Arm, and said he would help me over the Boards; I said if I wanted any Assistance, I could give the Man a Half-penny; notwithstanding that, he held my Arm up a great<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174101160007"></xptr> Height, so that he numm'd my Fingers that I had no use of them. While he was doing this the Prisoner Young came before me, and immediately I felt her Hand in my Pocket; upon that I put my Hand into my Pocket and seized her by the Wrist; - her Hand was clench'd in the Bottom of my Pocket; upon my doing this, she with her other Hand struck me a great Blow on the side of the Face, so that I was obliged to quit her Hand which was in my Pocket, else I should not have left my Money. I then took fast hold of her Cloak and never left her 'till I got Assistance to take her from me. The Man immediately quitted me, and ran away; I cry'd out, For God's Sake stop that Man, for he has held me, while the Woman has robbed me: A Coal-Heaver happening to come by, laid hold of him by the Collar, and that other Woman Davis went up to the Man and help'd to get him away, she said she knew him for he was a very good House-keeper and lived the other Side of Moorfields; - she did not molest me but endeavoured to get the Man away from my Friend, and on his escaping she was secured. I am positive the Prisoner Young is the Person whose Hand I took in my Pocket, for it was just under the first Lamp by the Mansion House as you go from hence. When she pull'd her Hand out of my Pocket it was clenched, and I lost out of the 13 s. and Half-penny, two half Crowns and 7 s. - I am sure I had it in my Pocket when the Prisoner came up to me. I can't say how near Davis was to me, but she help'd to pull the Man from the Coal-Heaver, and Young dragg'd me 'till she came up to them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you see any Money in either of our Hands?</p>
               <p>Gardner. No, but Young had her Hand clenched in my Pocket , and I said, Hussey you have got my Money, upon which she struck me such a Blow, that I was obliged to quit her Hand; I should not have lost my Money if I could have kept her Hand.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner Young offer'd me, at the Butcher's Shop in Bearbinder-Lane , a Guinea and a gold Ring, if I would put up with this and let her go; she offer'd to leave it with Mrs. Jefferies the Mistress of the Shop. I had her near an Hour in Custody before I could get an Officer. - The other Woman Davis on the Man's escaping was secured by the Coal Heaver. I found Young's Hand in my Pocket, but she gave me the Blow before she left my Pocket .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was you in Fear?</p>
               <p>Gardner. Yes, to be sure I was, I was in Danger of my Life; the Man kept me close up to the Boards, and the Woman came before me immediately.</p>
               <p>Young . How long was it between your losing your Money, and your laying hold of me?</p>
               <p>Gardner . I never left her 'till Mr. Day the Green-Grocer came to my Assistance.</p>
               <p>Young . Where did you lay hold of me?</p>
               <p>Gardner. Just at the Corner of Walbrook; - I had not set my Foot on the Planks , but I was as near to them as could be.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person123">
                  Davis 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person123" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person123" type="given" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             far from Stocks-Market was it that you laid hold of me?</p>
               <p>Gardner. I never laid hold of you, but I saw you pull the Man away. Mr. Day laid hold of the Woman in the red Cloak (Young) and the Mob help'd to bring the other into Bearbinder-Lane.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was you in any Fear when your Money was taken away?</p>
               <p>Gardner. Yes; I was afraid I should get a Mischief by them, I was afraid of my Life. I had her Hand in my Pocket some Time after the Man left me, and the moment I cry'd out, he ran away. It was my right Arm which the Man held, and my Pocket I commonly wear under my Gown on the right Side, so I clapp'd my left Hand which was at Liberty, under my Apron, into my Pocket in this Manner [Here the Witness shewed the Manner in which she seiz'd Young's Hand in her Pocket] and seized her Hand clench'd in the Bottom of my Pocket. The Man when he took hold of me, said, I will help you over Child, for if you should slip into the Water, you will be worse off: immediately Young's Hand was in my Pocket, and I said, this Woman has got all that I have in the World. I quitted her Hand in my Pocket to get hold of her Cloak, and to prevent her doing me further mischief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person124">
                  Samuel 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person124" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person124" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Last Saturday Night, I was going to see my Sister and her Child Home, and just as we came to the Mansion House, the poor Woman cry'd out, Lord, I am ruin'd! I am ruin'd! I left my Sister, and laid hold of the Man, and this Woman said, this Man has ruin'd me: I held him about a Minute and a half, and these two Women (the Prisoners) came to me, and got hold of me: - Those are the Women at the Bar, I will take my Affidavit of it, they were both upon me at once, and if it had not been for them, I should have held him. I saw them both near the Prosecutrix, before she cried out.</p>
               <p>Davis. How far was it from the Place where the Man got away, to the Place that he laid hold of me?</p>
               <p>How. While the Man and I were struggling, and they were upon me, away run the Man; I pursued him, and they ran after me, and then I laid hold of that Woman in the white Cloak (Davis) but she had a red Cloak on then; - I would not tell a Lie if I knew it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Day. I was sitting in my back Room, and a great many People were running by to Bearbinder-Lane, and just against the Butcher's Shop, this Man had hold of the Woman with the white Cloak (Davis.) The Prosecutrix said that Woman (Young) had pick'd her Pocket of 12 Shillings, she had not a Hat on then, but one under her Cloak I was resolv'd to see the Upshot of this, so I held her, and desired Mr. Jefferies to get an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174101160008"></xptr> Officer, but he could not; however, at last I got one who took the Prisoners into Custody.</p>
               <p>Young . Was the Man at the Butcher's Shop by?</p>
               <p>Day . Yes; the Woman said, that is the Woman that pick'd my Pocket, and I said I would not let you go 'till it was set to Rights; - You took a Black Hat out of your Cloak, and put it on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person125">
                  Mary 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person125" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person125" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . My Brother was going Home with me and my Child, and just at the End of the Pales at Stocks-Market, I heard the Woman cry out, the Man had held her, while the Woman robb'd her; my Brother then laid hold of the Man's Collar , and the two Prisoners slew at him, with both their Hands in his Face; I heard them say, the Man was a good House-keeper, and they knew him well. I laid hold of Davis's Cloak, and she desired me not to use her ill. The Woman that cry'd out, was by the two Prisoners, but I really can't say whether she had hold of Young's Cloak.</p>
               <p>C. Was the Woman that complain'd she was robb'd, following the Man?</p>
               <p>Mrs. How . Yes, directly down the Lane, they all went down by the Side of the Boards together; I put my Child into the China-Shop and followed them.</p>
               <p>Young's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person126">
                  John 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person126" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person126" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Hatter's-Shop, in Lothbury , under the Church. Last Saturday Night about 7 o'Clock, I had been at a Wine-Vault in Bearbinder-Lane , for a Hat to dress, and coming down the Lane back again, I heard a great Noise, the People cry'd, Stop him! Stop him! just by the Mansion-House . Coming nearer to the Place, I saw two Women, one nearer, the other farther off, one seem'd to be in the Croud, and they said, this is one of the Women. They were both taken up, and somebody cry'd, he has pick'd my Pocket; I was surpriz'd, for these Women to my thinking, were going soberly along. The first Woman (I can't say which it was) had a white Cloak under her Scarlet one; I believe it was that Woman that stands there (Davis.) They were going before a Justice, and I went down Bishop's-gate-street with them to a Square there, - I thought it a strange Thing that the Woman should cry stop him; so I ran down T hrogmorton-street with them, but my Cough coming, I could not keep even with them, but I founded them all the Way, 'till they came hither; and while I stood here in the Yard, I heard a Man say, I am sure I could never say who pick'd her Pocket, but I catched hold of the Man's Collar, and he got away. I was close by the Mansion-House when I heard the Words Stop him! - I was coming down Bearbinder-Lane , and turning the Corner, there was a great Mob; - I had been to Salter's-Hall.</p>
               <p>Jury. We desire he may be ask'd, who these Wine-Vaults belong to?</p>
               <p>Howard . I was order'd to go there, - it is a Wine-Vault just through Salter's-Hall. I can't tell the Name. I went to one of the Servants, who had left Word at my Shop for me to come to him.</p>
               <p>Jury. What is his Name?</p>
               <p>Howard. I can't tell, - if I go to a Wine Vault, I ask for the Servant that ordered me to carry the Hat.</p>
               <p>Jury. Is it a Wholesale or Retale Cellar?</p>
               <p>Howard. I don't know; there are a great many Hundred Pipes in the Cellar.</p>
               <p>C. Is it customary to dress Hats for People whose Names you do not know?</p>
               <p>Howard. Yes; I carry them Home, and sometimes I am paid, and sometimes not; if I carry a Hat to a Tavern, I say it is for one of the Drawers, and they enquire about the House for the Owner. I did not hear Women mention'd, but the Woman cry'd Stop him, he has robb'd me; and when I saw the Croud altogether, that Davis was a matter of 20 Yards from the Croud.</p>
               <p>C. Were they not held by any Body?</p>
               <p>Howard . I believe it was that Gentlewoman (Young) in the Croud, but I can't say any Body held her. I have seen Davis before: - I know her no farther than her passing by my Shop two or three Times, but if I was to meet her in the Street again, I don't know her, - I could not swear to her.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I never saw this Man all the Time.</p>
               <p>Mr. Day. I know the Man very well, and should have seen him if he had been there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person127">
                  John 
                  Michena 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person127" type="surname" value="Michena"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I had been to Mr. Siddal's, on London-Bridge, and coming back about 7 at Night, there was a Mob, and I went to see what was the Matter; I heard a Woman cry out, the Lord have Mercy on me, the Rogue has pick'd my Pocket; and nothing said about Women; - no one had hold of the Man, neither Man nor Woman. There was a Man, and likewise 2 Women coming along, and another Woman after them, and there was no Body laid hold of, that I saw, for I did not stop, but went directly Home.</p>
               <p>Davis's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person128">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person128" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person128" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mrs. Davis very well; she is a <rs id="t17410116-15-deflabel75" type="occupation">Mantua-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend117 t17410116-15-deflabel75"></join>, and lives near me, by Bethlem-Wall, through Great-Moregate . She call'd me between 3 or 4 in the Afternoon, to go with her to the Black-Boy, in Deadman's-Place, and coming back by Stocks-Market, there was fighting and noise, I was frighten'd, and lost her in the Croud; - they said, they had laid hold of a Woman, but I did not see her; I heard a Woman say she had lost her Money, and spoke something of a Man,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174101160009"></xptr> but nothing of a Woman. I take in Clear starching and Plain-Work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person129">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadwater 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person129" type="surname" value="Broadwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person129" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of this Affair , but the Gentlewoman (Davis) has lodg'd in my House about eight or nine Months; she is a Mantua-Maker ; she behav'd very well to me, and paid for every Thing . I keep a Cook's-shop, almost the very next Door to Mr. Wright's, the Baker's, at London-Wall, by Great-Moregate .</p>
               <p>Jury. I am afraid you are near Stocks-Market, very often.</p>
               <p>Broadwater . No; I am not, - I live with my Father, and my Father lives with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person130">
                  Lydia 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person130" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person130" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Walk which leads from Holy-Well Mount , to Hoxton, and take in Quilting . Mrs. Young I have known better than a Year; she rents a Room in my House at 2 s. a Week, and takes in Plain-work. I have seen her receive Money, and never saw nothing but what was modest and well behaved.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410116-15-person131">
                  Amelia 
                  Harwood 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person131" type="surname" value="Harwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person131" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known Mrs. Young about 3 Quarters of a Year; Mrs Walker desired me to help her to some Plain-work, and a very good Workwoman she is; she has worked for a great many good House-keepers that I know, and they liked her extraordinary well. I met her in Whitechapel. and desired her to go with me to the Rose, at Holborn-Bridge, so, just as we came by the China-Shop , the Corner of the Market, there was a Croud , - it was about 6 o'Clock, and Mrs. Young said, somebody is beating his Wife, and she would go to see what was the Matter. We went up a Passage, and the Woman laid hold of her, and said, you are one of the Women that help'd to rob me: presently another Woman was taken, and I was afraid they would lay hold of me.</p>
               <p>C. Where was it that the Woman laid hold of Young?</p>
               <p>Harwood. I was in so much Surprize, that I could not take Notice.</p>
               <p>C. to 
               <persName id="t17410116-15-person132">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17410116-15-person132" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person132" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-person132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was any Body in your Company except Davis?</p>
               <p>Jones . No; I did not meet that Woman in the red Cloak (Young) all the way. Both <rs id="t17410116-15-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17410116-15-punish77" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410116-15-punish77" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend115 t17410116-15-punish77"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410116-15-defend117 t17410116-15-punish77"></join>
               Death
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
