<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400227-21">
               <interp inst="t17400227-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-21" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400227-21" type="date" value="17400227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400227-21-off124-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-21-defend220 t17400227-21-off124 t17400227-21-verdict127"></join>
         
               <p>175. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400227-21-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Briggs  alias <rs id="t17400227-21-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-21-defend220 t17400227-21-alias-4"></join>Hollis</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-defend220" type="surname" value="Briggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-defend220" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-defend220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17400227-21-off124" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-off124" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-off124" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing 2 Thirty-six Shilling-picces, a Moidore, 3 Guineas, a Half-Guinea, and 40 s. in Money, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400227-21-victim222" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Kent 
                        <interp inst="t17400227-21-victim222" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-21-victim222" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400227-21-victim222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-21-off124 t17400227-21-victim222"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17400227-21-cd125" type="crimeDate">January 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-21-off124 t17400227-21-cd125"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-21-person223">
                  Richard 
                  Kent 
               <interp inst="t17400227-21-person223" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-person223" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Ely-Court in Holborn, and on the 14th of January, about 9 at Night, I was coming thro' <placeName id="t17400227-21-crimeloc126">Titchburn-Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-21-crimeloc126" type="placeName" value="Titchburn-Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400227-21-crimeloc126" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400227-21-off124 t17400227-21-crimeloc126"></join> , which is about 300 Yards from the Place where I live, and being a little merry, (it being Christmas Time) I looked in at a Door which stood a little open, and saw 2 Women sitting by the Fire. They said 'twas very cold Weather, and asked me to give them a hot Pint. I agreed to that, and when it was drank out, I was for going away, knowing I had a Charge of Money about me. But they took hold of my Cloaths, and said I should give them t'other hot Pint. Accordingly I agreed to it: but when that was out, I found myself in such a prodigious Disorder that I could not get up, nor go; but the Gentlewoman at the Bar kept me from falling, by sitting in my Lap. I found she began to be busy with my Pockets, so I covered them, with the Flaps of my Coat. As soon as I came to myself, I went Home to put my Money up; I had 8 l. 12 s. in one Pocket: 2 l. in Silver, in another; and some more Silver in another. I had three Pockets with Money in them; - but 'twas all gone, and I had no more than Eighteen-pence left in all my Pockets. As to the Liquor I drank, had it been honestly brewed, I could have drank it all up myself and have been sober, but I believe there was Opium, or something put into it, which disordered me for about 15 Minutes, and during that Time I felt the Gentlewoman's Hand in my Pocket. There was 3 of them in all, but no Utensils or Household-Goods in the House.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400227-21-person224">
                  Mary 
                  Woodcock 
               <interp inst="t17400227-21-person224" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-person224" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner put her Hand into Mr Kent's Pocket, and pull out a handful of Money, - half Crowns and Shillings: but as for Gold, I saw none. This was taken out of his right Side-Pocket; 'twas done in the Kitchen, upon the Ground-Floor, and she was sitting upon his Knee, at the same Time. Furthermore, I made the Hot-pots; and the Prisoner grated something into them, which got into my Head, I believe it was Opium, for I had like to have fallen off my Chair myself. I saw her hold the Gentleman's Money in her Hand, but he and I were so disordered, that we took no notice of it. I am Landlady of the House, and one of my Lodgers brought the Prisoner in, for 2 or 3 Nights unknown to me. I am sure I saw her pull out the Money, and put it into her Pocket, and moreover, she paid me 9 s. in part of the Reckoning. She gave it me for the Hot-pots; I did not take notice of above 2 or 3 Hot-pots, and the Price of a Hot-pot is but a Shilling, and moreover she gave me 6 s. and 6 d. besides, what it was for, I can't tell; the first and second Hot-pot, was enough to turn my Head: whether the Reckoning came to 9 s. or not, I can't tell. There was more than 2, or 3, or 4 Hotpots, but the first two turned my Head so, that I can't tell where she put the Money when she had taken it; but she took it openly and held it in her Hand, but whether she put it in her Bosom or Pocket, I know not, and to be sure she took it in a clandestine Manner, for I believe the Gentleman did not know it. <rs id="t17400227-21-verdict127" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400227-21-verdict127" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
