<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17491209-18">
               <interp inst="t17491209-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-18" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17491209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17491209-18" type="date" value="17491209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491209-18-off89-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-18-defend183 t17491209-18-off89 t17491209-18-verdict91"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17491209-18-off89-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-18-person184 t17491209-18-off89 t17491209-18-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>19. 
               <persName id="t17491209-18-defend183" type="defendantName">
                  Susannah, Wife to 
                     <persName id="t17491209-18-person184" type="defendantName">
                        George 
                        Sackvile 
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-person184" type="surname" value="Sackvile"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-18-person184" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17491209-18-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-defend183" type="surname" value="Sackvile"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-defend183" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-defend183" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17491209-18-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 5 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17491209-18-victim186" type="victimName">
                     Matth.ew 
                     Salmon 
                  <interp inst="t17491209-18-victim186" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-victim186" type="given" value="Matth.ew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-18-off89 t17491209-18-victim186"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17491209-18-cd90" type="crimeDate">Nov. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17491209-18-off89 t17491209-18-cd90"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17491209-18-person187">
                  Matthew 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17491209-18-person187" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-person187" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along the Park the 29th of Nov. among the thickest of the trees, there was this woman, she said, how do you my dear; I said, how do you do my girl, how goes trading : she said, very dull; she had not took hansel that night: I said, I had got a penny in my pocket in half-pence, if you are willing to lie down for that, you shall have it: she said, as she had not broke her fast, she would; upon this condition, that I should give her a dram afterwards; to which I agreed; so to the diversion we went - afterwards, as I was going to give her a dram, from Rosamonds pond, towards the iron gate, into Queen's-Square, the lamp gave an opportunity of seeing what sort of a lass I had got, for I did not see her before: when, I saw her, I did not like her; and wanted to get rid of her: as it happened a man came by in a mean dress with a leather apron on, she went up to him and while they were talking together, I went over the broad way to the gin shop, and looking about for her, found she was gone; I thought her the first of her trade that ever refused a dram, I was then suspicious that she had rob me; feeling, I immediately missed my watch : I ran after her from Queen's Square, the nearest to the Globe tavern, where I found her and the man close together, and but a little way off from a lamp. I took hold of her and said; Madam my Watch? the gentleman he ran away; but I secured her, and carried her before justice Lediard, in Palace Yard; to whom I told every thing; the justice said, how do you know but you might loose your watch out of your pocket upon the grass, when your breeches were down: I said, they were only turned down a little way; and if they had been turned quite down, my job was so streight, that it would not have fell out; the justice then was so curious as to take me, into an inward room to look at my breeches. I felt my watch the moment I went to be concerned with her; and I am as sure she had it, as I am sure of death; though she was willing to be search'd.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence. He took his sword (he is a soldier) and swore he would run me thro', if I would not be concerned with him. I said, I would not lie down for six pence, and afterwards he said, we must go to a bawdy-house, because I did not do it right. He was much in liquor; thinks I this is but a poor sort of a man to give me but a penny; I chose rather to go with the other man; than he came running back, and said I had got his watch, and he would have it out of my neck.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She has had many a watch before now. I am sure she had mine.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17491209-18-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17491209-18-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
