<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480115-13">
               <interp inst="t17480115-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-13" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480115-13" type="date" value="17480115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480115-13-off76-c169" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-13-defend194 t17480115-13-off76 t17480115-13-verdict79"></join>
         
               <p>86. + 
               <persName id="t17480115-13-defend194" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Smallwood 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-defend194" type="surname" value="Smallwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-defend194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-defend194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17480115-13-defloc75">St. Paul's, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-13-defloc75" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-13-defloc75" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-13-defend194 t17480115-13-defloc75"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480115-13-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480115-13-victim196" type="victimName">
                           Lawrence 
                           Potts 
                        <interp inst="t17480115-13-victim196" type="surname" value="Potts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-13-victim196" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480115-13-victim196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-13-off76 t17480115-13-victim196"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway, putting him in fear, and taking from him a hat, value 5 s. a Peruke, value 5 s. and an oak stick, value 1 d.
            </rs> the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17480115-13-person197">
                  Lawrence 
                  Potts 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-person197" type="surname" value="Potts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person197" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17480115-13-cd77" type="crimeDate">December 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-13-off76 t17480115-13-cd77"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-13-person198">
                  Laurence 
                  Potts 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-person198" type="surname" value="Potts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person198" type="given" value="Laurence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of December, at night, I had been at the two blue posts in Russel-Street, Covent-Garden, and coming down <placeName id="t17480115-13-crimeloc78">Bridges Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-13-crimeloc78" type="placeName" value="Bridges Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480115-13-crimeloc78" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480115-13-off76 t17480115-13-crimeloc78"></join>, between ten and eleven o'clock, the Prisoner and two more were standing at a door; the Prisoner stepped up to me, laid hold of my arm, and stopped me in the street; I asked him whether he wanted to rob me; he said, D - n you, I believe you want to rob me, for I have got a watch in my pocket; I gave myself a jerk and got from him, and turning about I saw a man; upon that I called out, Watch! but the man replied, I am no watchman, I am a chairman; then the Prisoner cried out, two Paddies, by G - d, (that is two Irishmen) met together; he took hold of me again after the chairman came up; said he, I will fight you; no, says I, I am no fighting man; said he, I will fight you for a tankard of beer; I replied, I would not fight at all; then he gave me a slap on the face, and I struck him again with a stick; upon that he collared me, and beat me very much on my body, the effects of which blows I now feel; then a little fellow, one of his accomplices, came and tripped up my heels, and my hat and wig fell off; the Prisoner fell upon me, and kept me down a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of your hat and wig?</p>
               <p>Potts. They were gone, and I never heard of them since.</p>
               <p>Q. You was stunned I suppose?</p>
               <p>Potts. I was very much bruised; then Smallwood was taken and carried into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What became of the man who said he was a chairman?</p>
               <p>Potts. I have inquired, and have not been able to find him.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Where do you live, Sir?</p>
               <p>Potts. I live in St. Martin's Legrand , I am a jeweller.</p>
               <p>Q. What account did you give before the magistrate?</p>
               <p>Potts. The same as I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with a robbery or not?</p>
               <p>Potts. The Justice asked me if I would swear a point blank robbery against him, or only an assault, with an intent of a robbery? Said I, I do not suppose a man should assault me with an intent to rob, when he stole my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge him with?</p>
               <p>P. I said he stopped me in the street, and I lost my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Give me an answer, whether you did, before the Magistrate , charge him with a robbery, or whether he was committed for a robbery?</p>
               <p>Potts. He was committed for a robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge him for?</p>
               <p>Potts. For being stopped in the street, and robbed by his companions of my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did you relate the thing to the Justice as you say now?</p>
               <p>Potts. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did the Magistrate say he had committed him for a robbery?</p>
               <p>Potts. Yes.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. I have the Magistrate's warrant for a common assault.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you what you said, when you went to the watch-house?</p>
               <p>Potts. I told you that this man assaulted me in the street, and I lost my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What did you say to Smallwood before he struck you?</p>
               <p>Potts. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he attempt to knock you down?</p>
               <p>Potts. No, he took hold of me by my arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Who struck first?</p>
               <p>Potts. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ask you for any money, or order you to deliver any thing?</p>
               <p>Potts. No.</p>
               <p>- Burton . I am a watchman in Bridges-Street ; on the 5th of December, at night, as I was upon my watch , Mr. Smallwood, and two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174801150016"></xptr> more, stood over against me, and by and by Mr. Potts came singly by himself.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Burton . About eleven o'clock: and I heard Mr. Potts say, what do you assault me for? Can't a man go along quietly? and Smallwood said to him, I will fight you for a full pot; and Mr. Potts said, I am no fighting man, I will not fight you. Mr. Potts stepped six or seven steps forward, and a little fellow came and tripped him up; and Mr. Potts was almost smothered in the dirt, and I took Smallwood off him, and took him to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they both kept in the watch-house all night ?</p>
               <p>Burton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor's Coun. What passed at the watch-house ?</p>
               <p>Burton. Mr. Potts said, the Prisoner wanted to fight him, and he would not fight with him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Coun. Did he say he wanted to rob him?</p>
               <p>Burton. He said, he believed he wanted to rob him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Smallwood charge him?</p>
               <p>Burton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Smallwood charge him with?</p>
               <p>Burton. I can't tell, but he was charged.</p>
               <p>Q. What words did Potts make use of?</p>
               <p>Burton. That he had lost his hat, wig, and stick.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Coun. What passed before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Burton. The Justice examined Potts, and he said, he was stopped in such a place, and lost his hat, wig, and stick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-13-person199">
                  Robert 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-person199" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person199" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a glover, and live in Vinegar-yard , in that neighbourhood; I was going home, and saw four men together: Mr. Potts, the Prisoner, and two others. I heard some blows, I looked and saw this gentleman and Smallwood engaged, and a little fellow came and tripped Mr. Potts up upon his back, and Smallwood lay upon him, and Smallwood gave the first charge: and the little man who tripped Mr. Potts up, gathered up his hat and wig, and went away with them.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor's Coun. Was there any thing offered you to prevent you from coming to give evidence to day?</p>
               <p>Powell. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Who offered it to you?</p>
               <p>Powell. It was a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who the woman was?</p>
               <p>Powell . I don't know who she was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it offered you by the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Powell . No.</p>
               <p>Potts. The Prisoner's brother told me the night afterwards, where my stick was to be had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Coun. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Potts . I was quite perfectly sober.</p>
               <p>Q. You was just come from an ale-house, was not you?</p>
               <p>Potts. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. You was a little reeling I suppose?</p>
               <p>Burton, the watchman. He was as sober as he is now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . I had been drinking at a publick-house, and was going home to bed; I was very much fuddled, and run against this man, and fell down: and after I was down, he gave me several blows. I got up, and took him by the collar; I knocked him down, and I lost my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Burton. The Prisoner had no wig when he came into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-13-person200">
                  Tamar 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-person200" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person200" type="given" value="Tamar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Smallwood between three and four years, he has used my house two years and an half; he came into my house between ten and eleven o'clock, it was the 5th of Dec. said I, where have you been, you are drunk, or that he was very much fuddled? said he, as fuddled as I am, I will have a pint of beer; he had a pint of beer drawn, and sat by it till after twelve o'clock, and unbuttoned the knees of his breeches, and took off his garters, and said, he would go home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with him?</p>
               <p>Stock. No, not came in with him.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Stock. That he is a very honest fellow.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would be guilty of robbing this man upon the highway.</p>
               <p>Stock. No, nor any body else.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your publick-house?</p>
               <p>Stock. The Crooked Billet in Bridges-Street, Covent Garden .</p>
               <p>Q. The squabble was said, I think, to be near Vinegar-Yard, how far is that from your house?</p>
               <p>Stock. About two stones throw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480115-13-person201">
                  Ambrose 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17480115-13-person201" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person201" type="given" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Smallwood at the Crooked Billet in Bridges-Street on the fifth of December, between ten and eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he go away?</p>
               <p>Ward. About ten minutes after twelve.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come in with any company, or go out with any company?</p>
               <p>Ward. No; when he came in he staggered, and hit his head against the wall.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480115-13-verdict79" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480115-13-verdict79" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
