<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17451016-13">
               <interp inst="t17451016-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-13" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17451016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17451016-13" type="date" value="17451016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17451016-13-off65-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-defend105 t17451016-13-off65 t17451016-13-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>376. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-defend105" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Graham 
                  <interp inst="t17451016-13-defend105" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-defend105" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17451016-13-defloc64">St. James's Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-13-defloc64" type="placeName" value="St. James's Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17451016-13-defloc64" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-defend105 t17451016-13-defloc64"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17451016-13-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for the murder of 
                     <persName id="t17451016-13-victim106" type="victimName">
                        Mary
                         his 
                        <rs id="t17451016-13-viclabel66" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-victim106 t17451016-13-viclabel66"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-victim109 t17451016-13-viclabel66"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim106" type="surname" value="his"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim106" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-off65 t17451016-13-victim106"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , by striking and stabbing her with a knife on the lower part of the belly, and giving her a mortal wound of the breadth of one inch, and the depth of five inches, on <rs id="t17451016-13-cd67" type="crimeDate">the third day of this instant October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-off65 t17451016-13-cd67"></join>, of which she languished till the sixth day of the said month, and then of the said mortal wound died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time charged by virtue of the Coroner's Inquisition, for the wilful murder of the said Mary his wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-person107">
                  Mark 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-person107" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person107" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (Surgeon.) On Thursday the 3 d of October I was sent for about nine o'clock in the evening to go and see Mrs. Graham: a lad came with the Prisoner at the bar to me, and told me that one of their journeymen's wives had fell down upon a knife and almost killed herself. I found a wound on the lower part of the belly, and part of the caul hung out. I asked her how she came by it; she said her husband did it; said I, he says you fell down upon a knife; and she said again that her husband gave it her. I found very bad symptoms, and that she must die, so I enquired more particularly into the affair. I asked her whether they had had any difference; she said they had no difference; and she said she did not know how he came to do it; but she said he was sometimes troubled with fits. And I satisfied the Coroner's Jury that this wound was the occasion of her death.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you form any judgment , whether this wound was given by any body, or whether it came by accident?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. She said it was given by her husband, but it is possible such a wound may happen by a person's falling down upon a knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she sensible to the time of her death?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. Very sensible, and therefore I was willing to get all the information I could from her, for I was of opinion she would die soon.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174510160007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-person108">
                  Sarah 
                  Wilkins 
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-person108" type="surname" value="Wilkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person108" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was very well acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17451016-13-victim109" type="victimName">
                  Mrs.
                   Graham
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim109" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim109" type="given" value="Mrs."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-victim109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-off65 t17451016-13-victim109"></join>
                  </persName>
            , she had a wound of which I believe she died.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she by that wound?</p>
               <p>Wilkins . She said her husband stabbed her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he and his wife live at variance?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. No; they always lived a happy couple till this thing happened; and Graham never in his life offered to strike her but once. I saw her on the Friday about one o'clock after she was stabbed, and very bad. I asked her how it came; she said her husband had stabbed her. He is subject to convulsion fits, and there are sometimes eight or nine men to hold him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he by the knife?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any fit that day?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. He had the next day, for he went to Dr. Mcdaniel to have some other advice, for his wife, and he fell down in a fit then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say he was in a fit, and stabbed her in a fit?</p>
               <p>Wilkins . No; she said he was just come out of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-person110">
                  Hannah 
                  North 
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-person110" type="surname" value="North"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person110" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner is my own cousin; he is very subject to fits; his father died raving mad in Bethlehem.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-person111">
                  Jane 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-person111" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person111" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner a great many years, and know him to be a very honest man till this unfortunate thing happened. I asked his wife, whether he was in his senses when he did it; and she said, Jenny, no he was not; for he was just come out of one of his fits, and then you know he is not sensible.</p>
               <p>Another witness said, she went to see her after the wound, and asked if her husband and she had had any words, and she said, No; that he was just come out of a fit, and was not sensible; and that this witness had seen ten men to carry him up when he was in a fit, that his wife and he lived very peaceably and quietly, and she never knew him to strike her: she saw him in a fit last Summer, and he almost bit his tongue in two, and was ill for a month.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17451016-13-person112">
                  Richard 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17451016-13-person112" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person112" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is a <rs id="t17451016-13-deflabel68" type="occupation">printer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17451016-13-defend105 t17451016-13-deflabel68"></join>, I have known him twenty years, and have worked with him five or six years, and he lived very justly and very well with his wife: I was very intimate with them, and never heard the least complaint in the world; he was troubled with convulsion fits, and would sometimes fall down by the press in them: I have seen him in one for an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him in a fit since his wife died?</p>
               <p>Phillips. He was in one yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Perhaps they may be counterfeits?</p>
               <p>Phillips. I don't know as to that.</p>
               <p>Two other witnesses proved his being troubled with convulsion fits. The Jury <rs id="t17451016-13-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17451016-13-verdict69" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               acquitted him of the felony and murder, and also on the Coroner's inquisition, and found that the deceased came to her death by accident
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
