<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-10">
               <interp inst="t17460903-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-10" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-10" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-10-off36-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-10-defend127 t17460903-10-off36 t17460903-10-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>292. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Webster 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-10-defend127" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-defend127" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-10-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Piece of Gold Coin, call'd a Six and thirty Shilling Piece, and another Piece of Gold Coin, call'd a Guinea
            </rs>, the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-victim129" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Marshall 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-10-victim129" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-victim129" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-10-off36 t17460903-10-victim129"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , the <rs id="t17460903-10-cd37" type="crimeDate">12th of August</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-10-off36 t17460903-10-cd37"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-10-person130">
                  William 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person130" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person130" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Marshall. The Prisoner at the Bar with me about four Months, in which Time I lost several Sums of Money; upon which I mark'd some, in order to find it out, on Monday, (this was on Tuesday, the 12th of August); I had mark'd twelve Pounds, and put in my Desk, as usual; but a Gentleman came and paid me some Money, and brought me a Three-Pound Twelve-Shilling Piece; I gave him some Change out of it, and left it on the Desk all Night. I consulted proper Means to find it out; I suspected the Man more than the Maid. We contriv'd that her Mistress should send her down to get some Water, and in the mean Time she should examine her Pocket: Her Mistress follow'd her to the Kitchen Door, and ask'd her for her Pocket; upon which I found the Thirty-Six Shilling Piece and Guinea, which I had mark'd. Upon that I call'd my Wife's Father, Mr. Glass, who is here, and she acknowledg'd she had taken them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she acknowledge it before?</p>
               <p>Marshall. She acknowledged it before myself, my Wife, and my Wife's Father, Mr. Glass.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-person131">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person131" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person131" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-10-person132">
                  Thomas 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person132" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say in this Affair?</p>
               <p>Glass. Mr. Marshall has often complain'd of the Loss of Money out of the Shop, from the Time mention'd, the 12th of August, on Tuesday Night, (I board in the House with him.) He look'd very dull, and told me his Cash came considerably short. I said, Are you sure that you have lost it; he said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030013"></xptr> he told it the last Night, and To-day, and cast it up again, and found it three Pounds short of the Money, and had ticketed it down. I ask'd him if he mistrust'd any Body; he said he did not like his Maid, for no body had been in the Counting-House but her: But however, at Night, when I went up to my Chamber. I had not been there but a very little while, but my Son Marshall knock'd at the Chamber Door, and said, that he had found the Thief. When I went down to his Room, there was he and his Wife and Maid, together; he said he could forever it; with that the Maid cry'd, and said, she acknowledg'd she did take it, and if we would forgive her she would never do so any more; and she frankly did acknowledge that she did take Money from the first fortnight of her coming into the House, and that she had taken in all near thirty or forty Pounds.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-person133">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person133" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person133" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-10-person134">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person134" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person134" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) What do you know of this Affair ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-person135">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person135" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person135" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person135" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I follow'd her down Stairs before I could get Courage to take her Pocket; but at last I did take it, and there I found the two Pieces of Money that were mark'd, and she fell a crying, and begg'd I would shew her Money, and she would confess every Thing that she had done.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-10-person136">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-10-person136" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-person136" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to the Prisoner) Would you ask this Witness any Questions.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What I said to you was only in a Fright; the Money you had of me was my own, what I borrow'd to buy a Gown; I am innocent of what my Mistress charges me with.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-10-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-10-punish39" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-punish39" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-10-punish39" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-10-defend127 t17460903-10-punish39"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
