<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17401015-64">
               <interp inst="t17401015-64" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-64" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-64" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17401015"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17401015-64" type="date" value="17401015"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17401015-64-off343-c358" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-defend443 t17401015-64-off343 t17401015-64-verdict347"></join>
         
               <p>502. 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-defend443" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Deleroy 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-64-defend443" type="surname" value="Deleroy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-defend443" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-defend443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17401015-64-defloc342">St. James Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-64-defloc342" type="placeName" value="St. James Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17401015-64-defloc342" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-defend443 t17401015-64-defloc342"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17401015-64-off343" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-off343" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-off343" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing 2 Linnen Pillowbiers, 1 pair of Linnen Sheets, a Child's Shirt, a Child's Wastcoat, a Piece of Silk, and other Things
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-victim445" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Trueman 
                  <interp inst="t17401015-64-victim445" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-victim445" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-victim445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-off343 t17401015-64-victim445"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17401015-64-viclabel344" type="occupation">Gent</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-victim445 t17401015-64-viclabel344"></join>. <rs id="t17401015-64-cd345" type="crimeDate">Sept. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-off343 t17401015-64-cd345"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr Trueman. The Prisoner was my <rs id="t17401015-64-deflabel346" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17401015-64-defend443 t17401015-64-deflabel346"></join>; On the 17th of September she went away and took her Things with her. She came again the next Day and ask'd me for her Wages, and desir'd my Wife to let her fetch her Bundle down, for when she went away, she said, she had left one behind her; my Wife said, I don't know of any Bundle you have here, pray let me see what is in it. We open'd the Bundle, and found these Things in it, which the Prisoner said were given her by a former Mistress; but they were my Goods, and had my Mark on them. She brought them out of the Garret, and would have gone off with them if we had not stopp'd her. They were a piece of Silk, 2 Pillowbiers, a pair of Sheets, and some Childbed Linnen, a Hatband, a Child's Shirt, a Wastcoat, a Cap, a Forehead Cloth and a Biggin, I know of nothing more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person446">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Boyce 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person446" type="surname" value="Boyce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person446" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived with Mr Trueman a great many Years, and saw the Prisoner take the Goods away, I was above Stairs when she took them, but she did not know that I saw her. I did not say any thing to her 'till she was brought into the Parlour, and the Bundle was open'd. There were in the Bundle a piece of Silk, 2 Pillow-biers, a Hatband, and several other Things of Mr Trueman's; I knew them to be his by the Marks; some of them were mark'd with 2 T's, and some with M and M T. The Prisoner would not confess any thing when we took her, but when she was carry'd before the Justice, she own'd she had taken them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I ask my Mistress to look at my Bundle when I brought it down?</p>
               <p>Boyce. She went into the Shop, and did not ask her Mistress to look at it before I made the Discovery. She had these things under her Arm, and was carrying them away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I went up Stairs for my own Bundle, there was this in the Room of it, and when I came to look at it, I found it was not my own; I wanted to ask my Mistress for my Things, but she hid herself behind the Screen, and would not see me.</p>
               <p>Boyce. There was no other Bundle put in the Room of her's.</p>
               <p>Jury. Why is not the Prisoner's Mistress here?</p>
               <p>Boyce. She is at Market in her Business; Mr Trueman was bound over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>Defence. 
               <persName id="t17401015-64-person447">
                  Mary 
                  Cuart 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person447" type="surname" value="Cuart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person447" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person447" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lived with me twice; and behaved as an honest Servant: I have known her 16 Years; she always had the Character of a sober Girl. I had a Lodger who used frequently to leave his Desk open, and scatter Money out of his Pocket, and she always gave it him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person448">
                  Peter 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person448" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person448" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her almost from a Child, and always knew her to be a very honest Body; I was surpriz'd when I heard that she was taken up for this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person449">
                  William 
                  Cash 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person449" type="surname" value="Cash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person449" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have know her about 5 Years, and always though her honest. I have entrusted her in my House several Times, and she never wrong'd me of any Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person450">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Coward 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person450" type="surname" value="Coward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person450" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person450" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner to be a very honest, modest, sober Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person451">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cash 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person451" type="surname" value="Cash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person451" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 6 Years, and never heard an ill Thing of her in my Life, I have entrusted her with the Key of my Cupboard when there has been Money in it, and she never wrong'd me of any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17401015-64-person452">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17401015-64-person452" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person452" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have known her 12 Years, and liv'd in the same House with her. I have come Home several Times in Liquor, and forgot to lock my Desk when there has been Money in it, and she never wrong'd me of any thing. I have dropp'd Money out of my Pocket, and she always gave it to me again. <rs id="t17401015-64-verdict347" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17401015-64-verdict347" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
