<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490705-5">
               <interp inst="t17490705-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-5" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490705"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490705-5" type="date" value="17490705"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490705-5-off28-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-defend55 t17490705-5-off28 t17490705-5-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>376. 
               <persName id="t17490705-5-defend55" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Bartholomew 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-defend55" type="surname" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-defend55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late of <placeName id="t17490705-5-defloc26">St. James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-5-defloc26" type="placeName" value="St. James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490705-5-defloc26" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-defend55 t17490705-5-defloc26"></join>, <rs id="t17490705-5-deflabel27" type="occupation">Stable-keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-defend55 t17490705-5-deflabel27"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17490705-5-off28" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-off28" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-off28" type="offenceSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               he, with a certain knife made of iron and steel, val. 1 s. upon one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490705-5-victim57" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17490705-5-victim57" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-5-victim57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490705-5-victim57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-off28 t17490705-5-victim57"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the left side of his belly, did make one mortal wound, breadth two inches, and depth three; whereupon he, the said William, did languish from the <rs id="t17490705-5-cd29" type="crimeDate">20th of June</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-off28 t17490705-5-cd29"></join> to the 23d of the same month, and then died
            </rs>: He also stood charged on the Coroner's Inquest for Man-slaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person58">
                  Sarah 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person58" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person58" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17490705-5-person59">
                  John 
                  Bartholomew 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person59" type="surname" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came the Tuesday before quarter-day into the house, and he and I and his wife went into the little room, he was an <rs id="t17490705-5-deflabel30" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-defend55 t17490705-5-deflabel30"></join> of Bailey's: presently comes 
               <persName id="t17490705-5-person60">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person60" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person60" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into the house, I knew his voice. I had lock'd the door, and given the key to the prisoner; 
               <persName id="t17490705-5-person61">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person61" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person61" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to the door, and tap'd, and said, open the door; the prisoner said, let any man open it on his peril; the door opened inwards, he shoved against it, the prisoner and his wife clapp'd their hands on the lock to secure it; Smith said he would have the door open; he, shoving hard, the door flew open immediately; it was burst open by violence: then the prisoner fetched a blow at him; but I saw no weapon, I did not see the wound till about an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any words pass between them after the door was open?</p>
               <p>Turner. I did not, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any former quarrels between them?</p>
               <p>Turner. I have heard the prisoner forewarn 
               <persName id="t17490705-5-person62">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person62" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             his house; telling him, if he had any thing belonging to him upon the premisses, to take it away, and be gone from his house.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you a servant there?</p>
               <p>Turner. I am a lodger there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person63">
                  Joseph 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person63" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person63" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at supper with my fellow servants, and the prisoner came in with his wife, and Mr. Smith the deceased came in with his whip in his hand; the prisoner was in the back room, Mr. Smith went up to the door, and knock'd with his knuckles; presently the door flew open, and I saw the prisoner come out; I heard a shreek out, my fellow-servant took hold of the prisoner, and I took the knife out of his hand. It was shewed in Court, a long Clasp knife with a sharp point. Mr. Smith went into the street, and desir'd a Surgeon might be sent for.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the knife open?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. It was, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it bloody?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. There was some blood upon it, I helped the deceased up stairs, and laid him down on the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any quarrelling between them before this?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. I have heard the deceased abuse the prisoner in his own house, calling him rogue and scoundrel, telling him, he had no business there; saying, he himself was landlord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person64">
                  William 
                  Segwick 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person64" type="surname" value="Segwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person64" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the house the time this thing happened; I saw Mr. Smith come in with his whip in his hand, he came to the door, and, after a little time, the door flew open. The prisoner and the deceased came and rushed forward towards the street; who came first, I cannot tell: I was sitting behind the last witness almost in the dark, I went out and laid hold of the prisoner, while the other witness took a knife out of his hand; in the fright I did not see the knife. I was servant to the prisoner, he is a very honest man, he always appeared as such to me.</p>
               <p>Husband Messinger. I am a Surgeon; when I was called to the deceased, I found him with his bowels lying out of his body, which was very soon after it happened. It was my judgment that he could not live, and I told all about me so; he lived near three days, in which time I visited him six times; he was sensible during the whole till a little before he died; I never saw him insensible: he did not give me any account how it happen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that wound was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Messinger. I believe it was; but how he receiv'd it, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I have been turned out of my own house by that man into the street, and abused by him, and have been driven out of my senses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person65">
                  Bathsheba 
                  Chethem 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person65" type="surname" value="Chethem"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person65" type="given" value="Bathsheba"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen Mr. Smith stand at Mr. Bartholomew's door, and forbid him his own house, and shut the door against him, and he, the prisoner, has gone about the street, and cried like a child. It is a public inn the prisoner kept, and he used to let out coaches and chaises.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174907050006"></xptr> I have known him about ten or eleven years; he is a soft, inoffensive man. The deceased once put the prisoner into the Gate-house, and when he came home, he would not let him come into his own house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person66">
                  William 
                  Cherrey 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person66" type="surname" value="Cherrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person66" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he <rs id="t17490705-5-viclabel31" type="occupation">kept the inn</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-victim57 t17490705-5-viclabel31"></join>. It is the Plough inn in Princess-street; it is about nine or ten years. I always looked upon him as an honest, inoffensive man. I never saw the deceased but a few days before he died standing at the door, as though he was master of the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person67">
                  Margaret 
                  Christian 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person67" type="surname" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person67" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived with the prisoner six years, he is a very honest man. I was present when the accident happen'd; I was not his servant then, I was there for a pint of beer; I was standing upon the stairs, and I heard the prisoner say, let any man open the door upon his peril. Mr. Smith said, he would do for him presently, he would have a baily there in half an hour's time; he pushed open the door with his hand, the prisoner met him, and fetched a blow at him; but I saw no weapen he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know the prisoner guilty of passion?</p>
               <p>Christian. No, I never did. I know this Smith has been a great enemy to him, and has troubled him many times.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think might be the reason of his thus using the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Christian. I believe he was greater with the prisoner's wife than he should be.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you made any observations of that the time you lived in the house?</p>
               <p>Christian. I cannot say I have.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person68">
                  James 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person68" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person68" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the neighbourhood, I have known the prisoner fourteen or fifteen years, and always looked upon him as an honest, inoffensive man, a very hard labouring man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490705-5-person69">
                  Hugh 
                  Bedle 
               <interp inst="t17490705-5-person69" type="surname" value="Bedle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person69" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live within three or four doors of the prisoner; the character of the man appeared extraordinary good, a pains-taking man. It was talked in the neighbourhood Mr. Smith was too great with his wife; but how far, I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Hen. Kellsoe. I live near the prisoner, he is a very honest hard working man; I have traded with him, and always found him so.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a man of passion?</p>
               <p>Kellsoe. I never saw or heard he was a passionate man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-5-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of man-slaughter.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490705-5-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490705-5-punish33" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490705-5-defend55 t17490705-5-punish33"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
