<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460515-19">
               <interp inst="t17460515-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-19" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-19" type="date" value="17460515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460515-19-off93-c279" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-19-defend314 t17460515-19-off93 t17460515-19-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>215. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Fox 
                  <interp inst="t17460515-19-defend314" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-defend314" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-defend314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460515-19-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing five Shillings and Sixpence, from 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460515-19-victim316" type="victimName">
                           Timothy 
                           Seamans 
                        <interp inst="t17460515-19-victim316" type="surname" value="Seamans"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460515-19-victim316" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460515-19-victim316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-19-off93 t17460515-19-victim316"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, the 10th of this Month, in <placeName id="t17460515-19-crimeloc94">St. Peter's, Cornhill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-19-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="St. Peter's, Cornhill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-19-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-19-off93 t17460515-19-crimeloc94"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person317">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person317" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person317" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person318">
                  Timothy 
                  Seamans 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person318" type="surname" value="Seamans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person318" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Seamans. Last Saturday Night, coming from Bishopsgate-Street, there was a Woman that said to me, Whither are you going? I said, going home. She ask'd me if I would give her a Glass of Wine? I said it was too late, it was Time to go home. There were to or three of them; I saw them stoop down and speak to one another. I put my Hand to my Pocket and found it turn'd out.</p>
               <p>Q. You say there were two Women, How do you know it was this? it might be the other.</p>
               <p>Seamans. It was not the other Woman, she was not so near.</p>
               <p>Q. How much Money had you in your Pocket?</p>
               <p>Seamans. Five Shillings and Sixpence, my Lord, and no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no Notion of their picking your Pocket?</p>
               <p>Seamans. No, my Lord, 'till I saw them looking down to the Ground.</p>
               <p>Q. What Mistruit could you have by seeing them looking down to the Ground ?</p>
               <p>Seamans. I then clapp'd my Hand to my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What Company had you been in before?</p>
               <p>Seamans. I was in Company with some young Men; my Master's Son, and several of us, were at a Merriment on the Account of a young Man's being out of his Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person319">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person319" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person319" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (by the Council for the Prisoner.) You say it was Twelve o'Clock at Night; Where had you been?</p>
               <p>Seamans. At the Helmet in Bishopsgate-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say that you was entirely sober ?</p>
               <p>Seamans. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person320">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person320" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person320" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Jeffreys.) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Jeffreys. When I came out of White-lion-Court there was nobody there then : I said to him, when he had charg'd her with picking his Pocket, Are you sure that she has it; did not you go by the Watch-house as she was going to it? She said she had chang'd a Guinea in Leadenhall-Market. I never saw the Woman in no ill Company in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person321">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person321" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person321" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) What have you to say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I had been to a House to meet my Husband : When I went there my Husband was sent for, and could not come home with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174605150024"></xptr> me; because he did not come; I would not stay, but came away. The Prosecutor came out of a pav'd Court; I saw him with a Woman in a white Gown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person322">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person322" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person322" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (by the Council to - Walker.) Mr. Walker, Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Walker. I never saw her before the Saturday Night she was taken up. I had been to a Friend of Mr. Dun's; and as Mr. Dun, and another Man, that went along with us, were coming by St. Michael's Alley, near the Exchange, we saw a Man with a Woman up in the Gateway; as soon as they heard us the Man got his Breeches up as soon as he could, and the Woman run away towards the Exchange; and there was that young Woman at the Bar, who was about seven or eight Yards towards Cornhill; this young Man runs to her, and says, You are the Person that was along with me up in the Alley. She declar'd her Innocency. Then the Prosecutor said, You are a Confederate with her, if you are not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person323">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person323" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person323" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person324">
                  Thomas 
                  Dun 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person324" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person324" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Dun. No, Sir; I do not remember her. I remember Mr. Walker the Butcher, and I were coming from Covent-Garden; Hyp, says he, here's somebody up the Alley; said I, Never mind that, come along about your Business. A Man and Woman was there; the Woman run from the Man, towards the Exchange, as if the D - I drove her: He was shuffling, as we thought, to put up his Breeches. When he run to this Woman he said, They are all Whores alike; I'll keep this Woman 'till I find the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person325">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person325" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person325" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Walker) Mr. Walker, How came you here?</p>
               <p>Walker. I came by a Subparna.</p>
               <p>Q. Who sent it to you?</p>
               <p>Walker. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live? (also to the other Witness ) How came you here, Mr. Dun?</p>
               <p>Dun. By a Subparna.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray did you go before the Justice with these People ?</p>
               <p>Dun. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you went away about your Business.</p>
               <p>Dun. Yes; but the next Day I went to the Compter, and I saw the Woman crying in the Place; she desir'd me to leave her my Name and Place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her?</p>
               <p>Dun. Yes, my Lord; I took particular Notice of her Face?</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you by?</p>
               <p>Dun. I believe about five or six Minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. If it was so unjust a Charge, Why did you not go before the Magistrate?</p>
               <p>Dun. I had something else to do.</p>
               <p>Court. That is every one's Business, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Business, Walker?</p>
               <p>Walker. The last Business that I kept was a Publick House; but I have been out of Business for near a Twelvemonth. I now kill for the Butchers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person326">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person326" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person326" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person327">
                  Mary 
                  Blair 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person327" type="surname" value="Blair"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person327" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Blair. My Lord, she is my Mantua-maker; She brought me home a Gown on Saturday Night. She expected her Husband to come to her. I have known her ever since she has been married to Mr. Fox. She waited at my House 'till Eleven o'Clock. She has work'd for me near three Years. I believe she would not be guilty of such a Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person328">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person328" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person328" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Mannaton ) What do you know of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mannaton. I believe her to be a very honest Woman: I have seen her very industrious; and she keeps her House and every Thing very clean.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person329">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person329" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person329" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Hughes) How long have you known Mrs. Fox?</p>
               <p>Hughes. She has work'd for my Wife for about two Years and a Half: I believe her to be a very honest Woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know her Husband?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I was an Officer as well as he.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person330">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person330" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person330" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person331">
                  Katherine 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person331" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person331" type="given" value="Katherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know Mrs. Fox, the Prisoner at the Bar ? What are you?</p>
               <p>Holland. I keep a Chandler's Shop in Katherine-Wheel-Alley, where Mrs. Fox lives; I have known Mrs. Fox four or five Years, and she has made Mantuas for me about three Years, and never heard but she was a civil Neighbour, and a good Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person332">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person332" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person332" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person333">
                  John 
                  Kitchen 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person333" type="surname" value="Kitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person333" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know Mrs. Fox?</p>
               <p>Kitchen. Yes, very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what's her general Character?</p>
               <p>Kitchen. Her Husband's an Officer belonging to Whitechapel Court. She always had a very fair Character, as far as I have heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-19-person334">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person334" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person334" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-19-person335">
                  Anne 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17460515-19-person335" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person335" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Burton. In Red Lion Street, Whitechapel; my Husband is a Bricklayer.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mrs. Fox, the Prisoner, at the Bar, what's her general Character ?</p>
               <p>Burton. A very good Character. She is a <rs id="t17460515-19-deflabel95" type="occupation">Mantua-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-19-defend314 t17460515-19-deflabel95"></join>, has made for me, and several of my Acquaintance. I never heard any Thing ill of her in my Life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460515-19-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460515-19-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
