<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420603-18">
               <interp inst="t17420603-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-18" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420603-18" type="date" value="17420603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420603-18-off71-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-18-defend125 t17420603-18-off71 t17420603-18-verdict73"></join>
         
               <p>20. 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-defend125" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Bury 
                  , alias 
                     <rs id="t17420603-18-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-18-defend125 t17420603-18-alias-2"></join>Henry Parminter</rs>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-defend125" type="surname" value="Bury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-defend125" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-defend125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was <rs id="t17420603-18-off71" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-off71" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-off71" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               indicted for marrying Mrs. 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420603-18-victim129" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Proctor 
                        <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim129" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim129" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , a second Wife, <rs id="t17420603-18-cd72" type="crimeDate">Sept. 27, 1739</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-18-off71 t17420603-18-cd72"></join>, his former Wife being now living
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Counsel for the Prosecution in opening the Charge, took Notice that Mrs. Proctor came from her Brother's in Somersetshire, and lodged at Mrs. Davidge's a Milliner in Covent Garden, where the Prisoner came acquainted with her and married her, and pretended to be a Person of very considerable Fortune; that as he understood her Fortune was not very large, and that as he had a Dependance on an Uncle, therefore desir'd it might be kept a Secret; he promised he would bring a Friend to be Witness of the Marriage; but when he came there was no body in the Coach with him, and the only Reason he gave for not bringing his Friend was, his Fear that his Uncle might know it. Mrs. Proctor was over persuaded, and went with him to Chelsea, and there was married. He took Lodgings for her, and owned her for his Wife, and wrote a Letter to the Brother of this Lady, in which he calls himself his Brother; as one Artisice always wants another to support it, he thought proper to produce a Ring, in which was the Name of Parminter which he said was his Brother deceased, this Crime is of a deep dye; because he had as good and virtuous a Wife as any Man. We shall bring the strongest Evidence to prove the Fact upon him, and doubt not but the Jury will find him guilt, of the Indictment.</p>
               <p>2d Council. My Lord, and Gentlemen of the Jury, I am Council on the same Side, this is an Indictment against 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person130">
                  William 
                  Bury 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person130" type="surname" value="Bury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person130" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who went under the Name of Parminter, for marrying a second Wife; and we shall prove he wrote a great many Letters full of Love, and afterwards broke open her Box and took them away, we have some of those very Letters to produce, some with, and some without a Name; he told her she might enquire after him at one Mr. Burys, by the Name of Parminter, and said he had a very rich Uncle on whom he had a great Dependance, and therefore desired that the Marriage might be kept secret. On the 27th of Sept. 1739, he drove the young Lady from Mr. Seaton's in Suffolk-street to a House at Chelsea, and a Clergyman came and married them, he staid with her two Days, and then said he must leave her on account of Business; he afterwards moved her from Lodging to Lodging, and the Lady seeing him uneasy in his Mind, asked him what was the Matter? then he fell on his Knees and confessed the whole Fact; we shall shew you this Gentlemen, in a full Light, and we doubt not but you will find him guilty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person131">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person131" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is the Register Book of Marriages for the Parish of St. Saviour's Southwark, Oct. 13, 1727, 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person132">
                  William 
                  Bury 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person132" type="surname" value="Bury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person132" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-victim134" type="victimName">
                     Anna
                      Maria Fleetwood
                  <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim134" type="surname" value="Maria Fleetwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim134" type="given" value="Anna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-victim134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person135">
                  Henry 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person135" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person135" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was at the Wedding Dinner, and they have lived together ever since as Man and Wife, I have lodged in his House in Abchurch-Lane, he has two Sons living by her, I cannot remember the Day not the Year, but it was about 12 or 13 Years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person136">
                  Sarah 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person136" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person136" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The latter End of May 1739, I was first acquainted with him. That Man came to Mrs. Davidges and enquired for me, I did not see him the first Time, he came again the next Day, I went with him into the Parlour, and there he told me, that he saw me a going to my Brother's, and asked who I was, and was told where I lived, on which he came to me, and there he declared how much he was in Love, and begged me to give him Leave to make me frequent Visits, which I refused, because he was a Stranger; after that he wrote Letters to me every Day, without my answering any one of them, on which he sent a Porter to me with a Letter, declaring how much he was in Love, he begg'd that if I would not give him Leave to come and see me, that I would meet him in Somerset<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030009"></xptr> Gardens, or the Park, he would often endeavour to get me into a Coach, but that I always refused till the Day I was married to him. He went by the Name of 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person137">
                  Henry 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person137" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person137" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he shewed me a Ring which he said was for his Brother 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person138">
                  William 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person138" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person138" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he often pressed me to go into some House or Coach with him, saying I might venture, for he was no Boy. We were to have been married at Richmond, where he said he had taken Lodgings for me, but I put it off till my Friends knew of it, then he let me know that he had taken Lodgings at Chelsea, and we were to be married there, and he consented to let Mr. Seaton in Suffolk-street go along with us, but at Night he sent me a Letter, and in it said, that as the Thing was to be kept private, he would have no body with him but his Friend Bury; at 9 o'Clock I received this Letter, but I had before acquainted Mr. Senton that he was to go along with us; he also said in the Letter, that he would bring a Friend along with him to be present at the Marriage, in the Morning he came there was none but that Man, (pointing to the Prisoner) in the Coach, I asked where his Friend was, and he said he would tell me in going along, which he did, and he said he was afraid Mr. Bury would tell his Wife, and then it would be blown. When we came to Chelsea we went into a House up Stairs, and there a Clergyman came and married us.</p>
               <p>Coun. Do you know it was Chelsea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person139">
                  Sarah 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person139" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person139" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He told me it was Chelsea. I went to sit down in the Window, and he told me I must not sit down, and there that Man married me (she produced a Ring) and said, that is the very Ring which that very Man married me with. After we was married we went to the Hospital, and we din'd at a Gardiner's where we lodged, whose Name is Singleton. We staid 2 Nights and three Days there, and afterwards I went to Greenwich, and staid there from Saturday till Monday, he said he was obliged to go to Exeter on special Business, but he took Care to write to me every Post, that Man did (pointing again to the Prisoner) Exeter was stamp'd on the outside of the Letters. He staid there a Month, and on his Return I told him, it was sitting that my Brother should know of our being married, I told him that several had wished me Joy; why said he, several of my Friends have wished me Joy too.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know that?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I know no more than that Man told me so. I wrote to him at the Bath, and he told me in a Letter, he had a Grandmother dead, and desired I would put myself in Mourning, and that he would let my Brother know of the marriage.</p>
               <p>Counc. When did you see him next, after he wrote about the Mourning?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I did not see him till about the 14th of January.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where did you see him next?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He directed me to meet him in Somerset-Gardens, and I met him in the Street going thither.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was that.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was in Jan. I was with Child when I went from Mrs. Davidge's, and had about a quarter to go, and while I was there, this Man came to me, and told me, he would go to my Brother himself, and discover the Marriage to him, but instead of that, I had a Letter from him, that his Uncle must not know it; after that he wrote to me, as from Rotterdam, when he came from Exeter, he came to see me, at one Mrs. Jones's, where I then Lodged, he disliked the Lodgings, and desired me to remove to one Mrs. Williams's, in New-North-Street, Red-Lyon-Square, and I was there about 13 or 14 Months, and was there deliver'd of a Daughter now alive. He wrote to me several Letters, acquainting that he had something to tell me, that would shock me to the last degree; when he came to me I desired to know what it was, whether he was in Debt, or had murder'd any body, as to his being in Debt, he said he was, for he was bound for a Person now dead, in a large Sum of Money. I ask'd him if this was true, and he told me, that there was something more than that, and then seeing him again, about 2 Months before I was brought to bed, he told me that he had something to tell me, that he must now let me know, with that he fell on his Knees, hung his Head down, and said that there he would remain till I bid him rise, says he, do you know where you directed your Letters to me my Name is not Parminter, but it is Bury, that he had suffered a great deal for me, and he begg'd that I would keep it a secret, and said that as he had D - d himself for me, he hoped that I would not hang him, and that if I had no regard for him, I should consider what uneasiness it would be to my own Family, I let him remain<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030010"></xptr> upon his Knees, till he got up himself; then he put my Hand up to his Eyes to feel his Tears, but I believe he had spit on his Fingers to counterfeit them, and then that Man, (pointing to the Prisoner) left me, and told me that if I made a Noise, he would never come near me again, and at last went away. Two Days afterwards I was taken exceeding ill, and that Man, came to see me, but I could not speak to him.</p>

               <p>Counc. After this Discovery, did he come to you again?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He came 2 Days after and found me exceeding ill.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he come two Days after he said he had d - d himself.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He did come two Days after he said he had d - d himself.</p>
               <p>Counc. After these two Days did you see him.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I saw him frequently after that, for I was then big with Child.</p>
               <p>Counc. When you was brought to Bed, did he come and Father it.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was you brought to bed?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I was brought to Bed, October 14, 1740.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he come during your Lying-in.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He was prodigious ill at the same Time.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was the Child christened.</p>
               <p>S. Proctors. About a Week afterwards, after the Child was got to Nurse, he came to see it.</p>
               <p>Counc. When did the Child go out to Nurse?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. When 6 Weeks old, in New North-street, Red-lyon-square.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you discover this to your Friends?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I did not discover it to my Friends first, but I was determined to discover it to his.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who did you discover it to first.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I discover'd it first to one Mr. Shippen, who was an Acquaintance of that Man's there (pointing to the Prisoner) that marry'd me; I discover'd it afterwards to one Mr. Fleetwood in the Temple, Brother to his first Wife.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long was it after you lay in, that you discover'd it.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was about 3 Months after I lay in, after this, I saw him at Mr. Shippen's, in Boswell court, and there I charged him with every thing, as I do now.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he own it.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No Sir, he said he knew nothing at all of me, and that he had never seen me before, and called God Almighty to witness that he knew nothing at all of me.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did he ever make you a Present of any thing.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir, a Gold Seal.</p>
               <p>Counc. Is this the Seal.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes, it is.</p>
               <p>Council. Did you ever see him write?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir; I saw him write two Songs once.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know his Hand if you see it? Look on these Letters?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. There are none here but what are of his writing, and these Letters came from him to me. I had a vast Number of his Letters, but he took them from me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person140">
                  Henry 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person140" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person140" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was asked if he ever saw the Prisoner write, and said he had.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you believe these to be his writing?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person141">
                  Henry 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person141" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person141" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I do believe they are.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He took many Letters from me three Months after I was brought to bed.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where did he take them from you?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. At Mr. Williams's, they were in a black Box, and he took them from me by force.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you in the Nature of an Apprentice at Mrs. Davidge's.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you bound to her for any time.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. When a Porter came to you, did you never go with him according to his Message?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No, never.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you never with the Gentleman at a Bagnio?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I was with him once after I was married.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you never at a Place known by the Name of the Turks-Head Bagnio ?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I never was there with him in my Life.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say you was married at Chelsea, where did you dine at Chelsea?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. At the Gardiner's House.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did not they call it by the Name of the Whim?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Not as I knew of.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know the Clergyman's Name that married you ?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir, his Name was Rider.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030011"></xptr>Counc. Did you ever see that Man before or since?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I never saw him after he married me.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who gave you away?	</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. There was nobody gave me away.</p>
               <p>Counc. What became of the Parson afterwards, did he go to dinner with you?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No Sir, he wished us both Joy and Happiness, and he said, that he was sure, that he had made him (meaning the Prisoner) happy, and then went away.</p>
               <p>Counc. Had you a Licence?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He told me that he had a Licence; that he left it among some Papers, but was so lucky as to find it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Counc. Had not you the Curiosity to see it?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No Sir, I depended then on every Thing he did.</p>
               <p>Counc. You say he went to Exeter, when he returned, how long after was it you saw him?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. I did not see him for three Months afterwards.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was it first that you knew his Name was Bury ?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. About two Months before I was brought to bed.</p>
               <p>Counc. How came you not to prosecute him all this while?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Because I had no Friend on Earth to go to at that Time.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go to Mr. Shippen with the Warrant.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Yes Sir, I did a little after it was taken out.</p>
               <p>Counc. Why was he not taken up sooner?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was not in my Power to do myself Justice.</p>
               <p>Counc. By what Name did you christen the Child.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person142">
                  Anne Camilla 
                  Parminter 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person142" type="surname" value="Parminter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person142" type="given" value="Anne Camilla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counc. A very soft Name, how came you to call it so?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. He told me his Sister's Name was Camilla.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who was it christened the Child?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. The Clergyman of New-North-Street Parish.</p>
               <p>Counc. What was his Name?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Indeed I don't know what his Name is very well.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you never with him at the Turks-Head Bagnio in Golden-Square?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Only once.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Month was it in?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was in the Month of January.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Year?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was after I was married 4 or 5 Months.</p>
               <p>Counc. What was the Reason you consented to be married when Mr. Seaton did not go with you?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. The longer I then knew this Man I had the better Opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Counc. You mentioned some Letters dated at Rotterdam, do you know where they were wrote.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor No Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Were they not wrote at Mr. William's House in your Presence, and at your Request.</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. No Sir.</p>
               <p>2d Counc. for Prosecutor. Who had you that Seal of?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. Of that Man.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was it before Marriage or after it?</p>
               <p>S. Proctor. It was the Day we was married.</p>
               <p>A Letter was read directed to Mrs. Proctor, at Mrs. Davidge's, Milliner, at the Three Flower-Pots, Tavistock-street, Covent-Garden. Desiring she would condescend to see him once more, and to direct for him at Mr. Bury's in Abchurch lane. Signed, H. Parminter.</p>
               <p>Another Letter,</p>
               <p>Rotterdam, June 1740.</p>
               <p>Desiring that the Marriage might be kept secret, for his Uncle was such an odd-temper'd Man, that should he hear such a Thing, he would never give him a Groat, and concluded your most affectionate Husband,</p>
               <p>H. Parminter.</p>
               <p>Another Letter, dated Jan: 20. 1740. directed to 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person143">
                  William 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person143" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person143" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; in Crutched Fryars. Wherein he declares, that he was married to his Sister, September was twelvemonth, subscribing himself his unknown affectionate Brother,</p>
               <p>Signed H. Parminter.</p>
               <p>Counc. Mr. Proctor, did you receive that Letter ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person144">
                  Wm 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person144" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person144" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Are you her Brother?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person145">
                  Wm 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person145" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person145" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did the Prisoner ever come to your House?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person146">
                  Wm 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person146" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person146" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, he came after his Marriage with my Sister, and told me, that he came to assure me, that to his Knowledge, my Sister was regularly married; I said to him, I hope you do not come to play Tricks with me, and he said, Oh Sir! not for the World; then said your Humble Servant, and went away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not tell me that your Sister had told you a great many Stories, of being married to one Parminter, that you did not believe her, and would not trouble yourself about her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person147">
                  Wm 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person147" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person147" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davdige. At the Three Flower pots in Tavistock street.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did Mrs. Proctor live with you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did Mr. Bury ever come to see her at your House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. Yes, he came twice to ask for her, the first Time she was not at Home, and I asked him to leave his Name, and he said, no, he would call again; the second Time he came, he walked in the Parlour, and was there with her, about half an Hour; I took him to be a Relation of hers.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long was Mrs. Proctor at your House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. Thirteen or 14 Months.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was she bound to you as an Apprentide ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge, Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Don't you remember any Thing of Poters coming with Messages, and fetching her from your-House.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge No Sir; she behaved as civil as and young Woman whatever.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did she never lie out of your House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. Not till the Day she was married, and then she asked me to go to her Brothers.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did she acquaint you at that Time, that she was going to be married.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge No Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pray by what Name did you call her after that ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge We called her by the Name of Parminter before she left our House.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long was that before she left you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. I can't justly tell, she told me she was married to Mr. Parminter, and after she went by that Name.</p>
               <p>Counc. When she was with Child, did he give her any Money to be discharged from you.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. She had an ill State of Health, and had the Rheumatism, and I said, I would give her Part of the Money back again; (I had 20 Guineas with her.)</p>
               <p>Counc. How much did you give her back?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. I can't tell what I proposed then to return.</p>
               <p>Council for Pris. I ask you whether she did not give you Money to be discharged?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. No Sir, I did not receive any Money.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you suspect her to be married, or with Child?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. I did not till she told me herself.</p>
               <p>Counc. When did she tell you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davidge. I cannot tell the Day, nor the Month.</p>
               <p>Mr. Winterton sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Winterton. At Chelsea, when the Gentleman came to our House, we was cutting up a Pig, and he said it looked very good, and ordered some of it for Dinner?</p>
               <p>Counc. When was this ?</p>
               <p>Winterton. About September the 27th, 1739, after they had dined, he desired me to help him to a Lodging, for him and his Wife near that Place; I called my Wife, and she got one for them at Mr. Singleton's a Gardiners.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. I live at Chelsea.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know that Gentleman ? Did he lodge at your House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long ago was it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. It is three Years ago come next Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who was with him?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. That Lady Sir, (pointing to Mrs. Proctor)</p>
               <p>Counc. In what Manner did they live at your House, as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. They went for such to us, and lay together.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did they lodge there as Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Singleton. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person148">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person148" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person148" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in King-street, Golden-square,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030013"></xptr> I knew Mrs. Proctor before she was married, she lodged a Month at my House after her Marriage, the Prisoner came to see her, and did not like the Lodgings.</p>
               <p>Counc. By what Name did she go by at your House?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person149">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person149" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person149" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She went by the Name of Parminter.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you take him for her Husband?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person150">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person150" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person150" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, I took him to be a Friend of her Husband's.</p>
               <p>Eliz Williams Sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever see the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Williams. Yes, Sir, many Times at my House; the Day the Lady was to come to my Lodgings he came and met her there, as a Friend of her Husband's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did I ever lie in your House?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Williams. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long did she lodge at your House?</p>
               <p>Williams. About 14 Months from Aug. 13, 1740.</p>
               <p>DEFENCE.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The first Time I saw this Mrs. Proctor was by Accident, I met her in Cannon-street, she had a Hat over her Face, I took her by her Air to be a Mistress of the Town, I followed her, and spoke to her, and asked her Name, which she immediately told me; I asked her to drink a Glass of Wine, she said she could not then stay, and was going to a Persons in the City, but I live says she at Mrs. Davidges a Milliner, at the 3 Flower-Pots in Tavistock-street, Covent-Garden, and there you shall be welcome to drink a Dish of Tea; in 2 or 3 Days after I went to see her, the first Time she was not at Home, the second Time I found her at Home, and we drank Tea together, when we had so done, I told her I should be glad of an Opportunity of seeing her abroad, and she said, if I would send a Message to her she would come, or let me know why she could not by a Letter. I told her to direct her Letter to Mr. Parminter, to be left at my House, that if the Letter came directed to me it might fall into my Wife's Hands, and the Thing would be discover'd; upon this she directs a Letter to Mr. Parminter, to be left at my House, which my young Man received, and gave to Mr. Parminter, who afterwards told me he had received such a Letter, but could not tell what to make of it, but he thought it might come from an old Mistress of his. After this I sent a Porter to Mrs. Proctor from under the Piazza's in Covent-Garden, and she came to me, and said that at Time she was very busy, that if I came another Day she might be more at Leisure. The next Time I sent a Porter again, and she came to me, and I called a Coach, and we went to a Bagnio, I took her up into a Room, and told her here we was private, and might stay all Night; she did not deny me any sort of Freedom, (I must do her that Justice) I sent a Porter another Time, and she came to me, and said, if you will get me a Lodging I will go with you. This second Time I had her out to the Park, and walking near Rosamon d's-Pond there was some Trees cut down, which serv'd us for a Bed, and there I told Mrs. Proctor my Name was Bury, and that I was a married Man, and said, if you will give me the Pleasure of your Conversation I shall be very much obliged to you, from that Time she sent Letters to me directed to be left at Will's Coffee-House, Cornhill. After this I went up to Jenny's Whim at Chelsea, and I asked the Man of the House to get me a Lodging, and I declare I did say that it was for my Wife, and I should bring her next Week, it was at Mr. Singleton's. The next Week she went with me, I called upon her at Mr. Seaton's in Suffolk-street, there was two Ladies at the Door, and we drove to Chelsea, went to the Whim and bespoke a Dinner; I enquired how long it would be before Dinner would be ready, and in the Interim we took a Walk in the Garden, after that went to dine at Mr. Singleton's where the Lodging was taken, and lay there two Nights; then we came down by Water, I was landed at Billingsgate, and she said she was going to her Sister's. Soon after that I went out of Town to Exeter, and saw no more of her till the Month of January, and indeed I heartily repent that I ever saw her; I believe at Will's Coffee-House I received 100 Letters from her. After I came to Town she sent a Letter desiring to see me, and that she must speak with me, or otherwise she would come to my House, accordingly I met her in Somerset Garden, and she told me a Story of her being under great uneasiness, because Mrs. Davidge had discovered that she did not come to her Brother's House till Saturday Night, and she said that made her very uneasy; I asked her if she could go out with me to Night, she said she would go with me any where, I then said we will go to a Bagnio, the next Morning<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030014"></xptr> I brought her Home again. This was the second Time we had been there, and the Woman Waiter gave her a Handkerchief she left there the Time before. Some Time after this about Midsummer, she said she was out of Order, and was with Child, and that Mrs. Davidge had a Suspicion of it, says I, I am very busy now and left her. I met her a second Time, and she said that Mrs. Davidge has intercepted some Letters, that she was big with Child, and threaten'd to tell her Brother of it; she said that her Mistress had 40l. with her when bound Apprentice, and that she expected 20 l. more if she quitted her Service. Says I, you must see and moderate the Matter with your Mistress; however I was to meet her again, and when I met her she told me that she had prevailed on her Mistress to take 12 Guineas, says I, you should speak to your Brother, it is a most abominable Imposition on me; she wept, and asked if I would let her have the Money, says I, I will give you 6 Guineas, which I did then give her to get rid of her; afterwards she told me at another Time that she had brought her Mistress down to 10 Guineas, and I gave her 4 more, and then she said she would look out for a Lodging, which when she had done she sent to me to come to her there, I saw it was a little poor Lodging, and she said she did not intend to stay there, and would look out for another. After this she sent me Word that she had found another Lodging, but refused being taken in except somebody knew her, she said she had mentioned my Name, I went up there, and the People of the House asked me if I knew one Mrs. Proctor, I said, yes, and then they took her in; after this she grew near her Time, and when she was brought to Bed she came to me, and asked me to go and see the Child, I said it was no Business of mine, and I did not go to see her for 6 Weeks or two Months after, and then the Child was at Nurse in at the next Door; she would have sent for it for me to see it, says I, I don't want to see the Child, in short, she prevailed with me at last to go and see it, and there the Nurse was, and that was the only Time I ever was there. After this she came to me, and said her Brother would be reconciled to her if I would go and tell him that she was married to Mr. Parminter, Parminter! says I, how can you mention such a Name, Mr. Parminter is a first Cousin of mine, says she, if you will write a Letter in the Name of Parminter that will satisfy my Brother, I shall go out of Town and never return again; why, says I, a Thing of this Nature may be of ill Consequence, Mr. Parminter is in London, and will (provibly) find it out, but however, by her Intreaties and Tears I was at length very foolishly brought to a Compliance, and I wrote while she was by me, and directed it, she would have me send it myself, and I said no, at the same Time I wrote Letters to her in the Name of Parminter, as from Rotterdam, there was no Post Mark upon those Letters, that I wrote them is very certain, and this she said would satisfy her, accordingly I did do it, and heard no more of her till some Days after; then she told me her Brother was not yet satisfied, but insisted upon seeing me, who was a supposed Friend of her Husband's, says I, I don't know your Brother, if he will not believe it I can't help it, says she, why will you not be so good as to go, it is but to Crutched-Fryers; at last one Morning I went, and waited for him, he came down, then I told him I waited on him at the Desire of his Sister. Sister, says he I say Sister, Sister tells me many Stories of a Cock and a Bull, and tells me of being married to one Parminter, but I do not believe any Thing about it. I said if he did not believe it 'twas no Fault of mine. After this she came to my House, and found me at Home, and said if I would write her a Letter of Recommendation, it would help her off with the Child; accordingly I did write a Letter, and in it represented that I knew her, and thought her an Object of Compassion, (whilst I was writing this my Wife came into the Compting-House) and told her this is the last Thing I can or will do for you, and when I had so said she went away, and I saw or heard nothing of her till 3 Months after that, when Mr. Shippen acquainted me that a Woman told him a Story about a Bond; after that she desired to see me there, accordingly I went, and there she run on a rig-me-roll Story, and said, that I had married her at Chelsea; when she charged me with it, I flew into a Passion, and quitted the Room, or otherwise I might have done her a Mischief. Mr. Shippen afterwards asked me why I could not keep my Temper, says I don't talk to me, I happen'd only to pick her up as a common Woman, afterwards she went to my Brother-in-law's, but however he did not think fit to send to me, but when he saw me told me, that there was a Woman that said she was married to me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030015"></xptr> but bid me take no Notice of her, for he supposed she only wanted to get a little Money out of me. After this I heard no more of her, till she had applied for a Bill of Indictment, which was in January last, the Sessions passed over and no Notice taken of it, at last brings a Warrant to Mr. Shippen, here is says she, a Warrant, and if he does not comply he will be taken up in in two or three Days Time. Mr. Shippen after told me of this, and I could not believe it; says he, you must go and enquire, and upon Enquiry I found it was so, and when I found it, I immediately gave Notice of Trial, why, says my Brother, says he, they only want a little Money of you, you had better give it them. No, says I, as it is made public I will at all Events bring it to a Hearing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person151">
                  James 
                  Legg 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person151" type="surname" value="Legg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . sworn. (seeming much afflicted with the Palsy.)</p>
               <p>Coun. What is your Business?</p>
               <p>Legg. A Porter in Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Coun. Was you so in the Year 1739?</p>
               <p>Legg. I have been a Porter this 30 Years.</p>
               <p>Coun. How long have you been in this bad Condition?</p>
               <p>Legg. About 4 Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know Mr. Bury.</p>
               <p>Legg. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you go for him to one Mrs. Davidge's to enquire for any one, with a Message.</p>
               <p>Legg. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Who was it you went to enquire for?</p>
               <p>Legg. I enquired for one 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person152">
                  Sarah 
                  Boulton 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person152" type="surname" value="Boulton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person152" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counc. How many Times did you go for her?</p>
               <p>Legg. About half a dozen Times.</p>
               <p>Counc Where does Mrs. Davidge live.</p>
               <p>Legg. In Tavistock street, Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Business was she?</p>
               <p>Legg. A Limner.</p>
               <p>Counc Was it a Man or Woman who keeps the Shop.</p>
               <p>Legg A Woman</p>
               <p>Counc. Can't you recollect what Business ?</p>
               <p>Legg Yes, a Milliner.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pray what was the Name you went to ask for?</p>
               <p>Legg. I went and asked for one 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person153">
                  Sarah 
                  Boulton 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person153" type="surname" value="Boulton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person153" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counc. Should you know her again if you saw her?</p>
               <p>Legg. Yes, there she sits (pointing to Mrs. Proctor.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was she always ready to come?</p>
               <p>Legg. Yes, she was always ready.</p>
               <p>Counc. How many Years ago was this?</p>
               <p>Legg. This Summer was 2 Years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person154">
                  William 
                  Best 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person154" type="surname" value="Best"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person154" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn, but not examined.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person155">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person155" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person155" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person156">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person156" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person156" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the Turk's-Head Bagnio in Golden Square.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know Mrs. Proctor?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person157">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person157" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person157" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen her twice at our House with that Gentleman.</p>
               <p>Counc. When was that?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person158">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person158" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person158" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A little before I came away. She left a Cambrick Handkerchief the first Time; I did not think ever to see her again, but when they came the second Time I knew them.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pray what did you hear the Gentleman call her?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person159">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person159" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person159" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard him call her Sally, and they went into a Room, and I asked if she had not left a Handkerchief here, she said, yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you take us to be Man and Wife?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person160">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person160" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person160" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long did we stay the first Time?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person161">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person161" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person161" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All Night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. How long the 2d Time?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person162">
                  Alice 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person162" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person162" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Some Hours.</p>
               <p>It was taken Notice of that this was after the Marriage.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person163">
                  Hugh 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person163" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person163" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17420603-18-person164">
                  Sarah 
                  Proctor 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person164" type="surname" value="Proctor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person164" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person165">
                  Hugh 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person165" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person165" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person166">
                  Hugh 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person166" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person166" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Bury's.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you remember any Thing of Mrs. Proctor's coming there in March last was twelve Months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person167">
                  Hugh 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person167" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person167" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came 2 or 3 Times one Afternoon, and enquired if he was within? I answer'd No, at last says she, I beg Leave to stay till he does come in; in a very little Time Mr. Bury came in, and went into the Parlour with her, and then into the Compting-House, and there was a writing, but what passed I do not know.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did she see Mrs. Bury?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030016"></xptr>H. Bennet: After they had been some Time in the Compting House, Mrs. Bury came down Stairs, and went into the Compting-House to them, but what passed I cannot tell. Mrs. Proctor saw Mrs. Bury, and took her Leave of her, and went out.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know of any Letters sent to your House, directed for Mr. Parminter?</p>
               <p>H. Bennet. Such Letters came often to our House, Mr. Bury read one of them, then flung the Letter into the Fire; before it was quite burnt, it went out, and one of the Maids I believe, had a Suspicion of something, - catched it out of the Fire, before it was extinguished.</p>
               <p>Counc. Have you got it here?</p>
               <p>H. Bennet. No, I have lost it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person168">
                  Frances 
                  Lock 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person168" type="surname" value="Lock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person168" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>F Lock. At a Public House at Chelsea.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know any Thing of Mrs. Proctor?</p>
               <p>F. Lock. Yes, I have seen her twice: She came in Company with several Persons, to our House, she went up Stairs, and told me, she was married in my Room, and desired to know if I knew any Thing of the Wedding, I said I knew nothing of it to my Knowledge, and that it was a very odd Thing for any one to offer to have a Marriage there, and not acquaint me with it.</p>
               <p>Counc. Pray can't you recollect that about Michaelmas, 1739, three Persons, a Man, Woman, and a Clergyman, came to your House, and was up Stairs together?</p>
               <p>F. Lock I know nothing of it, it was a wrong Thing, if it was done, afterwards Mr. Bury, came and asked me about the same Thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person169">
                  William 
                  Lock 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person169" type="surname" value="Lock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person169" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did you ever see Mrs. Proctor at your House?</p>
               <p>W. Lock. Never but twice, the first Time was about four Months agone, and she asked me if I saw three People come in a Coach, then went up Stairs, and staid there a little while, and neither eat nor drank, and came down again; one Mr. Compton ask'd several Questions about the same Matter, whether I could remember any Marriage about two Years ago, and I said, I could remember nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Council to Mrs. Proctor. I beg Leave to know how you got into the House?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Proctor. The Coach stop'd there with that Man in it along with me, there was that Woman stood at the Door with a Child in her Arms, he, the Prisoner, walked up, and I follow'd, and the Clergyman came into the Room immediately afterwards.</p>
               <p>Counc. Did nobody introduce you into the room?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Proctor. No body: After we was married, that Man and I came down Stairs, and went into the Coach, and the Clergyman went away.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lock was asked whether she ever remember'd a Coach coming to her House with three People in it: Said, she remember'd to have been told, that three People did come in a Coach whilst she was gone to buy Vinegar, but was gone before she came back.</p>
               <p>Counc. How long was that ago?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lock. About five Years ago.</p>
               <p>Counc. How often did Mrs. Proctor come to you about this Affair?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lock. About five or six Times.</p>
               <p>Court. You said first it was but twice, now you say 5 or 6 times.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Lock I am sure it was 4 times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person170">
                  Mary 
                  Ham 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person170" type="surname" value="Ham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person170" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person170" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know Mrs. Proctor?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person171">
                  Mary 
                  Ham 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person171" type="surname" value="Ham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person171" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes Sir, she asked me if I remember'd any private Wedding, and I said no: Then she asked me, if I remember'd a Coach coming there with 3 People in it: I said I did remember something of a Coach coming there with 3 People in it, about 5 or 6 Years agone, when Mrs. Lock was gone out to buy Vinegar.</p>
               <p>Court. How old is your Child?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person172">
                  Mary 
                  Ham 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person172" type="surname" value="Ham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person172" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person172" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . If it had lived it would have been five Years old.</p>
               <p>Court. How old was your Child when the Coach came to the Door?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person173">
                  Mary 
                  Ham 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person173" type="surname" value="Ham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person173" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person173" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can't tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420603-18-person174">
                  William 
                  Raine 
               <interp inst="t17420603-18-person174" type="surname" value="Raine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person174" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counc. Was you in Woodstreet-compter in January last.</p>
               <p>W. Raine. Yes Sir.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know one Mr. Compton?</p>
               <p>W. Raine. Yes Sir, I saw him in Woodstreet-Compter about the beginning of January last, he call'd Mr. Rider, and I went down to drink a Pot of Beer in the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you know what pass'd betwixt them?</p>
               <p>W. Raine. I know nothing but what Mr. Rider told me afterwards.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174206030017"></xptr>Court. That is no Evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kelk, sworn. I have known Mr. Bury this 18 Years, and have dealt with him for a great deal of Money.</p>
               <p>Counc. What is his private Character as to Chastity ?</p>
               <p>Kelk. If I may go by hearsay, I have heard he has been addicted to Women.</p>
               <p>Mr. Winterbottom, sworn. I have known Mr. Bury 22 Years, and he always bore the Character of a very fair Trader.</p>
               <p>Rev. Mr. Bourn I have known him between 9 and 10 Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. What is his general Character?</p>
               <p>Bourn. His general Character is that of a good Neighbour and Parishoner, I never heard any Thing bad of him.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you think he would not converse criminally with a Woman?</p>
               <p>Bourn. That I will not take upon me to say.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eldrige. I have known Mr. Bury 20 Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you think he would be guilty of such a Thing as he is charged with.</p>
               <p>Eldrige. I believe not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. I have known him these 20 Years.</p>
               <p>Counc. What Character does he bear?</p>
               <p>Brown. Bears the Character of a considerable Dealer and an honest Man.</p>
               <p>Counc. Do you think he would be guilty of the Fact he is charged with?</p>
               <p>Brown. I have heard the whole Charge, and I can't think he would be guilty of such a Crime.</p>
               <p>Alderman Lambert. I have known him more than 20 Years, I know him to be a considerable Dealer, I know nothing of his private Character.</p>
               <p>Upon offering to call Witnesses to the Character of Mrs. Proctor, the Court declared it was sufficiently cleared already.</p>
               <p>The Jury went out, and after a short Stay brought the Prisoner in <rs id="t17420603-18-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> of the Indictment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420603-18-punish74" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-punish74" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420603-18-punish74" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420603-18-defend125 t17420603-18-punish74"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
