<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430413-51">
               <interp inst="t17430413-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-51" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430413-51" type="date" value="17430413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430413-51-off296-c502" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-51-defend620 t17430413-51-off296 t17430413-51-verdict298"></join>
         
               <p>246. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-defend620" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Stuart 
                  <interp inst="t17430413-51-defend620" type="surname" value="Stuart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-defend620" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-defend620" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17430413-51-deflabel295" type="occupation">single Woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-51-defend620 t17430413-51-deflabel295"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17430413-51-off296" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-off296" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-off296" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               Murder of her Female Bastard Child, by throwing it into a Necessary-House, by which the Child was suffocated and died
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430413-51-cd297" type="crimeDate">Feb 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430413-51-off296 t17430413-51-cd297"></join>.</p>
               <p>She was a Second Time indicted on the Coroners Inquest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person621">
                  Jane 
                  Wotton 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person621" type="surname" value="Wotton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person621" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person621" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am near thirteen Years of Age; last Thursday I saw the Prisoner go by our House, between one and two o'Clock, to a Vault belonging to Mr. Burkit at Chelsea, with something under her Petticoat; about a Quarter of an Hour afterwards, I saw her come back with something in her Lap, but it was not quite so big as it was before; she had a Stick in her Hand, which was clean when she went, and when she came back it was soiled. I went to the Vault soon after, and saw some Drops of Blood upon the Seat, and I heard something blubber in the Vault. I came Home directly, and told my Mother; my Mother said some Child had been there and cut their Fingers.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Wootton (the Girl's Mother, repeated what the Child had told her). I went to the Vault myself, and there was a little Blood upon the Seat, and the Soil looked as if it had been disturbed. At Night I told an old Gentlewoman of it, that lives in the House, and the next Morning we searched the Vault, and found something that seemed to be hard and heavy; I went for a Pair of Tongs, and happened to take hold of a Child's Arm; when I saw the Child, I squalled out, and let the Child drop down again into the Vault. The Child was taken out stark naked. I did not perceive any Marks of Violence. - I live next Door but one to the Prisoner, and observed before, that she seemed to be big. I have heard she has a Husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person622">
                  Esther 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person622" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person622" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person622" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             searched the Vault with Mrs Wotton, and took up a Female Child; and said she observed the young Woman to look pretty big, but does not know how long she had gone, and that there were no Marks of Violence upon the Child. - She lives with her Mother, who gets her Bread by nursing of Children.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person623">
                  Mary 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person623" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person623" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person623" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday last, I was sent for to the Coach and Horses in Chelsea, opposite to the College-Wall; Mrs Wotton brought a Child to me, which she said she had taken out of a Vault, and desired I would search it; there were no Marks of Violence; it had the Navel String three Times round its Neck, so that it was impossible the Child could be born alive.</p>
               <p>Mr. King, the Coroner. I would ask her whether she had any Discourse with the Prisoner about disposing of the Child, and what her Confession was.</p>
               <p>Andrews. Last Sunday, the Overseers sent for me to come to the Workhouse, to meet another Midwife, to search the Prisoner. I asked her how she did, and said, I hope you have no Milk in your Breast; she cried: Said I, it does not signify any Thing to cry, tell me how it was. She owned the having the Child, but said she did not kill it, indeed I did not lay violent Hands on it. She said she was in Bed, and had the Belly-ach, and after two Pains, the Child was born; and her Husband being away from her several Years, she was ashamed of its being discovered, and she laid the Child under the Bed; and on Thursday Morning, before it was light, she put it into the Vault - She said she did not observe any Body see her do it, and that she went that Thursday with a Stick, because she had seen part of it, and took the Stick to push is down with. That the Friday before she was delivered,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174304130039"></xptr> she was helping a Man down with a Bushel and they fell upon her Belly, and she nev hold stir afterwards; that she thought Weeks to go - She said she some Things for the Child, and that such a Room; I went with her and so. there. - These are the Things. - Though to dress a Child. - I think she was her full Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person624">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bromley 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person624" type="surname" value="Bromley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person624" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person624" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed Mrs Andrew's Evidence, Relation to the Prisoner's owning of the its being still-born</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person625">
                  George 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person625" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person625" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person625" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable, deposed he found the Linner he Child, in the Room where the Prisoner him to go.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person626">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thomson 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person626" type="surname" value="Thomson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person626" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person626" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner is my Child, and never lived from me; she told her Father the Coals had hurt her. She never gave me any Account of her Condition. I told her the People said so of her, and she said they would say any Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. According to your Account, she must be very big indeed.</p>
               <p>Thomson. She said she thought she had six Weeks longer to go, and that she did design to tell me of it before then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person627">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bothmaker 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person627" type="surname" value="Bothmaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person627" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person627" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the next Room to her; I never heard any Noise of a Child. She said she had received a Hurt by some Coals, and that her Back was almost broke.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430413-51-person628">
                  Sarah 
                  Ryan 
               <interp inst="t17430413-51-person628" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person628" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-person628" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her a great many Years, and never heard any Harm of her.</p>
               <p>Mrs Andrews's Mother. The Prisoner has been married twelve Years, her Husband has been gone from her six Years. - I do not know whether she has a Husband now. <rs id="t17430413-51-verdict298" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430413-51-verdict298" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
