<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-20">
               <interp inst="t17431012-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-20" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-20" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-20-off89-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-20-defend205 t17431012-20-off89 t17431012-20-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>482. + 
               <persName id="t17431012-20-defend205" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Shudrick 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-defend205" type="surname" value="Shudrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-defend205" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-defend205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-defend205" type="age" value="27 Years of Age"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17431012-20-defloc87">Harefield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-20-defloc87" type="placeName" value="Harefield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17431012-20-defloc87" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-20-defend205 t17431012-20-defloc87"></join>, <rs id="t17431012-20-deflabel88" type="occupation">single Woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-20-defend205 t17431012-20-deflabel88"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17431012-20-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               she, on the <rs id="t17431012-20-cd90" type="crimeDate">28th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-20-off89 t17431012-20-cd90"></join>, in the 17th Year of his present Majesty, being big with a Female Child; on the said 28th of August, she, the said Female Child, by the Providence of God, privately and secretly, did bring forth alive, which said Female Child, by the Laws of this Land is a Bastard; and that she, the said 
                     <persName id="t17431012-20-person206">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Shudrick 
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person206" type="surname" value="Shudrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person206" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not having God before her Eyes, &amp;c. afterwards, to wit, on the said 28th of August, the said Female Bastard Child, feloniously, wilfully, and of her Malice aforethought, in both her Hands did take, the said Child being alive, her Hands about the Neck of the said Child being fixed, she, the said 
                     <persName id="t17431012-20-person207">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Shudrick 
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person207" type="surname" value="Shudrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person207" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said Child did choak, and strangle, by Means of which choaking and strangling, the said Child instantly died; and that she, the said 
                     <persName id="t17431012-20-person208">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Shudrick 
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person208" type="surname" value="Shudrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person208" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17431012-20-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the said Female Bastard Child did kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time charged on the Coroner's Inquest for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person209">
                  Joseph 
                  Ives 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person209" type="surname" value="Ives"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person209" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Neighbours knowing that the Prisoner had a Child; and the Child not being to be found, they thought she had made away with it; so we took her up; and then, she owned, that she had the Child dead in the House; she would have had the Neighbours have gone to have seen it, but they were afraid to go after the Child was dead - I believe the Child had been dead about a Fortnight; she had buried the Child under the Bed; it had been buried a Fortnight before any Body knew of it - she had scratched a Hole, and put the Child into it - it is an earthen Floor - she pulled it out from under the Bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person210">
                  John 
                  Warren 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person210" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (The Constable) I was ordered by the Church-Warden to take the Prisoner up, which I did, and carried her to Uxbridge; when she was examined about it; she said, she had the Child at Home; and that it was on the off Side of the Bed; I went with her Home, and she took the Child out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Child put in the Ground?</p>
               <p>Warren. Not in the Ground that I saw; she pulled the Child out from behind the Bed; I never saw the Child alive - it had been dead a Fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Marks of Violence upon the Child?</p>
               <p>Warren. I did not see any Marks of Violence; there could be no Marks of Violence to be seen, it had been dead so long.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person211">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Christwood 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person211" type="surname" value="Christwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person211" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has had a Child lately, I cannot say how long since - I believe about five or six Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q How do you know she has had a Child lately?</p>
               <p>Christwood. She looked as if she was with Child, and I do suppose she had a Child; after she had been at Uxbridge, she owned it, but not before; she said, she had put it on the off Side of her Bed; I saw the Child after it was found - I did not make any Observations on the Body - I did not see any Marks of Violence.</p>
               <p>Jury. Did the Prisoner say the Child died a natural Death, or what did she say?</p>
               <p>Christwood She did not say any Thing about that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it at its full Growth?</p>
               <p>Christwood. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. During the Time she was with Child, did she say she was with Child?</p>
               <p>Christwood I never heard her say she was - she was not a Servant; she lived with her Mother, a Widow Woman, at Harefield.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person212">
                  Sarah 
                  Webster 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person212" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person212" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner had a Child about five or six Weeks ago; the Child was carried to Uxbridge before the Justices, and brought Home again and buried; I saw it after it was carried to Uxbridge - I knew she was with Child before she was delivered; I have taxed her with it, but she denied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person213">
                  William 
                  Mellish 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person213" type="surname" value="Mellish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person213" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (Surgeon) I was called before the Bench of Justices at Uxbridge, the Day the Prisoner was before them; and I saw her, with the Child in her Lap; it was a Female Child - it had been dead about a Fortnight; it smelt very strong.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Child at its full Growth?</p>
               <p>Mellish. Yes, my Lord, she had gone her full Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any Marks of Violence upon the Child?</p>
               <p>Mellish. The Head appeared black and livid, the Face looked as if some Body had sat their Feet upon it, or sat down upon it; the Nose was flat.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether you can be at any Certainty whether the Child was born dead or alive?</p>
               <p>Mellish. I cannot be certain of that; there is an Experiment to be made, by taking out the Lungs, and putting them into Water, to see whether they will sink or swim; but I apprehend the Lungs of this Child were so putrified, that it would not have been a just Trial.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120016"></xptr>Prisoner. I am very ignorant of the Matter; here is the Childbed-Linnen, that I had provided for the Child.</p>
               <p>Mellish. She did produce such a Parcel of Childbed-Linnen as those are, before the Bench of Justices.</p>
               <p>Jury. Is her Mother living?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Mother is living, but she is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you show that you did not conceal the Death of this Child? *</p>
               <p> * Tis thought Cases of this Kind would not so frequently occur at the Old-Bailey, if the Law were more generally known, viz. 21 Jac. I. c. 27. ''Whereas many lewd Women that have been delivered of '' Bastard Children, to avoid their Shame, and to escape Punishment, do secretly bury, or conceal the '' Death of their Child, and after, if the Child be found dead, the said Women do alledge that the said '' Child was born dead; whereas it falleth out sometimes, although hardly it is to be proved, that the '' said Child or Children were murdered by the said Women, their lewd Mothers, or by their Assent, '' or Procurement. </p>
               <p>'' For the preventing therefore of this great Mischief, Be it Enacted by the Authority of this present '' Parliament, That if any Woman, after one Month next ensuing the End of this Session of Parliament, '' be delivered of any Issue of her Body, Male or Female, which being born alive, should by the Laws '' of this Realm be a Bastard, and that she endeavour privately, either by drowning, or secret burying '' thereof, or any other Way, either by herself, or the procuring of others, so to conceal the Death thereof, '' as that it may not come to light, whether it were born alive, or not, but he concealed: In  '' such Case, the said Mother so offending, shall suffer Death as in the Case of Murder, except such '' Mother can make Proof by one Witness at the least, that the Child, (whose Death was by her so intended '' to be concealed) was born dead.''</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No body was with me when the Child was born; it was in the Night in my Mother's House, but she was not at Home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-20-person214">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Christwood 
               <interp inst="t17431012-20-person214" type="surname" value="Christwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person214" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner has a Child of five Years old last Valentine's-Day, and no Woman could ever be fonder of a Child than she is of that; this Childbed-Linnen was prepared beforehand, and was shown before the Justices.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am 27 Years of Age. <rs id="t17431012-20-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-20-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>On the Coroner's Inquisition, the Jury found that the Child was Still-born.</p>
            </div1>
