<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17481012-10">
               <interp inst="t17481012-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-10" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17481012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-10" type="date" value="17481012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481012-10-off53-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-defend106 t17481012-10-off53 t17481012-10-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>+ 488 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-defend106" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Weston 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-10-defend106" type="surname" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-defend106" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-defend106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17481012-10-defloc52">St. Andrew's, Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-10-defloc52" type="placeName" value="St. Andrew's, Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-10-defloc52" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-defend106 t17481012-10-defloc52"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17481012-10-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17481012-10-victim108" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Daniel 
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim108" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim108" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , between the hours of one and two in the night, and stealing a silk gown, a cotton gown, a linen gown, a cambrick bonnet, and a woollen petticoat, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17481012-10-victim110" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Cook 
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim110" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim110" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17481012-10-viclabel54" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-victim110 t17481012-10-viclabel54"></join>; two pair of stockings, and a brass cock, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17481012-10-person111">
                        James 
                        Daniel 
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person111" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-person111" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-10-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; a cloth coat, val. 20 s. a pair of breeches, a dimitty waistcoat, and a pair of trousers
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-victim113" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Lemmon 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim113" type="surname" value="Lemmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim113" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-victim113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17481012-10-cd55" type="crimeDate">Sept. 11th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-off53 t17481012-10-cd55"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-person114">
                  Margaret 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person114" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person114" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 11th of Sept. I was entrusted by 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person115">
                  James 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person115" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person115" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to take care of his house; the watchman came up to my bed side about two o'clock, and wak'd me, and said, mistress, your house is broke open; and when I got up, I found the street door open.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fasten all the doors before you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Cook. I fastened them all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine that the thief got in at the fore door?</p>
               <p>Cook. No; I believe he got in backwards , for there is a skittle ground, and a garden ground; I believe the watchman pushed back the lock of the fore door, to come in there; and he gave me two shirts, and a pair of black silk stockings, which he took off the ground; my drawers were all open, and I missed a silk gown, a cotton gown, a linen gown, and a petticoat, &amp;c. There were two pair of stockings, and a brass cock, the property of 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person116">
                  James 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person116" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person116" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; and a coat, waistcoat, and breeches, &amp;c. the property of 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person117">
                  William 
                  Lemon 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person117" type="surname" value="Lemon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a <rs id="t17481012-10-viclabel56" type="occupation">sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-victim113 t17481012-10-viclabel56"></join>, that were taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who took them?</p>
               <p>Cook. The prisoner was the last man we let out of the house, and then we went to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What night was this?</p>
               <p>Cook . On the Saturday night; and he was taken on the Sunday morning at my Lord Cobham's head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess the fact?</p>
               <p>Cook. He said to Mr. Whitton, if he would go to such an empty house in Chancery Lane, he would find the things, and they were found there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he broke the house open?</p>
               <p>Cook. No; he said he broke open the drawers with a wire; and the Justice ordered Mr. Ind to go to the house in Chancery Lane, and there he found the things.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ind. What are you?</p>
               <p>Ind. I am turnkey of Clerkenwell Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Pris. Cook to Mrs. Cook . Did not the prisoner live over against you ?</p>
               <p>Cook . I knew him only by his coming and mending the locks .</p>
               <p>Q. I am not asking you how intimate you was with him; I ask you how long you have known him?</p>
               <p>Cook. I believe twelve months.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he come often to Daniel's house?</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes; he used to come almost every day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he spend an evening there sometimes</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this house?</p>
               <p>Cook. The Queen's Head, in Middle-row, Holborn.</p>
               <p>Q. What business was the man that lived over against you?</p>
               <p>Cook. A lock-smith.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the house that Saturday night? was not the sailor there?</p>
               <p>Cook. I cannot tell whether he was or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you to go out upon a party of pleasure the next day?</p>
               <p>Cook. I was to go and see a gentlewoman at Paddington , which is Mr. Daniel's sister.</p>
               <p>Q. Now did not he say he would find a trick to prevent you?</p>
               <p>Cook. No; he never said any such thing.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. I say it is fact, and it will turn out so; take your time, and consider whether this was not spoke in the hearing of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Cook. No; it was not said in his hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to hear of your things?</p>
               <p>Cook. By means of the watchman; for the watchman said, peggy, there is the man that has your things.</p>
               <p>Q. When you say the watchman said, Peggy, there is the man that had your things, did he tell you it was the prisoner had them?</p>
               <p>Cook. No; he said, Peggy, I hear you are robbed; he asked me what I had lost, and I told him every thing; and he said, the last man that went out of your house was 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person118">
                  James 
                  Weston 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person118" type="surname" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person118" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Pris. Did you fasten the doors and all the drawers before you went to bed.</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes; they were all fastened but one drawer, and that had no lock to it; and I went to bed at 12 o'clock, because I was to go out the next morning.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun . Was you perfectly sober at that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120012"></xptr>Cook. I cannot say I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the sailor sober?</p>
               <p>Cook . The sailor was not there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-person119">
                  William 
                  Lemmon 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person119" type="surname" value="Lemmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person119" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             [the sailor.] I lodged at Daniel's house, and went to bed about eleven o'clock on the Saturday night, when the house was robbed ; and between two and three in the morning, I heard the house was broke open and robbed. On the Sunday morning, between ten and eleven o'clock, Fox (the watchman) came, and asked me if I had been robbed, and seemed to smile; I said the house had been robbed, but not I; but I found it was so: and Fox said , if I would give him some small satisfaction, he could help me to my things again.</p>
               <p>Q. I suppose you would have been willing to have given him a small satisfaction?</p>
               <p>Lemmon . Yes; I was to have given him half a guinea, and Daniel was to have given him another half guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you who had them?</p>
               <p>Lemmon . He said he saw Weston go along between two and three with a bundle. I asked him, why he did not stop him; he said, because he knew him before, and knew him to be an honest man, and one that worked in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where Weston lived?</p>
               <p>Lemmon. No, I did not; but I knew where to find him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know his name?</p>
               <p>Lemmon . I knew him by the name of Jemmy the smith; and she called him by the name of Jemmy the smith.</p>
               <p>[The Things belonging to 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person120">
                  Margaret 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person120" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person120" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person121">
                  William 
                  Lemmon 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person121" type="surname" value="Lemmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person121" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were produced, and owned by them.]</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun . Mrs. Cook says she went to bed at twelve, because she was to go abroad in the morning. I ask you, whether you was not to go abroad with her?</p>
               <p>Lemmon . I did not know but I might go with her; or to see an acquaintance just by.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-person122">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person122" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person122" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday, the 11th of Sept. I was sent for to take a man, who had broke open a house, and I was charged with the prisoner by 
               <persName id="t17481012-10-person123">
                  Mary 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person123" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person123" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said, she was house-keeper to Mr. Daniel, at the Queen's Head, in Middle-row, Holborn; I carried him before Justice Hole, and the watchman was talking as if he saw the prisoner go down Chancery Lane with a bundle.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Ind. This was at Lord Cobham's Head . And Justice Hole said, he would be a friend to him, if he would own where the things were. The prisoner was fuddled, and he gave me directions to go to an empty house in Chancery Lane, at the end of White's Alley, and there I found the things.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get into this empty house?</p>
               <p>Ind. I went to a publick house, and borrowed a candle, and got up the wall, and went in to the house, and on the first floor I found them; there was with the things a screw driver, and a gimblet , and I took another screw driver out of his pocket, before the Justice ; the prisoner owned he took the things, and that no body was concerned with him, for he said, he would not charge any body wrongfully.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any thing of the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Ind. I never knew any thing of him before in my life.</p>
               <p>Pris. The woman that appeared here is a very bad woman, and induced me to neglect my master's business, and to do other things that I should not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dolley. I live in Holborn. I have known the prisoner three years as working with Mr. John Hill, and I never heard any complaint of him before; and as he is a jobbing smith, who is employed promiscuously at other people's houses, if he had done any thing amiss, I should have heard it. I never heard that he wronged any body; and it is such a notorious house, that people are afraid to live there.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say as to the Woman who has been the evidence against him?</p>
               <p>Dolley. I would not take her word for a pin ; for she has been the ruin of half the young men in our neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>John Hill. I am the prisoner's master; the prisoner has work'd with me near three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he work with you till he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend him to be an honest man?</p>
               <p>Hill. I do take him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would wrong you?</p>
               <p>Hill. I believe not. I took him to be as honest a boy as any in the world, 'till he got into this woman's company; and there is not a boy of fifteen years of age can go by, without being pulled in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-person124">
                  Edmund 
                  Gunter 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person124" type="surname" value="Gunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person124" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a broker. I have known the prisoner about two years and a half; his master works for me; the prisoner has been at my house an hundred times.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120013"></xptr>Q. Should you have any reason to mistrust him, if he was left in your shop?</p>
               <p>Gunter. I had no reason to think so, for he has had opportunities enough, if he had had a mind to have wrong'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of this house?</p>
               <p>Gunter. I do verily believe it as it is represented to be, a very infamous house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-10-person125">
                  William 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17481012-10-person125" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person125" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house in Middle row, Holborn. I have known the prisoner at the bar three quarter of a year and take him to be a very honest, hardworking-man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481012-10-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-verdict57" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Acquitted of the Burglary, and guilty of single Felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481012-10-punish58" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-punish58" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-10-punish58" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-10-defend106 t17481012-10-punish58"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
