<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-6">
               <interp inst="t17470225-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-6" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-6" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-6-off25-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-6-defend83 t17470225-6-off25 t17470225-6-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>134. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-6-defend83" type="defendantName">
                     Catharine 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-6-defend83" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-defend83" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-defend83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-6-off25" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-off25" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-off25" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing one Pint Silver Mug, and two large Silver Spoons, and four Yards of Thread Fringe
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-6-victim85" type="victimName">
                     Catharine 
                     Bowyer 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-6-victim85" type="surname" value="Bowyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-victim85" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-victim85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-6-off25 t17470225-6-victim85"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , of Gough-square.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person86">
                  Catharine 
                  Bowyer 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person86" type="surname" value="Bowyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person86" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know with regard to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person87">
                  Susannah 
                  Pymer 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person87" type="surname" value="Pymer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person87" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person87" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a Boarder of mine: We went into the Country together on Saturday: I intended then to stay but till Monday: This Lady came to Town the Tuesday following: I did not come home for two or three Weeks. When I came home on the Friday, as I left my Servant 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person88">
                  Catharine 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person88" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person88" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prisoner, to the Care of my House, I gave her eleven Guineas to pay away, and she came back immediately, and told me she had lost one. I was obliged to go out of Town on the Saturday. I came home on Monday Night, and I desired her to give me the Remainder of the Money, and she gave me nine Guineas, and told me, she had changed one for the Use of the House; and she would give an Account of the Things committed to her Charge. But before I got up in the Morning, she was gone. I must tell you, my Lord, when I came home on Tuesday, I saw the Pint Mug on the Dresser in my Kitchen, and the two large Silver Spoons, which I did not see when I came home; which she owned before the Justice. She went away on Tuesday Morning. She sent back the two large Silver Spoons, and Pint Mug, by a Porter, on the Wednesday before she was taken up: I took her up after she had sent these Things; because I lost a great many Things, and I could only judge her to be the Thief.</p>

               <p>Court. You had not got a Warrant for her, till she had sent these Things?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. No, my Lord; she went to a Man that curls Hair in Holborn, 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person89">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person89" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person89" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know that she was at 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person90">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person90" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person90" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's ?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person91">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person91" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person91" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent me that Word by his Apprentice, about Four in the Afternoon, that she was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought you this Silver Mug, and Spoons?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. A Porter, my Lord; he said he received them from a Woman with a red Cloak.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where the Fringe is?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. In Pawn; but I don't know where.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-6-person92">
                  Susannah 
                  Pymer 
               <interp inst="t17470225-6-person92" type="surname" value="Pymer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person92" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-person92" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you had any Conversation with the Prisoner? or do you know any thing of these Goods charged upon her?</p>
               <p>Pymer. The Mug and the Spoons she took out of the House, and sent them back again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she send the Thread Fringe back?</p>
               <p>Pymer. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know in relation to the Thread Fringe?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250010"></xptr>Pymer. My Lord, she told me that she had pawned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you for how much?</p>
               <p>Pymer. Whether it was eight or nine Shillings, I cannot say which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say to whom?</p>
               <p>Pymer. No, my Lord; but to somebody at the Bottom of Gough square.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she tell you this?</p>
               <p>Pymer. She told me at New-Prison, where she was, that she had pawned a Shirt. When I came out of the Country from Mrs Bowyer, she desired I would let the Maid have every thing she wanted; and I took Care of the House, and paid every thing myself, I laid out about forty Shillings in Housekeeping, while her Mistress was gone. The Maid took care of the House from Friday till Monday Night; she provided every thing herself, she laid out about seven Shillings of her own.</p>
               <p>Q. to Thomas Brown. What have you to say in relation to the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. On Tuesday in the Afternoon I called at Mrs Bowyer's House, to know whether she wanted me: I heard Mrs Bowyer to say that she had lost a Pint Mug, and two large Silver Spoons. I called between twelve and one o'Clock; and when she had told me of the Loss of these Things, I left Mrs Bowyer, and went home to my House. I found the Prisoner at my House: She asked me what her Mistress said about her. I told the Prisoner, that her Mistress was very much enraged against her, and would take her up, if she could be found. She desired the Favour of me, if I would be so good, as to let my Apprentice step down, and acquaint her Mistress that she was at my House. Upon this her Mistress came in a Coach along with Mrs Pymer, and desired me to keep the Prisoner till she came back again, for she was going before the Justice. I went up and told the Prisoner, that her Mistress was gone to take out a Warrant for her; but I did not offer to detain the Prisoner in the least, as I thought I had no Authority. Mrs Bowyer took her at my House.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say? Did she offer to go away?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, my Lord; the Prisoner said she pawned these Things, the Pint Silver Mug, the two large Silver Spoons, while her Mistress was out of Town, for the Use of the House.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you known the Prisoner any Time?</p>
               <p>Brown. Not before she lived with her Mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lived with her Mistress?</p>
               <p>Brown. I cannot justly say.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs Bowyer. How long has the Maid lived with you?</p>
               <p>Bowyer. Since last March, to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prisoner. What have you to say for yourself? and what Witnesses have you to call?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I have none here; I never had any Opportunity to send for any body; the Plate was pawned for the Use of the House.</p>
               <p>Court to Mrs Bowyer. She says the Plate was pawned for the Use of the House.</p>
               <p>Bowyer. My Lord, she had eleven Guineas in her Hands, from Saturday to Monday.</p>
               <p>Court. Though she had the eleven Guineas, she was not to apply them to the Use of the House by your Leave; I thought you gave her the eleven Guineas to pay to some particular Person.</p>
               <p>Bowyer. Yes, my Lord; but she had changed one.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lived with her from last March, and I wanted Money to make use of: I laid out a great deal of Money, for I never had but 16 s. of her from the Time that I lived with her.</p>
               <p>Court to Mrs Bowyer. You have not paid her any Wages.</p>
               <p>Bowyer. She borrowed 16 s. of me, that was all.</p>
               <p>Upon this Representation of the Prisoner's receiving little Wages, and her Mistress not being able to prove that she had paid her any except the 16 s. the Prisoner borrowed of her, the Jury <rs id="t17470225-6-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-6-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> the Prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
