<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420909-10">
               <interp inst="t17420909-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-10" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420909-10" type="date" value="17420909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420909-10-off51-c96" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-defend117 t17420909-10-off51 t17420909-10-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>64. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Griffiths 
                  <interp inst="t17420909-10-defend117" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-defend117" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-defend117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             
                  <rs id="t17420909-10-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17420909-10-cd52" type="crimeDate">Ninth Day of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-off51 t17420909-10-cd52"></join>, not having God before his Eyes, and in the Parish of <placeName id="t17420909-10-crimeloc53">St Giles's Cripplegate</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-crimeloc53" type="placeName" value="St Giles's Cripplegate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-crimeloc53" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-off51 t17420909-10-crimeloc53"></join> , in and upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420909-10-victim119" type="victimName">
                           Judith 
                           Haswell 
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-victim119" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-victim119" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-victim119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-off51 t17420909-10-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17420909-10-viclabel54" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-victim119 t17420909-10-viclabel54"></join>, with a certain large Piece of Brick, the said 
                     <persName id="t17420909-10-person120">
                        Judith 
                        Haswell 
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person120" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-person120" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   on the upper Part of the Head did hit; and gave her one mortal Wound of the Breadth of one Inch, and the Depth of half an Inch, of which said Wound the said 
                     <persName id="t17420909-10-person121">
                        Judith 
                        Haswell 
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person121" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-person121" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420909-10-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did die
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second Time indicted on the Coroner's Inquisition, for the Murder of 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person122">
                  Judith 
                  Haswell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person122" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person122" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person123">
                  Samuel 
                  Walton 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person123" type="surname" value="Walton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person123" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the Prisoner at the Bar throw a Piece of Brick at his Wife. - She asked him to go and carry Malt at the Peacock Brewhouse, he would not go; but taking up a Piece of Brick, said if she was not easy, he would throw the Brick at her, which he did; and then said he would throw another if she did not get away; she said a good while unconcerned, but at Length the Neighbours got her away.* - She never went by any other Name than that of Griffiths. - The Brick was almost as big as my Fist. - He stood five or six Yards from her; he bid her get away several Times, yet she would not go, and then he threw it at her with his Left Hand, it hit her pretty hard on the Head, and flew behind her.</p>
               <p>* The Breaks, in this and other Evidence, are to shew, that what follows is in Answer to Questions put to the Witnesses; which Questions are omitted for Brevity sake, the Answers denoting what they were.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if I did it designedly .</p>
               <p>Walton. To be sure he did, because he said he would, and did, throw it; and he said if I say I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090007"></xptr> will throw it, I will be as good as my Word. - I never knew any Harm of the Man before. - I think it was on a Thursday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person124">
                  Robert 
                  Rollison 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person124" type="surname" value="Rollison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person124" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person125">
                  Thomas 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person125" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person125" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person126">
                  Judith 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person126" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person126" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (as I then thought, I did not know her Name was otherwise before ) go up Three Leg Court , in Whitecross-street, I think it was the eighth of July, it was on a Thursday. I did not see the Brick thrown, but I heard Words pass between the said 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person127">
                  Thomas 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person127" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person127" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his Wife; he said, Damn your Blood, I will knock your Brains out if you do not get away. I will speak the Truth, for we must all appear before one Tribunal Judge, to be sure; he said afterwards, God damn your Eyes and limbs, if I have not kill'd you, I will kill you, and to be hanged for it I do not value it. I heard nothing else worth mentioning.</p>
               <p>Court. What was it she said to put him in such a Passion?</p>
               <p>Rollison . She gave him very provoking Words I do assure you; she damn'd him for a Rogue in an illiterate Sort of a Way, for Ignorance and Impudence meet together, it mixes very much, and God will be a righteous Judge.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That's as true a Thing as ever was spoke in this World. Ask him if he did not say he would hang me.</p>
               <p>Rollison . My Soul, is that apparent. I shall always speak the Truth; and if I say any thing amiss, I shall ask God's Pardon, not your's. I will say nothing to the Blemish of my Escutcheon .</p>
               <p>Court. Have you at any Time said that you would hang him?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I declare upon my Oath I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person128">
                  Margaret 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person128" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person128" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw him holl a Brick at the Woman, and saw the Blood come, - it was done with Violence, for it flew from her. - I do not know what Occasion was given for throwing it. - He was about 10 Yards from her - it was about half a Brickbat - I saw him have a second up in his Hand to throw at her, and he said after he had thrown one that he would do the same, for he did not value being hang'd for such a Bitch as she was. - I believe she lived about 9 Days after this happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person129">
                  Diana 
                  Brislet 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person129" type="surname" value="Brislet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person129" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw the Prisoner at the Bar throw a Brickbat at her Head, - it was thrown at her - I did not know her by any other Name than 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person130">
                  Judith 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person130" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person130" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she went for his Wife; he did take up a second Brickbat, and Mr White was the Man that took it from him, for he said , if he had struck her under the Burr of the Ear he might have killed her on the Spot; the Prisoner said , Damn the Bitch he did not value being hanged for her, for if he did kill her he was sure he should be hanged for her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person131">
                  Charles 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person131" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person131" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Surgeon. The Wound she had was down to the Skull, about one Inch and an half long, and the Skull was bare, it was about the Middle of July, she came to my Surgery in Basing-hall Street, these Wounds are frequently healed, but I believe she caught Cold in coming in the Rain, and had a Fever, and that was the Occasion of her Death; for the Membrane of the Brain was inflam'd and that caused her Death; she came to me for a Week, and I complained to the Church warden and said, she would die if she was not got into a better Place, it was for want of a warm Room and Necessaries, I believe, that was more the Occasion of her. Death than any thing else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person132">
                  Thomas 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person132" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Surgeon. I attended the Deceased for two Days; she had a large confused Wound on the upper Part of her Head: The Woman had no Symptoms of a fractured Skull, or any Injury done to the Brain when I attended her; her Head and Neck were very much tumisied, and all I did prov'd unsuccessful, the Humour was suddenly repelled and struck into her Brain: I believe she got Cold, as Mr Wheeler has said, and that was the Occasion of her Death. I do not think but that if she had not caught Cold, that the Wound might have been cured: I laid the Skull bare, and carefully examined it after she was dead, and I did not observe any Injury done to the Skull: Sometimes the Skull shall remain whole and there may be a Concussion of the Brain, I searched the Brain very carefully and it look'd as in dead Bodies.</p>
               <p>Q. How can he be indicted for the Murder of 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person133">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Haswell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person133" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person133" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Widow, when the Witnesses say she was his Wife?</p>
               <p>Rollison and Walton were called up again, and said they did not know her by any other Name than Griffiths.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person134">
                  Mary 
                  Petts 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person134" type="surname" value="Petts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person134" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person135">
                  Judith 
                  Haswell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person135" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person135" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person135" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before she departed her Life, and she said her Name was 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person136">
                  Judith 
                  Haswell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person136" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person136" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and being asked, whether the Man was her Husband, she said no, and that the Man that gave her the Blow did not do it designedly , or with a design to do her any Damage, for he was in Liquor, and she had provoked him very much, and she desired he might not come to any Damage, for she should not rest in her Grave if he did.</p>
               <p>Another Witness said she heard the very same Words.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner in his Defence said, that there was some Malt came into the Peacock Brewhouse, and he went to pump some Water, that she came and rioted him very much, that he took it patiently till he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174209090008"></xptr> could bear it no longer, and then he took up that Piece of Brickbat and hit her on the Head with it, but not with a Design to do her any Damage.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person137">
                  Mary 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person137" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person137" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a small Relation , - but very little - I am his Aunt : I was Nurse in the Work-house where this Woman died: Her Name was 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person138">
                  Judith 
                  Haswell 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person138" type="surname" value="Haswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person138" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she said she provoked him very much, and it was that Provocation occasioned is to be done, and she would not have him die for it for all the World.</p>
               <p>Rollison. That Woman that swore last is his own Mother, and she owned she was so.</p>
               <p>Court. You swore you was his Aunt; there was no Crime in swearing you was his Mother, but there is a Crime in swearing you are his Aunt when you are his Mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person139">
                  Mary 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person139" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person139" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his Mother indeed, but I am distracted, I do not know what I say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person140">
                  Judith 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person140" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person140" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the Prisoner was always a poor, harmless, inoffensive Fellow, but a little half-witted : She was a sad provoking Woman in Liquor, and would be both Master and Mistress: I was with her about two Days before she died; and she desired it might not be laid to his Charge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420909-10-person141">
                  Susan 
                  Baily 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person141" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person141" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Elizabeth arlow , and 
               <persName id="t17420909-10-person142">
                  Joseph 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17420909-10-person142" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person142" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave him the Character of a Peaceable, harmless, honest, laborious Man. <rs id="t17420909-10-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-verdict55" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420909-10-punish56" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-punish56" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420909-10-punish56" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420909-10-defend117 t17420909-10-punish56"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
