<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470909-23">
               <interp inst="t17470909-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-23" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470909-23" type="date" value="17470909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470909-23-off100-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-23-defend210 t17470909-23-off100 t17470909-23-verdict103"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090016"></xptr>338. + 
               <persName id="t17470909-23-defend210" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     May 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17470909-23-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-23-defend210 t17470909-23-alias-1"></join>Roel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-defend210" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-defend210" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-defend210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17470909-23-off100" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-off100" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-off100" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     <persName id="t17470909-23-victim212" type="victimName">
                        Joseph 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-victim212" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-23-victim212" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17470909-23-victim212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-23-off100 t17470909-23-victim212"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the King's Highway, and putting him in corporal Fear and Danger of his Life, and stealing 3 l. 12 s. and three Guineas, and 2 s. in Silver
            </rs>, the Property of the said Joseph Hall, <rs id="t17470909-23-cd101" type="crimeDate">July the 18th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-23-off100 t17470909-23-cd101"></join>.</p>
               <p>Joseph Hall Between ten and eleven o'Clock, as I was going out of the Fox Alehouse, this Woman was standing at the Corner of <placeName id="t17470909-23-crimeloc102">Russel-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-23-crimeloc102" type="placeName" value="Russel-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470909-23-crimeloc102" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470909-23-off100 t17470909-23-crimeloc102"></join>. She comes up to me, and ask'd me, Whither I was a going? And I walk'd about ten or fifteen Yards; and there was a Man came up, and she; the first Question she ask'd me was, Whither are you going? I ask'd her, What was that to her? So I walk'd on, and then she attack'd me, and thrust me up to the Wall, and took my Purse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Man do any Thing to you?</p>
               <p>Hall. I don't know that the Man touch'd me; she gave me a Blow and I fell against the Wall.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that Blow beat you against the Wall or Door; Where did the Blow hit you ?</p>
               <p>Hall. The Man was between me and the Post; then she put her Hand into my Pocket and took out the Purse that my Money was in; there was one 3 l. 12 s. Piece, and three Guineas, and 2 s. in Silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the Woman up?</p>
               <p>Hall. I was so surpriz'd I did not take her up that Night, but I said I was robb'd, and I describ'd the Woman. They mention'd her Name; they said she was got amongst her Gang to Night, but the next Morning I might find her at such a Place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry, Stop Thief, or Murder ?</p>
               <p>Hall. I was really afraid, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the Watch set at that Time?</p>
               <p>Hall. I saw none.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she use Violence to you?</p>
               <p>Hall. She forc'd me against the Wall, and put her Hand into my Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been at the Alehouse?</p>
               <p>Hall. About Half an Hour; I was Lame at that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. When was she taken up?</p>
               <p>Hall. The next Morning I saw her, and told her about the Thing, but there were three or four of her Companions, or her Accomplices; that is, People that are her daily Companions; they began to curse and swear, what did I want with her ?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find her Name out?</p>
               <p>Hall. The Constable told me her Name, and he went and fetch'd a Warrant for her, and the mean Time she was gone: The Constable told me her Name was 
               <persName id="t17470909-23-person213">
                  Elizabeth 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person213" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person213" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was this a dark Night?</p>
               <p>Hall. It was middling. It was not a dark Night, and there were Lamps, that I could discern her.</p>
               <p>To the Prisoner. Would you ask him any Questions ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw him till he employed one Macdonald, who makes it his Business to take People.</p>
               <p>Hall. Macdonald took her by Ludgate-hill, or some where.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-23-person214">
                  Sophia 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person214" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person214" type="given" value="Sophia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lodges with me. I live in Wild-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a Housekeeper.</p>
               <p>Wilson. I have a Place furnish'd of my own; I take in Washing; my Husband is at Sea on board a a Man of War. I have known her a good many Years; she ha lodg'd with me about Half a Year. The Day that he swears to is the Day when the Women play'd the Cricket-Match. This Woman went with me into the City for Mr Locke's Linen to the Back of the Royal Exchange, and stay'd there till 10 o'Clock; it was of a Monday, I can't till the Day of the Month.</p>
               <p>Q. How has she behav'd?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Very honest, and very soberly. I never saw any Thing else by her. She was with me when the Gentleman came in and gave me his Linen, and said, it was a Quarter of an Hour after Ten; he lodges at one Mrs Hunter's, the Back of the Royal Exchange.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go so late?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I went at seven o'Clock, but he was gone to the Cricket-Match, and we stay'd till he came home. And she laid in the same Bed with me, and never went over the Door afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-23-person215">
                  Margaret 
                  Bush 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person215" type="surname" value="Bush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person215" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Russel-street, Covent Garden, I am Servant to one Mr Goddard a Wine-Cooper; he came into my Master's House. My Master lives next Door to the Crown and Cushion in Russel-street, he came in, and charged me with the Watchman, and said, I was his Prisoner. He charg'd me with robbing him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hall. What House did you go into that Night to complain of your being robb'd.</p>
               <p>Hall. I believe Pullman's. I don't know her by any other Name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-23-person216">
                  Mary 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person216" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person216" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at that Mr Goddard's, and the Prosecutor came in with one Giles a Watchman.</p>
               <p>Q. What Trade does this Goddard follow?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I don't know; a Kind of a Shop. This Hall, he brings in the Watchman, I comes down and saw them with the Girl.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174709090017"></xptr>Johnson. No. I don't know any Thing of her but in a civil Way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-23-person217">
                  Margaret 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person217" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person217" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Goddard's. I was accused for the same Thing, and he carried me down Russel-street, and Covent-Garden. I sent to my Mistress, and she ask'd him, how he could charge an innocent Woman. So he discharg'd me, and said he was in Liquor, and a Fortnight afterwards he gave me 6 d. He said he had charg'd me wrongfully. This was at the Fox Alehouse in Drury lane a Fortnight after that. He offer'd me a Crown the next Morning not to come to speak for this Woman. It was at the Plough Alehouse; there were present at that Time Mr Body, Macdonald, and another Man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470909-23-person218">
                  Leonard 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17470909-23-person218" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person218" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Prosecutor's Character?</p>
               <p>Lee. He has a very good Character. My Lord, he is a very honest Man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Body. Was you at the Plough Alehouse when he offered Money to this Woman?</p>
               <p>Body. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470909-23-verdict103" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470909-23-verdict103" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
