<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430519-18">
               <interp inst="t17430519-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-18" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430519"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-18" type="date" value="17430519"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-18-off100-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-defend188 t17430519-18-off100 t17430519-18-verdict102"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-18-off103-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-defend188 t17430519-18-off103 t17430519-18-verdict102"></join>
         
               <p>266. 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-defend188" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-18-defend188" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-defend188" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-defend188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17430519-18-deflabel98" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-defend188 t17430519-18-deflabel98"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person189">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person189" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17430519-18-defloc99">St George, in Middlesex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-18-defloc99" type="placeName" value="St George, in Middlesex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-18-defloc99" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-defend188 t17430519-18-defloc99"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17430519-18-off100" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-off100" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-off100" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               feloniously receiving of one 
                     <persName id="t17430519-18-person190">
                        John 
                        Read 
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person190" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-18-person190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430519-18-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   *, 26 Pound Weight of Chocolate, val. 4 l knowing the same to be stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430519-18-cd101" type="crimeDate">November 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-off100 t17430519-18-cd101"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-off103 t17430519-18-cd101"></join>. Of which Felony, the said 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person191">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person191" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person191" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was last Sessions convicted.</p>
               <p>* See last April Sessions, No. 195.</p>
               <p>[The Record of his Conviction was read.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-victim192" type="victimName">
                  Josias 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim192" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim192" type="given" value="Josias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 16th of November last, there was 26 Pound Weight of Chocolate stole from my Shop: I had Information that there were several Persons taken up, and one 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person193">
                  David 
                  Shields 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person193" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person193" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             made himself an Evidence; and 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person194">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person194" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was last Sessions convicted of the Fact: I begged the Favour of the Court, to continue Shields in Custody, to be an Evidence against the Receivers of these Goods; which the Court was so good as to indulge me in: 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person195">
                  David 
                  Shields 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person195" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person195" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was examined before Justice Rickards , and his Examination was taken in Writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person196">
                  David 
                  Shields 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person196" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person196" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of November last, 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person197">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person197" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person198">
                  Emanuel 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person198" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person198" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (who is since dead) 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person199">
                  John 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person199" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person199" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (who goes by the Name of Cutos) and myself, lifted up a Grate belonging to Mr Taylor's Shop, and took out 26 Pound Weight of Chocolate: - That was the Chocolate, with Relation to which I gave Evidence here last Sessions: We carried it to the Yorkshire-Grey , in Rag Fair, and set there some time with it; and the other three staid there while I carried it to this 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person200">
                  Jane 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person200" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person200" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's (the Prisoner, who then lived in Cable street, but now lives at the Corner of Shorter street; she has been an abominable Receiver for a long Time) she asked me where I got it, which I was not very ready to tell her, but I told her, that I got it in Bishopsgate-street; Oh? said she, It comes far enough off, that I am not afraid of a Search; she asked me how much I must have a Pound for it; I told her, 18 d a Pound was the common Price; she said, she would give me but a Shilling, I went and asked the rest of my Companions, whether I should take it or not, and they said no; they always used to have 18 d. a Pound; but as we did not know a proper Place to sell it at, they bid me go and take it; and I had 26 s. of her for it, which is a Shilling a Pound. - She knew how I came by it, for I lodged in her<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190016"></xptr> House; I saw her deliver the Chocolate in a Hand-Basket to one 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person201">
                  Isaac 
                  Aldridge 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person201" type="surname" value="Aldridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person201" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to carry it out, in order to sell it; as I was sitting by the Fire, she showed me a Piece of Gold which she had for it, and said it was safe, for she had seen some Part of it melted down. - It was melted down because it was stamped. - This was the same Day that we stole it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Duty on this Chocolate, and the Value of the Chocolate?</p>
               <p>Mr. Taylor. The Excise Duty is 18 d. per Pound, and the Value of the Chocolate besides is about 2 s. which in the whole, is 3 s. 6 d. per Pound.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person202">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person202" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person202" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live just by the Prisoner; I lodged some Time in her House in Cable Street. - I lived there on and off about three Years. - I lived there when these Things were stole, but they were not brought there.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you know what Month it was that these Goods were taken.</p>
               <p>Davis. I know no otherwise than by their being advertised the 17th of November last.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the Prisoner live then?</p>
               <p>Davis. She was not at Home at her own House then - She was not to my Knowledge, for I did not see her.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was it you called there to see whether she was at Home or not?</p>
               <p>Davis. I was in and out every Day for a Dram. - Her Husband and her Mother kept the House.</p>
               <p>Q. For how long before this 17th of November might you be in and out every Day?</p>
               <p>Davis. I seldom missed a Day going in, since I lived there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner there on the 17th of November?</p>
               <p>Davis. She was not. - I cannot tell whether she was there on the 16th. I knew a Man that came to her House sometimes, and he said he sold these Things to a Jew in Rosemary-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Shields lodge in that House at that Time?</p>
               <p>Davis. I never was there all Night to see who lodged there. - I do not know he lodged there then, but he had lodged there.</p>
               <p>Q. to Shields. At what Hour was this that you went to the Prisoner's House?</p>
               <p>Shields. It was about eight o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Davis. They have taken other People up on this Account, and having Money, they have let them go again; and because this is a poor Woman, and has Children, and no Money to give them, she is taken up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person203">
                  William 
                  Downes 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person203" type="surname" value="Downes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I know the Prisoner to have been at my House in November last, about the Middle of the Month. I am a Rope-Maker and work in Sun-Tavern-Fields; I am a Man that goes out in the Morning, and does not come home till Night. - My House is at Mile-End. She came for the Air, and was so very bad at my House, that she laid down eight Hours in a Day upon the Bed together. - She was at my House about three Weeks.</p>

               <p>Q. Cannot you tell what Day of the Month it was that she came to your House?</p>
               <p>Downes. To the best of my Knowledge it was the 15th or 16th - I think it was not the 17th - I can tell by the Club that I belong to, which is every third Monday in the Month, and she came a Week before that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Week did she come?</p>
               <p>Downes. To the best of my Knowledge it was on a Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the Sunday before, or the Sunday se'nnight before?</p>
               <p>Downes . It was the Sunday se'nnight before.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>Downes . I cannot say to a Day, but what I have said I know to be true.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you out or at home when she came?</p>
               <p>Downes . I was at home when she came.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she ill all the Time she was at your House?</p>
               <p>Downes. She was ill all the while.</p>
               <p>Q. Now as she was three Weeks at your House, did not she when she was a little better go to Town.</p>
               <p>Downes . She never went out any farther than into the Yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that when you are at Work all Day?</p>
               <p>Downes . Sometimes I come home and lie down for an Hour or two, for we cannot make Ropes when the Sun shines; and sometimes we work till nine or ten o'Clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you work now till 9 or 10 o'Clock at Night?</p>
               <p>Downes . Yes. We begin at 8 o'Clock at Night, and work till 8 in the Morning, and sometimes we work all Day if we can hold it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then if this be your way of working, how can you take upon you to say the Prisoner did not come to Town while you were out?</p>
               <p>Downes . Because where I left her I found her: - I look upon her to be a very honest Woman; I never heard any thing to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person204">
                  Susannah 
                  Downes 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person204" type="surname" value="Downes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person204" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The Prisoner came to lodge at my Hou se the beginning of November.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you think it was the beginning of the Month , more than the middle, or the end?</p>
               <p>Downes . I think the Month was not above a Week spent .</p>
               <p>Q. Might it not be a Fortnight spent?</p>
               <p>Downes . No, I am sure it was not a Fortnight. - She was ill, and came for the Benefit of the Air , and staid, I believe, 18 or 20 Days.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she pay for it, or did you receive her as a Friend ?</p>
               <p>Downes . She paid me half a Crown a Week , tho' she did not eat a Shilling's-worth of Victuals - She used to be in my Room all Day, and lie down upon my Bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person205">
                  Michael 
                  Hildridge 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person205" type="surname" value="Hildridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person205" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner almost ever since she was a Child, and I never knew anything laid to her Charge; she has a great Charge of Children, and endeavours to get Bread for them in an honest Way .</p>
               <p>Edw Canwell . The Prisoner lives in my Neighbourhood , and behaves like a good Neighbour, she maintains her Family by buying and selling old Cloaths in Rag-Fair, is in the same Way of Dealing as I am. Nobody will say any thing to the contrary of her being an honest Woman, unless those People who carry on the Prosecution. <rs id="t17430519-18-verdict102" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-verdict102" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person206">
                  Jane 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person206" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person206" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a second Time indicted for <rs id="t17430519-18-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               feloniously receiving 2 dozen Pair of Steel Buckles, 3 dozen Pair of Bath-Metal Buckles, 3 Pair of Brass Candlesticks, 2 Pair of Brass Feet for Stove Grates, and a Brass Knob, knowing the same to be stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430519-18-cd104" type="crimeDate">Dec. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-off100 t17430519-18-cd104"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-18-off103 t17430519-18-cd104"></join>. of which Felony the said 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person207">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person207" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person207" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was last Sessions convicted.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-victim209" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Harding 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim209" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim209" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-victim209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             . On the 8th of Dec. last, I lost the Goods mentioned in the Indictment out of my Shop, and 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person210">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person210" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was last Sessions convicted of the Felony. I know the Prisoner's House is a very bad House, and have seen very bad Company frequently resort there. The Prisoner had a Son acquitted the last Sessions for want of a Prosecution, and her Husband was acquitted the Sessions before for the same Reason.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person211">
                  David 
                  Shields 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person211" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person211" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 8th of December last, this 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person212">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person212" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person213">
                  Emanuel 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person213" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person213" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (who is since dead) and myself, took the Goods mentioned in the Indictment, out of Mr. Harding's Shop in the Minories , by breaking a Pane of Glass in the Shop Window; we went directly to the Yorkshire-Grey , in Rag-Fair, with them; I carried part of the Goods to the Prisoner, she asked me where they came from; I was not willing to tell her, for I was afraid she would not buy them, because it was so near home; at last, I did tell her they came out of the Minories , facing the Flower-pot Ale-house ; that we shoved three Shutters back, and broke a Pane of Glass to take them out; (I told her this, before I sold them to her) she bid me make haste and sell them, for Fear there should be a Search; and I sold her eight Pair of Brass Candlesticks, eleven Papers of Buckles, and a Brass Knob , about seven Pound Weight, for 15 s. she called for 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person214">
                  Isaac 
                  Aldridge 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person214" type="surname" value="Aldridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person214" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and sent him out to sell them; the next Morning I told her I had got the Remainder of the Goods; said she, What is the Matter you did not bring them to me last Night, then they would have been all out of the Way. I sold her the Remainder 2 Pair of Candlesticks, and 9 Papers of Buckles for 11 s. she bid me put them into her Apron, and go to the Door, and see if nobody was there to see her come out; she keeps a very bad House - there are none resort to the House but a parcel of Boys who go out a robbing and picking of Pockets; there are some of them in my Information , - there are two Rooms on a Floor, 2 or 3 Beds in a Room, and 3 or 4 of these Boys lie in a Bed.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. Unwin the Thieftaker prompts the Man to swear against me because he wants my House, for it is a Corner-House, and has a good Trade, and he shall have it with all my Heart; I never saw any of these Goods in my Life, and should not know what to do with them if I had them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person215">
                  Margaret 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person215" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person215" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This Shields brought [took] my Husband along with him, and made a Thief of him, and they went and stole Buckles and Things; (I know nothing but what my Husband told me) he said, the things came out of the Minories; (he is dead) I went to the Yorkshire Grey , and asked Shields where my Husband was, and he told me he was gone to sell these things in Rosemary-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you told this?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-18-person216">
                  Hubbard My 
                  Husband 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person216" type="surname" value="Husband"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person216" type="given" value="Hubbard My"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person216" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came back and told them, that a Jew had bid 20 s. for them, but afterwards he sell to 17 s. and he had 17 s. for them, and they had 4 s. 3 d. a-piece, there were 4 of them; there was my Husband, one who is to be taken, another is transported, and this young Fellow Shields. - I believe it was between 8 and 9 o'Clock; he was not gone with the Things above a quarter of an Hour, or half an Hour at farthest .</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Husband carry out all that they brought into the Yorkshire Grey ?</p>
               <p>Hubbard . Yes; for they will not allow any body to leave any thing there - My Husband and Shields both came out together, and parted about 10 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Shields. Marg. Hubbard was not there when I went in, nor when I came out, and knew nothing of the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190018"></xptr> Goods till the next Morning, for she was gone out with 2 Boys a Shoplifting.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever carry any Buckles to the Prisoner at any other Time?</p>
               <p>Shields . No, I never did; I never went out a thieving with 
               <persName id="t17430519-18-person217">
                  Emanuel 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17430519-18-person217" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person217" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at any other Time but this. <rs id="t17430519-18-verdict105" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-18-verdict105" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs> .</p>
            </div1>
