<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-50">
               <interp inst="t17400903-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-50" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-50" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-50-off281-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-defend355 t17400903-50-off281 t17400903-50-verdict285"></join>
         
               <p>419. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-defend355" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Izard 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-50-defend355" type="surname" value="Izard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-defend355" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-defend355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-50-defloc280">Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-50-defloc280" type="placeName" value="Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-50-defloc280" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-defend355 t17400903-50-defloc280"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-50-off281" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-off281" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-off281" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17400903-50-victim357" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Mason 
                        <interp inst="t17400903-50-victim357" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-50-victim357" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-50-victim357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-off281 t17400903-50-victim357"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Silver Watch, val. 40 s. and a Cornelian Seal set in Gold, val. 10 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17400903-50-cd282" type="crimeDate">May 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-off281 t17400903-50-cd282"></join>.</p>
               <p>Richard Mason. On the 6th of May last, between 1 and 2 in the Afternoon, as I was going to Colney-Hatch , the Prisoner stood poring over the Side of a Pond, and said, there was a large Rat ran out. I said, it may be so. The Prisoner then came from the Pond, and about 20 Yards from it, he pick'd up a Catcher and Ball. Upon that, 
               <persName id="t17400903-50-person358">
                  John 
                  Clarke 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person358" type="surname" value="Clarke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person358" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (who was convicted for this Robbery last May Sessions) stepped up, and bought the Catcher and Ball for Six-pence; and they desired me to go with them, and drink Part of the Money out, because I was at the picking it up. I went cross the Fields with them to Mr. Spencer's, at the <placeName id="t17400903-50-crimeloc283">Adam and Eve at Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-50-crimeloc283" type="placeName" value="Adam and Eve at Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-50-crimeloc283" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-off281 t17400903-50-crimeloc283"></join>; John Clarke called for a Pint of Home-brew'd, I sat down on the Bench at the Door, but they desired me to go backwards with them; I did so, and Mrs. Spencer brought the Home-brew'd and some Bread and Cheese to us. As soon as we had set down, Clarke went farther backwards, and left his Hat, as if he was gone only to the little House. He returned to the Prisoner and me, and brought another Man with him. Then the Prisoner desired Clarke to lay a Wager of a Shilling, (in play with the Catcher and Ball,) to make the Company drink. The Prisoner and Clarke play'd for a Shilling , and then the Prisoner desired me to give him 2 Six-pences for a Shilling. I pull'd out a Guinea, and 4 or 5 Shillings, and the Prisoner snatch'd the Gui- nea out of my Hand. Then they made a Hustle, and turn'd me out at the Back-Gate of Spencer's House. Finding what Company I was in, I was glad to go off with the Loss of my Money; but they followed me beyond the 
               <persName id="t17400903-50-person359">
                  George 
                  Alehouse 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person359" type="surname" value="Alehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person359" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about a Hundred Yards from Spencer's, and John Clarke made a full Stop before me; the Prisoner kept close to my Right side; the third Man got close to me on the Left-hand, and they seemed as if they were going to something of the Game again, which they had been at before. I seem'd to draw back, and then the third Man (who is not taken) demanded my Watch; and in the Surprise and Fear, that I was in, (for they put me in fear, when my Watch was demanded,) the Man who is not taken, threw up the Flap of my Coat, and took it out of my Pocket; then he gave it to John Clarke , who ran away with it directly, over the Fields. I made after Clarke, but the Prisoner and the other stood in the Road to boggle me, and so I lost Clarke first, and the Prisoner and the other Man soon after. Upon this, I went back to Spencer's, but I could find nobody in the House, who belonged to it. The second Time I went, I saw Spencer's Wife, and told her, I had been robb'd of my Watch, by the Men who had been there. She seem'd to refuse to hear me, till I told her, I would speak to her. Then she went out at the Back-Door, and hush'd me, that I should say nothing before the Company; and at the Back-Door she told me, she was very sorry, and if I pleased to come again the next Day, which was Hanging-Day, they would be certainly there, and I might take 'em, if I brought an Officer with me; for one of the Malefactors (she said) was to be bury'd there, that Night. The next Day I took 2 Officers, and another Man, and we went thither. I desired the Men to go into the House, and see if such Persons were there. They went, and were inform'd that such a Thing had happened, and then I went in myself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you not declare that you had lost your Watch and Money at Play?</p>
               <p>Mason. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not you say, after you had been at Franklin's , that you had lost your Money and Watch at play with a Footman and 2 other Men? And did not you ask how you must come by them again?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030034"></xptr>Mason. No, I did not. The first Person I went to was Mr Justice Chamberlain, and took out a Warrant for these Men; but not knowing their Names, I went to 
               <persName id="t17400903-50-person360">
                  Henry 
                  Mould 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person360" type="surname" value="Mould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person360" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and described them to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not Mould tell you, the only Way to get your Watch and Money again, was to prosecute them, and then you'd get them again, and something for your self to boot?</p>
               <p>Mason. No; no such Thing. No one designed any such Thing.</p>
               <p>Snowden Hall. I know the Prisoner absconded after this supposed Robbery was committed. He used a House of a bad Character, - the Horse and Groom , in the Lane next to where I live, before the Fact; but he did not use it afterwards. I know the Prisoner, and he knows me; but when he was taken, he would not know me. Afterwards he confessed he knew me, but did not care to own it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person361">
                  Robert 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person361" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person361" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mason brought this Warrant to me, the 7th of May, in the Morning. Mould, and another Brother-Officer went with us to Spencer's, and we went in first, and called for a Pint of Wine, and talked to the Woman of the House. Then Mason came in, and not finding any of the Men there, we went to several other Places; but in the Evening we took 
               <persName id="t17400903-50-person362">
                  Jack 
                  Clarke 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person362" type="surname" value="Clarke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person362" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . in James-Street, Covent-Garden. The Prisoner lodg'd in the Bowl-Yard, but after this, he absconded, and went to Thomas's-Street , and from thence to Moorfields. When he was taken, he said he knew us to be a parcel of Thief-takers, and that he knew nothing of the Matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person363">
                  Henry 
                  Mould 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person363" type="surname" value="Mould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person363" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Robbery; I very well remember the Prosecutor work'd at Colney-Hatch , the 6th of May. He is a <rs id="t17400903-50-viclabel284" type="occupation">Carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-50-victim357 t17400903-50-viclabel284"></join>, and was at work, where I did the Turner's Work. In the Afternoon he came running to my House, out of Breath, and said he had been robb'd of his Watch and a Guinea, as he was going to Colney-Hatch . He described the Men to me, and I knowing such People, living in the Neighbourhood, I put it close him, - Richard, Did not you game with them? He deny'd it very strongly, and shewed me a Warrant he had to take them up, but the Warrant was for no body, for there was no Name mentioned in it. So he went to Colonel De Veil, and got a Warrant, and Clarke was apprehended very soon after. I am a Turner, and keep a Publick House; the Two Blue-Posts, at the upper end of Drury Lane .</p>
               <p>The Prisoner, in his Defence, urged that the Prosecutor first lost his Money, by wagering with Clarke that he did not catch the Ball upon the little End of the Catcher, once in 6 Times; that he af- ter this followed them out into the Road, and insisted that Clarke should lay a Guinea 6 Times against the Watch, and if he won, he was to have it. That Clarke having won the Watch, went away with it, and the Prosecutor afterwards came to the Prisoner at the George, and told him the Seal which hung to the Watch was none of his own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person364">
                  Sarah 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person364" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person364" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About May last Mason came to our House, but I can't say I saw him drink any Thing, or that I saw him with any Company, only with a Man in a green Livery, and he was sitting upon a Bench at the Door. I can't say where he went, when he went away, but about an Hour afterward he came again, and asked if his Company were gone? I told him I did not know what he meant. He asked me, if I did not know the People he was with? I said, I knew them by passing by the Door, and drinking, and that they were what We call Orange-Barrow-Men. I asked him, - What was the Matter ? He said he had lost a Silver Watch, a Guinea, and a Gold Seal. Pray what Way? and he said, by the Ball and Catcher, - upon my Oath he did.</p>
               <p>Jury. We would ask her, if he did not say he was robb'd of his Watch, &amp;c. For he might say he lost it, when the People were there with their Ball and Catcher?</p>
               <p>Spencer. He said he lost it - with - the Ball and Catcher. He did not say he had been robb'd, - to my Knowledge. - I don't know that he did.</p>
               <p>Mason. I beg she may be ask'd, if she did not tell me they were a Pack of Thieves, and that I might take them, if I would come there next Day?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I said they were a Pack of Villains, and that they had been with my Husband to treat with him about burying a Man, and the next Day being Execution-day, I judged they would come and bring the Man to be buried. I thought it was a Fraud, - and being a Fraud, I thought he might get his Things again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person365">
                  William 
                  Cheatham 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person365" type="surname" value="Cheatham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person365" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a Stove grate Maker. I don't know Mason, - but I was going to my Mistress, on the 6th of May (one Mrs Petty, at Kentish Town) and my Master bid me call at Spencer's , at the Adam and Eve at Pancras , for a Pitch-pot. When I came there I saw 2 or 3 Men at the Door, all in a Heap and I look'd in , and saw two Men playing with a Catcher. This was at about five or six o'clock at Night. I went by them into Spencer's House, and got the Pitch-pot. As I went home I met Mason, and he asked me if I had seen 2 or 3 Men pass by? and he told me he had lost his Money and Watch with the Fellow, with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030035"></xptr> Catcher, - he had lost them with playing with a Catcher. He did not complain to me of the Robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person366">
                  Charles 
                  Berriman 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person366" type="surname" value="Berriman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person366" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he heard Mould say they must keep the Prosecutor to it, now he had sworn, else they should lose their Money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person367">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person367" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person367" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner lodged with me, about a Twelve-month ago, and paid me honestly. He always kept very good Hours; and if he came home when I was a-bed, he always had the Key of the Door to let himself in; and I never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person368">
                  Nicholas 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person368" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person368" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We have entrusted him with the Key of the Door, to let himself in. He generally came home at 9 or 10 o'clock, - seldom kept any later Hours. I never lost any thing in my Life, nor ever heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person369">
                  John 
                  Thrist 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person369" type="surname" value="Thrist"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person369" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (the Executioner) was called next, (by the Prisoner) who desired he might give an Account of Jack the Catcher's Declarations concerning him; but as this was not legal Evidence, he was dismissed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person370">
                  John 
                  Arthur 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person370" type="surname" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person370" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When we went to Spencer's, I heard her say, - This Thing might be made up, very easily, for her Husband had made up such Things as these several Times. I took it with Relation to the Robbery, - I believe Mrs Spencer meant it, as the Things were won at Play.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Spencer. Did not I say, he told me, the Things were lost with the Catcher and Ball?</p>
               <p>Arthur. I don't remember it.</p>
               <p>Rhodes. I heard her say, if he would be easy, he might have his Things again.</p>
               <p>M ould. As for my Part, I can't say nothing to the Words of Mrs Spencer at this Time, for I was drinking Wine, and eating Bacon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-50-person371">
                  William 
                  Brownjohn 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person371" type="surname" value="Brownjohn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person371" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Whiston Bristow, and 
               <persName id="t17400903-50-person372">
                  John 
                  Burges 
               <interp inst="t17400903-50-person372" type="surname" value="Burges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person372" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave Spencer and his Wife a good Character, and did not believe she would perjure herself. The Jury <rs id="t17400903-50-verdict285" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-50-verdict285" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> him.</p>
            </div1>
