<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430114-30">
               <interp inst="t17430114-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-30" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430114-30" type="date" value="17430114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430114-30-off151-c329" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-30-defend392 t17430114-30-off151 t17430114-30-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140024"></xptr>103. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-defend392" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Cummins 
                  <interp inst="t17430114-30-defend392" type="surname" value="Cummins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-defend392" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-defend392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17430114-30-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430114-30-victim394" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Bond 
                        <interp inst="t17430114-30-victim394" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-30-victim394" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-30-victim394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-30-off151 t17430114-30-victim394"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Shirt, Value 20 s . a long Muslin Neckcloth, Value 2 s. a Cambrick Handkerchief , Value 3 s. and a Pair of Shoes, Value 5 s. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17430114-30-person395">
                        Samuel 
                        Bond 
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person395" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-30-person395" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430114-30-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-30-cd152" type="crimeDate">Dec. 17th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-30-off151 t17430114-30-cd152"></join> .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person396">
                  Samuel 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person396" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person396" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of Dec. last, I was coming down <placeName id="t17430114-30-crimeloc153">Snow Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-30-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="Snow Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430114-30-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-30-off151 t17430114-30-crimeloc153"></join> , from the Hand-in-Hand Fire Office, and near the Rainbow Coffee-House , I was stopped by a Man not yet taken; there was a Man stood in the Foot-way, I said, Sir, let me pass you ; he made me no Answer, but in a Minute or two I was in the Middle of 10 or 12 Men: I had a Whip in my Hand, a Great Coat and Boots on. Said I, You Villain are you going to rob me? The Man who made the Stop first, had a Stick in his Hand, which came up to his Chin, and he said, If you say a Word more, I will knock out your Brains. I said no more, but took particular Notice of the Man that fronted me, whose Breast was close to mine, and likewise the Prisoner, who was at my Left Hand, and another Person, who was at my Right: They were some Time before they could get the Things out of my Pockets, they were so fast in, and when they had, they walked gently up the Hill; said I, You Villains you have robbed me of such and such Things. Then one of them said, Do you hear the Country Cull ? he says he has lost a Shirt . I went into the Rainbow Coffee-house , staid about two Minutes , and then went to the Brush-maker's opposite to it, and told them I had been robbed, and said I would stay there a little, for I was apt to think they would come that way presently. I had not staid long, before the Prisoner and the Person who first stopped me , and another, who took the Things out of my Pocket, came by; I followed them by the Door of the Three Tuns, they were robbing a Gentleman: I took hold of two of them, and said, Sir, if you will draw your Sword, and keep the third Man from me, I will secure these two ; but the Gentleman went away. The Man who stood in the Front, gave me a violent Blow on the Head, which obliged me to quit one of the Men; I did not tumble, but it was with a great deal of Difficulty that I kept my Legs, and was again in the Middle of 10 or 12 Villains. I said, Gentlemen, I know nothing of you , I desire I may pass ; for I was afraid of my Life; the Prisoner, and two others, stood in the Front of me a second Time: A Man came up, and said, Sir, what have you lost? upon that the Prisoner and another Person run towards Field-Lane, and as they began to run, I run, and cried out, and Mr Clarke, who asked me what I had lost, got up with one of them , and was stabbed an Inch and an half in the Head. I went Home, and did not come out for three Days, I was so much out of Order from the Blow I received . The Wednesday following, just as I came out of Mr. Harris's, on London-Bridge, I saw the Prisoner, the Man who was in the Front, and the other, who was on my Right when I was robbed; I went back-to Mr Harris's, desired him to go with me, we pursued them, and at the Bottom of Fish-street Hill I got up with them, one of them goes by the Name of Black Sam: I struck at his Legs, but could not reach them, but I came up with the Prisoner, and got him into a Fishmonger's Shop. - I am a Carpenter and Surveyor to the Hand-in-Hand Fire Office,</p>

               <p>Q. This was very late in December, how could you discover a Person's Face, and remember it five Days afterwards?</p>

               <p>Bond. I saw him by the Light of a Lamp; I think I am so sure of it, that it is not possible for a Man to be mistaken.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person397">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person397" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person397" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of December, between 6 and 7 o'Clock in the Evening, I saw four Men a robbing this Gentleman; they had got something from him; the Prisoner is one of the Men, to the best of my Knowledge - I cannot positively swear to him, but he is very like one of the Four: I went up to the Gentleman on purpose to assist him, and said, Why do you let him go, I am sure he is a Pick-pocket. Then he run away, and the Gentleman and I after him; when he came near Field Lane , he said, Damn you I am at Home now. He went into an Alley, and I would not follow him any farther: I went about two Doors down Field-Lane, and was stuck with a Knife in my Head; I believe I bled a Quart of Blood; it was God's Mercy, I did not lose my Life.</p>

               <p>Mr Cook and Mr Harris gave an Account of the taking the Prisoner, agreeable to what had been given in Evidence by Mr. Bond.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing at all of what I am charged with, and hope to make it appear that I am innocent.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person398">
                  Thomas 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person398" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person398" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in New Bedford Court, in the Strand; I do not know either the Prisoner, or the Prosecutor: I was coming down Snow-Hill that Night, between 6 and 7 o'Clock, and that Gentleman said, three or four Men had hussled him, and picked his Pocket, and a Butcher, as I thought, said aloud, There is a Number of People passing; if you had cried out, they must certainly have been taken; and the Gentleman said, It was done in such a Hurry, that he could not have Time to call out.</p>

               <p>Bond. What Coat had I on?</p>

               <p>How. The Gentleman had a white Surtout Coat on that Night.</p>


               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174301140025"></xptr>Bond. I am sure you do not know me; I had a Coat almost as dark as this on.</p>

               <p>How. I get my Bread by my Pen; I was bred to the Law: I am not a sworn Attorney: I do Business for one who is Agent to Colonel 
               <persName id="t17430114-30-person399">
                  Paulet
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person399" type="given" value="Paulet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and Mr Eades of Lion's-Inn. - I do not want for Money: I thank God I live as handsomely as any Body need to live.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person400">
                  Thomas 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person400" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person400" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner 22 Years: I went to School with him. - I was with the Prisoner on Friday before Christmas-Eve: I remember it for a very particular Reason, I am sure: I called at Mr Wish's, the Corner of Hanover-Yard , over-against Great-Russel-Street, in Bloomsbury, facing Tottenham-Court-Road : The Prisoner at the Bar, and another, brought in some Pork-Stakes; and Mr Cummins (the Prisoner) asked me if I would eat a Bit: I sat down and ate a Stake; I had not seen him for four Months; and we drank, I think, to the Tune of six full Pots, and paid Sixpence-Half penny a-piece. We staid there till between eight and nine; and just as I parted from them, by a Barber's Shop in Monmouth-street, I made a little sort of a Slip, and hurt myself, so that I did not go out of my Room till the Holiday-Week: He was not five Minutes out of my Company all the While, except going into the Yard. - I keep a Chandler's Shop in Peter's-street, the Backside of St. Ann's. The Prisoner is a Vintner by Trade, and follows that Business I believe now; he does not keep a House as a Vintner, but goes to Tunbridge, Bath, and other Places, as a Drawer or Waiter: I've heard he was Apprentice in Fleet-street.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person401">
                  Nicholas 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person401" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person401" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner six Years : I was in company with him the Friday before Christmas-Eve: I went into St James's-Park to see the Gentlemen scate, and there I met the Prisoner, whom I had not seen for half a Year: We bought some Pork-Stakes, and went in to Mr Wish's and had them dressed. I never saw the other Witness before that Time: We spent Nineteen-pence-Halfpenny, an d staid till almost nine o'Clock, and in Monmouth-street I took my Leave of the Prisoner. - I live with my Brother in Earl's Court . I am a Printer, I have worked with several Gentlemen in London : I printed the Bishop of St Asaph's Works in the Country; I worked with Mr Hughes in Whetstone-Park , and with Mr Bettenham, and Mr Bowyer .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person402">
                  William 
                  Selby 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person402" type="surname" value="Selby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person402" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I lodge at Mr Goodison's in Cross-Lane, Long-Acre , and keep a Hatter's Shop. I have known the Prisoner six Years; he used to buy his Hats of me: I believe him to be an honest Man. - I never had the Curiosity to ask where he lived.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person403">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Kingston 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person403" type="surname" value="Kingston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person403" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person403" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to see Mrs Wish the Friday before Christmas-Eve; she was going out to buy some Things which were necessary for her Lying-in , and desired I would stay and assist her Husband till she came home. About four o'Clock in the Afternoon , the Prisoner and another Person came in, and I dressed them some Pork-Stakes: I believe they continued there till between 8 and 9.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person404">
                  Isaac 
                  Craven 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person404" type="surname" value="Craven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person404" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Harrow in Salisbury-Court, in Fleet-street, - the Tap-house to Mr Bell's Brew-house. - I have known the Prisoner upwards of six Years, and he always bore a good Character - He gets his Living by going up and down the Country as a Drawer or Tapster to Vintners at Horse-Races, or other publick Meetings; when he is in Town, he lodges in Queen's-head-Alley in Shoe-Lane : I take him to be an honest, industrious young Fellow.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430114-30-person405">
                  Mary 
                  Rowe 
               <interp inst="t17430114-30-person405" type="surname" value="Rowe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person405" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-person405" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . His Wife, and he, have lodged in my House eight Years. I live in Shoe-Lane: They paid 2 s. and 6 d. a Week: His Wife is sick in St Bartholomew's Hospital; she used to take in Washing or Ironing, he goes into the Country as a Tapster, sometimes stays a Month or two in Town; he has no Estate. All the Neighbourhood, I believe, would give him a good Character. <rs id="t17430114-30-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17430114-30-punish155" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430114-30-punish155" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430114-30-defend392 t17430114-30-punish155"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
