<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-4">
               <interp inst="t17460903-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-4" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-4" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-4-off14-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-4-defend56 t17460903-4-off14 t17460903-4-verdict17"></join>
         
               <p>285. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-4-defend56" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Ellingworth 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-4-defend56" type="surname" value="Ellingworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-defend56" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-defend56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-4-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               picking the Pocket of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460903-4-victim58" type="victimName">
                           Terence 
                           King 
                        <interp inst="t17460903-4-victim58" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-4-victim58" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460903-4-victim58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-4-off14 t17460903-4-victim58"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , of an Iron Tobacco-Box, containing between three and four Pounds in Money
            </rs>, the <rs id="t17460903-4-cd15" type="crimeDate">22d of July</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-4-off14 t17460903-4-cd15"></join> last.</p>
               <p>Q. (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person59">
                  Terence 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person59" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person59" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>King. The Prisoner invited my Wife and I to drink Share of a Pot of Beer with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she invite you to?</p>
               <p>King. To the Castle, by the Seven Dials.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she meet with you?</p>
               <p>King. At my own Door; we had two or three Words there; she stood at the Door and call'd me Names. It was on Tuesday Night, the 22d of July last, that we had those Words. She went to Sir Thomas to get a Warrant for me; she went late, and he was at Supper, and would not grant it to her. I follow'd her to vindicate my own Cause. Sir Thomas advis'd me to go and take a Pot of Beer with her, and make it up. As we were coming back from Sir Thomas we went into an Alehouse, &amp;c. My Wife saw her pick my Pocket, and I found it upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go to make it up ?</p>
               <p>King. We went first to the 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person60">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person60" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person60" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Bow-Street. As we went towards home she ask'd my Wife to lend her Three-half-pence, and to drink Part of a Pot of Beer, and she would be Three-half-pence. She pick'd my Pocket <placeName id="t17460903-4-crimeloc16">at the Castle near the Seven Dials</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-4-crimeloc16" type="placeName" value="at the Castle near the Seven Dials"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460903-4-crimeloc16" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-4-off14 t17460903-4-crimeloc16"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was all that Money?</p>
               <p>King. In a Tobacco-Box; there was forty-eight Shillings in Silver, and a Guinea in Gold. She was discover'd immediately. She offer'd me the Guinea back at the very Beginning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the Box?</p>
               <p>King. The Box she wanted to convey into my Pocket; I made her lay it down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are the eight and forty Shillings?</p>
               <p>King. Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person61">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person61" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person61" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             has got the Money She said, when she was carried to the Round-House, that all she had above six Shillings and six Pence was my Property. She told me, before I call'd the Watch, if I laid Hands on any of the Money she would hang me. There was but twenty Shillings in Silver, I found, and a Guinea in Gold.</p>
               <p>Q. (to the Prisoner) Will you ask any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him where the Box was taken from, and who saw the Box in my Hand?</p>
               <p>King. The Box lay in my Right-hand Pocket, and my Wife saw her take it.</p>
               <p>Q. (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person62">
                  William 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person62" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Barker. All that I know is, that she was brought to the Watch-House on my Watch Night, the 22d of July, between the Hours of Eleven and Twelve.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Barker. When she was brought there she was charg'd, by Mr. King, with robbing him of between three and four Pounds, and a Tobacco-Box.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that Box produced at that Time ?</p>
               <p>Barker. Not at that Time, but before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person63">
                  Thomas
                   De Veil
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person63" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person63" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the next Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Who produced it ?</p>
               <p>Barker. Who produced it I can't say; the Watchman said he had taken the Guinea in Gold from her before she came to the Watch-House: After she came there, I ask'd her if she had any more of the Man's Money? She said she had but six Shillings and six Pence of the Half-Guinea: She said she chang'd at the 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person64">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person64" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person64" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Bow-Street; whereas she pull'd out eight and twenty Shillings in Silver:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030007"></xptr> She said, I have six Shillings and six Pence of my own; and the other I will leave with you, for 'tis none of my own.</p>
               <p>Q. What pass'd before Sir Thomas?</p>
               <p>Barker. The Prisoner could not make any Defence; but said she did not know how the Money came into her Pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. (to the Prisoner) Would you have the Constable ask'd any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I would ask him one Question. Did I not say these Words when I came into the Round-house, that I had Twenty-seven Shillings and a Guinea ?</p>
               <p>Q. (to Barker) She would ask you besides the 6 s. 6 d. if she had not half a Guinea in Gold?</p>
               <p>Barker. She did not say so then, but the next Morning she brought a young Woman to say she had lent her a Moidore to pay for some small Trifles, but she never spoke about this until the next Morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How began this Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person65">
                  Terence 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person65" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person65" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Wife went to put her Hands up my Coats, and I did not like it from a Woman's Hands; having some Words, she wanted me to go and drink a Dram; she went to clap her Hands up my Coats. I had never knew such Doings from our own Sex; with that the Husband went to strike me. My Neighbour told me that he, 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person66">
                  Terence 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person66" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person66" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , went to fetch a Warrant for me; with that I went down to Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person67">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person67" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person67" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's to fetch a Warrant for him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17460903-4-person68">
                  Richard 
                  Curtane 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person68" type="surname" value="Curtane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person68" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What are you?</p>
               <p>Curtane. My Lord, I am a Watchman. I was call'd to the Sign of the Castle, where I saw Mr. King, the Prosecutor, and this Woman, the Prisoner. She said if she had any Guinea in her Pocket, it was his, for he had charg'd her with robbing him of Forty-eight Shillings and a Guinea in Gold.</p>
               <p>Q. Any Thing else besides Money? any mention of a Tobacco Box?</p>
               <p>Curtane. No, my Lord, not then; it was the Wife that mention'd he had been robb'd; she call'd out Watch, Watch, my Husband is robb'd: I said where is the Person that robb'd him. The Prisoner said, that if she had a Guinea in Gold, it was his; with that she put her Hand in her Pocket; pull'd out a Handful of Silver, and said if she had a Guinea in Gold, it was his.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any Thing how she came by it?</p>
               <p>Curtane. No, but Mr. King said that she had robb'd him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prosecutor sober ?</p>
               <p>Curtane. He was not sober, nor was he drunk; he was between drunk and sober, but I think his Wife was sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-4-person69">
                  John 
                  Cousins 
               <interp inst="t17460903-4-person69" type="surname" value="Cousins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman belonging to the same Walk.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cousins. What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Cousins. Between Eleven and Twelve o'Clock I heard a Noise at the Casile, so I went to hear what was the Matter. When I came I saw the Man of the House, Bartles, holding of the Prisoner, who said, you B - h you have robb'd this Man. Mr. King said he was robb'd of 48 s. in Silver, and a Guinea in Gold. The Prisoner said if she had a Guinea in Gold in her Pocket, it belong'd to that Man, so she pull'd it out herself.</p>
               <p>Q. (to the Prisoner) Will you ask him any Questions?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, to ask him if the Prosecutor's Wife was there, and what Condition she was in?</p>
               <p>Cousins. The Woman was fuddled, but the Prosecutor was neither fuddled nor sober.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, Mrs. King and I had some Words; as I stood at the Door she clapp'd her Hands up my Coats: I said I was never used so by a Woman, I don't know what you mean by it; so King and his great Brother-in-law, an Irishman, was about to strike me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-4-verdict17" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-4-verdict17" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
