<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420428-4">
               <interp inst="t17420428-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-4" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420428"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420428-4" type="date" value="17420428"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420428-4-off29-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-defend83 t17420428-4-off29 t17420428-4-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>5 + 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-defend83" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-defend83" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-defend83" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-defend83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17420428-4-defloc28">St. Martin in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-4-defloc28" type="placeName" value="St. Martin in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-4-defloc28" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-defend83 t17420428-4-defloc28"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420428-4-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a lac'd Mob, val. 1 l. 2 Linnen Aprons, val. 4 s. a silk Handkerchief, val. 2 s. a Case of Instruments, val. 4 s 28 Portugal Pieces, val. 43 l. 4 s. a 2 Guinea Piece, 9 Guineas and 15 s. the Goods and Money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420428-4-victim85" type="victimName">
                           Martha 
                           Hammers 
                        <interp inst="t17420428-4-victim85" type="surname" value="Hammers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-4-victim85" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420428-4-victim85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-off29 t17420428-4-victim85"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in her Dwelling house
            </rs>, March 29.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person86">
                  Martha 
                  Hammers 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person86" type="surname" value="Hammers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person86" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th Day of March last, the Prisoner robb'd my House in <placeName id="t17420428-4-crimeloc30">Hungerford-Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-4-crimeloc30" type="placeName" value="Hungerford-Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420428-4-crimeloc30" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-off29 t17420428-4-crimeloc30"></join>, of a Mob, 2 Aprons, and several other Things mention'd in the Indictment, and about 50 l. in Money. They were taken out of the Drawers in my Bed-chamber. The Prisoner had been my <rs id="t17420428-4-deflabel31" type="occupation">Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-defend83 t17420428-4-deflabel31"></join> about nine Months before, and I did not mistrust her 'till I was informed by one 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person87">
                  Mary 
                  Hutchinson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person87" type="surname" value="Hutchinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person87" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person87" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that such a Person had such and such Things which I knew to be mine. Upon that I went to seek after them. I took the Prisoner up and carry'd her before Justice Copeland in Surrey, where she own'd the Fact and sign'd her Confession?</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any other Knowledge of her taking these Things but by her Confession?</p>
               <p>Hammers No; the Prisoner was search'd in the Watch-house by the Constable's Orders before she went to the Justice's, and there were found upon her a 3 l. 12 s. piece, two 36 s. pieces, a Guinea and 2 s. the rest of the Money was taken from another Person whom she gave it to, and who is a Prisoner in the King's Bench, his Name is Loveit.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know it was in his Hand?</p>
               <p>Hammers. 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person88">
                  Ann 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person88" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person88" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me she had deliver'd the Money to him. When this Money was taken from the Prisoner, she told me I might say what I pleas'd, but she never wrong'd me in her Life, but she had my Cap upon her Head at that very Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person89">
                  Ann 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person89" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person89" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person89" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner and I lodg'd together in East Smithfield. On Monday about 6 o'Clock, - I can't tell how long ago it was, but I got up and let in the Prisoner. She had been out all Night, and she told me she had got her Money from her Mother in Law. She shew'd me a great many pieces of Gold in a little Trunk; they were very large pieces, and there were a great many of them. She went out and bought herself some Things, and then bought me a Gown, a pair of Stays, and a pair of Shoes, and made me a Present of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person90">
                  Mary 
                  Hutchinson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person90" type="surname" value="Hutchinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person90" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person90" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner went out between 7 or 8 on the Sunday Night, and said she was going to her Mother's to receive 20 l. that was left to her: I believe it was about a Month ago. She came Home between 5 and 6 next Morning, and this Woman (Robinson) let her in. She said her Mother refus'd to let her have the Money, but her Father had taken the Pocket Apron out of a Drawer and had given it to her. She likewise said she had got four Guineas, but I saw none, only some Silver and Half-pence, and a Case of Instruments; I am no Judge of Instruments, but it was a pretty large Bath-metal Case, and she shew'd me besides, a clasp Knife and a Bath-metal Thimble.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person91">
                  Joseph 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person91" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person91" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Constable. I saw the Things in this Bag taken from the Prisoner in the Watch-house. I had one 3 l. 12 s. piece, and two 36 s. pieces, a Guinea, 2 s. a lac'd Mob and this Instrument-case from the Prisoner herself; the rest of the Things I had from 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person92">
                  Beaumont 
                  Loveit 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person92" type="surname" value="Loveit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person92" type="given" value="Beaumont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person93">
                  Andrew 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person93" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person93" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This lac'd Mob, I saw on the Prisoner's Head.</p>
               <p>King. These are all the Things that I have. This Mob was deliver'd to me in the Watch-House, but there was such a 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person94">
                  Hurley 
                  Burley 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person94" type="surname" value="Burley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person94" type="given" value="Hurley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person94" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that I can't tell from whence it was taken, but the Prisoner gave it to me, and she was bare headed. She gave all the rest of the Things to me, and said there was all she had left of her Mistress's Mone, and that 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person95">
                  Beaumont 
                  Loveit 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person95" type="surname" value="Loveit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person95" type="given" value="Beaumont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had taken the rest from her. Upon that I took my Staff, and went directly to Loveit's; - he is a Bencher by the Marshalsea. I knock'd at the Door and ask'd him for the Money: he told us, his Girl had burnt the Trunk which it was in; but he pulled down a little Box like a Chest of Drawers, and produc'd this Money. I told him he had better return it; but he refus'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174204280007"></xptr> to deliver it to me, so he went with us to the Watch-House, and laid down 19 l. 13 s. in the Prisoner's presence, and said, that was all he had; the Prisoner answer'd, No, Mr. Loveit, you have more.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. This Mob and Instrument Case are mine, and were lost out of my House with the Money. The Prisoner confess'd when she was at the Watch-House that she had conceal'd herself in my House all Night, and that the Money which was taken from her was mine.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see your Money last before you miss'd it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix I saw it that very Day in the Child's Trunk in my Drawer.</p>
               <p>Hutchinson. This is the same Instrument Case that the Prisoner shew'd to me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Anderson. I went with Mrs. Hammers in quest of the Prisoner to her Lodging, but she was gone out. We were very industrious in enquiring after her at several Places, and at last we took her in Kent street, and carry'd her before the Constable in the Watch-house, and upon searching her, these Things were found upon her. When this Money was taken out of her Pocket, she said that was all the Money she had: I ask'd her what she had done with the rest? for it was but two Days after the Robbery, and there was 60 l. 9 Shillings lost in all. Robinson inform'd me, that the Prisoner had given the rest of the Money to 
               <persName id="t17420428-4-person96">
                  Beaumont 
                  Loveit 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person96" type="surname" value="Loveit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person96" type="given" value="Beaumont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I then applied to Mr. King for Assistance, to go to Loveit, and we accordingly went to him. I desired him to deliver the Money to the Constable, but he refus'd for some Time; at last he agreed to go with us to the Watch-House, and did deliver the Money in the Prisoner's Presence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420428-4-person97">
                  John 
                  Hodder 
               <interp inst="t17420428-4-person97" type="surname" value="Hodder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person97" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman. On the 31st of March, between 10 and 11 o'Clock, Mrs. Hammers and Mr. Anderson came in a Coach to the Watch House, and ask'd for the Constable. I told them my Master King was gone into the Borough and so my Fellow Servant and I went with Anderson, and took the Prisoner in the Boot Alehouse. She made her Escape from us, and got into Boot Alley, and there we took her again, and brought her to the Watch-House. We found in her Pocket a 3 l 12 s. piece, a 36 s. piece, a Guinea, and some Silver, and the Mob was upon her Head when we put her into the Cage, but she afterwards took it off, and gave it to Mr. Anderson. We then went to Loveit's, and he brought the rest of the Money to the Watch-House.</p>
               <p>Pris. Loveit and this young Woman got me in Liquor, and they both held together to take the Money from me as soon as I had got it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17420428-4-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17420428-4-punish33" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420428-4-punish33" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420428-4-defend83 t17420428-4-punish33"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
