<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17481012-34">
               <interp inst="t17481012-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-34" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17481012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-34" type="date" value="17481012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481012-34-off196-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-34-defend325 t17481012-34-off196 t17481012-34-verdict199"></join>
         
               <p>+. 517 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-defend325" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Glover 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-34-defend325" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-defend325" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-defend325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17481012-34-defloc195">New Inn Green, in the county of Kent</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-34-defloc195" type="placeName" value="New Inn Green, in the county of Kent"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-34-defloc195" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-34-defend325 t17481012-34-defloc195"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17481012-34-off196" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-off196" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-off196" type="offenceSubcategory" value="taxOffences"></interp>
               he, together with divers other persons, to the number of fifty, on the <rs id="t17481012-34-cd197" type="crimeDate">twenty-fourth October, 1746</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-34-off196 t17481012-34-cd197"></join>. at the parish of <placeName id="t17481012-34-crimeloc198">St. Margaret's, at Cliff, in the county of Kent</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-crimeloc198" type="placeName" value="St. Margaret's, at Cliff, in the county of Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-crimeloc198" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-34-off196 t17481012-34-crimeloc198"></join>, were assembled together with fire arms, and other offensive weapons, in order to be aiding and assisting in running, and landing uncustomed goods, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Call 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person326">
                  David 
                  Croud 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person326" type="surname" value="Croud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person326" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Croud. Above a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you on the twenty-fourth of October at St. Margaret's Bay , in the county of Kent?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What October?</p>
               <p>Crowd. October 1746.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you then see any vessel hover about the shore?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a vessel was it?</p>
               <p>Crowd. It looked like a cutter.</p>
               <p>Q. I think you was at one French's house?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes; and I staid there all night, and till twelve o'clock at noon the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when the smugglers came there?</p>
               <p>Croud. It was about eleven o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you go out to see how many there were of them ?</p>
               <p>Croud. I went out of the house when they came by, and they ordered me and French's to go in and stay there, and in a little time they came<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120032"></xptr> down upon the Cliff on the Beach, and I saw the goods brought on shore, and saw them load their Goods .</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a moon light night?</p>
               <p>Croud. It was starlight .</p>
               <p>Q. How far might the company be from this house when you saw them?</p>
               <p>Croud. About twenty rods.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near enough to distinguish the number of people upon the Beach?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the horses loaden with ?</p>
               <p>Croud . Some with oil skin bags, and others with casks .</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think were in the oil-skin bags ?</p>
               <p>Croud. I suppose it to be tea, it is the common paccage of run tea.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with any of them when they came upon the Beach ?</p>
               <p>Croud. The officers detected them, and then they fell to beating the officers , and knocked one of them down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Glover among them?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes; he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any arms?</p>
               <p>Croud. Yes; he had a carbine slung upon his shoulder , and he desired me to help him upon his horse, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What arms had the rest?</p>
               <p>Croud. Some had pistols , and some had carbines.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they all armed?</p>
               <p>Croud. I cannot say; a great many of them were armed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen Glover frequently before that?</p>
               <p>Croud. I had seen him very often.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. What induced you to go to French's house, and stay there till eleven o'clock at night?</p>
               <p>Croud. I staid there all night, and staid to keep them company.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your place of abode?</p>
               <p>Croud . At Staining Mins.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Croud . I am a labourer.</p>
               <p>Q. I think you say you was at French's house, when you saw the smugglers, how far distant were they from you then?</p>
               <p>Croud. They were just by, and ordered us to go in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you then see 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person327">
                  Thomas 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person327" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person327" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Croud. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you first saw the prisoner?</p>

               <p>Croud. When he was loaded, when he came back from the watcp the hill.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is this from the house ?</p>
               <p>Croud. About two rods .</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the Beach?</p>
               <p>Croud. About twenty rods from the water side .</p>
               <p>Q. Was he on horseback , or on foot?</p>
               <p>Croud . He was on foot when I first saw him and I helped him up upon his horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Now among this number of people and that time of night , I ask you whether you will not be mistaken ?</p>
               <p>Croud. I am sure I am not, for I was as him , as I am to that gentleman; I asked them something to drink , and they said they would not give me any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a starry night?</p>
               <p>Croud . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any n ?</p>
               <p>Croud. I cannot tell whether there was or it but it was a clear night.</p>
               <p>Q. What clothes had on?</p>
               <p>Croud. He had blush thes on.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you saw him on the Beach?</p>
               <p>Croud. About four in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person328">
                  Isaac 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person328" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person328" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called.</p>
               <p>Coun. for the Cro. I think you keep a publick house at St. Margaret's Bay ?</p>
               <p>French. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any number of people being there last Oct. was twelve month.</p>
               <p>French. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were at your house?</p>
               <p>French. There were four or five people.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person329">
                  David 
                  Croud 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person329" type="surname" value="Croud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person329" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there?</p>
               <p>French. Yes; he staid all night, and went away the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the number of people that were coming by the house?</p>
               <p>French. No; but some body bid us keep in.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember whether Croud mentioned the names of any particular persons that were in this gang?</p>
               <p>French. I cannot say; if I don't mistake he said he knew some of them, but I don't remember their names.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. The defendant was married but two days before this, he was married the twenty-second of October 1746 . and went to the house of one Snowton, and staid there till the twenty-fifth.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120033"></xptr>Mr. Forman. I am clerk of Goodneston, near Feversham , in Kent.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person330">
                  Thomas 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person330" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person330" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's being married, and when?</p>
               <p>Forman. Yes; he was married the twenty-second of October.</p>
               <p>'' The certificate was produced by Mr. Forman; '' 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person331">
                  Thomas 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person331" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person331" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was married the twenty-second '' of October 1746. at Goodneston, near Feversham , in Kent, to 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person332">
                  Mary 
                  Chittenden 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person332" type="surname" value="Chittenden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person332" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; it is signed by the parson, and it is signed by me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were they married by?</p>
               <p>Forman . By Mr. Gerrard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person333">
                  William 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person333" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person333" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . produced a copy of the register , and compared with the register.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did they go to afterwards?</p>
               <p>Forman. To Mr. Snowton's, and I went with them .</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that off?</p>
               <p>Forman. About two miles and an half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you on the twenty-third, or twenty-fourth of October, see the prisoner at any place?</p>
               <p>Forman . I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person334">
                  Robert 
                  Snowton 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person334" type="surname" value="Snowton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person334" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Snowton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner a married man?</p>
               <p>Snowton . Yes; he was married the twenty-second of October 1746, at the parish church of Goodneston .</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from St. Margaret's Bay .</p>
               <p>Snowton. About twenty-two miles; after the marriage, they went to my house, and he was at my house the next day?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you keep a publick house, or a private house ?</p>
               <p>Snowton. I keep a publick house, within a mile of Goodneston .</p>
               <p>Q. Did they lye at your house?</p>
               <p>Snowton . No.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him next?</p>
               <p>Snowton. On the twenty-third in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. What day were they married on?</p>
               <p>Snowton. On the Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a horse?</p>
               <p>Snowton. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the horse stay in your stable?</p>
               <p>Snowton. From Wednesday till Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Thursday?</p>
               <p>Snowton. I saw him on Thursday morning .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Friday?</p>
               <p>Snowton. cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Saturday?</p>
               <p>Snowton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time on the Saturday?</p>
               <p>Snowton. About noon .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person335">
                  John 
                  Foreman 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person335" type="surname" value="Foreman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person335" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Pris . Coun. Look on the prisoner, do you know him?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect the time of the marriage ?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you scholar enough to recollect the day they were married?</p>
               <p>Foreman. They were married on the Wednesday</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them on the Friday?</p>
               <p>Foreman . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time on Friday?</p>
               <p>Foreman. About sun down, between five and six o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that?</p>
               <p>Foreman. At Wharton on the Green, about a quarter of a mile from Snowton's .</p>
               <p>Q. Did they lie at your house?</p>
               <p>Foreman. No, it is one building, there is a little wall parts us.</p>
               <p>Q. And are you positive you saw them two days after they were married?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing of their going to bed?</p>
               <p>Foreman. I heard them stamp.</p>
               <p>Q. So you heard some motion?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see them on the Saturday morning?</p>
               <p>Foreman. About sun rising.</p>
               <p>Q. What time is that?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Between eight and nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How many hours had the sun been up, when you saw them?</p>
               <p>Foreman . The sun does not rise till seven o'clock, at that time of the year.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Foreman . At Wharton on the Green .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live with the young woman the prisoner married?</p>
               <p>Foreman. It is all made one roof, but it is not one house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it on the Friday morning, or the evening that you saw the prisoner? Did you see him at all on Friday?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120034"></xptr>Foreman. Yes; I saw him about sun set.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that ?</p>
               <p>Foreman. In the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was him?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. How can you take upon you to say, you heard him and his wife go to bed, because you heard a stumping? Did you go to labouring in the morning?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Yes; but I saw him before I went.</p>
               <p>Q. I suppose this was at sun rising, yes? How long was it before any body spoke to you about this affair, after the man was married.</p>
               <p>Foreman. I cannot tell whether it was a week, or a fortnight, or a month.</p>
               <p>Q. Who spoke to you about coming to give this evidence?</p>
               <p>Foreman. Mrs. Glover, herself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person336">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Filmore 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person336" type="surname" value="Filmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person336" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17481012-34-person337">
                  Thomas 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person337" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person337" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the time of their marriage?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it on?</p>
               <p>Filmore. It was on a Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. And were they actually married?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you continue there?</p>
               <p>Filmore. That night and the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner after?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Not till Saturday morning, between seven and eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any boots on?</p>
               <p>Filmore. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any riding stockings?</p>
               <p>Filmore. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he look as if he had been going a journey?</p>
               <p>Filmore. No, he was but just up, and I breakfasted there, and I got there between seven and eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you got there before nine?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say you was there before eight?</p>
               <p>Filmore. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How far do you live off?</p>
               <p>Filmore. About two miles.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>Filmore. I was going to Canterbury market .</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it?</p>
               <p>Filmore. On a Saturday.</p>
               <p>Joseph Hill . I am a husbandman, I have a little farm of my own.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the time of their being married?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was it?</p>
               <p>Hill. The twenty-second of October, and it was on a Wednesday, I was at the wedding.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Thursday?</p>
               <p>Hill . I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Friday?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time?</p>
               <p>Hill. Between three and four in the afternoon, at Broughton .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the Saturday?</p>
               <p>Hill . I saw him about two at noon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-34-person338">
                  William 
                  Champney 
               <interp inst="t17481012-34-person338" type="surname" value="Champney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person338" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Esq; sworn .</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. I think you are a commissioner the revenues in Ireland, and a Justice of pence for the county of Kent.</p>
               <p>Champney. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner at the bar ?</p>
               <p>Champney. I have known him twenty years, and during which time, I have always looked upon him as an honest industrious man; and he has worked for me, my father is an old infirm man, or he would have been here to have given him a character; he is above fourscore years of age. The prisoner is a tenant of my father's, and rents 12 l . a year of him, I have a brother of his that has lived with me this twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear that the prisoner was a smuggler?</p>
               <p>Champney . My Lord, I believe all the people on the coast are given to smuggling, I have heard he was , but I do not know that he is.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. to Gibson. I think you are steward to Mr. Champney.</p>
               <p>Gibson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. And as steward to Mr. Champney, how long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Gibson. I have known him thirteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. And what is his character?</p>
               <p>Gibson. He has a very good character in his neighbourhood, and always had the character of an honest, judicious, laborious man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481012-34-verdict199" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-34-verdict199" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
