<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440404-29">
               <interp inst="t17440404-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-29" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440404"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-29" type="date" value="17440404"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440404-29-off168-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-29-defend324 t17440404-29-off168 t17440404-29-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>219. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-defend324" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Cooper 
                  <interp inst="t17440404-29-defend324" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-defend324" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-defend324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440404-29-defloc167">St. George the Martyr</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-29-defloc167" type="placeName" value="St. George the Martyr"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-29-defloc167" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-29-defend324 t17440404-29-defloc167"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440404-29-off168" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-off168" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-off168" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four cloth coats, value 3 l. a cloth waistcoat, value 10 s. a pair of cloth breeches, value 5 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-victim326" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Caswell 
                  <interp inst="t17440404-29-victim326" type="surname" value="Caswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-victim326" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-victim326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-29-off168 t17440404-29-victim326"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17440404-29-viclabel169" type="occupation">Esq;</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-29-victim326 t17440404-29-viclabel169"></join> 
                  <rs id="t17440404-29-cd170" type="crimeDate">March 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-29-off168 t17440404-29-cd170"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person327">
                  Richard 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person327" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person327" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner brought this coat to me. I had seen an advertisement of Mr. Caswell's the day before, and took it to be one of his coats. I asked the Prisoner how he came by it. He said he bought it of an acquaintance of his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174404040018"></xptr> who's out of place, in order to make a surtout coat. I advised him to go with me to Mr. Caswell's, and he went very readily .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person328">
                  Thomas 
                  Croon 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person328" type="surname" value="Croon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person328" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Monday, the 5th of March, I lost this coat out of the stable. I went to supper about nine o'clock, and left the lad in the stable; and I went back into the stable about ten o'clock, and my coat, waistcoat, and great coat were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not a large dog in the yard?</p>
               <p>Croon . Yes - he always does bark at strangers - I don't know the Prisoner - I know no body can get into the stable, without 'tis somebody the dog knows.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gillman. I lodge at Mr. Matthews's , and was in the shop when the Prisoner brought in the coat. The advertisement was read, and nothing could be painted more exact than this. I advised Mr. Matthews to stop the Prisoner, and go to Mr. Caswell's. The Prisoner would have gone away. I said, Friend, you must not go; you must go to Mr. Caswell's. He said he bought it for eight shillings, that he was then very much in liquor, and did not know the man he bought it of. - To tell you the truth, Sir, said he, I was dead drunk, and don't know the house where I bought it ; but afterwards he said, he had it of one Newman, who was servant to Mr. Caswell. I asked him, if he knew of any of the rest of the things. He said, he did not know any thing of them, I spoke to the Justice to have the house searched where he lived, and he ordered the door to be broke open. And then the Prisoner, rather than have the door broke open, pulled a key out of his pocket; and then he said they were in his room, and they were sent for; and these clothes were brought, which I judge to be the same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I discover that I had the clothes, before the butler?</p>
               <p>Gillman. I can't tell what you said to the butler, but before me you said you knew of no more than that numerical coat which is there produced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person329">
                  George 
                  Caswell 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person329" type="surname" value="Caswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person329" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; deposed, that after the Prisoner was committed, he went to see him, though he knew nothing of him; but the Prisoner knew him immediately, and declared, that he had been often all over the house and stables with Newman, during the time the house was repairing , which was about a year and an half ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person330">
                  Edward 
                  Bownan 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person330" type="surname" value="Bownan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person330" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner three years , he always was esteemed a very honest man, and I would entrust him with my property, notwithstanding this affair . I was informed that Mr. Newman was suspected of taking the clothes; and I did endeavour , on the behalf of the Prisoner, to get Newman taken up. I went to Mr. Caswell, and told him, it was hard an innocent man should suffer, when the principal might be taken; and desired Mr. Caswell to let somebody belonging to him make an information of this fact before the Justice, in order to get a warrant to take up the principal: but I could not get his assistance, and I could not get a warrant to take him up.</p>
               <p>To this Mr. Caswell replied, That he did apply to the Justice to grant a warrant to take up Newman; but that the Justice did not think proper to grant it for the reason, that if goods are found upon a person, and a warrant was to be granted upon their information, every one would say the goods were brought to them, and by that means every person might be acquitted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person331">
                  George 
                  Dowdell 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person331" type="surname" value="Dowdell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person331" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner eleven years, he has done a great deal of business for me in the upholders way. I have left him and his wife solely in my house when I have been in the country for four months together, and always found every thing as I left it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-29-person332">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17440404-29-person332" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known him eight or nine years; that he lodged with him five years, and always behaved well; and that he never saw him drunk in his life. <rs id="t17440404-29-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-29-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
