<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420714-11">
               <interp inst="t17420714-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-11" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-11" type="date" value="17420714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-11-off53-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-11-defend88 t17420714-11-off53 t17420714-11-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140004"></xptr>13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-defend88" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Young 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-defend88" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-defend88" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-defend88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17420714-11-defloc52">St. Martin in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-defloc52" type="placeName" value="St. Martin in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-defloc52" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-11-defend88 t17420714-11-defloc52"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17420714-11-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting Martha the Wife of 
                     <persName id="t17420714-11-person89">
                        George 
                        Washington 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person89" type="surname" value="Washington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-11-person89" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-11-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , near the King's High-way, putting her in Fear, and taking from her a Leather Pocket, val. 1 d. and 42 s. in Money
            </rs>, the Goods and Money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-victim91" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Washington 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim91" type="surname" value="Washington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim91" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17420714-11-cd54" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-11-off53 t17420714-11-cd54"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-victim93" type="victimName">
                     Martha 
                     Washington 
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim93" type="surname" value="Washington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim93" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-victim93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . I was going down <placeName id="t17420714-11-crimeloc55">Denmark Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-crimeloc55" type="placeName" value="Denmark Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-11-crimeloc55" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-11-off53 t17420714-11-crimeloc55"></join>, and the Prisoner Young came upon me on a Surprise, put his Hand down my Bosom, and took out a Leather Pocket, in which was 42 s. and gave it to another Man; there was a Woman with them, and she cried out, Cut her Throat; no says he, I will not cut her Throat, I have got her. Money, and she can't go to Law with us now. I did not hear the Man he gave the Purse to make any Answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been any Time acquainted with me?</p>
               <p>Washington. I have known him a good while, he <rs id="t17420714-11-deflabel56" type="occupation">kept the Bull and Butcher in Clare-Market</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-11-defend88 t17420714-11-deflabel56"></join>; I gave him a Groat for roasting a Green Goose for me, and he cut the Wings off. I know him to be the Person who robb'd me; I am sure of it, if I was this Minute to die, I would swear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did I come before or behind you?</p>
               <p>Washington. I cannot say which, he came upon me all on a sudden.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the Purse down your Stays?</p>
               <p>Washington. It was but a little way down, for I am pretty loose, and cannot go strait-laced, he laid hold of me on the Shoulder before he took the Money, then he run his Hand down and took it out, and then gave it to the other Man. - I think he laid hold on my Shoulder first, I cannot say he hurt my Flesh.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you under any Surprize when he took hold of your Shoulder?</p>
               <p>Washington. I was under some Surprize to have some Body lay hold of my Shoulder, and see a Man behind me and know nothing of it. -</p>
               <p>Q. Do you always put your Money in your Bosom?</p>
               <p>Washington. I generally do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you declare before Col. De Veil, that the People met you, and did not come behind you, but before you?</p>
               <p>Washington. No. For I cannot be certain which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you offer before Col. De Veil to make this Matter up, and give him a general Release?</p>
               <p>Washington. No, I never did, I will abide by that, I will till the Day I die. It was about 10 o'clock at Night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I leave my Defence to those Persons who were at Supper with me that Night, and staid till Eleven o'Clock; this is done out of Spite; I was informed against by her, for selling of spirituous Liquors, whereby I incurred the Penalty of ten Pounds. She has rioted me, and swore she would have my Life a great many Times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-person94">
                  Joshua 
                  Brogden 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person94" type="surname" value="Brogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person94" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Col. De Veil's Clerk to get a Warrant against the Prosecutor, for obstructing the Prisoner in the Execution of his Office as a Bailiff, and had a Warrant against her. The Prisoner did afterwards indeed agree to give a Release, for I told him he had better do it: When she came to charge him with the Robbery, Young brought half a Score-Witnesses, who could swear he was in his House all Night, till about Eleven o'Clock.</p>
               <p>- Saltmarsh. I was at Young's House from Half an Hour after Nine, I am positive, to half an Hour after Ten that Evening, and Young was not out of the House; 'tis in Eagle-Court, facing Somerset-House. And from thence to Denmark-Court is about as far as from hence to the End of the Old Baily.</p>
               <p>- Tooly. I was in Company at Young's House on Wednesday the 30th of June, this Day Fortnight at Supper on Mackarel; I went there at half and Hour, or a Quarter of an Hour after 9, and stand till near 11. The Prisoner was there all the Time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-person95">
                  Jonathan 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person95" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person95" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there from half an Hour after Nine till near Eleven, he was there all the Time, there were some Women a scolding, yet he would not go out, but said, D - n the Women they are always a scolding; I heard the Prosecutor say the same Day the Robbery was committed, D - n you, you Dog, I will be revenged on you.</p>
               <p>Mrs Biggs and Mrs West confirmed the above Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-person96">
                  Stephen 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person96" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person96" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prosecutrix is a wicked vile Woman, she said Young had used her ill in saying she had inform'd against him for selling of Gin, and wanted to have a Warrant for him, I think it was this Day Fortnight, but said nothing of robbing then.</p>
               <p>- Halfpenny. I heard her threaten Young and say if she could not hang him herself somebody else should.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-11-person97">
                  Martha 
                  Washington 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person97" type="surname" value="Washington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person97" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             desired to call some Persons to her Character; 
               <persName id="t17420714-11-person98">
                  William 
                  Salisbury 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person98" type="surname" value="Salisbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person98" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17420714-11-person99">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Poet 
               <interp inst="t17420714-11-person99" type="surname" value="Poet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person99" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known her 12 or 13 Years, and never knew any harm of her. <rs id="t17420714-11-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-11-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
