<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17471014-2">
               <interp inst="t17471014-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-2" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17471014"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17471014-2" type="date" value="17471014"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17471014-2-off7-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-2-defend37 t17471014-2-off7 t17471014-2-verdict9"></join>
         
               <p>379 + 
               
                  <persName id="t17471014-2-defend37" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Lickner 
                  <interp inst="t17471014-2-defend37" type="surname" value="Lickner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-defend37" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-defend37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17471014-2-defloc6">Saunders in Kent</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-2-defloc6" type="placeName" value="Saunders in Kent"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17471014-2-defloc6" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-2-defend37 t17471014-2-defloc6"></join>, was indicted, and the Indictment sets forth, <rs id="t17471014-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="taxOffences"></interp>
               That he together with 
                     <persName id="t17471014-2-person38">
                        Thomas 
                        Reynolds 
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person38" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471014-2-person38" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17471014-2-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and divers others not yet taken, on the 26th of September, at Hawkhurst in Kent, was armed with Fire arms, and other offensive weapons, unlawfully and feloniously aiding and assisting in carrying off uncustomed Goods, and Goods liable to pay Duties, which had not been paid, or secured; against the Statute in that Case made and provided
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person39">
                  Stephen 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person39" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person39" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. Give my Lord and the Jury an Account, when you saw him.</p>
               <p>Gosling. On the <rs id="t17471014-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">26th of September, 1746</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17471014-2-off7 t17471014-2-cd8"></join>. I saw the the Prisoner at the Bar, in Company with several others, arm'd with Fire-arms.</p>
               <p>Q. What Number were there?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I believe about eight or ten. The Prisoner was arm'd with a Brass Gun, and a Brace of Pistols. They were all on Horse-back, and had several drove Horses; they had with them several Half-Anchors and Oil skin Bags. I believe there might be eight or ten drove Horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what Gang it was?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I can't tell. He had People that he used to harbour in his House, which they used to call his Gang.</p>
               <p>Q. What are Oil skin Bags made use of for?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Oil-skin Bags are made use of purely to put Tea in. They are generally thrown on the Horse's Saddle, one on one side, and the other on the other side.</p>
               <p>Solicitor-General. I ask you, Whether Tea, that comes over run in that manner, is not generally put up ready to be thrown upon the Horses.</p>
               <p>Gosling. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Tea brought over by any other Persons in that Ways ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the whole Gang arm'd?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who makes use of these Half-Anchors ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. The Smugglers chiefly. They are flung on both ones of the Horse; and they sometimes contain Rum and sometimes Wine.</p>
               <p>Q. About what Size might there Cases be?</p>
               <p>Gosling. They might be, to the best of my Knowledge, about four Gallon.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. I think they can't be imported by Act of Parliament in those small Casks; they can't be imported under sixty Gallon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know Merchants, or fair Dealers, import their Tea in Oil-skin Bags?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Never in my Life.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination.]</p>
               <p>Council. What are you?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I am an Attorney.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you acquainted with the Manner of Merchants bringing Goods?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I am unacquainted with the Manner of Merchants bringing Goods.</p>
               <p>Council. This Fact you speak of was in September was a Twelvemonth.</p>
               <p>Gosling. It was the 26th of September 1746.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you give an Information against this Man for Smuggling?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I can't say, it was a little before the last Assizes.</p>
               <p>Council. Then it might possibly be in August; how can you recollect particularly September 1746, now you can't give an Account of the Day or the Week?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I know it was before the Assizes; I think it was some time in August; he was committed to Maidstone Goal in June; I charged him with the Fact before.</p>
               <p>Council. Why did you not charge him before?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Because I had been in the North of England, I did not dare to do it till there was a Party of Dragoons down.</p>
               <p>Council. I think you charged him upon something of your own Prosecution?</p>
               <p>Gosling. He was acquitted of that by the Act of Grace.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140005"></xptr>Q. Had you never a Dispute, or Law-suit, with him? Did you not declared Mr Merchant, that you borrowed some Swords in order to kill Tickner?</p>
               <p>Gosling. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you buy these Swords of?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Of one Barthalomew Thompson.</p>
               <p>Council. I ask you, upon what Day was it you charged this Prisoner at the Bar to be enquired after ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I gave an Information to Mr Cook for robbing of me, as well as riding thro' the Parish of Hawkhurst.</p>
               <p>Attorney General. I should be glad to know, whether the 26th of September was the only time?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I saw him the 4th of August before; I have seen him at divers other times before, but I can't take upon me to lay any particular Day.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. Then you did not dare to give this Information till you had a Party of Dragons?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I liv'd at Hawkhurst for some time, and was forc'd to quit the Parish and leave my Business, for I was in Danger of my life.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. Had you the Assistance of any Dragoons, of Foot Soldiers ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. There was a Party of Dragoons down about Goudhurst and Hawkhurst, and he was taken up by that Party of Dragoons, and what they call the Militia.</p>
               <p>[Cross Examination.]</p>
               <p>Council. You are upon Oath; I would ask you, whether you had not a Quarrel; and whether you had not Sheep and Oxen, from time to time, when you was pleased to command them?</p>
               <p>Gosling. The case is this, if I must relate the whole Story. When I first came to settle in the Parish of Hawkburst, the Prisoner employed me to sue one Sorrel, who was indebted to him four or five Pounds; I sued Sorrel to a Writ of Enquiry. Before I could take him up, he was committed to Maidstone Goal upon the Account of Horse-stealing, and I did not care to proceed any further. When he came out again, Tickner required me to pursue it; upon which I desired my Money, which was ten or a dozen Pounds; I ask'd him several times for my Money: I knowing the Man's case, offered to take it at ten Shillings a time as he could spare it; he promised me he would. After this, he brought me a Sack of Wheat, and a Hog, or two Bushels of Wheat, and a Hog; that is all I had: Upon his bringing these Things, he gave me a Note of Hand for eight or nine Pounds. I had divers times asked him for this Money; he would say, he would pay me this time and that time, and at last, that he would never pay me; he said, if I ask'd him for it he would whip me, or Horse pord me: With that I said, I would not ask him by Word of Mouth. After this, he rod after the Officer, with a drawn Sword, thro' the Parish of Hawkhurst.</p>

               <p>Council. When was this Affair of all this Law?</p>
               <p>Gosling. It was a matter of six Years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you the nineteen Lambs ?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Last July, or August after, I had got a Judgment.</p>
               <p>Q. What Dealings had you with him between 1744 and 1746?</p>
               <p>Gosling. No Dealings; but endeavoured to get my Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not a Pair of Oxen and a Stear, and nineteen Lambs and Sheep?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Yes; these I had in July last.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this did you give this Information?</p>
               <p>Gosling. He was in Custody, and in Goal; when I had these Goods of him; says he, If you will let me loose, I will pay you the nineteen Pounds? I said, Peter, if you like well to pay me the nineteen Pounds, or give me Value for it, you may: I will, says he, if you will give me a Release? I said, Peter, I will do you justice, if you will do me justice.</p>
               <p>Council. How came he to pay you when he was in Custody?</p>
               <p>Gosling. Because he thought to make a Friend of me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He told me, if I would pay him eighteen Pounds, nine Shillings, he would release me. I told him, I had not Money: He told me, If I would pay him, he would release me, and I should be the sooner Home to my Family.</p>
               <p>Court. Did you say any thing to him of that sort?</p>
               <p>Gosling. No, I never did say so.</p>
               <p>- Buckler. I have known the Prisoner three or four Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live?</p>
               <p>Buckler. In Saunders.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his usual Business?</p>
               <p>Buckler. He has been a Smuggler.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him smuggling?</p>

               <p>Buckler. I saw him last September was a Twelve-month.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see him?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I saw him in Hawkhurst.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they armed?</p>
               <p>Buckler. All armed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner armed?</p>
               <p>Buckler. He had a brass Blunderbuss, and a Brass of Pistols.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140006"></xptr>Q. Had the Gang any Number of load Horses?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they carrying?</p>
               <p>Buckler. They had Oil-skin Bags, and Half-Anchors; I take the Bags to be full of Tea.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual to bring it over from beyond sea in these Oil skin Bags?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. In what way do they make use of them?</p>
               <p>Buckler. They lay the Bags upon the Horses, one of one side, and the other on the other side.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual for Merchants and Traders to carry Tea in Oil skin Bags?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they carry in the small Tubs ?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Brandy; they hold about four Gallons, the Half-Anchor.</p>
               <p>[ Cross Examination.]</p>
               <p>Council. Are you Servant to Mr Gosling?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Yes, Sir; I have been Servant to him three Years and three Quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you his Clerk?</p>
               <p>Buckler. No, a common Servant.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you come out of his Service?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Last Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do after Christmas ?</p>
               <p>Buckler. He releas'd me at Christmas; he lived at Maidstone since Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times have you seen him since Christmas?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I have seen him three or four times. I saw him this Spring there.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you saw him since Christmas. - Is he a Housekeeper?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I can't say whether he keeps House, or whether he boards with another.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you left him?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I left him on the Twelfth-Day.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I live at Cranbreak, about twelve Miles from Maidstone.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I saw him at the Bull.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him after that?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I saw him last Week.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the second Time you saw him ?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I saw him last Week, and I saw him on the Twelfth Day.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you how many times you saw him after you had left him, before Midsummer last? Did ever any Massenger go from one to another in that time?</p>
               <p>Buckler. None at all. I saw him at Twelfth tide, and I saw him last Week.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw the Prisoner at Hawkhurst, what sort of a Horse was he upon ?</p>
               <p>Buckler. It was a grey-Horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he Oil-skin Bags upon his Horse?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you hear of this Man being taken up?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I heard of it last night.</p>
               <p>Q. Never before?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I can't tell; I believe it was a Month before.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came to speak to you about it?</p>
               <p>Buckler. It was a young Man that belongs to the Army.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr Gosling never speak to you about it?</p>
               <p>Buckler. He told me of it last Week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever speak to you about it before?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I don't remember he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he desire you to do?</p>
               <p>Buckler. He did not desire me to do any Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember it was the 26th of September?</p>
               <p>Buckler. Because I was loading Goods for Mr Gosling; and I remember the Loading that Day, and that Day I saw this Gang, and that help'd me to be so particular.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Day was it that you saw the Prisoner and others together ?</p>
               <p>Buckler. I take it to be between ten and eleven.</p>
               <p>Attorney General to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person40">
                  John 
                  Hepbourn 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person40" type="surname" value="Hepbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner? Give an Account to the Court of his Behaviour, when he was apprehended.</p>
               <p>Hepbourn. I was ordered upon a Party to take the Prisoner for smuggling; as we had Information we went, about four o'Clock in the Morning we came within sight of his House.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day was it?</p>
               <p>Hepbourn. It was of a Sunday last June; accordingly a Party of our Men went down to the Front of his House, and I and another, that knew him, went down backwards; accordingly as we were down in the Field I happen'd to see the Prisoner making his Escape with nothing but his Shirt on from the Backdoor; accordingly I stopp'd him, and bid him to stand, or else I would fire at him; accordingly he ask'd me, What I wanted with him? The other Man, that was with me, knew him, and said, it was Rough Tickner. I said he was rough enough, and he should go with me; Upon that I said he should go<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140007"></xptr> to the House and put his Clothes on. He went up and put his Clothes on, and we had him before the Justice of Peace. We were told, if we did not make half we should not light of him. When I took him he had he was going to case himself. I said, he need not to so far to case himself.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Now is your Time to make your Defence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, I never sent a Shilling out of the Nation in my Life. I never had a Bag of Tea in my Life. Never, never, had any Horse; and 'tis a malicious Prosecution by Gosling.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person41">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person41" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person41" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did Gosling ever buy any Swords of you?</p>
               <p>Thorp. He never bought any of me; he borrowed four Swords of me, but never paid me any Thing for them.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person42">
                  Robert 
                  Merchant 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person42" type="surname" value="Merchant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person42" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person43">
                  Stephen 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person43" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person43" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? What is his Character? Is he a Person to be credited upon his Oath?</p>
               <p>Merchant. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person44">
                  Joseph 
                  Luller 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person44" type="surname" value="Luller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person44" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person45">
                  Stephen 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person45" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person45" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Luller. I have known him for about three Months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you privy to some Actions between Gosling and Tickner?</p>
               <p>Luller. I never saw Tickner in my Life; but Gosling sent for me to buy some Stock, and while I was there Mrs Tickner was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Gosling say whose Goods they were?</p>
               <p>Luller. He said he had the selling of them upon his own Account. The Wife of the Prisoner was present in the Room. I bid Money for them, and Gosling said the Stock was aside over to him; so I bought the Stock of him, and paid him for it. He promis'd that he would be a Friend to Mrs Tickner, and get her Husband out of Goal as soon as possible. I paid him six Pounds for them. He promis'd Mrs Tickner to meet her at Mr Cook's, and get her Husband out of Gaol.</p>
               <p>Q. What Day of the Month was this?</p>
               <p>Luller. The 2d of July.</p>
               <p>Attorney General. Did he promise to get him out of Gaol?</p>
               <p>Luller. Yes, Sir, he did several Times, that he would do all that was in his Power.</p>
               <p>Gosling. I promis'd to be a Friend to her upon Conditions: I never promis'd but to do him Justice.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. What, was that to get him hang'd? That was what you promis'd the Woman; did you?</p>
               <p>Council to Luller. Did he say any Thing before the Justice of getting her Husband hang'd?</p>
               <p>Luller. He said he would do all that lay in his Power to the getting of him out.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17471014-2-person46">
                  Richard 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17471014-2-person46" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person46" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What have you heard Gosling say about Tickner?</p>
               <p>Holder. When I fetch'd the Bullock about a Mile out of Town, I believe he had been in Gaol about a Week or Fortnight, I did not see Gosling all the Time I was there</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Gosling at all?</p>
               <p>Holder. I saw him often before and after.</p>
               <p>Attorney-General. Do you know Tickner? What is his Employment?</p>
               <p>Holder. A Farmer.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he no other Employment?</p>
               <p>Holder. He keeps a pretty large Farm.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear he was a Smuggler?</p>
               <p>Holder. I have heard he has; and I have heard he has not; and he is a considerable Farmer at Saunders.</p>
               <p>Council for the Defendant. This Act of Parliament is against those that are arm'd with Fire-Arms, in order to be aiding and assisting in running and carrying away uncustomed Goods. This is laid to be uncustomed Goods. For my part, I don't know what uncustomed Goods are. Here's nothing appears that there are any Goods. Here's carrying something in Bags: Because Smugglers carry Tea in Oil-skin Bags, it therefore must be Tea. The Attorney General takes Notice of this extraordinary Point of Law, and submits it to the Court. This Evidence given to the Court and Jury is not sufficient to maintain the Indictment, because 'tis required by Act of Parliament, in order to bring a Person within the Description of this Act, that they go arm'd to the Number of Three or more; but the going arm'd alone is not sufficient to bring him within this Act of Parliament; but it must be in aiding and assisting in running and carrying away uncustomed Goods. Now, though 'tis fully prov'd, that the Person did thus appear with Arms, and some Goods, yet it does not appear they were uncustomed Goods.</p>
               <p>Attorney General. I readily grant these Things must appear to the Satisfaction of the Jury. It must appear to the Jury, that the Prisoner was armed, and that is proved by two Witnesses uncontradicted, and among seven Witnesses produced, there is not out of them produced to shew, whether he was not concerned in that Transaction with Arms and Fire arms mentioned; and there is not one single Word said by way of Objection, by Witness, or Council at the Bar. What is the next, in order to be assisting; in the first place, this is matter fact, which the Jury are to judge of; but, say they, it must not depend upon presumption, but by a Person seeing the Tea; now there is nothing more certain that that Fact is not necessary the Witness seeing of it, any more than seeing a Man kill another in the dark; if this kind of Rule is to be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174710140008"></xptr> laid, no one could be convicted, because no Witness saw him; but the Law knows otherwise, this Court knows otherwise, this Jury knows otherwise; that is the case here; it is not pretended that they saw the Tea taken out of the Bag, neither need that be proved; Circumstances are sufficient to prove to the Jury, that this was uncustomed Goods, it appears that they were just in the manner that all uncustomed Goods are; this has been proved by the Witnesses, which the known Experience of Mankind see it to be, and this is the only Commodity brought this way; the Witnesses have proved it to be so, and have the Gentlemen attempted to give an Account how this Man came to go with eight or nine Persons armed in a lawful legal Trade; let an Account be given, if possible, how eight Men, going in this way, with driven Horses, and Oil skin Bags; thus with respect to the Tea, the other with respect to Brandy, that they carry in these small Casks, made use of in all smuggling Ways, as being small and portable; and the Law itself has taken so much Notice, that Brandy in small Casks so imported, is forfeited, Ship and Goods; the Law has not made it necessary, in orde r to prove Persons guilty of this Crime by the Witnesses that saw the Goods unpack'd; the Law is made, upon this presumption, that by the Help of their armed Force they might prevent their being stopp'd; if it wants any thing, it is a negative Evidence on their Side; let any one of their Evidence be examined with respect to his Character; 'tis the strongest presumptive Evidence in the world, that the Man does not bring one Witness, to say, that they do not believe him to be a Smuggler.</p>
               <p>The Jury could not credit Gosling's Evidence, therefore the Prisoner was <rs id="t17471014-2-verdict9" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17471014-2-verdict9" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> of this Indictment; but was ordered to be continued in Custody by another Charge against him.</p>
            </div1>
