<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470429-5">
               <interp inst="t17470429-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-5" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470429-5" type="date" value="17470429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470429-5-off18-c53" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-5-defend60 t17470429-5-off18 t17470429-5-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>180. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-5-defend60" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Baker 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-5-defend60" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-defend60" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-defend60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470429-5-off18" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-off18" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-off18" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               privately stealing five Guineas , two Half Guineas, and a Six and thirty Shilling Piece
            </rs>, the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470429-5-victim62" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Tedman 
                  <interp inst="t17470429-5-victim62" type="surname" value="Tedman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-victim62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-victim62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-5-off18 t17470429-5-victim62"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17470429-5-cd19" type="crimeDate">March 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-5-off18 t17470429-5-cd19"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470429-5-person63">
                  Thomas 
                  Tedman 
               <interp inst="t17470429-5-person63" type="surname" value="Tedman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-person63" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I went into a House in <placeName id="t17470429-5-crimeloc20">James's-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-5-crimeloc20" type="placeName" value="James's-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470429-5-crimeloc20" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470429-5-off18 t17470429-5-crimeloc20"></join>, where this Creature was; the Woman of the House seeing of me in Liquor, said I would advise you to go to Bed , she lighted me up Stairs, and this Woman followed.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I can't say justly, it might be about five or six Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>Tedman . Into a House in James's-street, near the Hay-market .</p>
               <p>Q. What is the House?</p>
               <p>Tedman. They sell Liquor, I believe 'tis a bad House .</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I am a Farmer.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night was it you came into this House ?</p>
               <p>Tedman . It was late at Night.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you go into this House for?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I was fuddled, I was like other fuddled Men, I wanted more Liquor .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by yourself when you came to this Place?</p>
               <p>Tedman. Yes .</p>
               <p>Q. What then ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. The Woman of the House would have me go to Bed; I went and laid down upon the Bed, and this Woman came and laid down by me. I knew very well I had that Money in my Pocket , and I found her Hand in my Pocket, I am positive of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Cloaths on ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. Yes, my Lord , and this Woman came and lay by me.</p>
               <p>Q. What Money had you when you lay down?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I looked at my Money just when I went into the House, and I had five Guinea, two Half Guineas, and a Thirty-six Shilling Piece and some Half-pence in another Pocket .</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in the House before you went up Stairs?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I went up Stairs directly as soon as I came into the House.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you laid on the Bed before this Woman came?</p>
               <p>Tedman. She came directly .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire her to come?</p>
               <p>Tedman. No, my Lord, she came of her own Accord, and lay down by me, and I felt her Hand in my Pocket ; she took my Money out, and absconded directly .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do upon that?</p>
               <p>Tedman. Then I came down Stairs directly, and went out of the House.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say nothing about it ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I said nothing to no Body, but went and laid down at another House all Night, and went to that House again in the Morning, and said such a one has picked my Pocket; the Woman of the House said, I wondered she went away in such a hurry, I thought she had done something amiss, I was not above half an Hour in the House the whole Time .</p>
               <p>Court . If you was in Liquor, how could you remember all this? When you felt the Prisoner's Hand in your Pocket, and missed your Money immediately , did you not endeavour so apprehend her ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. It was late, and I did not .</p>
               <p>Q. When you felt her Hand in your Pocket , did you make no Resistance? you let her have it, you never opposed her?</p>
               <p>Tedman. No, my Lord, I did not .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you acquainted with her before ?</p>
               <p>Tedman. Yes my Lord, several Times; I knew her about the Place, my Hay-cart stands opposite the House .</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been acquainted with the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Tedman . I can't say, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174704290007"></xptr>Court . You had some Kindness for her, perhaps, that made you willing to let her have your Money ? Have you any thing further?</p>
               <p>Tedman . Here is a Witness; when we found her the next Day, she owned the Money, and gave me Six pence as Part of the Money.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Name of the Person that keeps this House?</p>
               <p>Tedman. Her Name is Goodroad.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner . You hear what the Witness says ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . He swears wrongfully against me, I was not with him .</p>
               <p>Q. to Tedman. You say it was late, was it Twelve or One?</p>
               <p>Tedman. I don't know but it might, my Lord.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I was with Tedman the next Day, when he found the Woman, and she said she found the Money upon the Bed, and that she gave a Six and thirty Piece to one, and two Guineas to another ; and that she had bought Cloaths with the rest; Tedman asked her if she had none left ; yes, said she, I have Six-pence left, and gave it him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Tedman. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Tedman. At a Place called St John's Wood .</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner . What do you say for yourself ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There was another young Woman that lived in the House, she asked me to go up Stairs with her to help her make the Bed, then she took up a Thirty-six Shilling Piece in particular , and some other Gold, and said, here's Money; I said how should Money come there ? Please yes, my Lord, she gave, me three Guineas and an Half to buy me some Cloaths, and I laid it out in Cloaths; and, my Lord , I have been robbed of all my Cloaths; the Prosecutor did say he would take the other young Woman up, he said she ought to be punished ; the Prosecutor went from that House to the next Bawdy-house in the same Street; the Bawd stripped me of what Cloaths I did buy, and never sent me a bit of Bread, since I have been in Goal .</p>
               <p>The Prisoner to Tedman . Have not I been with you a great many Times ? did I ever wrong you of a Farthing?</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Who are your Parents?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am not ashamed to own who my Parents were; my Father was a wholesale Carcase Butcher, at the Corner of Cow-cross .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470429-5-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470429-5-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
