<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490113-11">
               <interp inst="t17490113-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-11" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490113-11" type="date" value="17490113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490113-11-off56-c72" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-11-defend96 t17490113-11-off56 t17490113-11-verdict59"></join>
         
               <p>106. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490113-11-defend96" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Osborne 
                  <interp inst="t17490113-11-defend96" type="surname" value="Osborne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-defend96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-defend96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17490113-11-defloc55">St. Martin's in the Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-11-defloc55" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-11-defloc55" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-11-defend96 t17490113-11-defloc55"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17490113-11-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               for a Rape committed on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490113-11-victim98" type="victimName">
                           Susannah 
                           Tabart 
                        <interp inst="t17490113-11-victim98" type="surname" value="Tabart"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-11-victim98" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490113-11-victim98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-11-off56 t17490113-11-victim98"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17490113-11-viclabel57" type="occupation">infant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-11-victim98 t17490113-11-viclabel57"></join> under 10 years of age; and a second time for knowing the said person being an infant under twelve years of age
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-11-person99">
                  Susannah 
                  Tabart 
               <interp inst="t17490113-11-person99" type="surname" value="Tabart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person99" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When this thing happened, it was of a ball-night, that is, of a Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. How long since?</p>
               <p>Tabart. About three weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. What month is this?</p>
               <p>Tabart. January.</p>
               <p>Court. Go on child and tell the truth.</p>
               <p>Tabart. In carrying up the supper the Prisoner carried up some things, and I carried up two cold tongues, he took them and put them upon the table, shut the door, sat down in a chair, and call'd me to him; I went to him, and he pull'd me nearer to him.</p>
               <p>Q. And what then?</p>
               <p>Tabart. He pull'd up my coats, and put something into me, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he stir out of the chair?</p>
               <p>Tabart. No, sir, he sat in the chair.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with his hands at that time?</p>
               <p>Tabart. He had them round my waist; he draw'd me between his legs with his hands, sir; my legs were close together, but he open'd them.</p>
               <p>Q. How could he do that, for he drew you betwixt his legs.</p>
               <p>Tabart. With his hand, sir; so that he put something into me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he keep you betwixt his legs?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Yes, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you cry out?</p>
               <p>Tabart. I did, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was this?</p>
               <p>Tabart. It was a two pair of stairs room, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Yes, sir, he hurt me very much.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he keep you there?</p>
               <p>Tabart. not very long.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174901130006"></xptr>Q. Did you perceive any thing particular come from him?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Yes, sir, there was wet come from him?</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you feel that wet; upon your hands, or where?</p>
               <p>Tabart. It was betwixt my legs?</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Tabart. This was the first time.</p>
               <p>Cross examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Child, did not you use to be much in his company?</p>
               <p>Tabart. No, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you discover this affair that night ?</p>
               <p>Tabart. No, sir, I went to bed soon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you discover it the next day?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Yes, sir, I told the maid I was hurt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you intend to tell your mother-in-law?</p>
               <p>Tabart. No, sir, because I was afraid of my mother's beating me.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it discovered?</p>
               <p>Tabart. By my linen.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Tabart. It was not quite dark.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do the company first begin to come to the hall.</p>
               <p>Tabart. They generally come when it is dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a key in the door?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Sir, I did not see any key in the door, nor do I know the door was lock'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he ever made any attempt since that Night?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Yes, sir, it was one Sunday; I believe it was the Sunday was sev'n-night after.</p>
               <p>Q. Now child, between that Friday that the first fact was committed, and the next time, had not you found yourself very much out of order?</p>
               <p>Tabart. A little, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account of the other affair?</p>
               <p>Tabart. I went up stairs with a brush into the room where he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was that?</p>
               <p>Tabart. The <placeName id="t17490113-11-crimeloc58">Turk's-head</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-11-crimeloc58" type="placeName" value="Turk's-head"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490113-11-crimeloc58" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490113-11-off56 t17490113-11-crimeloc58"></join>, (a room call'd so) up one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Tabart. It was about the same time of day the other was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do then ?</p>
               <p>Tabart. Then he lay with me as before, he call'd me to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How near him was you when he call'd you?</p>
               <p>Tabart. I was not far off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you as near the door as to him?</p>
               <p>Tabart. No, I was nearer him.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you go down stairs, and not go to him?</p>
               <p>Tabart. I did not know what he wanted with me then?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Winch. I am the child's mother-in-law. I married her Father, he is dead, and I am married again: she was born in South-Carolina.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>Winch. I cannot justly say; I think she was about four months old when she came over.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they come over?</p>
               <p>Winch. I am not certain, I think about 1739. I cannot tell what time of the year, nor am I certain of the year; she has been with me these six years; I live in St. George's street at the seven Dials.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-11-person100">
                  Edward 
                  Toft 
               <interp inst="t17490113-11-person100" type="surname" value="Toft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person100" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the Beadle of the parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been in company with the prosecutor lately?</p>
               <p>Toft. No, only I happened to be in court; I knew the child's father, he went abroad with the consent of his parents, and staid some time, and then return'd, and there was a little child brought over, and I believe this to be the child.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you think it is ago since; the child's father came over?</p>
               <p>Toft. I believe it is about nine years since; I knew him an infant.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any particular circumstance that you can remember Mr. Tabart's coming over by?</p>
               <p>Toft. I remember his coming over very well; I will not pretend to say to two or three months.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you remember how long the mother lived after she came over ?</p>
               <p>Toft. No, I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Mr. Vilnoe. I am a Surgeon, I was sent for to visit this child, her mother being alarm'd at a washerwoman's bringing home some linen that was sent to wash, they supposing it to be uncommon to a child. Upon examination I found the discharge was like the common, general appearance; the same night I examin'd the Prisoner at the Bar, and he acknowledged he had lain with the child, before the constable; and at the Watch-house I examin'd him and found a running upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there appear any marks on the thighs that seem'd to prove a force upon the child?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. There was a small laceration and I believe had time to heal up.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any black and blue marks that express'd violence ?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. I observ'd no black or blue marks.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174901130007"></xptr>Q. Did not the prisoner confess he had lain with the child several times?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. He own'd two times.</p>
               <p>Q. At what distance of time?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. That he did not say, it did not appear to be the same day.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the time was it he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. By the child's account I believe about a fortnight after.</p>
               <p>Q. From your inspection of the child how old do you take her to be?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. The parts of some children are larger than others; I cannot be positive, but if I may speak from circumstances, I believe she is not ten years old, but I am not certain.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give any evident account of the difference between nine and eleven?</p>
               <p>Vilnoe. I really cannot; I observ'd to you before, that some children may have parts as large at nine as some again at eleven or twelve.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490113-11-person101">
                  William 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17490113-11-person101" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person101" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Constable, the child's father-in-law came to me and desired I would go to his house; I went and there was the Surgeon; presently came the mother-in-law into the room, and she told me the affair in a few minutes after he came down, and presented the prisoner to my charge; the prisoner own'd he did lie with the child two different times: to the best of my knowledge it was about ten or fourteen days between.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490113-11-verdict59" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490113-11-verdict59" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
