<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460903-12">
               <interp inst="t17460903-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-12" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460903-12" type="date" value="17460903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460903-12-off44-c128" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-12-defend149 t17460903-12-off44 t17460903-12-verdict46"></join>
         
               <p>294. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-defend149" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Harrison 
                  <interp inst="t17460903-12-defend149" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-defend149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-defend149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460903-12-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four Glasses for Coaches
            </rs>, the Property of 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-victim150" type="victimName">
                  William 
                  Tayler 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-victim150" type="surname" value="Tayler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-victim150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-victim150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-12-off44 t17460903-12-victim150"></join>
                  </persName>
            , the <rs id="t17460903-12-cd45" type="crimeDate">1st of August</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460903-12-off44 t17460903-12-cd45"></join> last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person151">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person151" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person151" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person152">
                  William 
                  Tayler 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person152" type="surname" value="Tayler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person152" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar; have you any thing to lay to his Charge?</p>
               <p>Tayler. I am the Man that had my Glasses stole; I advertis'd one Glass five Weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030014"></xptr>Q. What Glass was it?</p>
               <p>Tayler. A Machine Glass for Coaches. This Day five Weeks one Ward came to me and ask'd me if I had lost any Glasses, he said he had four brought to him; he ask'd me if I could swear to them; I said not, but my Man could: These four Glasses were brought to him by the Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know these were your Glasses? I ask you whether you know, from your own Knowledge, that you can swear to these Glasses?</p>
               <p>Tayler. I can swear to one of the four, because I bought it myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in Frames, or out of Frames?</p>
               <p>Tayler. They are for Coaches or Chariots.</p>
               <p>Q. Why are you sure to that one?</p>
               <p>Tayler. Because I had a Mark upon it that I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose that Glass from?</p>
               <p>Tayler. Out of my Shop, my Lord, the Prisoner work'd for me.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose them?</p>
               <p>Tayler. The 1st of August I believe I took the Man up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person153">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person153" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person153" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Mr. Tayler by the Council for the Prisoner.) Mr. Tayler, be so good as to tell me how long this Man had work'd for you?</p>
               <p>Tayler. I believe he had work'd for me a Year and half.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, Sir, have you a Nephew transacts Business for you?</p>
               <p>Tayler. Yes he does; one 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person154">
                  Francis 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person154" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person154" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person155">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person155" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person155" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person156">
                  James 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person156" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person156" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar? What is it you have to say against him, with respect to the Crime laid to his Charge?</p>
               <p>Ward. He brought these four Glasses to me and offer'd them to Sale; he brought some before, which I bought; he brought them the 30th Day of July; they are Glasses for Coach Doors.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Business?</p>
               <p>Ward. Mine is Glass Business, and Gilding besides.</p>
               <p>Q. When he brought them to you what did he bring them for?</p>
               <p>Ward. He brought them to sell to me; he had brought some to me before, which I had bought; the first of his coming to me was the 26th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy any of them?</p>
               <p>Ward. Yes, my Lord, I bought six of them, three on the 26th of July, and three more on the 28th or 29th, I can't tell which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he offer any on the 30th of July?</p>
               <p>Ward. On the 30th he brought three more; then I saw that those Glasses had never been in the Glew of the Coach; those I bought before were old, so that I could not suspect them; but who I saw these to be new Glasses I agreed with him for a Price for them, and said, call again, Mr. Harrison, about Two o'Clock in the Afternoon and I shall be ready for you; I then went about to the Trade: I took a Receipt in the Name of 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person157">
                  John 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person157" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , because I had a Suspicion of their being stolen; then I went about the Trade to enquire whether they knew of any such Man; I went first to Clerkenwell, and from thence to Mr. Tayler's, who said Harrison was his Journeyman; then he asked me whether I had read an Advertisement he had put out the Day before; I said that I never saw any News till about Three o'Clock in the Afternoon; Mr. Tayler had offer'd ten Guineas Reward for the Glasses: I told him I had three Pieces for Glass that I suspected were stolen, whereupon he desir'd to see them, and after he had so done, requested that his Journeyman might look at them, I told him he might and welcome, that I never secrered any Goods. One Mr. Hall came along with him to see them.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>Ward. The Day the Rebels were hang'd; I think the 30th of July. I shew'd them the four Glasses which were produced in Court.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you all those four Glasses from the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Ward. Yes. When Mr. Tayler saw them he could not be positive they were his; but desir'd his Journeyman might see them, who came down accordingly; but neither of them would swear to the particular Marks of the Glasses, except one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know which of the four it was?</p>
               <p>Ward. I cannot say my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What follow'd after that?</p>
               <p>Ward. Mr. Tayler sent down his Man to know whether the Prisoner had been with me; if not, he desir'd I would stop him when he came; but he had been with me, and I said to him, Mr. Harrison, I have a great Suspicion that you have not come honestly by these Goods; I'll stop them; he said very well, I will bring you Proof I have come by them honestly: Then Mr. Tayler sent for me to the Sun-Tavern in Holbourn, to know whether I had stopp'd him; I told him he had been there before he sent down to me, that I had not stopp'd him, but the Goods. I told him they might belong to other People as well as to him, and that I would advertise them, which I accordingly<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030015"></xptr> did, and the Advertisement was read in Court, viz. Stopped yesterday, four Coach-Door Glasses, supposed to be stolen; whoever applies to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person158">
                  James 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person158" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             paying for the Advertisement, shall have them again.</p>
               <p>Court. You mentioned before, that the Prisoner said he would bring People to prove he came honestly by them; did he come again?</p>
               <p>Ward. Never any more; about two Days after I was sent for to him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person159">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person159" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person159" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; when I came before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person160">
                  Thomas 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person160" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person160" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told him the Story.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any Thing before Sir 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person161">
                  Thomas 
                  De Veil 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person161" type="surname" value="De Veil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person161" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Ward. No further than that Mr. Tayler's Kinsman gave him the Goods to sell for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he name his Name ?</p>
               <p>Ward. I can't take upon me to say whether he did or no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person162">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person162" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person162" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person163">
                  John 
                  Horn 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person163" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person163" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What do you know of the Prisoner at the Bar or the Fact ?</p>
               <p>Horn. I was at Mr. Tayler's on Tuesday the 29th of July, and he was saying he had lost a Glass; we were at the Queen's-Head-Tavern, and I persuaded him to advertise this Glass. The next Day I went to Mr. Tayler's and Mr. Ward came in at the same Time; he said he had stopp'd four Glasses that he believed to belong to Mr. Tayler: Mr. Tayler was very cautious, he would not swear to them, and I persuaded him to send his Servant. Some Time after this I went along with him and Mr. Ward and he pull'd out a Receipt of John Harrison's of 3 l. 15 s. I saw one Glass that I could swear I sold to Mr. Tayler for 2 l. 6 s. one was a Looking-Glass.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person164">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person164" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person164" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person165">
                  John 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person165" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What is your Business?</p>
               <p>Austin. I am a Glass-grinder to Mr. Tayler.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you leave this Glass?</p>
               <p>Austin. In the Fore Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the Glass again?</p>
               <p>Austin. We heard that Mr. Bonnet had bought it of Mr. Ward; I said to Mr. Bonnet, if it is my Master's Glass it is rubb'd at the Crop Corner End; Bonnet said he bought it of Ward, and he sent to him to fetch it again, as it was stolen Goods.</p>
               <p>Bonnet. I bought the Glass of Mr. Ward; I gave 40 s. for it.</p>
               <p>Q. When.</p>
               <p>Bonnet. I can't say; but I think it was the Beginning of August.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of that Glass?</p>
               <p>Bonnet. I return'd it to Mr. Ward again, because Mr. Tayler's People said it was their Master's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person166">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person166" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person166" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Ward) Do you know any Thing of this Glass you sold to Mr. Bonnet.</p>
               <p>Ward. Yes, my Lord. I bought it of Harrison, the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask Mr. Austin how he can speak to this Glass so particularly.</p>
               <p>Austin. Because it has such a particular Mark that there is not one in a Thousand like it; I went to look on these Glasses but could not swear to them; but this Glass I could speak to, one Side of it being plain, and on the other there is a Roughness, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Jury. I understood that the Prisoner own'd the Glasses, but that he had them of Mr. Tayler's Nephew ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person167">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person167" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person167" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person168">
                  William 
                  Heritage 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person168" type="surname" value="Heritage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person168" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) What are you.</p>
               <p>Heritage. I have been a Journeyman to Mr. Tayler almost eight Years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any Glass here you can swear to?</p>
               <p>Heritage. Yes.</p>
               <p>[The Evidence Heritage swore to three out of the four, and that he put a Diamond to them.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person169">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person169" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person169" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Would you ask him any Questions ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask him what particular Mark he can swear to the three by, and not to the fourth ?</p>
               <p>Heritage. A Flaw on the contrary Side, and a particular Mark at the Corner of the other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Would you ask him whether he never saw such a Fault in a Glass before?</p>
               <p>Heritage. Not in the particular Place where that is.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you my Lord to ask him how long he work'd those Glasses for Mr. Tayler ?</p>
               <p>Heritage. It might be about a Fortnight before they were clandestinely taken out of my Master's Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How long from this Time?</p>
               <p>Heritage. About six or seven Weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the Glass you work'd at Mr. Tayler's.</p>
               <p>Heritage. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know they were not sold?</p>
               <p>Heritage. Not by Mr. Tayler; for they were not fram'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person170">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person170" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person170" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) What have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please you, my Lord, it is a malicious Prosecution; Mr. Tayler's Nephew knows that I had all these Glasses from him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030016"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person171">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person171" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person171" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person172">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person172" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say in behalf of the Prisoner? Do you know Mr. Brown?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I have seen him once or twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in Company with 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person173">
                  John 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person173" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person173" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Thompson. He was in Company with John Harrison at one Mr. Quee; I went down to my Officer to throw up my Pay, that I might get to work; I saw there the Prisoner at the Bar drinking alone; he said to me, Mr. Thompson, how do you do? By and by in comes this Man, (pointing to Mr. Brown) and Harrison the Prisoner said to him, What do you mean by throwing such a Scandal upon me by bringing Glass to my Wife? she has been taken up upon that Account; but, said Brown, did not I get her discharg'd ? Brown told him, that if he did not get out of the Way he would deny it; and offer'd him some Money.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Harrison say to him when Brown advis'd him to go out of the Way?</p>
               <p>Thompson. He said he would not go out of the Way.</p>
               <p>Q. What Money did he offer him?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I can't tell the Sum; I heard him say he would give him Money; but what it was I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Thompson. About three Quarters of a Year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person174">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person174" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person174" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Eleanor Hall.) Do you know the Prisoner and Mr. Brown? Tell us what you heard pass.</p>
               <p>Hall. I went to see Mrs. Harrison the Day after St. James's Day, the 26th of July; she was very ill, and desir'd me to stay and drink a Dish of Tea: While I sat there Mr. Brown came up with three Glasses under his Arm, and ask'd if Mr. Harrison was within; he said, lay these Glasses by, Mr. Harrison don't go out, I shall call by and by. In about an Hour after he brought four more of a larger Size, and desir'd they might be laid by. The Tuesday following I went to see Mrs. Harrison, as she was so ill. Mr. Brown came up the same Morning, and said to Mr. Harrison, go do down to Mr. Ward's in Holbourn with these three Glasses, and get what Money you can for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take the three Glasses?</p>
               <p>Hall. Yes, he took them and went down with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing more?</p>
               <p>Hall. Mr. Harrison return'd again in about an Hour; I saw no more of Mr. Brown till about Three o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see Brown?</p>
               <p>Hall. I staid with Mrs. Harrison all the Time; about Three o'Clock Mr. Brown came again, and he ask'd him what Money he got for them. Harrison said, what I have you shall have, and put his Hand in his Pocket and took out three Guineas in Gold, four Half-Crowns and two Shillings, and said he had given a Receipt to Alard; then Brown said he must go with the other Glasses To-morrow Mornin g.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live, Mrs. Hall?</p>
               <p>Hall. I live in Queen-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a House-Keeper ?</p>
               <p>Hall. No, Sir, I am a Lodger; I am a Woman that follows Washing and Scouring.</p>
               <p>Q. If you are a poor Woman, how could you waste three or four Hours to make a Visit ?</p>
               <p>Hall. I don't go out every Day; but when I hear of a Friend's being ill and in Distress I go to see them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person175">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person175" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person175" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person176">
                  Katherine 
                  Spence 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person176" type="surname" value="Spence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person176" type="given" value="Katherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person176" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person177">
                  John 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person177" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person177" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Brown ?</p>
               <p>Spence. I am a Woman that sometimes get my Bread in the Streets and sometimes at home; as I was coming from Clare-Market with Goods I met with my Baker; he said, how do you do, Mrs. Spence, have you got any Money for me? I said, my Husband is not come from the Pay-Table, but I will give you what Money I have, which was about five Shillings; so he ask'd me to go in and drink; the Prisoner at the Bar was standing by, and bought a Half-penny worth of Plumbs of me; he lives at the Tea Cannister; the Man brought a Pint of Beer to my Barrow, the next Door but one to the Place where Mr. Harrison lives; while I was drinking Brown came and brought four Glasses under his Arm: Says Harrison, What must I do with them? Brown says, take them to your Lodgings and I will tell you what you shall do with them on Wednesday. That is all I know of the Affair, good or bad.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Husband?</p>
               <p>Spence. A Bricklayer; we live in a House of eleven Pounds a Year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person178">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person178" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person178" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person179">
                  George 
                  Weaver 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person179" type="surname" value="Weaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person179" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Where do you live, and what is your Business?</p>
               <p>Weaver. I am a Glass-grinder; I live in Parker's Lane, near Drury-Lane, Queen-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Weaver. About three Years; when he first came to Town he serv'd me for a whole Year, the Year before he went to Mr. Tayler's; he was a very<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174609030017"></xptr> sober, careful industrious Man; I never heard any Harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person180">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person180" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person180" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person181">
                  Daniel 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person181" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person181" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Long. In Parker's Lane; I have liv'd nineteen Years in one House, just facing the House where Mr. Harrison works; I have known him a Year and a Half, and never heard any Harm of the Man in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person182">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person182" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person182" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person183">
                  William 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person183" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person183" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Where do you live?</p>
               <p>More. In Drury-Lane; my Business is a Gold and Silver Lace Weaver; I work'd for the King's Lace-man, but now for Mr. Hul at Charing-cross, and I tell you, Gentlemen, I never heard a Word amiss in his Character in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person184">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person184" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person184" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Frances Mitchell.) Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. In St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>Q. What Character has the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. He lodg'd in my House Half a Year, and I never heard any Ill of the Man in my Life; he was as Pains-taking a Man as ever I knew in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460903-12-person185">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person185" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person185" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460903-12-person186">
                  Walter 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17460903-12-person186" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person186" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known the Prisoner and Mr. Brown?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Mr. Brown came to my House; his Business was with Mr. Harrison; he desired that he would go away, for his Uncle had miss'd some Glass, and he would take him up.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your Business?</p>

               <p>Murphey. I am a Marshal's-Court-Officer.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Murphey. A Day or two before he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this that Brown came?</p>
               <p>Murphey. At the Bull in Peter's-Street, Clare-Market.</p>
               <p>Q. When he came there, who did he ask for?</p>
               <p>Murphey. He ask'd for Harrison; he said his Business was with him, for to go out of the Way, because his Uncle had miss'd some Glass, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he tell you?</p>
               <p>Murphey. He told me, if Harrison did not go out of the Way, his Uncle would take him up. The Friday following Harrison was taken to the Gatehouse; on Saturday following Brown came to that House again; he said, I advised him to go away, now the Villian has brought my Name in Question, I'll spend an hundred Pounds to have him hang'd for making use of my Name.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you known Mr. Brown?</p>
               <p>Murphey. Not above two or three Days; he spoke to me at the same time to advise Harrison to go away.</p>
               <p>Court. Has the Prosecutor any thing to say by Way of Answer to this ?</p>
               <p>Tayler. Please you, my Lord, Brown is my Nephew, my Wife is her Aunt; I trust him with thousands of Pounds, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460903-12-verdict46" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460903-12-verdict46" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
