<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480706-27">
               <interp inst="t17480706-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-27" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480706-27" type="date" value="17480706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480706-27-off131-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-defend234 t17480706-27-off131 t17480706-27-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>347. 
               
                  <persName id="t17480706-27-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Carne 
                  <interp inst="t17480706-27-defend234" type="surname" value="Carne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-defend234" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-defend234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of the <placeName id="t17480706-27-defloc130">precinct of St. Catherine's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-27-defloc130" type="placeName" value="precinct of St. Catherine's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-27-defloc130" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-defend234 t17480706-27-defloc130"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17480706-27-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing nine guineas, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17480706-27-victim235" type="victimName">
                        Clas 
                        Fanaltena 
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-victim235" type="surname" value="Fanaltena"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-27-victim235" type="given" value="Clas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480706-27-victim235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-off131 t17480706-27-victim235"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480706-27-cd132" type="crimeDate">June 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-off131 t17480706-27-cd132"></join>.</p>
               <p>[The Prosecutor and the Prisoner being both Dutch, an interpreter was sworn. ]</p>
               <p>Q. to Clas Fanaltena. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I know the Prisoner at the bar very well; she lives in a house, in an alley on <placeName id="t17480706-27-crimeloc133">Tower-Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-27-crimeloc133" type="placeName" value="Tower-Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480706-27-crimeloc133" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-off131 t17480706-27-crimeloc133"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she <rs id="t17480706-27-deflabel134" type="occupation">keep a publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-defend234 t17480706-27-deflabel134"></join>?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. She has nothing to sell; it is her own house, and she lives in it. About four weeks ago I was at her house, and she took my money out of my pocket; she took nine guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. What made you go there?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I came out of a publick-house, and was going to my lodging; she asked me for a pint of beer, and I went into her house; she said she had no beer, but brought two or three bottles of cyder; she asked for the money, and I gave her a guinea, but she would give me no change; and when I gave her this guinea, I had eight guineas more; I then fell asleep, and slept till about two o'clock, and she would have me pay for two bottles of cyder, or she would take my coat off.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose this money?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I lost it when I was asleep; and it is well known, to herself and the Justice, that she is the person that had it; she owned herself, that she took the money out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What language was it in?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. In Dutch. She said before the Justice, that she took it out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has been in my company for a fortnight, and before he went to sea. How did I steal the money from you?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I will swear to it, and stand by it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He was drunk, and gave the money into my hand. I wish the devil may carry me away, if he did not give me the money.</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I am sure I was not drunk, for I had only a share of a pot of beer, and I could drink ten before I should be touched.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you acquainted with her before?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I might see her in the street, but I never was acquainted with her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I can bring witnesses to prove it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Barron. The Prosecutor lodges with me; and when the Prisoner was taken up, the headborough brought her to my house, and she talked good English, and she said she would give a note of hand for the money, if the Prosecutor would not carry her before the Justice, to be paid when her husband comes home.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prosecutor charge her with?</p>
               <p>Barron. He charged her with eight guineas, and she said she would give her hand seriven (that is a note of hand) for the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480706-27-person236">
                  Robert 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17480706-27-person236" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-person236" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took up the Prisoner, and car ried her before a Justice; she owned she had eight guineas, and would pay it when her husband came home; she offered two guineas and an half down to make up the affair, and a note of hand for the remainder.</p>
               <p>Q. Can she speak English?</p>
               <p>Sutton. She can speak English as well as I can</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He came to my house every day.</p>
               <p>Q. Ask her whether she meddled with his money?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He put the money into my hand, and he was as drunk as a hoy; he gave me the money but in the morning he repented that he gave it me, and I gave him three pounds twelve shillings back, in three guineas, and nine shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fanaltena. Did you receive three guineas and nine shillings back of her?</p>
               <p>Fanaltena. I did receive three guineas and nine shillings.</p>
               <p>[The Prisoner, though she pretended at first that she could not speak English, was asked whether she could speak English, she said Yes very plain.]</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-27-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-verdict135" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of the felony, and acquitted of privately stealing
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480706-27-punish136" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480706-27-punish136" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480706-27-defend234 t17480706-27-punish136"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
