<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460515-6">
               <interp inst="t17460515-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-6" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460515-6" type="date" value="17460515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460515-6-off30-c124" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-defend136 t17460515-6-off30 t17460515-6-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>201. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-defend136" type="defendantName">
                     Walter 
                     Roberts 
                  <interp inst="t17460515-6-defend136" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-defend136" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-defend136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he, not having the Fear of God before his Eyes, and being mov'd by the Instigation of the Devil, on the <rs id="t17460515-6-cd29" type="crimeDate">24th of April</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-off30 t17460515-6-cd29"></join>, <rs id="t17460515-6-off30" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-off30" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-off30" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               in and upon one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460515-6-victim138" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Blackwell 
                        <interp inst="t17460515-6-victim138" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460515-6-victim138" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460515-6-victim138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-off30 t17460515-6-victim138"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did wilfully, and with Malice and Forethought, with his Right Hand, strike and stab, in the Left Breast, the said Thomas Blackwell, and gave him one mortal Wound, the Breadth of Half an Inch; and did feloniously kill and murder, &amp;c.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person139">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person139" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person139" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person140">
                  Samuel 
                  Dew 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person140" type="surname" value="Dew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person140" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) What do you know of the Death of 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person141">
                  Samuel 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person141" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person141" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Dew. When I came into <placeName id="t17460515-6-crimeloc31">Golden-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="Golden-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-off30 t17460515-6-crimeloc31"></join>, next Door to a Cook's-Shop, I saw the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What Part of the Town is that?</p>
               <p>Dew. <placeName id="t17460515-6-crimeloc32">Near Old-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-6-crimeloc32" type="placeName" value="Near Old-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460515-6-crimeloc32" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-off30 t17460515-6-crimeloc32"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time was that?</p>
               <p>Dew. It was on the Rejoicing Night for the Victory.</p>
               <p>Q. What Business are you?</p>
               <p>Dew. A Cooper.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night was it?</p>
               <p>Dew. About Dusk.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Dew. I know him by Sight; but before this Fact was done I did not know him. There were some Fellows making Game at the Prisoner as he was going home: Presently after I saw the Instrument that kill'd the Deceas'd; it seem'd to be Three-square, like a Bayonet.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it any Handle to it, any thing to take hold of?</p>
               <p>Dew. I cannot tell. There were some Men making Game of the Prisoner near his own Door; and he went in, and came out again with this Instrument in his Hand; and upon the Prisoner's coming up, the Deceas'd clos'd in with him. Upon seeing this, one Mr. Holland went to part them; and as he made his Endeavour, the Smith, the Prisoner, and the Deceas'd, reel'd back a little Way, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174605150011"></xptr> the Deceas'd dropp'd down, and never spoke a Word, but died immediately; and Roberts went in at the Door, and shut it after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see Roberts and the Man that is dead ? What was the Deceas'd?</p>
               <p>Dew. A <rs id="t17460515-6-viclabel33" type="occupation">Brewer's Servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-victim138 t17460515-6-viclabel33"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Brewer's Servant doing?</p>
               <p>Dew. He was talking to Roberts; but I did not mind what it was.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was it from Roberts's House?</p>
               <p>Dew. It was the next Door.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the Mens talking to Roberts, what did he say?</p>
               <p>Dew. I can't tell the Words.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you gone from them?</p>
               <p>Dew. About two or three Yards.</p>

               <p>Q. How long was Roberts gone into the House to fetch this Instrument?</p>
               <p>Dew. A very little while.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the Instrument before he went into his House?</p>
               <p>Dew. No.</p>
               <p>Q. You said something of their making Game at him; What did they make Game at him for?</p>
               <p>Dew. They seem'd to shame him for going into the House, and would not stay to scold at them, I suppose.</p>
               <p>Q. Now tell us in what way he came out.</p>
               <p>Dew. He came out in a great Passion.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Wound?</p>
               <p>Dew. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of Wound was it?</p>
               <p>Dew. But a little Wound; it was under his Ribs, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were they clos'd in before they parted them?</p>
               <p>Dew. A very little while.</p>
               <p>Questions to Dew by the Council for the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a Mob at the Door a little before the Murder was done?</p>
               <p>Dew. There was some People about there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Soldier there with his Piece; was the Soldier there at the Time when the Mischief was done?</p>
               <p>Dew. The Soldier was thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not this the Night there was the Rejoicing for the Victory of Culloden ?</p>
               <p>Dew. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear no Conversation from the Prisoner and the other about breaking of Windows?</p>
               <p>Dew. The People were talking of it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be positive that the Prisoner was not within-side of his Groundsel when they had the Scuffle ?</p>
               <p>Dew. He was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When they were in the Scuffle and clos'd how far were they from the House?</p>
               <p>Dew. About the Middle of the Street.</p>
               <p>Council. You said somebody endeavour'd to part them, and they stagger'd toward the House, and just before the Door the Man fell down dead.</p>
               <p>Dew. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray did not the Deceas'd insist upon it that he was Man enough for the Prisoner, and he would fight him ?</p>
               <p>Dew. I did not hear that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person142">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person142" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person142" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person143">
                  William 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person143" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person143" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say about this Matter?</p>
               <p>Harris. As my Wife and I were walking thro' Whitecross-Street into Playhouse-Street, and coming into Golden-Lane, I heard Mr. Roberts and the Deceas'd have many Words: The Deceas'd said he would lay Half a Crown with him; Mr. Roberts said, then he must pawn his Shirt for Half a Crown.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the Thing this was done with?</p>
               <p>Harris. That could not be found.</p>
               <p>Court. You say they clos'd in.</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes, my Lord, and I saw something glitter.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, what follow'd?</p>
               <p>Harris. With that Mr. Holland ran to part them, and laid hold of the Deceas'd; with that Mr. Roberts, the Prisoner, ran into his House, and the Deceas'd dropp'd down and never sigh'd nor groan'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Soldier there?</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any Talk of putting out Lights because of the Rejoicing?</p>
               <p>Harris. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person144">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person144" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person144" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person145">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Carlisle 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person145" type="surname" value="Carlisle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person145" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. Yes; I have known him about three Quarters of a Year.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Affair?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. As I was going home I heard the Deceas'd and the Prisoner have Words.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Quarrel about?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. I heard the Deceas'd say he would fight him for Half a Crown, if he would lay down his Arms.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Roberts with any Arms?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. No, my Lord; after that Mr. Roberts said, he lay Half a Crown! he had not Half a a Crown, nor a Shirt to his A - e; after that Mr. Roberts turn'd himself to go home, and the Deceas'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174605150012"></xptr> said he would fight him for Half a Crown, if he would lay down his Arms: Then, when Mr. Roberts was going to his own Door, the Men set up a laugh; with that Mr. Roberts stepp'd into his House, and presently came out again, and he clos'd with the Deceas'd, and gave him two Blows on his Side, and then gave him the Wound.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that he gave him the Wound?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. He had something of a bright Weapon in his Hand. I did not know what. Mr. Holland took hold of the Deceas'd, and parted them; and he never spoke another Word.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night was that?</p>
               <p>Carlisle. I believe, between 10 and 11 o'Clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person146">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person146" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person146" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person147">
                  James 
                  Seal 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person147" type="surname" value="Seal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person147" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What are you?</p>
               <p>Seal A Brewer's Servant.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this Matter?</p>
               <p>Seal. Please you, my Lord, as I was going from my Work the Night the Rejoicing was, there was a Bonfire made at the Upper-end of Golden-Lane. I went to the Bonfire, and as I stood by the deceas'd Man, this Roberts and he had some Words.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there at the Beginning of the Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Seal. My Lord, I was not at the Beginning. The deceas'd Man was by the Fire, and there was some Windows that had not Lights put up; and they were talking round the Fire side of breaking Windows; with that Roberts came to the Fire-side, and he and the Deceas'd had some Words.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the Words?</p>
               <p>Seal. I can't tell. With that Roberts goes back to his own House, and a little after he came again, and several more Words passing, they went towards Roberts's Door. With a great many Words the Deceas'd challeng'd to fight Roberts for Half a Crown: With that Roberts takes up the Flap of his Coat, and said all the Cloaths that he had upon his Back were not worth Half a Crown. Said the Deceas'd, if they are not worth Half a Crown, I have Half a Crown in my Pocket, for which I will fight you: With that, when Roberts came out again, he ran at the Deceas'd, and they collar'd one another, and scuffled 'till they had got just at the Threshold of Roberts's Door: I saw Roberts make an Offer of striking, but did not see any Weapon, or any Blow struck. That was all that I saw of it, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Man dead?</p>
               <p>Seal. Yes, I saw the Man dead.</p>
               <p>Q. What Time of the Night was it?</p>
               <p>Seal. I believe it was about half an Hour after Ten.</p>
               <p>Court. You saw no Weapon?</p>
               <p>Seal. No Weapon at all, please you, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person148">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person148" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person148" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Will you ask this Witness any Questions.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Sir, I don't know any thing of the Man ?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that Soldier there?</p>
               <p>Seal. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his Piece?</p>
               <p>Seal. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person149">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person149" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person149" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person150">
                  William 
                  Scarborough 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person150" type="surname" value="Scarborough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What have you to say about this Matter?</p>
               <p>Scarborough. I saw Mr. Roberts come to the Deceas'd, and said he would shoot him as dead as one of the Rebels.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they quarrel about?</p>
               <p>Scarborough. My Lord, I can't say I ever heard this Fellow, the Deceas'd, speak a Word to him: I saw Roberts go back to his own House, and said d - n Duke William and all the Family; must I have my Windows shut up?</p>
               <p>Court. Well then he was complaining that his Windows were shut up, and he was angry?</p>
               <p>Scarborough. I can't say what he was angry at, except it was shooting at the Bonfire; though this Fellow, the Deceas'd, never shot nor ever gave any Provocation, as I heard; I saw them close in, and Roberts had a Weapon in his Hand; but what it was I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Was you there at the Beginning of the Fire? Was not there some Guns fired at some People's Windows? and were no Windows broke that Night?</p>
               <p>Scarborough. I can't say that they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray why should he address himself so particularly to the Prisoner? Did not you hear that it was by reason of a Lodger in his House that the Prisoner could not light Candles?</p>
               <p>Scarborough. I know nothing of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person151">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person151" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person151" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person152">
                  John 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person152" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know concerning this unhappy Affair?</p>
               <p>Holland. Sir, As I was coming from the 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person153">
                  George 
                  Alehouse 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person153" type="surname" value="Alehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person153" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Old-Street, and passing by the Bonfire in Golden-Lane, many Words pass'd between the Deceas'd and Mr. Roberts: The Deceas'd follow'd him to his Door; Roberts steps in and comes out again, and they were engag'd with one another; Roberts's Wife was pulling him by the Skirt: I stepp'd in and said don't fight; I caught hold of the Deceas'd and he fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. Why, he appear'd very strong in his scuffling with the other, did he not?</p>
               <p>Holland. He appear'd very strong, and said, let<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174605150013"></xptr> me alone, I shall manage him; or some such Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you apprehend he receiv'd the Mischief then, do you?</p>
               <p>Holland. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What Wound was it?</p>
               <p>Holland. It was a Wound under the Rib.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was it?</p>
               <p>Holland. A little Hole, that you might put a Straw into it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Body open'd?</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Who call'd you to assist?</p>
               <p>Holland. Roberts's Wife, that they might not fight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person154">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person154" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person154" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person155">
                  Richard 
                  Hawes 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person155" type="surname" value="Hawes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person155" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What do you know of this Matter ?</p>
               <p>Hawes. My Wife and I, and a young Man, a Cooper, went out into the City, and as we return'd back, about a Quarter after Ten, we came to the Bonfire; I saw the Deceas'd, and several more, follow Mr. Roberts hollowing and hooting; when Roberts had got upon the Stone of his Door, says the Deceas'd, stand away, I warrant you I am Man enough for him; with that they clos'd, they might be the Space of half a Minute: Mr. Holland caught hold of the Deceas'd that they might not fight; as soon as Mr. Holland had laid hold of the Deceas'd a Woman takes hold of Roberts and gets him into his House; with that they said immediately the Man is kill'd; I said kill'd the D - I, for I did not see a Blow struck. I saw another Man with a Gun; he said he would fire at them I went over and saw the dead Man lie against the Prisoner's Window.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person156">
                  Osborne 
                  Skinner 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person156" type="surname" value="Skinner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person156" type="given" value="Osborne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the Goat Alehouse the poor Fellow, the Deceas'd, was singing a merry Song; Mr. Robert, the Prisoner, came in and call'd for a pennyworth of Beer, and a Gentleman subpoenied by Mr. Roberts, who is now in Court, was there; there were no cross Words pass'd at that Time, the Liquor was brought in and we drank the Duke's Health; Mr. Roberts said they magnify'd their Loss and lessen'd our own: I ask'd him to drink the Duke's Health, and he said no; then I said you are a Rebel. A little after that a Woman came in and said to me, Mr. Skinner, Roberts has kill'd Blackwell; I went and saw the Man dead; they had put on a Patch over it; when I saw the Hole it look'd black, but not so big as my Finger. Please you, my Lord, that Man, Roberts, said he would do for me. That Night I broke open his House, but he was gone; the next Morning I took him myself, at the King's Arms opposite Chiswell-Street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person157">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person157" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person157" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) Would you ask this Witness any thing ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Skinner, did I refuse to go with you? because you said you took me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person158">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person158" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person158" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person159">
                  Joseph 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person159" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person159" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Are you a Surgeon?</p>
               <p>James. Yes, Sir, I have about two Months to serve of my Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the dead Body?</p>
               <p>James. Yes, Sir, when I came there was a Puncture in the Breast, about two Fingers below the Nipple.</p>
               <p>Q. Which Breast?</p>
               <p>James. The Left Breast, an Inch below the Nipple, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep?</p>
               <p>James. I believe about four or five Inches deep, quite pierc'd through the Heart, and was immediate Death.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide was it?</p>
               <p>James. I believe about half an Inch.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you suppose it to be done with?</p>
               <p>James. It seems to be a Triangle.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person160">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person160" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person160" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to the Prisoner.) What do you say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I depend upon God's Mercy and the Justice of this honourable Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person161">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person161" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person161" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person162">
                  James 
                  Haws 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person162" type="surname" value="Haws"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person162" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Did you see the Prisoner and the other Man that Night the Rejoycing was for the Victory?</p>
               <p>Haws. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Beginning of the Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Haws. I was at the Bonfire, and there were some Soldiers looking all about it for Stones to put in their Guns, at which Time the Deceas'd call'd one of them by his Name, and said he wonder'd he had so much Patience with Mr. Roberts.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person163">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person163" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person163" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person164">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person164" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person164" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes, I have known him for seven or eight Years past, and I never saw him malicious or any thing of that Kind, but willing to do a good Action.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person165">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person165" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person165" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person166">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person166" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person166" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Do you know the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>King. Yes, I think he is a good temper'd Man.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you know nothing extraordinary of him, one way or another ?</p>
               <p>King. No, my Lord, we work'd in one Shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person167">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person167" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person167" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Nicks.) What have you heard Mr. Skinner say?</p>
               <p>Nicks. I am Headborough to St. Luke's Parish; I went along with him and we broke the Prisoner's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174605150014"></xptr> Door open; we were there a Couple of Hours, and in that Time the Prisoner at the Bar made his Escape: The Clerk belonging to the Brewhouse ask'd us to go to take part of a Pot of Beer at the Taphouse, and what I heard Skinner say was this; that the Prisoner at the Bar had said many treasonable Words, and that if he did not leave talking so he would have him taken up as a disaffected Person.</p>
               <p>Court. And he was to be commended for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person168">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person168" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person168" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person169">
                  Oliver 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person169" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person169" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) How long have you known the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Banks. I have known him for a considerable Time, and have paid him ten Pounds at a Time for Work; he alter'd me three Guns and a Pistol before these Wars: I maintain two Soldiers myself; and he said to me, I have a Blunderbuss, and if it was charg'd I would shoot the Pretender through the Head.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460515-6-person170">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person170" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person170" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Dukeson.) Was you by at this Quarrel?</p>
               <p>Dukeson. I was going to Old-Street; I pass'd by the Fire and saw two Men quarrelling; the Deceas'd said to this Man, you are a Rebel, a Villain and a Roman; he desir'd that he would let him alone; but the Deceas'd said that he would fight him for Half a Crown, and that he could knock his Head off; when the Prisoner got to his own Door the Deceas'd struck him two or three Times, and the Mob drawing near he said to them, let me alone, I am Man enough for him; but the Prisoner was taken into his own House by the Mob, or went in himself, I can't say which.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Prisoner's Door shut?</p>
               <p>Dukeson. It was open, to the best of my Knowledge.</p>
               <p>Court. 
               <persName id="t17460515-6-person171">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17460515-6-person171" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person171" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , give an Account of what you know of the Fact.</p>
               <p>Brown. I was in the Company of Mr. Skinner and Mr. Roberts about half an Hour before this Affair happen'd, and the Deceas'd and the Prisoner did not change a Word: I have known the Prisoner for some Time, and never heard any Harm of him before this Affair happen'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460515-6-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-verdict34" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460515-6-punish35" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-punish35" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460515-6-punish35" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460515-6-defend136 t17460515-6-punish35"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
