<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-14">
               <interp inst="t17400903-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-14" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-14" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-14-off90-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-14-defend131 t17400903-14-off90 t17400903-14-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>378. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-14-defend131" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Murphey 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-14-defend131" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-defend131" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-defend131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-14-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a Bag, val. 3 s. a Comb, val. 4 d. a Pair of Scissars, val. 2 s. and 2 lb. 12 Ounces of Human Hair, val. 4 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               <persName id="t17400903-14-victim132" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Murdock 
               <interp inst="t17400903-14-victim132" type="surname" value="Murdock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-victim132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-victim132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-14-off90 t17400903-14-victim132"></join>
                  </persName>
              , in the Parish of <placeName id="t17400903-14-defloc91">St George's Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-14-defloc91" type="placeName" value="St George's Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-14-defloc91" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-14-defend131 t17400903-14-defloc91"></join>, <rs id="t17400903-14-cd92" type="crimeDate">July 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-14-off90 t17400903-14-cd92"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Murdock . On the 15th of July I was coming out of the City, and had a Bag in my Hand, with 2 lb. 12 Ounces of Human Hair, and a Comb, and a Pair of Scissars in it. I walked up towards Bloomsbury , and not being well in Health, I sat down upon a Bench, by a Door, and two Men came and sat down by me. I had not been sat down long, before I fell fast a-sleep; then a Woman, (I suppose the Prisoner is the Person) came, and took hold of me, and said, - 'wake, for your Wife has been seeking for you this Half Hour. I got up, but being drowsy, I sat down again, and did not mind her. Well, (says the Woman) if you won't 'wake, I'll take your Bag, and will carry it away. And so she did, for she took it from me, and carried it quite off. I don't know what Woman it was: I suppose it was the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-14-person133">
                  John 
                  Giffard 
               <interp inst="t17400903-14-person133" type="surname" value="Giffard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While this Gentleman (the next Witness) and I were sitting on the Bench, by the Door of the House where we lodge, the Prosecutor came up, and sat down on the Bench a little disordered, and fell asleep. He sat about a Quarter of an Hour, and then a Woman (whom I take to be the Prisoner) came and took hold of him by the Arm, and said, - Will you go Home? This she repeated two or three Times over. Then she shook him again, and he got up. Your Wife and I, says she, have been seeking you this Half-Hour. I asked her if she knew the Gentleman? Yes, yes, (said she) I lodge in the same House with him; and she shook him again; and he got up upon the Steps, but soon sat himself down again. Well then, says the Woman, if you won't go Home, I'll take care of your Bag, and your Stick, and I'll go Home and call your Wife to fetch you. And she did take the Bag and Stick out of his Hand, and went away with them; but I can't say positively the Prisoner is the Woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-14-person134">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17400903-14-person134" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person134" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw a Woman come up to the Prosecutor as he sat upon the Bench, and she asked him where he had been all this while? Telling him his Wife and she had been to look for him. Upon this he 'wak'd and got up, but soon sat himself down again: Upon this she told him, if he would not 'wake, she'd take his Bag and Stick, and would fetch his Wife to him. But who the Woman was I can't tell, for it was Night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-14-person135">
                  Joseph 
                  Thomlinson 
               <interp inst="t17400903-14-person135" type="surname" value="Thomlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person135" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One Morning as I was standing at my Door, about 6 in the Morning, 2 Men came to me, with a Parcel of Hair in a Silk Handkerchief, and asked me to buy it. I told them I should not buy any; then they asked me if I knew any Hair-Merchants who would buy it? I told them I did, and they wanted me to go along with them to one. I appointed them to come again at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030014"></xptr> 11 o'Clock, and promised to go with them then, to a Hair-Merchant. Upon this they went away, but in half an Hour they returned, and said, they could not wait so long. I then asked them, how they came by the Hair? They told me, they had it of a Hair-Merchant (who lived in the House with them) for a Debt. I could not go with them, before 11 o'Clock, and so they agreed to wait till that Time. Then I carry'd them to one Mr Peterson ; he would not buy it himself, but recommended us to Mr Abery . We went to him, and he did not seem fond of buying it. They told him the same Story, they told me; and he asked me if I knew the Men. I told him I did; and that I believed there would be no Danger. Mr Abery then asked the Men the Value of the Hair. They said, they did not know, and hop'd he would give them a Market-Price for it. He offered them 18 s. for it, which they took, and they would have given me 2 s. for my Trouble, but I would not take any thing. A little Time afterwards, I heard the Hair was advertised, and upon my saying I knew who sold it, the Prosecutor was sent to me, and I carried him to Mr Abery, who had bought it, and he told the Prosecutor he should have it again, or any Hair he had by him, which he thought would make him satisfaction. I knew nothing of the Prisoner; but the Prosecutor gave the same Account of his losing them as he has done now.</p>
               <p>A Witness. When the Woman was before Sir Edward Hill, she said she found the Hair. <rs id="t17400903-14-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-14-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
