<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17450911-27">
               <interp inst="t17450911-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-27" type="year" value="1745"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17450911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17450911-27" type="date" value="17450911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-27-off135-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend262 t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-verdict139"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-27-off135-c215" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend263 t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-verdict139"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17450911-27-off135-c216" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend266 t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>328, 329, 330. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-defend262" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Girle 
                  <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend262" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend262" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-defend263" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Ann 
                     Walker 
                   *, [* She used to go by the name of 
                     Ann 
                     Basket 
                  
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend263" type="surname" value="Walker Basket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend263" type="given" value="Ann Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,] and 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-defend266" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend266" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend266" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-defend266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , of <placeName id="t17450911-27-defloc134">St. Butolph, Aldgate, London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-27-defloc134" type="placeName" value="St. Butolph, Aldgate, London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-27-defloc134" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend262 t17450911-27-defloc134"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend263 t17450911-27-defloc134"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend266 t17450911-27-defloc134"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17450911-27-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17450911-27-victim268" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Wilson 
                        <interp inst="t17450911-27-victim268" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-27-victim268" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-27-victim268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-victim268"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110017"></xptr> in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17450911-27-person269">
                        Ann 
                        Girle 
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person269" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-27-person269" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17450911-27-person269" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17450911-27-deflabel136" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend262 t17450911-27-deflabel136"></join>, putting him in fear and danger of his life, and feloniously taking fifteen guineas, and 4 s. 6 d. in money, from his person, and against his will, in the said dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450911-27-cd137" type="crimeDate">Sept. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-cd137"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person270">
                  Richard 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person270" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person270" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last night as I was going down the <placeName id="t17450911-27-crimeloc138">Minories</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-27-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Minories"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17450911-27-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-off135 t17450911-27-crimeloc138"></join>, Mary Green took me hold by the coat, and asked me if I wanted a pretty girl, I said, no, I have a wife of my own; she said, by G - d you shall have a girl, for I have got a very pretty girl in my house. I gave her a pretty handsom slap upon the hoop or the gown, or whatever she had on, and then out came another girl.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It was just by her own house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It was a little before 12 at night. The other girl took me by the left skirt of the coat, which we call the lar-board skirt (I ask pardon for the expression, as I am a tar, I hope you will excuse me) she took me by the collar, and forced me up an alley , and then forced me into a house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who forced you into the house?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I was forced into the house by Mary Green, and another woman, who is not taken [
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person271">
                  Moll 
                  Boston 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person271" type="surname" value="Boston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person271" type="given" value="Moll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] When they had got me into the house, they sat me down gently into a chair, they did not hurt me at all. Then Mary Green took hold of this left arm, and as she had hold of my arm, there was a door on the left hand which two chaps jumped out of.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of chaps were they?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Why men; one of them was a d - m lusty fellow, the other was but a little man, one of them took hold of my right leg, and hove it up, and one of the women who is gone [Moll Boston] took hold of me, and a man in a striped waistcoat got hold of my collar and tore my shirt all to pieces. I did not care to give out very soon, so they tore me all to pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see Mary Green do?</p>
               <p>Wilson. She was so good as to hold my arm, and one of the men took hold of my collar, and the other of my right leg; and that pale sickly woman [
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person272">
                  Ann 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person272" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person272" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] who pretends to be sick, but she is just as sick as I am, much the same; I believe she is mistress of the house. She took hold of me, and said she would put me to bed, and then the tall girl with the black hair [ Walker ] she is a pretty girl enough; she said she would shew me the way up stairs. Then Ann Girle, as soon as she had got hold of me, put the candle out, and my pocket was picked. This gentlewoman here [ Green ] had hold of my arm.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I lost fifteen guineas, a half crown piece, two shillings in silver, and some half-pence. Then this lady, who stands in the middle, 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person273">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person273" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person273" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said, you shall not stay to lose all, take care of yourself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they light the candle again?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes; the mistress of the house, 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person274">
                  Ann 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person274" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person274" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , lighted it. Indeed she was very civil, she lighted it presently: I believe the candle was not out above ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. When the candle was lighted again, was 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person275">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person275" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person275" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             so near you as to put her hand round your neck?</p>
               <p>Wilson. She had her hand about my neck after the candle was out, and she said, my dear, take care of yourself, and you shall not be hurt. Then I called out, and the two women took and hove me out of doors.</p>
               <p>Q. Who assisted in putting you out of the house?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Why the two men, a little one and a tall one, Mary Green and 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person276">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person276" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person276" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I got out of the house, I set my back against a bulk and called to the watch, and I told the watch that minute, that I had lost 15 guineas, but I don't believe that I mentioned any silver at all. The watch took Mary Green and 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person277">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person277" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person277" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the pump in the street. I desired the watch to break the house open, and they told me they could not. They went for the constable, and he said he could not; but when Green and Walker were brought back to the house, then the door was opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I had been at the Saracen's head within Aldgate, where I lodge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you quite sober?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I was as sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before that time, that you had your money?</p>
               <p>Wilson. About an hour. I brought the money from Sherness .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you come from Sheerness ?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I came from Sheerness on Tuesday, and I believe it was twelve o'clock yesterday morning when I came here, and I went to Mr. Busby's in Doctor's Commons with a ticket of 33 l. which was my brother's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Green. I desire to know whether you did not leave your watch in pledge at the watchhouse for a shilling, for some liquor?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes, I did, my Lord, and I saved my watch by chance, it was by mere accident, for the string was got into the inside of my breeches.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person278">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person278" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a watchman of Portsoken ward, Mr. Wilson had called out for the watch.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110018"></xptr>Q. Where was it that you saw Mr. Wilson first?</p>
               <p>Lee. It was in Well Alley in the Minories with another watchman. Mr. Wilson desired us to break open the door, I told him we could not break the door open. Then he said he would have a watchman stand all night at the door, and insisted upon it, and said he had lost fifteen guineas, and shewed me the house. Then Warner, a watchman, came and said, he believed the two women were passed by. I saw them, but they were then in the liberty of the little Minories, and I could not take them. But they came to the pump to drink, which is in our ward, and then Warner and I took them and carried them to the watch-house. When they came there, and finding no body that knew them, they began to be saucy. Then I fetched Mr. Wilson, and he came to the watch-house, and said, those were the women that robbed him.</p>
               <p>Ann Green said that 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person279">
                  Nan 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person279" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person279" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was to have five shillings in the pound of 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person280">
                  Tom 
                  Boston 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person280" type="surname" value="Boston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person280" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            *, out of what they plundered Mr. Wilson of.</p>
               <p>* He is the tall fellow that Mr. Wilson speaks of who took him by the collar and tore his shirt. He belongs to the Foot Guards now in the Tower . He was taken by Mr. Wilson on Monday the 16th instant, at the corner of Houndsditch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person281">
                  Arthur 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person281" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person281" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (a watchman) As I was beating the hour past twelve, Mr. Wilson called to me and said he was robbed of 15 guineas. I went into Well Alley with him, he found the door, and said, here is the place where I was robbed. Said he, watchman, break the door open, I said I could not; but if it was upon a cry of murder, I don't know what I might do. He staid there, and I went and fetched the watch and the constable directly. That is all I have to say in the full course of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them at the watch-house?</p>
               <p>Parker. I saw Walker and Green in the watchhouse first, and afterwards I saw all three there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when they got the door open?</p>
               <p>Parker. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person282">
                  William 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person282" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person282" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (constable) About 12 o'clock our watchmen came to me, to go to a house in Well Alley, about a gentleman who was robbed. I saw the gentleman [Mr. Wilson] and spoke to him. He said he was robbed of fifteen guineas, and desired I would break the door open. I told him I could not without a warrant. I knocked at the door with my staff, but could not get the door opened; he said if I would let two men stand at the door all night, he would pay them for it; so I let two watchmen stand there, and they stood I believe about an hour, and then Walker and Green came by and were taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Who lives there?</p>
               <p>Matthews. That woman, 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person283">
                  Ann 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person283" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person283" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How long has she lived there?</p>
               <p>Matthews. She has lived there but since Monday. It is a very bad house; people come in and stay about a fortnight or three weeks, then they are gone and others come in.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Walker. Was not I walking down the Minories when I was taken?</p>
               <p>Matthews. I did not see you in the Minories. The first time I saw you, was when you were brought to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they searched?</p>
               <p>Matthews. No, they were not searched, and I believe the person who had the money is got off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person284">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person284" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person284" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a watchman.) Parker called me and told me a gentleman was robbed of fifteen guineas. We went to 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person285">
                  Ann 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person285" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person285" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, and Walker and Green went with us to the door, and they knocked at the door, and 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person286">
                  Nan 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person286" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person286" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, who is there? they said, they were; she said, is there no body else? and they said, no. Then she opened the door, and we went in and took her. Girle said that 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person287">
                  Tom 
                  Boston 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person287" type="surname" value="Boston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person287" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his lady had robbed the gentleman. Then said Mary Green to her, must we go to Newgate for you, when you are to have a crown in the pound, out of the money they robbed the gentleman of?</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this discourse?</p>
               <p>Cartwright. It was in the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Green. Did you ever know me to be a prostitute or a street walker?</p>
               <p>Cartwright. I don't know you.</p>
               <p>Green to Matthews the constable. Do you know me to be such a person?</p>
               <p>Matthews. I have seen you twenty times about the streets.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Green, to Wilson. Where was it that I picked you up?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I can't justly say where, for I am unacquainted with that way; it was about the Minories. That lady was so kind as to take hold of the skirt of my coat.</p>
               <p>Green. Is the woman here that picked you up?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes, to be sure she is, if you are here.</p>
               <p>Green. Was it I that picked you up, or the other woman who is not here?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It was yourself, you was in a black<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174509110019"></xptr> gown then, but you have changed your colours now; I know the scar in your face very well</p>
               <p>Green. He said, Polly, I have been ill used, my shirt is torn; said I, I am sure you shall not be ill used.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Walker. Green and I were at supper that night upon a couple of rabbets at a neighbours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person288">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Warren 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person288" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person288" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Walker and Green were at supper at my house last night; and you supped there too, [speaking to one 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person289">
                  Sarah 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person289" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person289" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person290">
                  Sarah 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person290" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person290" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             replied, Not I indeed , I did not sup with you.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else supped with you?</p>
               <p>Warren. 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person291">
                  Rosamond 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person291" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person291" type="given" value="Rosamond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person292">
                  Mary 
                  Boston 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person292" type="surname" value="Boston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person292" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there? Warren. No, she was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person293">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person293" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person293" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            [to White.] What are you?</p>
               <p>White. I get my living by selling things in the streets; my husband has belonged to the Customhouse there twenty five years. Last night we went to bed about 8 o'clock, and about 12 there was an uproar which waked us, and a gentleman came to the door; he had a pair of white stockings, a red waistcoat, and I think a blue grey coat; he said he was robbed of fifteen guineas. There were three watchmen, and the gentleman would not let the watchmen go: there were some people came to call one 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person294">
                  Sarah 
                  Dobbs 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person294" type="surname" value="Dobbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person294" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person294" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and they said, you must come to 
               <persName id="t17450911-27-person295">
                  Mary 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person295" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person295" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to the Watch-house; but I find now she is prosecuted by the name of Green.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the candle put out before, or after the robbery?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It was put out just at the time, for the men and the women had hold of me then. The candle was put out just at the same instant that I was robbed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17450911-27-person296">
                  Ann 
                  Girle 
               <interp inst="t17450911-27-person296" type="surname" value="Girle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person296" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-person296" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Ann Walker <rs id="t17450911-27-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. Mary Green, <rs id="t17450911-27-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17450911-27-punish141" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17450911-27-punish141" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17450911-27-defend266 t17450911-27-punish141"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
