<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17410828-11">
               <interp inst="t17410828-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-11" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17410828"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17410828-11" type="date" value="17410828"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17410828-11-off63-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-defend95 t17410828-11-off63 t17410828-11-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>13. 
               
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-defend95" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     White , alias <rs id="t17410828-11-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-defend95 t17410828-11-alias-2"></join>Chaise</rs>, alias <rs id="t17410828-11-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-defend95 t17410828-11-alias-3"></join>Ryan</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-defend95" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-defend95" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-defend95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17410828-11-defloc62">Fulham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-11-defloc62" type="placeName" value="Fulham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17410828-11-defloc62" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-defend95 t17410828-11-defloc62"></join> was indicted for <rs id="t17410828-11-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 3 five guinea pieces, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17410828-11-victim97" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Maynard 
                        <interp inst="t17410828-11-victim97" type="surname" value="Maynard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410828-11-victim97" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17410828-11-victim97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-off63 t17410828-11-victim97"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   
                     <rs id="t17410828-11-viclabel64" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-victim97 t17410828-11-viclabel64"></join>; in his dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17410828-11-cd65" type="crimeDate">July 11th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-off63 t17410828-11-cd65"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Maynard. On the 11th of last month, between 9 and ten at night, I was at supper with some friends at my house, and one of my servants told me a dumb fortune teller was below, who must speak with me. Having a mind for a little diversion I order'd her to be brought up, and accordingly the Prisoner appear'd. When she saw me, she made signs with her fingers that an old servant of mine had robb'd me of 2 pieces of gold; I was very much surpriz'd at an accusation of this sort against a person who had liv'd with me 20 years, and therefore in the Prisoner's presence I went to my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174108280006"></xptr> closet where I had 11 five guinea pieces. I took out the drawer, and she came behind me, put her hand into the drawer, and before I could stop her, took out a handful. After this she toss'd them into a lady's lap, then upon the table, and afterwards into a little girl's pocket. She then began to speak, and accused my servant again, and I was going to send to a Justice of the peace that moment, but the Prisoner told me my servant had got a false key and robb'd me while I was asleep, and if I would be patient, she would come next morning at 9 clock, and bring the man who made the false key with her, and he would discover all. With some impatience I waited the Prisoner's coming next morning, and my servant was in great trouble at being accus'd in this manner, but the Prisoner not coming according to her promise I suspected her, and on looking over my money I miss'd the 3 five guinea pieces mentioned in the indictment. Upon this I sent a servant of mine with other people in search after the Prisoner, and offer'd a guinea reward to any person that should bring her to justice. On the monday following I heard that the Prisoner had bought a pair of shoes and changed a Queen Ann's 5 guinea piece at Kensington, and after that, by some other intelligence that my servants got, the Prisoner was taken in Drury Lane. This is the 5 guinea piece which the Prisoner changed, and I am positive it is mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He gave me a supper, wine, punch and money, and why did he not search me before I left his house?</p>
               <p>Mr. Maynard. I had no suspicion of her then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It is very hard that I could take the money before his daughter's and his house keeper's face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person98">
                  Robert 
                  Lincham 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person98" type="surname" value="Lincham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person98" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On sunday morning the 12th of July the Prisoner and another woman came to my shop at Kensington to buy a pair of shoes. I sold the Prisoner a pair, and she told me she could not pay me unless I could change her a five guinea piece. This piece she gave me, and I went to Mr. Lock's with it, and he changed it for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person99">
                  Tho 
                  Tucker 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person99" type="surname" value="Tucker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person99" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I fetch'd this piece from Mr. Lock's the distiller's on the monday morning.</p>
               <p>Lincham. I gave the Prisoner the change, and then she said she had saved it at work at a farmer's at Ealing, and that it was her summer's work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person100">
                  Isaac 
                  Lock 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person100" type="surname" value="Lock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person100" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the matter, only that Lincham brought a 5 guinea piece to me and desir'd me to change it for him, and I believe this to be the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person101">
                  Margaret 
                  Rigley 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person101" type="surname" value="Rigley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person101" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Grey-Hound at Hammersmith. The Prisoner came to our house and made signs for a lodging, I can't tell what day of the month it was, but it was on a sunday. We gave her a lodging out of charity, and about a fortnight afterward she came again, and then she spoke, and said she wanted to buy a pair of shoes: she desir'd me to lend her my hat to cover her face for fear she should be seen; I did so, and went with her to Mr. Lincham's, where I saw her buy a pair of shoes, and change this 5 guinea piece.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I change a guinea the thursday before the gentleman was robb'd; and did I not tell you I had five more?</p>
               <p>Rigley. She did change a guinea at my landlady's, and said she had 5 more in her petticoats beside that which she had changed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I brought this piece from Ireland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person102">
                  William 
                  Connor 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person102" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person102" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner about 6 months. I keep a public house, and she has come and spent 3 d. with me, and I never saw any thing by her but what was very good. She always us'd to speak when she came to my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17410828-11-person103">
                  Catharine 
                  Connor 
               <interp inst="t17410828-11-person103" type="surname" value="Connor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person103" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-person103" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 6 months. She has drank a pot of beer in my house, and always paid for it. <rs id="t17410828-11-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17410828-11-punish67" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17410828-11-punish67" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17410828-11-defend95 t17410828-11-punish67"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
