<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-13">
               <interp inst="t17470225-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-13" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-13" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-13-off56-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-13-defend192 t17470225-13-off56 t17470225-13-verdict58"></join>
         
               <p>144. 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-13-defend192" type="defendantName">
                     Paul 
                     Rankin 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-13-defend192" type="surname" value="Rankin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-defend192" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-defend192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-13-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing three Pair of Worsted Stockings, value 12 s. one Pair of Thread Stockings, value 2 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-13-victim194" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Colley 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-13-victim194" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-victim194" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-victim194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-13-off56 t17470225-13-victim194"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , of Chandois-street, <rs id="t17470225-13-cd57" type="crimeDate">February 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-13-off56 t17470225-13-cd57"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person195">
                  Anne 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person195" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person195" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What do you know in Relation to this Fact charged upon the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Colley. On the third of this Month the Prisoner at the Bar, and another, came into my Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married Woman?</p>
               <p>Colley. Yes, Sir, my Husband's Name is 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person196">
                  Richard 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person196" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person196" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the Prisoner and another came for a Pair of Stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. What then?</p>
               <p>Colley. Then I said, please to wait a Moment, I will light a Candle; while I went to light a Candle, and coming back I missed two Pair of Stockings, I charged them with it; I came round the Compter, as if I would search them, and they run out of the Shop, and I cried out, Stop Thief; I saw him pull out the Stockings from between his Legs, when I came to search him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were these Stockings lying?</p>
               <p>Colley. They were behind the Compter, where the Stockings lay.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they made of?</p>
               <p>Colley. They were three Pair of Worsted Stockings, and a Pair of Thread.</p>
               <p>Court. Could you see that they were the Stockings that you missed?</p>
               <p>Colley. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know that any thing was gone?</p>
               <p>Colley. I knew there were so many Stockings gone.</p>
               <p>Court. You say you called Stop Thief, did they catch them?</p>
               <p>Colley. There was a little Boy at a Silver Smiths, and another Man run after him, and he was taken in Castle-street; I live in Chandois street.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen these Stockings since?</p>
               <p>Colley. Yes, my Lord, I could swear to my Goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought them to you?</p>
               <p>Colley. The Man that took the Prisoner brought them, 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person197">
                  John 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person197" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. And the Stockings 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person198">
                  John 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person198" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person198" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought to you are your Stockings?</p>
               <p>Colley. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Will you ask any Questions to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person199">
                  Anne 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person199" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person199" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I want to know, Sir, that she will take her Oath that I was the Person that took these Stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person200">
                  Anne 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person200" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person200" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Could you swear that those Stockings were your's that he had between his Legs?</p>
               <p>Colley. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person201">
                  John 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person201" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person201" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner? What do you know in Relation to the cry of Stop Thief?</p>
               <p>Hicks. I was in my Master's Shop, the King's Glazier, Mr. Carn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your Master live?</p>
               <p>Hicks. In St. Martin's-lane. I was lighting Candles, and I heard a gre cry, Stop Thief, stop Thief! The Prisoner run with a Mob after him up Hemming's Row; I was informed the Prisoner at the Bar ran down with a Bundle under his Arm, and went down the Red Lyon Inn Yard in Castle-street: a Man turns down there, and sees the Prisoner doing his Occasions there, under a Shed; when the Person came that see him run away from the Woman's Door, he would swear that he was the Person that run from the Woman's Door; he said I had wronged him, I said I hoped I had, for you look a likely young Fellow, and I hoped he was not guilty of the Fact; we looked in the Chaise, he was between the two Shafts, doing his Occasions; and looking about the Chaise I picked up these two Bundles of Stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say then?</p>
               <p>Hicks. He would not own any thing of it; with that I brought him to this Woman's Shop, and she said that was the Person that went away with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you shew the Stockings to Mrs. Colley?</p>
               <p>Hicks. Yes, Sir, we gave them into her Possession directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Prisoner say there?</p>
               <p>Hicks. He said nothing there, but we took him before Justice Burdns, and he owned it, that his Comrade stooped over the Compter, and took them up for him to run away with them.</p>
               <p>John Ware. I was standing at my Master's Door, Mr. Gulte's, a Silver-Smith in Chandois-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How near Mrs. Colley's Shop?</p>
               <p>Ware. Almost over against it: I heard a Noise, Stop Thief! and I ran on as the rest did to see what was the Matter, and I run up Hemming's-Row, and we could not tell where the Prisoner was gone; some said they see him run down Red Lion yard, and there he was found doing his Occasions, and these two Bundles were found under a Board, hard by the Chaise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go with him to Mrs. Colley's?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250019"></xptr>Ware. Yes. Sir, and Mrs. Colley owned the Goods. but he said another Man was along with him, and took them.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. What have you to say in your Defence?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The young Man that was with me, that belonged to the Duke Privateer, he took these Stockings, and as there was a Cry of Stop Thief. I ran away too, for fear of being taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person202">
                  Anne 
                  Colley 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person202" type="surname" value="Colley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person202" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person203">
                  John 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person203" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the Boy brought him and the Bundles, were the Bundles as they were in your Shop?</p>
               <p>Colley. They were not opened, but as they were in the Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-13-person204">
                  William 
                  Cleugh 
               <interp inst="t17470225-13-person204" type="surname" value="Cleugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person204" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cleugh. I cannot say that I have known him of late Years; I have known his Father these twenty Years; his Father bore a good Character, nor I never heard any thing of the Prisoner before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-13-verdict58" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-verdict58" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-verdict58" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-13-punish59" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-13-punish59" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-13-defend192 t17470225-13-punish59"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
