<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17481012-1">
               <interp inst="t17481012-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-1" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17481012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17481012-1" type="date" value="17481012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17481012-1-off2-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-1-defend30 t17481012-1-off2 t17481012-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>479. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17481012-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17481012-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-defend30" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17481012-1-defloc1">St. Dunstan's Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-1-defloc1" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan's Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17481012-1-defloc1" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-1-defend30 t17481012-1-defloc1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17481012-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 50 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17481012-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17481012-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-1-victim32" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17481012-1-victim32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-1-off2 t17481012-1-victim32"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17481012-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">September 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-1-off2 t17481012-1-cd3"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-1-person33">
                  Thomas 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person33" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person33" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , on the 20th of September, I lost a silver watch off a chest of drawers out of my bed-chamber; and when I came down, I found the back door open and upon the jar: I advertised it the next day, and Mr. Herring brought it to me, and told me he had bought it of 
               <persName id="t17481012-1-person34">
                  John 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person34" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person34" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I know him, because I saw him in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any thing of him of your own knowledge?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No; Mr. Herring told me, he bought the watch of Morris, and that he told him he bought it at Chatham ; he said afterwards, he bought it of a man that was going to Chatham , and desired I would not do him any harm. Mr. Herring had heard of a man that was found concealed in a house at Wapping-wall, and he knew him to be the man he bought the watch of.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever see me before that time in your Life.</p>
               <p>Johnson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray my lad what trade are you? [here the prosecutor was stopped.]</p>
               <p>Mr. Herring . On the 22d of September, between 4 and 5 in the afternoon, the prisoner came to my house [by alderman Parson's brew-house] and offered to sell me a watch; I asked him where he had the watch from; he said he was a sailor just come from Guinea, and had money to receive, but he must sell the watch; and he told me he had some gold dust to sell; I told him I did not understand Gold dust, and would not look at it; I look'd on the watch, and asked him what he would have for it; he said it cost him 3 l. at Chatham ; I told him I would give him 45 s. for it; it was worth about that, for the watch was dirty,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120003"></xptr> and the dial-plate was hardly to be seen; and I told him when he had received his money he should have the watch again for 5 s. more. When I found the watch was advertised, I carried it to Mr. Johnson, and he gave me the 45 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>Herring. I know he is the man, but I do not know that I saw him before; some of the people said he was a dangerous fellow; and that some Irish fellows would rescue him, he being an Irish man. When he came to my shop, he appeared very remarkable with his face scratched: he brought the watch to me the very same day it was lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give an account how you came by this watch?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought it of a sailor, at the three tuns at Greenwich.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before you offered it to this Gentleman?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. About 12 o'clock in the day.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his name?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not ask his name.</p>
               <p>Q. What ship did he say he belonged to?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . He said he belonged to the Monmouth, Captain Harrison, a 70 gun ship.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was upon a Thursday, last Thursday was a month.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was upon a Thursday?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, my lord, it was upon a Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. What Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was a month yesterday *.</p>
               <p>* The watch was not lost then, it was not lost till the 22d of September.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-1-person35">
                  Mary 
                  Follyer 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person35" type="surname" value="Follyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person35" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person35" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the 3 Tuns in Greenwich on the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. What Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Follyer . Why this day month if I am not mistaken.</p>
               <p>Q. Why this is Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Follyer . Oh, it was a month yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I live in St. Catherine's Lane by the Tower.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Follyer. This young woman [
               <persName id="t17481012-1-person36">
                  Mary 
                  Connelly 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person36" type="surname" value="Connelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person36" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person36" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ] and I were drinking in a box, and the prisoner and a sailor came in, and the prisoner and the sailor were arguing.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they arguing about?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I found at the latter end that it was about a watch, and the sailor asked the prisoner 3 guineas for it, and said it cost him 3 guineas; the prisoner said it was too dear, and I think they agreed for 40 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any other company in the house?</p>
               <p>Follyer. There was no company in the foreroom.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do there?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I went to receive some money for rabbits, I deal in rabbits.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any money paid for it?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I saw 40 s. paid for it.</p>
               <p>Q. What money was it paid in?</p>
               <p>Follyer. It was paid in small silver and large silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gold?</p>
               <p>Follyer. Not to my knowledge, and he bid me take notice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he suppose it to be stolen?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to come here?</p>
               <p>Follyer. The prisoner sent for us this morning, he knew where to send to us.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he send to you?</p>
               <p>Follyer. To St. Catherine's Lane .</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to know your names?</p>
               <p>Follyer. He took down our names, and I suppose if there had been other people in the house he would have taken down their names.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before you saw him at Greenwich?</p>
               <p>Follyer. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Greenwich?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I can't pretend to say.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you go over the water to it?</p>
               <p>Follyer. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you cross the water?</p>
               <p>Follyer. It is against Iron Gate I believe that we cross'd the water.</p>
               <p>Q. You don't appear ever to have been at Greenwich in your life, speak nothing but the truth, what sort of a place is Greenwich?</p>
               <p>Follyer. It is a very pretty place.</p>
               <p>Q. How many churches are there in it.</p>
               <p>Follyer. I can't tell; there is a park and an hospital there.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is nearest the water side, the park or the hospital?</p>
               <p>Follyer. Upon my word I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know the prisoner's name?</p>
               <p>Follyer. I did not know his Name till this morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it to Greenwich? is it half a mile or a mile.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174810120004"></xptr>Follyer. It is a great deal more than that.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you been at Greenwich?</p>
               <p>Follyer. 2 or 3 times I believe, not very often.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17481012-1-person37">
                  Mary 
                  Connelly 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person37" type="surname" value="Connelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person37" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person37" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with 
               <persName id="t17481012-1-person38">
                  Mary 
                  Follyer 
               <interp inst="t17481012-1-person38" type="surname" value="Follyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person38" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-person38" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at a public house, at the 3 tuns .</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Connelly . At Chelsea I think, and the prisoner and a sailor came in, and they were bargaining about a watch, and I heard the sailor ask 3 guineas for it, and they bargained for 40 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else in the house then?</p>
               <p>Connelly . No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the watch paid for?</p>
               <p>Connelly. I saw the Money paid down upon the table.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>Connelly. It was this day Month.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it paid in?</p>
               <p>Connelly. It was paid in silver; half crowns and shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gold.</p>
               <p>Connelly . I don't know but there might be half a guinea, and this young man [the prisoner] came into my company and the seafaring man went away, and I never saw the prisoner before nor since I saw him that day.</p>
               <p>Q. And have not you seen him from that day to this?</p>
               <p>Connelly. Never but once.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him in Newgate?</p>
               <p>Connelly . I saw him in the hole.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Connelly . Not long ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How many hours?</p>
               <p>Connelly . Not many hours, about two hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know his name then?</p>
               <p>Connelly . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live at Chelsea.</p>
               <p>Connelly. No I live in St. Catherine's Lane .</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come from Chelsea?</p>
               <p>Connelly. I came on foot all the way.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not come in a boat any part of the way.</p>
               <p>Connelly. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your constant employ?</p>
               <p>Connelly. Service.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever deal in Rabbits?</p>
               <p>Connelly . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the other young woman any rabbits then ?</p>
               <p>Connelly . Yes, but she had sold them all.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did you get to London after you had been at Chelsea.</p>
               <p>Connelly . My lord it was not Chelsea, but I can't think of the name of the place.</p>
               <p>Q. What place did you go over to go to it?</p>
               <p>Connelly. Over Battle-bridge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ask you your name?</p>
               <p>Connelly. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Connelly. This day month.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you remember this man's face so long ago as a month, and have never seen him before nor since, till within these 2 hours?</p>
               <p>Connelly. I do remember it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Greenwich park?</p>
               <p>Connelly. I don't think I should know it if I was to see it.</p>
               <p>Pris. My lord they are drunk now.</p>
               <p>The Jury <rs id="t17481012-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-verdict4" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               acquitted the prisoner of stealing in the dwelling-house, and found him guilty of single felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Court committed Follyer and Connelly into the custody of the keeper of Newgate, in order to their being indicted the next sessions for perjury.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17481012-1-punish5" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17481012-1-punish5" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17481012-1-defend30 t17481012-1-punish5"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
