<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17480526-25">
               <interp inst="t17480526-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-25" type="year" value="1748"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17480526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17480526-25" type="date" value="17480526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480526-25-off143-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-defend268 t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-verdict146"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17480526-25-off147-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-defend268 t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-verdict146"></join>
         
               <p>289. + 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-defend268" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-defend268" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-defend268" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-defend268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17480526-25-defloc142">St. George Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-defloc142" type="placeName" value="St. George Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-defloc142" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-defend268 t17480526-25-defloc142"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17480526-25-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               (with Elizabeth Johnson, not taken) for stealing thirteen silk handkerchiefs, value 48 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480526-25-victim270" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Flower 
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim270" type="surname" value="Flower"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim270" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17480526-25-cd144" type="crimeDate">May 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-cd144"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-cd144"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person271">
                  Francis 
                  Flower 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person271" type="surname" value="Flower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person271" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday was sevennight the Prisoner came to my shop, under pretence of buying some silk handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your shop?</p>
               <p>Flower. In <placeName id="t17480526-25-crimeloc145">King's-street, Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc145" type="placeName" value="King's-street, Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc145" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-crimeloc145"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-crimeloc145"></join>. I had but one servant in the shop, and I heard two people there; I was busy writing backwards, and did not go into the shop; afterwards I heard a third person come in, it was in the dusk of the evening, and I thought three persons were too many for my boy to serve, and the Prisoner at the bar, or another woman, had some money in her hand, and paid for a handkerchief. A neighbour came in and cautioned me, that if such a person was not gone, to examine her, for she believed she was a shop-lifter . The handkerchiefs were all in a confusion, but the boy gave me a pretty good account, and I was satisfied; and I did not miss the handkerchiefs till the Friday following, and then I missed a piece. Mrs. Wycherly sent me word, that she had been searching after her goods, and had found her muslin, and that she believed she had seen some handkerchiefs that she had seen at my house. I went to Mrs. Wycherly, and she told me, if I would go with her in the evening, she believed she could find the people that had them; I told her I should take it very kindly. Mrs. Wycherly saw the two women [the Prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person272">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person272" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person272" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ] accidentally coming by, just about the dusk of the evening; these two women were taken up, and carried before Justice Broadhead .</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take them herself?</p>
               <p>Flower . She secured them in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What in your shop, or Mrs. Wycherly's?</p>
               <p>Flower. No, in the shop where the goods were found. The minute I saw the Prisoner's face , I was certain to her face, for I was too well acquainted with her, and knew she had been too often with me, and the person who was in my shop positively said she was the person who was in the shop that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find your goods again?</p>
               <p>Flower. I got part of them at Mrs. Loach's, in Bow-street, Bloomsbury , and part of them in Holborn .</p>
               <p>[The handkerchiefs were produced.]</p>
               <p>Q. Are these the handkerchiefs that were taken out of your shop?</p>
               <p>Flower . Yes; here are seven of them, and there have been six sold.</p>
               <p>Q. You are sure the whole thirteen were your handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Flower. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. You say there were two women in your shop, you don't know who took them?</p>
               <p>Flower. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. If you had met the Prisoner in Cheapside. could you have known her?</p>
               <p>Flower. If I had looked at her earnestly I should have known her again.</p>
               <p>Court. Are you sure she is the person?</p>
               <p>Flower. Yes.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Are you sure that these are part of your goods?</p>
               <p>Flower. Yes , I am sure of it, because I never sold any but singly .</p>
               <p>Q. They are a common sort of handkerchiefs, are there no other of that pattern but what you had?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174805260023"></xptr>Flower . There are some; though but few.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person273">
                  Martha 
                  Esham 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person273" type="surname" value="Esham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person273" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Esham. Yes, I have seen her about three times in my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your shop?</p>
               <p>Esham. In Holborn.</p>
               <p>Q What business is yours?</p>
               <p>Esham. I deal in clothes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of these handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Esham. About the 16th or 17th of this instant the Prisoner came with some handkerchiefs to my shop, and another woman with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they come for?</p>
               <p>Esham. With handkerchiefs, and I bought six of them, and gave her eighteen shillings for them, and I thought it was a very good price.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe these to be the handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Esham . I believe they are. Mr. Flower came to my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to come there?</p>
               <p>Esham. He was informed by Mrs. Wycherly, that she believed she could help him to the handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Mr. Flower come to your shop?</p>
               <p>Esham. Mr. Flowe came to my shop on Saturday last, in the morning, and said I had got very pretty handkerchiefs , and he looked at them, and said he believed they were his, and I went with him to the Justice's.</p>
               <p>Pris. Coun. Did Mr. Flower say positively, that they were his handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Esham. Mr. Flower said he could positively swear to this piece (the red ones) but not to the others.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any reason to suspect the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Esham . No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the Prisoner often?</p>
               <p>Esham . I had seen her about three times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person274">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Loach 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person274" type="surname" value="Loach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person274" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the Prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Loach. Yes, three times.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Loach . In Bow-street, Bloomsbury.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to see her there?</p>
               <p>Loach. The Prisoner and another woman brought some handkerchiefs, and they sold me seven of them for twenty shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy them?</p>
               <p>Loach. Some time last week, but I cannot be sure what day.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the handkerchiefs to be out of your custody?</p>
               <p>Loach. I put them out to sale, and Mrs. Wycherly came and looked at them, and asked me the price of them, I asked her three shillings and sixpence, and she was to give me three shillings. I gave two shillings and sixpence for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Flower come afterwards?</p>
               <p>Loach. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say they were his?</p>
               <p>Loach. He did as good as say so, but he was not quite positive; he could scarcely say they were his?</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Loach. He said he could not swear they were his, but at last he was positive, and then he took them away.</p>
               <p>Q. So you are sure the Prisoner at the bar was one of the women that brought them to your house?</p>
               <p>Loach. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person275">
                  Ann 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person275" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person275" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I saw the Prisoner in Mr. Flower's shop, while I was buying some tape.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I cannot be certain; but to the best of my knowledge it was Tuesday was sevennight. There were two women in the shop, and when I came in I was the third.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they doing?</p>
               <p>Robinson. The young man was cutting off a handkerchief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person276">
                  Francis 
                  Bishop 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person276" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person276" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say against the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bishop. The Prisoner and another woman came into the shop to buy some handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you Mr. Flower's servant?</p>
               <p>Bishop. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Bishop. I believe it was Tuesday or Wednesday sevennight.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say?</p>
               <p>Bishop. When they came into the shop, they said they wanted a handkerchief with a border; I shewed them some, and they did not like them; I reached some more down, and they did not like them; then they wanted a sattinet handkerchief, I shewed them some, and we bargained for four shillings and sixpence for one. I had begun to cut it off, but my master cut it quite off, and took the money for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174805260024"></xptr>Prisoner . I do not know but they might be stole , but I bought the muslin and the handkerchiefs together, and I sold the muslin first, and the handkerchiefs afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where di d you buy the handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. In Dean-street, Soho .</p>
               <p>Q. Of who?</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Of a pedling sort of a man, who looked very well; he said he wanted money, and was going into the country; I went into an alehouse, and bought them. The gentlewoman, who was along with me, is gone away, she was so frightened .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person277">
                  Bridget 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person277" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person277" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>Smith. Eight or nine years.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she a husband?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, he is a sailor.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does she follow?</p>
               <p>Smith. She follows her needle.</p>
               <p>Rose Conway. I have known the Prisoner three or four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of her?</p>
               <p>Conway . I never knew any thing but what was honest by her.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does she follow?</p>
               <p>Conway . I don't know that she follows any business .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person278">
                  Peter 
                  Churchill 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person278" type="surname" value="Churchill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person278" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known the Prisoner three years, she lodged in my house about three or four months.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago was this?</p>
               <p>Churchill. This time twelve month.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she get her livelyhood?</p>
               <p>Churchill . Her husband belonged to the Prince 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person279">
                  Frederick 
                  Privateer 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person279" type="surname" value="Privateer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person279" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she had a bill of sale left her by her husband ?</p>
               <p>Pris . Coun. Then she was in good circumstances I suppose.</p>
               <p>Churchill . She paid me very honestly .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person280">
                  James 
                  Conway 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person280" type="surname" value="Conway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person280" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner better than four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know her charged with a crime of this nature before?</p>
               <p>Conway. Never; and I never heard any harm of her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I bought them at the Crown Alehouse, in Dean-street, Soho. <rs id="t17480526-25-verdict146" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-verdict146" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-verdict146" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Acquitted of privately stealing in the shop: Guilty of the felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person281">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person281" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person281" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was a second time indicted, for that <rs id="t17480526-25-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               she on the <rs id="t17480526-25-cd148" type="crimeDate">13th day of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-cd148"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-cd148"></join>, at the parish of <placeName id="t17480526-25-crimeloc149">St. Paul, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc149" type="placeName" value="St. Paul, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc149" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-crimeloc149"></join>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-crimeloc149"></join>, twenty-seven yards and a half of muslin, value 7 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17480526-25-victim283" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Wycherly 
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim283" type="surname" value="Wycherly"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim283" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17480526-25-victim283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop of the said Mary, did privately and feloniously steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, against the peace of our sovereign lord the King, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person284">
                  Mary 
                  Wycherly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person284" type="surname" value="Wycherly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person284" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. In <placeName id="t17480526-25-crimeloc150">St. James's Street, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc150" type="placeName" value="St. James's Street, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17480526-25-crimeloc150" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off143 t17480526-25-crimeloc150"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-off147 t17480526-25-crimeloc150"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What shop do you keep?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. A <rs id="t17480526-25-viclabel151" type="occupation">Linen-draper's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-victim270 t17480526-25-viclabel151"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-victim283 t17480526-25-viclabel151"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of losing any muslin ?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . Yes, I lost twenty-seven yards and a half of muslin out of my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . I think it was this day fortnight, in the evening, as near as I can remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the muslin when it was lost?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . I believe it was upon my Counter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she come into your Shop for?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. She and another woman came under pretence of buying some muslin, but they bought half a yard of cambrick; I suspected them, and I did not like them.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason had you to suspect them?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . Because they pulled the cambricks and lawns about very much, and spread out very near a whole piece of cambrick.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after this?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . They went away.</p>
               <p>Q When did you miss this muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . I missed it that evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. To the best of my knowledge it was in a drawer upon the end of the counter. There is one 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person285">
                  Sarah 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person285" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person285" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who deals with me, said she had bought some muslin at a shop in Holborn, and asked my opinion of it?</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . The Tuesday or Wednesday following, and she shewing me the muslin, I thought it looked so much like mine, that I believed it to be mine; and I asked her what she gave a yard for it ? she said 4 s. 6 d. and that cost me 6 s. a yard. I then desired that 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person286">
                  Sarah 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person286" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person286" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would go with my servant to the shop in Holborn, where she said she bought it; and they both did go.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not go with them?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it that they bought it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174805260025"></xptr>Wycherly. At the Anchor; I don't know the gentlewoman's name.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your servant's name?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. It is Betty; but I don't know her other name.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner afterwards?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. Yes, I took her and 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person287">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person287" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person287" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at a shop in Holborn, and the Prisoner said she had sold one of the pieces in Bow-street, Bloomsbury .</p>
               <p>Q. What was there of it?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. There were twenty yards of yard-wide, and seven yards and a half of yard and half-wide: I went the next morning to that shop in Bow-street, and there I heard where the other muslin was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person288">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Instant 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person288" type="surname" value="Instant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person288" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you servant to Mrs. Wycherly?</p>
               <p>Instant. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sent into Holborn with Mrs. Wells?</p>
               <p>Instant. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of that.</p>
               <p>Instant. Mrs. Wells and I went to the shop in Holborn.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the name of the person who keeps it?</p>
               <p>Instant. Esham, it is a clothes-shop. I asked her how she came by the muslin, and who she bought it of? she said she bought it of a Holland trader. I asked her what sort of a person it was? she said there were two, one was a tall woman, and the other a short one, and she said she bought it of the short one, 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person289">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person289" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person289" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What, did she say she bought of 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person290">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person290" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person290" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Instant. She said she bought seven yards and an half of yard and half-wide muslin.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person291">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Esham 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person291" type="surname" value="Esham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person291" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account what muslin you bought of the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Esham . On the 13th instant the Prisoner brought seven yards and an half of muslin to my shop, and she said she had ten yards of another sort.</p>
               <p>Q. And did you buy this of her?</p>
               <p>Esham . I bought seven yards and an half of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the woman at the bar?</p>
               <p>Esham . Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. You did not buy the other, I think.</p>
               <p>Esham . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you buy the other?</p>
               <p>Esham. I bid her money for the seven yards and an half, and she went out of the shop and went away. She came a second time, and said she had sold the other piece .</p>
               <p>Q. What price did you give for that muslin?</p>
               <p>Esham. 3 s. 6 d. a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is it?</p>
               <p>Esham. Yard and half wide.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person292">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Loach 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person292" type="surname" value="Loach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person292" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>The same day the Prisoner at the bar came to me, and I bought some muslin of her.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it?</p>
               <p>Loach. I think it was this day fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you deal in?</p>
               <p>Loach. I deal in clothes, as that gentlewoman does [Mrs. Esham]. I bought twenty yards of muslin of the Prisoner, it was but yard wide, and I gave her 3 s. 6 d. a yard for it; I have sold all the muslin, unless one yard that I kept for my own use.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got that here?</p>
               <p>Loach. Yes, I have.</p>
               <p>[The muslin was produced.]</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wycherly. Here is another yard that was bought at Mrs. Loach's; I suspected my muslin to be there, and I sent a young woman to buy a yard of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that your muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. Yes, they are both mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any mark upon them?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What, don't you mark your goods at the end?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. Yes; but neither of these are marked.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not one of them the fag end?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. Neither of them is the fag end.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Esham called again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sell any of this muslin?</p>
               <p>Esham. I sold two yards of this muslin to a gentlewoman here in court.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is that?</p>
               <p>Esham. One Mrs. Wells.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wells called.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy any muslin of Mrs. Esham?</p>
               <p>Wells. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sent by Mrs. Wycherly ?</p>
               <p>Wells . No, it was casually; I went in for some handkerchiefs, and she said she had got some muslin to dispose of; and I bought two yards and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Wells . I think it was Wednesday was sev'nnight, and I took it to Mrs. Wycherly's.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take it there?</p>
               <p>Wells . Because I sell goods for Mrs. Wycherly.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174805260026"></xptr>[The two yards and an half of muslin was produced.]</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Wycherly . Can you swear that to be your muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. No, my Lord, I cannot positively, because there is no mark upon it; but 'tis very like it; I had a suspicion that it was my muslin that was at the shop in Bow-street, and I sent a young woman to buy some.</p>
               <p>Q. You cannot positively say that is your muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . No, but I have a great deal of reason to suspect the Prisoner, and the shop where it was found, for I saw 
               <persName id="t17480526-25-person293">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person293" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person293" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there. I heard that part of my muslin was sold in Bow-street; I went to the shop, and told her, I wanted some goods; she asked me, if I was a country milliner? I said, yes, and I should be here a fortnight, and if she had any goods in that time that would suit me, I would buy them. I shut up my own shop, and made it my business to detect them : I went to the shop, and found Kelly and Johnson in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the shop in Bow-street?</p>
               <p>Wycherly . Yes; I said they were shop-lifters, and kept them in the shop, and I was there for a quarter of an hour, and could not get any body to assist me; but at last I got Kelly and Johnson secured, and carried them before a justice of the peace: there is a piece of muslin that they had, which is in the hands of one Jones a constable; for they would have made it up with me.</p>
               <p>[Mr. Jones was called, and produced the muslin.]</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Wycherly . Is this your muslin?</p>
               <p>Wycherly. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>[This not being owned, it was the property of the Sheriffs, but Mr. Sheriff Davis made a present of it to Mrs. Wycherly.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person294">
                  Thomas 
                  Barrett 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person294" type="surname" value="Barrett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person294" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn .</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Barrett. I am a constable; when the constable brought the Prisoner before the justice, I was there with other people, and the Prisoner and the other denied it; and after she was examined before the justice , I took her down into the yard with Mrs. Wycherly, and desired she would acknowledge to Mrs. Wycherly, whether she took the muslin or no, and then she might have favour; and she did by that means own, that she took it out of Mrs. Wycherly's shop, and sold twenty yards to a gentlewoman in Bow-street, Bloomsbury, and seven yards and an half to a gentlewoman in Holborn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17480526-25-person295">
                  John 
                  Rishton 
               <interp inst="t17480526-25-person295" type="surname" value="Rishton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mrs. Wycherly's shop, in order to help her, for she was selling off; I folded up this muslin, and put it into a drawer: yesterday se'nnight Mrs. Wycherly and Mrs. Wells came to our house.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is your house?</p>
               <p>Rishton. I live at a Linen-draper's in Duke's-Court, and Mrs. Wycherly and Mrs. Wells asked me, whether I knew the muslin? and I said it looked very much like hers, for it run a very great breadth; it run a nail above yard and half wide, and I asked Mrs. Well, whether she saw the fag end? she said, no: I said there was a mark upon it, and two stripes at the end.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480526-25-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-verdict152" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17480526-25-punish153" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17480526-25-punish153" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17480526-25-defend268 t17480526-25-punish153"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
