<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421208-33">
               <interp inst="t17421208-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-33" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421208-33" type="date" value="17421208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421208-33-off171-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-defend292 t17421208-33-off171 t17421208-33-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080022"></xptr>35. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-defend292" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Hassell 
                  <interp inst="t17421208-33-defend292" type="surname" value="Hassell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-defend292" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-defend292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17421208-33-defloc170">St Margaret, Fish-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-33-defloc170" type="placeName" value="St Margaret, Fish-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-33-defloc170" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-defend292 t17421208-33-defloc170"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17421208-33-off171" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-off171" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-off171" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing forty Pieces of Portugal Gold Coin, called Moidores, Value 54 l. and thirty-five Pieces of Gold Coin called Guineas, Value 36 l. 15 s. the Monies of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-33-victim294" type="victimName">
                           Philip 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim294" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim294" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-33-victim296" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Slater 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim296" type="surname" value="Slater"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim296" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17421208-33-victim298" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim298" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim298" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421208-33-victim298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in their Dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17421208-33-cd172" type="crimeDate">Oct. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-off171 t17421208-33-cd172"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-person299">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person299" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person299" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was <rs id="t17421208-33-deflabel173" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-defend292 t17421208-33-deflabel173"></join> to 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person300">
                  Philip 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person300" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person300" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person301">
                  Samuel 
                  Slater 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person301" type="surname" value="Slater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person301" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and my self: He li ved with us on <placeName id="t17421208-33-crimeloc174">Fish-street Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-33-crimeloc174" type="placeName" value="Fish-street Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421208-33-crimeloc174" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-off171 t17421208-33-crimeloc174"></join> by the Monument upwards of two Months. On the 30th of October in the Forenoon, I was informed that he left the House at 8 in the Morning with a Bundle under his Arm; and my Servants thought he would not return any more. I went into the Compting-House, examined the Cash, and found a Deficiency of 90 l. 15 s. I suspected him, because he was the only Servant who had Access to the Compting-House. The Money was in a Desk in the Compting-House, of which he had a Key, but did not take it away with him. We enquired what Places he frequented, and endeavoured to pursue him: The same Morning, about twelve o'Clock, my Partner, 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person302">
                  Samuel 
                  Slater 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person302" type="surname" value="Slater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person302" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , apprehended him at his Barber's, and he was brought back to the Compting-House by my Partner and 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person303">
                  David 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person303" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person303" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - I was there when he was brought in. He seemed a little confounded : I told him I wondered he should take away such a Sum of Money. I sent for a Constable, and ordered my Servant and the Constable to search him. The Prisoner put his Hand in his Pocket, and took out six Moidores and one Guinea; and in a little Time he owned the Fact, and that he had taken out of the Desk forty Moidores and thirty-five Guineas; that he went to a Gaming-House, and had lost it all but this. Upon searching his Pockets there was this Letter found, which was then sealed up, and the Wafer hardly dry; it is directed to Mr Fuller, a worthy Gentleman whom he had lived with. I believe it to be his Hand-writing.</p>
               <p>The Letter was then read, viz.</p>
               <p>To Mr Fuller, Writing Master, in Ingram-Court, Fenchurch-Street.</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>'' I Doubt not but by this Time you're informed '' of my unfortunate Conduct, which has put '' a Period to Happiness in this Life, and have nothing '' to hope for, but to drag on a miserable '' and disgraceful Life, ne'er more to expect any '' Favour from that Part of Mankind which I '' flatter'd myself have some generous Sentiments '' of me. For unhappily was I led the Way to '' a Gaming-House, which induc'd me to venture '' the Money I was intrusted with, in Hopes of recovering '' myself from the indigent Circumstances '' you are thoroughly acquainted with, but was so '' unhappy to lose it all, to the Value of an 100 l. '' and therefore am become a Vagabond, and '' God only knows the Consequence. I remain,</p>
               <p>'' The most miserable among Mankind,</p>
               <p>'' 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person304">
                  RICHARD 
                  HASSELL 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person304" type="surname" value="HASSELL"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person304" type="given" value="RICHARD"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask my Master, if it was not in my Power to have defrauded him of a great deal more Money than he charges me with?</p>
               <p>Mr 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person305">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person305" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person305" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, my Lord, he had an Opportunity of taking more than he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-person306">
                  David 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person306" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person306" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Prisoner was Fellow-Servant with me about two Months. - I saw him come in in the Morning after Lord-Mayor's-Day, about eight o'Clock, and go out again with a Bundle under his Arm. My Fellow-Servant told me he had been out all Night. My! Master came down half an Hour after, and enquired where he was; and he being absent for two or three Hours, my Master enquired again, and then examined his Cash, and finding it deficient, he asked me where he us'd to go; I told him it was likely that he was at his Barber's. on St Mary-hill. My Master Slater and I found him there: We brought him back to my Master's House, and the Constable searched him in my Presence. He owned he took the Money laid in the Indictment out of the Desk in the Compting-House, and had lost it at a Gaming-House.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My having a Key, was the Reason of their suspecting me. I desire he may be asked, whether he does not know other People, who have not been concerned in the Compting-House, that have defrauded these Gentlemen?</p>
               <p>Todd. There's no body trusted with the Key, but my Master and himself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Slater's Son had a Key of the Compting-house.</p>
               <p>Todd. Yes, my Master Slater's Son had a Key; there are five Keys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-person307">
                  Thomas 
                  Nettlefold 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person307" type="surname" value="Nettlefold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person307" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Constable. On the 30th of October, I was sent for to the Prisoner's Masters, when I came into the Compting-House, Mr Brown and Mr Slater charged me with him, for robbing them of 90 l. and upwards; I was ordered to search him, so he put his Hand in his Pocket , and delivered to me six Moidores and one Guinea.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174212080023"></xptr> This is the Money, it was sealed up by Sir 
               <persName id="t17421208-33-person308">
                  William 
                  Billers 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person308" type="surname" value="Billers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person308" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , with his Seal. He owned to me that he took forty Moidores and thirty-five Guineas, and that he went to my Lord Mordington's, where he was all Night, and there lost the rest of the Money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Reason of my Absence in the Morning, was on Account of my being out all Night, and I thought I should be discharged. I had my Coat under my Arm, which I carried to the Taylor's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-person309">
                  William 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person309" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person309" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Writing-Master: I am very sorry to see the Prisoner, who behaved well in my Family for 9 Years, in these Circumstances: He served his Time with me, and left my Family with a good Character about 20 Months ago: He has lived since with one Mr Johnson, a Chymist, about six Months, and was afterwards an Usher in a Boarding-School at Enfield . I happened to be the unfortunate Person to recommend him to that Gentleman Mr Brown; but before I did it, I desired a Friend of mine to enquire his Character of Mr Blade, who keeps a Boarding-School at Enfield , and I was in Hopes he would have been a useful Member of the Public; and if he can find Favour of the Court, I hope it will have a good Influence upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421208-33-person310">
                  Henry 
                  Blade 
               <interp inst="t17421208-33-person310" type="surname" value="Blade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person310" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I keep a Boarding School at Enfield . I have known the Prisoner about 7 Months. He staid with me about 5 Weeks, and behaved himself very honestly and soberly.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I beg Favour of the honourable Court. <rs id="t17421208-33-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17421208-33-punish176" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421208-33-punish176" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421208-33-defend292 t17421208-33-punish176"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>N. B. After the Jury had given their Verdict, Mr Brown acquainted the Court, that by the strictest Enquiry he could make concerning the Prisoner, he had no Reason to believe he had behaved otherwise than well till this Time, and therefore desired he might be recommended as a fit Object of his Majesty's Mercy; and the rather, for that when he came Home again the next Morning, he might have taken a larger Sum.</p>
            </div1>
