<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17490222-51">
               <interp inst="t17490222-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-51" type="year" value="1749"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17490222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17490222-51" type="date" value="17490222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-51-off233-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend312 t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-verdict240"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-51-off233-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend314 t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-verdict241"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17490222-51-off233-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend316 t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-verdict242"></join>
         
               <p>219, 220, 221. 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-defend312" type="defendantName">
                     Archibald 
                     Blare 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend312" type="surname" value="Blare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend312" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , <rs id="t17490222-51-deflabel232" type="occupation">surgeon</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend312 t17490222-51-deflabel232"></join>, 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Morton 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend314" type="surname" value="Morton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend314" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-defend316" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend316" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend316" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-defend316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , were indicted, for <rs id="t17490222-51-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               being concern'd, together with 
                     <persName id="t17490222-51-person317">
                        James 
                        Campbel 
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person317" type="surname" value="Campbel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-51-person317" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-51-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, in the murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17490222-51-victim319" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Howard 
                        <interp inst="t17490222-51-victim319" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-51-victim319" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17490222-51-victim319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-victim319"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17490222-51-cd234" type="crimeDate">Jan. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-cd234"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-person320">
                  Edward 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person320" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person320" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . The deceased 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person321">
                  William 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person321" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person321" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17490222-51-viclabel235" type="occupation">coach-harness maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-victim319 t17490222-51-viclabel235"></join>, work'd with me at Mr. Aubury's, at Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account what happened on the thirteenth of January last.</p>
               <p>Wood . The deceased and I had been out together, about eight o'clock, concerning the Duke of Cumberland's work; we was going home at about eleven at night; he said to me, you shall go home and lie along with me to night, then we will get up together in the morning, and go to work. He lodg'd in Chandois-Street ; we went that way, to go to Mr. Young's to get a light to light me up to the room, I being a stranger, but Mr. Young was gone to bed. In our return coming up again, at a corner of a passage called <placeName id="t17490222-51-crimeloc236">Mr. Durand's Passage</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-crimeloc236" type="placeName" value="Mr. Durand's Passage"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-crimeloc236" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-crimeloc236"></join>, in <placeName id="t17490222-51-crimeloc237">St. Martin's Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-crimeloc237" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17490222-51-crimeloc237" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-off233 t17490222-51-crimeloc237"></join>, we saw Mr. Blare leaning against a post. I walked foremost; and whether the deceased kick'd his foot against a stone, or whether against Mr. Blare's foot, I do not know, but he had like to have fallen down. There were words arose, such as d - n you, and d - n you, but no blows struck on either side. We went on about one hundred and fifty, or two hundred yards, the deceased stopp'd there; says he, I'll go back, and ask the gentleman why he insults me thus. Going along the street, we returned back to the passage where we first had the words; there was Mr. Blare standing in the middle of the passage; then William Howard said to him as I said before, putting his hands by his sides , What is the reason why I am to be insulted in this manner as I am going along the streets? The gentleman made no answer as I remember, but knocked at the door in this passage immediately; this door is about four or five yards from the street where we first found him standing; as soon as he knocked at the door, there came down a person in officer's clothes, [since I suppose it to have been Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person322">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person322" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ] who ran immediately and collared the deceased, who stood at the passage door: then the deceased asked him the reason of his collaring him; they had a word or two. Said I, you don't do right in collaring my friend; you look like a gentleman, and if you will behave as such, I'll give you a reason why we came back, and if he is in fault we will ask your pardon; before I had got the last word out of my mouth he struck at my partner, and I catched the blow, so it did but just touch his face; this was with his fist: as soon as I let go his hand he repeated his blow upon the deceased, then the fray began; he did not let go the deceased's collar, there were several blows struck. I went back to the door where Campbel came out; I received several blows during this time, but I do not know from whom; I had been knocked down twice, rising the second time I saw two naked swords, or one sword and a hanger, come down stairs; upon seeing them I thought proper to run for assistance to the watch-house: I went to the door, and told them if they did not come to the assistance of a man he would be immediately killed.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the watch-house off from that place?</p>
               <p>Wood . It may be about 100 yards; they asked me if I knew the man; I said he was my fellow-<rs id="t17490222-51-viclabel238" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-victim319 t17490222-51-viclabel238"></join>. There was the constable of the night and a plaisterer came to our assistance; in our return we saw the deceased, lying between the place where it first begun and the Roundhouse, on his belly, with his hat and wig off; that was much about the middle betwixt where the quarrel began in St. Martin's lane and the Roundhouse. I went immediately to him, and asked him how he did? and all the words he ever spoke after were, O dear Ned! then Mr. Benson the plaisterer turned him on his back, saying, what poor Will Howard. Benson and I took him up and carried him into the watch-house; somebody pulled up his shirt, and I saw a wound on the right side of his body: Mr. Benson ran for a surgeon, one Mr. Perkins; when he returned, the constable, and he and I, and one or more of the watchmen, went to the house to see after the people that were in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220015"></xptr> the house which Blare knocked at, and out of which came Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person323">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person323" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; but I did not go directly with them, but went to knock Mr. Young up, to tell him what had happened; when I came back they were admitted into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Young live?</p>
               <p>Wood . In Chequer court, St. Martin's lane: When we returned to the watch-house Mr. Howard was dead. The constable of the night brought into the watch-house Mr. Morgan, Mr. Clark, Mrs. Carr, and Mrs. Hall; it was said by the people of the house, Blare and Campbel were gone off.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did these people come out that struck you?</p>
               <p>Wood. They all came down stairs where Blare rapped, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before Campbel collared the deceased, or when those people came down stairs?</p>
               <p>Wood . Instantly upon his striking the deceased they came down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, when you got up you saw a sword or swords coming down stairs; can you tell, was Campbel then in the house or in the court?</p>
               <p>Wood . I think the sword must be brought him, I did not see that he parted from the deceased at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you saw two such weapons come down those stairs?</p>
               <p>Wood. I am sure I did; they came into the passage, and I saw no other sword but what was brought down stairs; they came down naked; I was in the passage then.</p>
               <p>Q. What business could you do at eleven o'clock at night?</p>
               <p>Wood . We had been at several tradesmen's, and had been drinking two tankards of beer at one Mr. White's in Long Acre between five or six of us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink any thing at those other house?</p>
               <p>Wood . We had a glass of rum at the currier's house .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink nothing more?</p>
               <p>Wood . After the two tankards of beer, we had three shillings in punch between five or six of us; this is all we drank from the time we left work till the time the thing happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink none at work?</p>
               <p>Wood . Yes, as is usual in tippling time; we had a pint of beer each; that is between four and five in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What size man was this 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person324">
                  William 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person324" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person324" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Wood . A middle size man.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you in your working clothes?</p>
               <p>Wood. Yes; he had his apron on, I had not mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Howard esteem himself to be much of a man as they call it; a courageous fellow ?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, I never heard he did; he was always a quiet, peacable man.</p>
               <p>Q. Who began to use this language first?</p>
               <p>Wood. I was before; but I suppose Mr. Blare spoke first, but I cannot be certain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Blare when you came back call out for assistance?</p>
               <p>Wood. I don't remember he did, only knocked at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the cry, Pickpocket?</p>
               <p>Wood. No. I heard no such word.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the deceased?</p>
               <p>Wood. About ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you said at any time since that the deceased was in liquor?</p>
               <p>Wood . No, I never did: I have said he was merry, but not drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the deceased used to be quarrelsome sometimes?</p>
               <p>Wood . I never heard any character of him but that of a quiet peacable man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-person325">
                  Jane 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person325" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person325" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in St. Martin's lane at Mrs. Hall's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person326">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person326" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Carr . I never saw him but that night; he was at Mrs. Hall's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Blare?</p>
               <p>Carr . Yes; Mr. Blare brought Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person327">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person327" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Morton?</p>
               <p>Carr . Yes; he gave a call in by accident; he did not know these gentlemen that were there; neither was he in the same room and company .</p>
               <p>Q. Who did Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person328">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person328" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             come to see?</p>
               <p>Carr . He came to see me; there are two rooms, Campbel and Blare were in one room, and Morton was in the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Mr. Clark?</p>
               <p>Carr . <rs id="t17490222-51-deflabel239" type="occupation">Captain</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend316 t17490222-51-deflabel239"></join> Clark asked who was above? I said Mr. Blare had brought in Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person329">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person329" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; says he, I know the young gentleman very well, I'll go up and drink a glass of wine with him; he came to see me, not knowing Blare or Campbel were in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he call for you out of your room?</p>
               <p>Carr . Yes, I went down stairs to see him; when I told him who were above, he went up and sat down with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he call him Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person330">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person330" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220016"></xptr>Carr. No; but I fancy he knew him.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect during this time, whether Mr. Blare went out of doors?</p>
               <p>Carr. I went into the next room to Mr. Morton, and during this time Mr. Blare went out; the affair happened before I went into the room again. I was in the fore room and heard it begin.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you hear of it?</p>
               <p>Carr. I heard two men say, there is some sailor with a fine laced waistcoat, let us take it from off his back; he has been at sea and took a little prize money, &amp;c. it was dark, I could not tell their faces; with that I shut the window, and in three or four minutes Mr. Blare cried out murder, three times, saying he was insulted by two pickpockets in the streets: I did not till then know he was in the street; I did not hear his voice before Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person331">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person331" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             cried out, that is Blare, I'll go and assist him; he went down stairs; I strove to keep him back; he swore he would go out; my landlady would not let him go out, but he gave her a shove, took the key from her and opened the door himself; we within shut the door quite close; there was a scuffle in the court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Campbel carry any sword out with him?</p>
               <p>Carr. I do not know; we heard a little noise in the passage after this, and in six or seven minutes Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person332">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person332" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and rapped at the door, and wanted to come in again; he came in, says he, these are certainly two pickpockets; he sat down and drank two or three glasses of wine with Captain Clark; he said he had hurt his finger: This other witness came back again, and said he would either kill or be killed; we all came together to the stairs; when we head this noise, those two men fell upon Mr. Blare again, and he cried out murder a second time; he was standing in the passage ; he was gone out to change a guinea, and was waiting there till a person he had sent brought it to him: Campbel went out again on this second cry of murder by Mr. Blare, and left Captain Clark in the room, and staid a good while.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take his sword with him this time?</p>
               <p>Carr . I did not see that he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Clark go out?</p>
               <p>Carr. No, my Lord, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Morgan go out?</p>
               <p>Carr. No, my Lord, they both remained with me on the stairs , and the door was shut. Presently Campbel came back and made a terrible noise at the door, wanting to come in a second time: we let him in.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let him in?</p>
               <p>Carr. I don't know who let him in: Blare and Campbel came in together.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was Campbel when he came in?</p>
               <p>Carr . His hair was all torn, and his shoulder knot in his pocket; it was a silver shoulder knot I asked him to let me keep it for him? but he would not let me.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was Blare?</p>
               <p>Carr. Mr. Blare was limping with his thigh and his head was all bruised with sticks.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he bloody?</p>
               <p>Carr. I saw no blood on him; he said his head was broke. Campbel had his sword drawn in his hand, and he looked at it; (it was bloody, I saw blood on it) he said, I believe I have killed a man Captain Clark said to him, I hope you have not . Said Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person333">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person333" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , it is not time for me to stay here; and he asked Clark, Morton, and me, to go along with him; we answered we knew nothing about it, and whatever was the consequence of it we would stay in the house .</p>
               <p>Q. Who did go with him?</p>
               <p>Carr. Mr. Blare and Campbel went away together.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in your house at this time?</p>
               <p>Carr. There were none in the house but the mistress of the house, myself, and my servant, and these three gentlemen .</p>
               <p>Q. In this conversation betwixt Clark and Campbel was the sword then bloody?</p>
               <p>Carr. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after that?</p>
               <p>Carr. After that he and Blare went out together .</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he go out?</p>
               <p>Carr. He went out at a back door into the same passage.</p>
               <p>Q. Then he did not go out at the common door?</p>
               <p>Carr. No, he did not; it is a door that leads to the necessary house. The constable and others came in about half an hour, and we all went to the watch-house, and before the Justice the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. When Campbel came in again, you say he had a sword drawn in his hand; had Mr. Blare a sword in his hand at that time?</p>
               <p>Carr. He never wears a sword .</p>
               <p>Q. Had he one on then?</p>
               <p>Carr. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a stick in his hand?</p>
               <p>Carr. He left that in my room when he went down first to get change for a guinea; it was afterwards found in my room</p>
               <p>Q. Did it remain all the me in your house ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220017"></xptr>Carr . Yes, I can swear that. Before this scuffle began, he was preparing to go to his lodging. He was going to change a guinea, to pay for a bottle of wine, and then depart.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceas'd before?</p>
               <p>Carr. I never saw him, before I saw him lying by the fire dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Campbel go out the second time?</p>
               <p>Carr . Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his sword then?</p>
               <p>Carr . No, I never saw his sword till he came in with it bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any more swords in the house at that time?</p>
               <p>Carr. None but captain Clark's , and he was never out of the house all that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17490222-51-person334">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person334" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person334" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I am a watchman in Charing-Cross Ward.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell us what happened on the thirteenth of January last, in this little court in St. Martin's Lane .</p>
               <p>Williams . Betwixt eleven and twelve o'clock at night, one of the inhabitants ask'd me to go and call a coach at Charing-Cross; I coming there, could not get a coach; they then desir'd me to get a chair. Mr. Blare came, and asked the gentlewoman, that I called the chair for, if she would let me go and get a guinea chang'd; I goes to the Old Charing-Cross , there gets half a guinea in gold, and the rest in silver: then coming up, there was a dispute betwixt the deceas'd and Mr. Blare; I says to the deceas'd, Honest man, go home . I did not know him. Says I, there is no damage done, the gentleman will forgive you.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Blare then?</p>
               <p>Williams . No, I did not. They went some way and return'd back . This was in a very few minutes. Captain Clark was come down stairs, within two or three stairs of the bottom, with a candle in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Captain Clark in the fray?</p>
               <p>Williams . No, I did not. When the deceas'd return'd, then Mr. Blare and the other was together; the deceas'd said, What is the reason I must be insulted going along the streets?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body strike the deceased?</p>
               <p>Williams . I saw Mr. Morton strike the deceased several times with a stick; captain Campbel would have had my staff out of my hand ; I threw my lanthorn down, put my light out, and would not let go my staff.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at this time?</p>
               <p>Williams . I was within a yard or two.</p>
               <p>Q. How near did Captain Clark come to the in the fray ?</p>
               <p>Williams . He was upon the stairs all the while. I saw the door open, and saw him on the stairs; they were all in a scuffle together. This was the first time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a second time?</p>
               <p>Williams. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell us what happen'd the first time?</p>
               <p>Williams. 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person335">
                  William 
                  Blare 
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person335" type="surname" value="Blare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person335" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did return no answer, but knocked at the door, and it was open'd to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came down stairs?</p>
               <p>Williams . The first was captain Campbel.</p>
               <p>Q. Who followed him?</p>
               <p>Williams . Mr. Morgan followed him. The first time captain Clark came down with a brass candlestick in his hand; then I said it was all over, and they all return'd up stairs again. I was in the passage or entry; the place was so crouded, I could not see a blow struck. When that was over, they went up stairs again.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went up stairs?</p>
               <p>Williams. Captain Clark, Mr. Blare, and Mr. Morton. The deceased went a good way towards the Round-House, and dropped down in about five minutes after.</p>
               <p>Court. You give us a very confus'd account of the matter, tell us in your own way.</p>
               <p>Williams begins again, and sometimes Mr. Morton, sometimes Captain 
               <persName id="t17490222-51-person336">
                  Campbel
               <interp inst="t17490222-51-person336" type="given" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and sometimes captain Clark, came down first, so that little regard could be given to him; but he never varied in this, that he saw Mr. Morton strike the deceased over the bead with a stick divers times.</p>
               <p>Williams Proceeds . Then the constable of the night ordered me to go and get assistance, and surround the house, which I did; and there we found Clark and Morton in a room with Mrs. Carr , and we took them all to the Watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you, after the deceased had received his death wound, say at the Watch-house, if the deceased was killed, he had got his deserts, adding , he had no business to affront gentlemen?</p>
               <p>Williams . No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you did not make use of such like words?</p>
               <p>Williams . I might say something like it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Perkins . I am the surgeon that was fetch'd to the deceas'd . When I went into the Watch-house I saw him lying dead. I inspected him two days afterward. I was sent for before the coroner. I found four wounds on his body, one on the right side , the other on the left, where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174902220018"></xptr> the sword pass'd in on one side, and out at the other: it had a triangular point, and pretty large, and it must have been a very violent thrust. There was a wound on his head, which was broke, and seemed to have been done with some stick . There was a little scratch on his hand, one of the bone, of the left arm was broke, and a bruise upon the part.</p>
               <p>Blare <rs id="t17490222-51-verdict240" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-verdict240" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, Morgan <rs id="t17490222-51-verdict241" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-verdict241" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-verdict241" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>, Clark <rs id="t17490222-51-verdict242" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-verdict242" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17490222-51-punish243" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-punish243" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17490222-51-punish243" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17490222-51-defend314 t17490222-51-punish243"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
