<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460409-29">
               <interp inst="t17460409-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-29" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-29" type="date" value="17460409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460409-29-off125-c370" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-29-defend433 t17460409-29-off125 t17460409-29-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>167. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-defend433" type="defendantName">
                     WillIAM 
                     Askew 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-29-defend433" type="surname" value="Askew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-defend433" type="given" value="WillIAM"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-defend433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460409-29-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a large Silver Tankard, Value 10 l. a Pint Silver Mug, Value 4 l. twelve Silver Tea Spoons, Value 12 s. a Silver Strainer, Value 1 s. 6 d. a Silver Pepper-Box, Value 18 s. and a Pewter Milk-Pot, Value 9 d.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-victim435" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Appelby 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-29-victim435" type="surname" value="Appelby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-victim435" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-victim435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-29-off125 t17460409-29-victim435"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17460409-29-viclabel126" type="occupation">the Elder</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-29-victim435 t17460409-29-viclabel126"></join>, on the <rs id="t17460409-29-cd127" type="crimeDate">22d of March</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-29-off125 t17460409-29-cd127"></join>.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prosecutor. Please your Lordship and the Gentlemen of the Jury, I am Council in the Cause against the Prisoner at the Bar, 
               <persName id="t17460409-29-person436">
                  William 
                  Askew 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person436" type="surname" value="Askew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person436" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is charg'd with Felony committed in the House of 
               <persName id="t17460409-29-person437">
                  Charles 
                  Appeiby 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person437" type="surname" value="Appeiby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person437" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to whom he was a Journeyman. Gentlemen, the Facts we have to lay before you are all Circumstances, and seem to be such as we cannot err in, when they are laid all together. There is nothing of a positive Proof, neither was he taken in Means, as the Law calls it, in having any Goods found upon him; but as 'tis on Circumstances the Affair entirely depends, I shall submit it to the Court, whether they are so satisfactory as to convince you that this is the Man who robb'd his Master. As the Case is represented to me, by Mr. Appleby, Brasier, in Harp-Alley, the Prisoner's Bed, Gentlemen, was placed in the Shop, pretty near a little Room by the Parlour; it lies so near the Doors that 'tis impossible for any one to make the least Noise without waking the Person who lies in that Bed. On Friday Night, the 21st of March, young Mr. Appelby coming home very late, between Eleven and Twelve o'Clock, he look'd about, as he commonly does, to see if all Things were safe, and at that Time they were so. His Father and Mother lay up one Pair of Stairs and his Sisters up three; young Mr. Appelby's Room was up two Pair of Stairs, and only this Servant on the Ground Floor, who was suppos'd to be in Bed close by the Parlour. Some time after Twelve the Watchmen beat their respective Rounds, when the Door was safe, and continued so 'till a little after Four, at which Time the Watchman discover'd it open and went into the Shop, who, seeing the Prisoner at the Bar, ask'd him the Meaning of it; oh, says he, nothing at all, a small Matter, I suppose some of the Family are gone out; though, as the Door had been open'd, it could not be done without his Privity; but he shuts the Door again and takes no other Notice of of it. When the Porter came in the Morning, as usual, to open the Shop, he went into the Parlour and discover'd the Escrutore had been forced open: Afterwards, upon searching the Prisoner's Box, an old Nailpiercer, newly fil'd up, was found, which appear'd to be a very proper Instrument for forcing those Locks and Holts. If any Stranger, Gentlemen, had done this, 'tis extreamly odd that the Servant, intrusted in the Family, should take no Notice of it, not alarm them. There is another Circumstance, viz. a cross, crabbed Dog, as surly perhaps as any in Town, which this Brazier keeps for the Safety of his Shop, and will hardly suffer any Stranger to come into the Shop in the Day Time, and much less in the Evening, without giving an Alarm; and this Dog was then within the House. The Master of the Family, the four Daughters and Son were also within. These can hardly be suppos'd to be Partners with the Man in robbing the House, there being no Maid Servant there at this time. The Noise that must have been made by the Violence us'd in the forcing the Place where the Plate was secur'd, could not but awake any one who lay so near, unless he had been so found asleep as not to be awakened even by the Noise of a Gun. Gentlemen,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090023"></xptr> this is the Nature of the Case, and the Question is, whether there be any satisfactory Evidence to convince the Court and you in Point of Law, that the Man is guilty.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not a Dog?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes. We have got a good middling siz'd Dog; when any comes to the Door he makes so great a Noise, that the Watchman said he would kill it.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Mr. Appelby, are you the Son of Mr. Appleby, the Prosecutor; you know the Defendant; how many Months has he liv'd with your Father; how did he behave during that Time; how did he behave always?</p>
               <p>Appelby. He always behav'd very well, 'till this very Affair happen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to go out often?</p>
               <p>Appelby. No. He us'd to go out about once a Week. He lays in the Shop; only a Partition between the Parlour and the Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any Body lie up one Pair of Stairs?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council. You mention the Flap of the Buroe broke open, and the Closet broke open: I would ask you whether the Prisoner knew where your Plate was kept ?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes. I don't doubt, as well as we did.</p>
               <p>Council. You say the Closet Door was broke open, and the Prisoner knew where your Plate was: You said there was not Plate usually kept there. Was there any Money frequently kept there?</p>
               <p>Appelby. That Afternoon I took almost 12 l. out of the Scrutore; which no Doubt they would have taken.</p>
               <p>Council. Pray Mr. Appelby where does your Parlour look into.</p>
               <p>Appelby. The one Part into the Shop; the other into the Burying Ground.</p>
               <p>Council. You say there must be a great deal of Violence us'd, but none of the Family heard any Thing of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Serjeant says, that at Four o'Clock in the Morning, when the Door was discover'd to be open, none of the Things mention'd in the Indictment were found upon this young Man at the Bar. Pray do you know any Thing of this Advertisement in the Papers?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes Sir. It was by my Father's Orders.</p>
               <p>Council. And did you find your Journeyman in Bed when you came down Stairs: You say he always gets up to let the rest of the Workmen in; then he was in; was he dress'd, or half dress'd when you came down?</p>
               <p>Appelby. I was in such a Surprize I did not look after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who fastned the Door?</p>
               <p>Appelby. The Prisoner fastened the Door, and I felt of the Bolt and Things afterwards.</p>
               <p>Council. What Time was you in?</p>
               <p>Appelby. About Twelve, or a Quarter after.</p>
               <p>Council. So then I find the Prisoner keeps better Hours than you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-person438">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person438" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person438" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Godyn, Watchman) Do you beat the Rounds at Harp-Alley?</p>
               <p>Godyn. Yes, I went every Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the Time when it was said the House was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Godyn. I was the Round every Hour in the Night. I went the regular Round every Hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you beat at this Door of Mr. Appelby's ?</p>
               <p>Godyn. yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long can you venture to say it was shut fast?</p>
               <p>Godyn. It was shut every Hour I went my Rounds.</p>
               <p>Council. You beat it 'till Six o'Clock?</p>
               <p>Godyn. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-person439">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person439" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person439" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ( to 
               <persName id="t17460409-29-person440">
                  Jonathan 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person440" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person440" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) What Discovery did you make?</p>
               <p>Perkins. About half an Hour after Four I was going down to the Watch-house with my Lanthorn, and going through Harp-Alley, I saw the Door a little open. I went in and saw a Man in Bed, and bid him get up. I said get up and fasten the Door, the Shop is liable to be robb'd: I went up to the Bedside, made the Man to get up, and he got up out of his Bed, and fastned the Door.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Man awake or asleep?</p>
               <p>Perkins. The Man answer'd me readily enough then; he said he suppos'd there might be somebody just gone out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see or hear any Thing of a Dog?</p>
               <p>Perkins. There was never a Dog bark'd at me.</p>
               <p>Council. You went into the Shop, and made a Knock with the Watchman's Staff just by his Bed-side? You made a Thump with your Staff, upon that the Person answer'd; he did not, upon your coming first into the Shop, Cry, Who is this?</p>
               <p>Perkins. No.</p>
               <p>Council. Only give me Leave to ask you, whether the Prisoner was without his Cloaths?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He was.</p>
               <p>Council. He had nothing but his Shirt on?</p>
               <p>Perkins. No, nothing else.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090024"></xptr>Council. Then you went out?</p>
               <p>Perkins. Yes, but before I had got the Length of my Cane, he got up and fastned the Door.</p>
               <p>Council. (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-29-person441">
                  Ed 
                  Cordel 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person441" type="surname" value="Cordel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person441" type="given" value="Ed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) They tell me you are Porter to Mr. Appelby.</p>
               <p>Cordel. Yes, and when I came in the Morning, a Quarter after Six, as soon as I knock'd, my Fellow Prisoner got out of his Bed, and let me in; and I said this Flap was open for something last Night: I ask'd him for what, he said he forgot: I push'd up the other Flap, then I went my Ways into the Parlour to unbolt the Parlour Window; then I saw my Master's Buroe, and Cupboard, by the Fireside, broke open, and I said to the Prisoner, William, Did my Master leave his Buroe so last Night? he said I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine about the House? Did there seem to be any Force used in any Part of the House?</p>
               <p>Cordel. There was nothing but the Flap hung loose over the Street Door; with that we went down into the Cellar.</p>
               <p>Council against the Prisoner. I am surpriz'd you should lie so near to this Parlour, and not hear any Thing of it.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. You would not have the Man hang'd for being fast asleep?</p>
               <p>Council. No; I should be as tender of that as you are.</p>
               <p>Court. The Flap you say hung loose?</p>
               <p>Cordel. He said the Flap was left loose last Night.</p>
               <p>Q. As you have lived with Mr. Appelby all this Time, have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cordel. Yes, but I never saw any Injustice by him, or any Thing of that Kind.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he up when he let you in?</p>
               <p>Cordel. No, my Lord, he was in his Shirt.</p>
               <p>Q. Now pray what Time of the Night is Mr. Appelby's Shop kept open?</p>
               <p>Cordel. They are shut in between Seven and Eight o'Clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not a Person be conceal'd there?</p>
               <p>Cordel. No, I believe not; for commonly my Master, or young Master, are near the Door.</p>
               <p>Council. (to Mr. Appelby the Elder) What is your Family?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Only my Wife and self, this Son and four Daughters; no Servant but the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What Part of the House do you lie in?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Two Pair of Stairs forwards?</p>
               <p>Q. Was you apprehensive of any Disturbance?</p>
               <p>Appelby. I knew of none.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell that your House was safe ?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes, all was safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any of your Family that lie so near to this Room as you?</p>
               <p>Appelby. None so near as myself.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask you whether it was possible for any one to come into that Room, to do any Thing without being heard by the Man in Bed?</p>
               <p>Appelby. I think not; then I think there is another Thing, the boldest Rogue would hardly come by that Bed, which they could scarce get by, and if they did, he might have immediately gone out and call'd the Watch.</p>
               <p>Council. (for the Prisoner.) Mr. Appelby, the Prisoner has liv'd with you four Months: I would ask you whether he behaved in a sober, modest Way?</p>
               <p>Appelby. I believ'd him to be very sober and honest.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any Reason to imagine that he could be guilty of such a Crime? I would ask whether you look upon the Prisoner at the Bar to be an artful cunning Person, or a low weak Capacity?</p>
               <p>Appelby. He is not so ready in his Business as some People are; but here is a Copy of a Letter to prove that he is not a Person of so mean a Capacity.</p>
               <p>Council. Have you not declar'd since, you believed the Prisoner at the Bar to be innocent?</p>
               <p>Appelby. No.</p>
               <p>Council. I would ask you whether you have not offer'd any of the Prisoner's Friends, if they would give you any Thing, you would make it up? Did you ever know Mr. Willis? 'twas pretty late for your Son to be out? Does your Son usually keep such Hours?</p>
               <p>Appelby. Yes, sometimes.</p>
               <p>Council. I am sorry for your Loss; I wish you may find out the Thief.</p>
               <p>With your Lordship's Leave I am Council for the Prisoner. As the Serjeant has candidly open'd it, that there was nothing but Circumstances, whether they were such Circumstances to take away the Life of a Man. The Person is indicted; it amounts to this. Here is a Person indicted for being asleep. If a Person has any Character to support him, the Jury will never believe them, unless there are some other Circumstances. This is laid as a Crime, that a Person shall not be awaken'd by a Noise, as that at best is but a doubtful Case. We shall call our Witness to prove that he is a most sober and honest Person.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090025"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-person442">
                  John 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person442" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person442" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I gave 20 l. Apprentice with the Prisoner to Mr. Norris.</p>
               <p>Council. Now I would ask you whether you had any Discourse with Mr. Appelby before?</p>
               <p>Willis. Mr. Appelby offer'd to make it up; I told him and his Wife, if he (the Prisoner) was Guilty, I would not give Six-pence to save him from the Gallows. He is second Cousin. He is a Boy of a very shallow Capacity. Mr. Appelby gives but Seven Pounds per Year. I believe him to be innocent; he said so before the Gentleman at my Lord Mayor's Court.</p>

               <p>Q. How has he behaved?</p>
               <p>Willis. Sober and well; has always been in Places; he was put Apprentice to a Brazier.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it that you did not set him up?</p>
               <p>Willis. I told him, if he could cast up a Sum of 20 s. I would set him up.</p>
               <p>Council. (to 
               <persName id="t17460409-29-person443">
                  John 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person443" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person443" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun.) Was you at that Time along with your Uncle, at Mr. Appelby's?</p>
               <p>Willis. Yes, and I saw Mr. Appelby's Wife and three Daughters, and I think a young Man.</p>
               <p>Council. I ask you upon your Oath, what Mr. Appelby said about the young Man?</p>
               <p>Willis. When we went to Mr. Appelby's House, it was upon the Circumstance of the Watchmen. Mrs. Appelby made a great Noise, and said they had never such a Misfortune before; she said Circumstances were so strong, that it was impossible but it must be he: I said I did not know any Thing of the Circumstances, but only I had been talking with the Prisoner at the Bar a great Part of the Afternoon, and I found from his Discourse, that he must be a real honest Man; and what confirm'd me in it, that his Master gave him the best of Characters: One Circumstance was this; one of the Masters that he was with, his Affairs went back in the World, and he could not employ all his Hands; the Prisoner at the Bar was very industrious, and his Master was not willing that he should be dismissed.</p>
               <p>Council. The Question that I ask you, is, whether Mr. Appelby declar'd any Thing at all with respect to the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Willis. I intended to come to it, but I'll answer your Question. Mr. Appelby said they were willing to make it up, if he was concern'd in it, as being drawn in from his Weakness; but Mr. Willis said if he was guilty, if Six-pence would save him, he would not give it.</p>
               <p>Council (to - Norris.) Mr. Norris, I think the young Man at the Bar serv'd you seven Years as an Apprentice?</p>
               <p>Norris. Yes, and he behav'd very suitably.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been out of his Time?</p>
               <p>Norris. Four or five Years, and I never heard any thing against him 'till this Time, at which I was much surpriz'd; I should think him one of the last Persons for such an Undertaking; and if it was attended with any Difficulties, I don't think he could do it, for he has but a very indifferent Capacity. While he was with me he was a very sober honest Man.</p>
               <p>Council. I suppose it was in his Power to have wrong'd you very much, if it was his Inclination.</p>
               <p>Norris. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-29-person444">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-29-person444" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-person444" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to - Wade.) How long have you known the Prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wade. He work'd with me. My Husband belong'd to Deptford-Yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Wade. Above six Months.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he go from you?</p>
               <p>Wade. Mr. Appelby took him upon my Character.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave in your Service?</p>
               <p>Wade. He behaved very honest.</p>
               <p>Council. Was he extravagant in his Expences? Was he very sober ? You say Mr. Appelby took him upon your Character; that is your Opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he could be capable of breaking open his Masters Escrutore, or such Things?</p>
               <p>Wade. No, I believe not. He lived with me a Twelvemonth, all but a few Days; and I knew him about two Months before he came to live with me.</p>
               <p>Q. During the whole Time he lived with you, how did he behave?</p>
               <p>Wade. I never had a better Servant in my Life, for what he was capable of doing; he kept very good Hours, nobody came after him to spend any Money.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard of this unhappy Affair?</p>
               <p>Wade. Yes, but I cannot think he had Courage or Capacity for such a Thing.</p>
               <p>Council against the Prisoner. They have call'd Witnesses to the Prisoner's Character; doubtless Character is a Scale to turn very much; but 'tis a wonderful Thing to me that the Plate is gone. Which way could any one get into this House? This is the only Man that lay below, and was within hearing, and to be so very found asleep! All Men are honest 'till they begin to be otherwise; but they say he is a Man quite contented and easy in Disposition and Temper. We had some Difficulty to prove his Hand-writing; but at last it comes out that 'tis his Hand-writing. 'Tis plain that he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090026"></xptr> was restless and discontented, and it went to his very Heart, Blood and Guts of his Body, that he wanted Substance, and wanted Money, and would have his Uncle apply'd to, to set him up.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner's general Character was so good, and he appear'd such a plain, simple, honest Man, that he was <rs id="t17460409-29-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-29-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>His Uncle apply'd to the Court for a Copy of his Indictment.</p>
            </div1>
