<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430519-7">
               <interp inst="t17430519-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-7" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430519"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430519-7" type="date" value="17430519"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430519-7-off31-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-7-defend82 t17430519-7-off31 t17430519-7-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>254. 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-7-defend82" type="defendantName">
                     Andrew Thomas 
                     Davenport 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-7-defend82" type="surname" value="Davenport"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-defend82" type="given" value="Andrew Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-defend82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17430519-7-defloc30">St Paul Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-7-defloc30" type="placeName" value="St Paul Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430519-7-defloc30" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-7-defend82 t17430519-7-defloc30"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17430519-7-off31" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-off31" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-off31" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five Yards of black Velvet, val. 40 s. ten Yards of Silk Damask, val. 3 l. and forty Yards of Lustring, val. 5 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-7-victim84" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Buck 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim84" type="surname" value="Buck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim84" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17430519-7-victim86" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Swan 
                  <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim86" type="surname" value="Swan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim86" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-victim86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17430519-7-cd32" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430519-7-off31 t17430519-7-cd32"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-7-person87">
                  Robert 
                  Buck 
               <interp inst="t17430519-7-person87" type="surname" value="Buck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-person87" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of April, I had an Information of the Prisoner's having robbed us, and was directed to go to one Madam Deson's Lodging, and there I found several Sorts of Silk which were mine; I went home to my Shop, seized the Prisoner, and charged him with the Robbery, (he has been Apprentice to Mr Swan, who is my Partner, three Years) at first he denied it, but afterwards owned it. He had got acquainted with this Woman, and he had hired a Coach, in Order to have gone to France with her, and he would certainly have gone that Evening. Some of these Goods were made up into Garments, and some of them have our own Mark upon them. There was a white Damask, and the Lustrings were made into Dresses, for Madam Deson's Use; and the black Velvet was made into a Waistcoat and Breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know these are your Goods?</p>
               <p>Buck . We have a very regular Method of entering them in a Number-Book , and keeping an Account of what is cut off each Piece, in order to know whether we are defrauded by our Servants or no; and there are particular Patterns which we know. I compared this Pattern with a Piece of Damask in our Shop, and found it to be part of that Piece, which appeared to be deficient by the Number-Book; and there were about forty Yards of Lustring deficient.</p>
               <p>Court . Sir, when you and your Partner are out, and any Person comes to buy any Lustring or Damask, has the Prisoner a Right to dispose of them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Buck . We do allow a Right to our Servants to sell. I am very certain to fifteen Yards of Damask, and five Yards of black Velvet being cut off our Pieces; and I think, to the best of my Remembrance,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174305190007"></xptr> there were our Marks on some of the Remnants. He owned before Colonel De Veil, that all these Things were our Property. I do not know whether it was through Madam Deson's Means that he did this, she was indicted but the Bill was thrown out. These are the Patterns of the Goods laid in the Indictment, which Mrs Gost gave me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430519-7-person88">
                  Mary 
                  Gost 
               <interp inst="t17430519-7-person88" type="surname" value="Gost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-person88" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was examined by an Interpreter , she said she made a French Sack of the white Damask; and four other Patterns of Lustring, &amp;c. being shown her , she said she had made a French Sack of each of them for Madam Deson.</p>
               <p>Buck . The Prisoner owned the taking them before several Witnesses, and that Madam Deson had them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he sold them to Madam Deson ?</p>
               <p>Buck. No; he owned he gave them to Madam Deson .</p>
               <p>The Prisoner was <rs id="t17430519-7-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430519-7-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, (Vid. Ante, p. 107, &amp;c. ) and the Prosecutor had leave to bring another Kind of Indictment, but did not.</p>
            </div1>
