<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17470225-10">
               <interp inst="t17470225-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-10" type="year" value="1747"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17470225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17470225-10" type="date" value="17470225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17470225-10-off41-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-defend161 t17470225-10-off41 t17470225-10-verdict45"></join>
         
               <p>141. 
               <persName id="t17470225-10-defend161" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Peter 
                     Warner 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17470225-10-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-defend161 t17470225-10-alias-1"></join>Johnson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-defend161" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-defend161" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-defend161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17470225-10-off41" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-off41" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-off41" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one Silver Spoon, value 10 s.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17470225-10-victim164" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Tomm 
                  <interp inst="t17470225-10-victim164" type="surname" value="Tomm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-victim164" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-victim164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-off41 t17470225-10-victim164"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             at <placeName id="t17470225-10-crimeloc42">Charing Cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-10-crimeloc42" type="placeName" value="Charing Cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17470225-10-crimeloc42" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-off41 t17470225-10-crimeloc42"></join>. <rs id="t17470225-10-cd43" type="crimeDate">Jan. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-off41 t17470225-10-cd43"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17470225-10-person165">
                  Charles 
                  Tonn 
               <interp inst="t17470225-10-person165" type="surname" value="Tonn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person165" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Golden Fleece, I keep an Eating-House at Charing Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose this Spoon?</p>
               <p>Tonn. The 9th of January.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say against the Prisoner ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174702250015"></xptr>Tonn. I cannot swear the Prisoner stole it, but the Silver-Smith is here that stopped it.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17470225-10-person166">
                  Stephen 
                  Quillet 
               <interp inst="t17470225-10-person166" type="surname" value="Quillet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person166" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What have you to say against the Prisoner at the Bar?</p>
               <p>Quillet The Prisoner came into my Shop the 17th of January last, and offered me the Bowl of a Spoon to sell, (I live at Charing-Cross) I asked him how he came by it? he told me his Master gave it him; I told him he had a very fine Master to give him a Silver Spoon; I asked him where the Remainder of it was; I said I believed he had it in his Pocket; he told me he lived with 'Squire Belse in Duke-street, and his Name was 
               <persName id="t17470225-10-person167">
                  Peter 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17470225-10-person167" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person167" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I called a Porter and bid him to go and enquire of his Master, if he had lost a Spoon; he was for going with the Porter, I said you shall stay, if you go, I shall not see you again; with that he ran away out of my Shop; John, said I, run after him, and endeavour to catch him, and bring him back; but the Porter came back, and said he could not find him, he said he believed he lived in Whitehall; I said I have a Notion, by his Livery, that he lives with Capt. Gerring, in Westminster; and I sent to him, but he sent me Word he had no such Servant; with that, my Lord, I saw a Person go by my Shop half an Hour after that, and I enquired of him after such a Person, and he told me where I might meet with him, he said he used the King's-head in Downing-street; I went to the Master of the House, and he told me that the Prisoner lived over the way, that he was Servant with Dr Pile in Downing-street</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to find out Mr Tonn?</p>
               <p>Quillet. It was by this Publick house Man; the next Morning his Master looked over his Plate, he did not miss any thing, but, says he, he uses Mr Tonn's House, and it may be it might be their's; I went to Mr Tonn's and he said he had lost a Spoon the Night before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by the other Part of the Spoon.</p>
               <p>Quillet. It was found in the Boy's Waistcoat Pocket; here is the Name at Length on the Handle.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Value of this Spoon?</p>
               <p>Quillet. Ten Shillings.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Will you ask the Witnesses any Questions?</p>
               <p>The Prisoner, they say, is a <rs id="t17470225-10-deflabel44" type="occupation">Swiss</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17470225-10-defend161 t17470225-10-deflabel44"></join>; he cried most bitterly, and said with great Vehemence, Tu, dey did find de Spoon upon me, but I did no stole it, but a Mans give it me, said, if you do no sell it for me, I will sharge you wid the Robberee.</p>
               <p>Tonn. The Boy, when he was in Place, had dined, by his Master's Orders, with me, for half or three Quarters of a Year, and always behaved very sober; all I can say, the Person that he laid the Charge upon, has absconded the House since; the Boy described the Man a fort of a Sea-faring Man; he has been at my House eight or ten Times; he has never been at my House but once since.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did not you take him up then?</p>
               <p>Tonn. I did not care to bring myself into further Trouble, as we found the Spoon upon the Prisoner, and we had only his Word for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17470225-10-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17470225-10-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
