<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420714-19">
               <interp inst="t17420714-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-19" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420714-19" type="date" value="17420714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420714-19-off90-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-defend153 t17420714-19-off90 t17420714-19-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>22. 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-defend153" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Terry 
                   otherwise <rs id="t17420714-19-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-defend153 t17420714-19-alias-2"></join>Rhodes</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-defend153" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-defend153" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-defend153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the Parish of <placeName id="t17420714-19-defloc89">St Catherine's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-19-defloc89" type="placeName" value="St Catherine's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420714-19-defloc89" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-defend153 t17420714-19-defloc89"></join>, was indicted for that she <rs id="t17420714-19-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               not having the Fear of God before her Eyes, &amp;c. on the <rs id="t17420714-19-cd91" type="crimeDate">30th Day of June, in the 16th Year of His Majesty's Reign</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-off90 t17420714-19-cd91"></join>, in and upon the Body of one 
                     <persName id="t17420714-19-victim155" type="victimName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17420714-19-person156" type="victimName">
                              John 
                              Hussey 
                           <interp inst="t17420714-19-person156" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17420714-19-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17420714-19-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-off90 t17420714-19-person156"></join>
                        </persName>
                        , otherwise <rs id="t17420714-19-alias-3" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-victim155 t17420714-19-alias-3"></join>Husday</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-19-victim155" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-19-victim155" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-19-victim155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420714-19-off90 t17420714-19-victim155"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , did make an Assault, and with a certain Razor of the Value of 1 Penny held in her Right-hand, upon the Throat of the said 
                     <persName id="t17420714-19-person157">
                        John 
                        Hussey 
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person157" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-19-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420714-19-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise Husday, did give him one mortal Wound of the Length of 5 Inches, and the Depth of 2 Inches, of which Wound instantly died.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>She was likewise charged on to Prisoner's Inquest for feloniously slaying the said Hussey.</p>
               <p>At the Prisoner's Request the Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person158">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person158" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person158" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of June I had been making merry with my Friends, it was my Birth-Day, I was then 26 years of Age. As I was coming over Tower-Hill I met the Prisoner, she lodged in a House that I was Servant at, one 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-person159">
                  Richard 
                  Dyer 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person159" type="surname" value="Dyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person159" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, She asked me to drink, I told her I had but three Half-pence and I would spend it with her, so we drank a Pint of Beer; we met a middle sized Man, and he said to her Molly how do you do, and they began to talk very lovingly together, and I sat down at the Door of the Hamburgh Arms and drank a Pint of Beer; I said I could not stay, she desired me to stay a little; she went into her Lodging which was just by, and stay'd better than a Quarter of an Hour, I was tired with waiting, so I goes up Stairs, and calls, Molly.</p>
               <p>Q. What Room did they go into?</p>
               <p>Holder. They went into a Room two Pair of Stairs backwards. I went up Stairs and heard a very great Debate, as if he had lain with her, for she asked him for a Shilling; I was then at the Door where they were. I came down again, In about 10 or 12 Minutes, or a Quarter of an Hour, I saw the Prisoner holding a Hat under his Chin to his Throat, and he bleeding into it, the Man was standing thus, the Head leaning a little forward.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a Hat was it?</p>
               <p>Holder. It seemed to be an old Hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a Man's Hat, or a Woman's Hat?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140008"></xptr>Holder. A Man's black Hat. With that I said to her, Molly, what are you about? Molly, said I, how can you be so barbarous?</p>
               <p>Q. What Reason had you to believe it was her Barbarity?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person160">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person160" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person160" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At first I asked her, how she could be so barbarous as to let me stand so long at the Door when I have no Money in my Pocket? And when I saw the Man bleeding, then I asked her, how she could be so barbarous to murder the Man? She said, if I knew the old Rogue so well as she did, I would not call her barbarous; but she desir'd I would not take any Notice of it. She has never been at home since. I call'd upon one 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-person161">
                  Ann 
                  Hyam 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person161" type="surname" value="Hyam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person161" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Grubstreet, and told her, I was very much shock'd to see the Thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Man alive when you saw him bleeding and under his Throat?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person162">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person162" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person162" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot tell, I did not go in to see; I run down Stairs very much surprized - I saw not the Man afterwards. The Prisoner's Right-hand was bloody, her Apron and Neck-Handkerchief were both bloody - I never saw her after that Night. - I was last Monday before the Coroner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Why did you not make a Declaration of this sooner?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person163">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person163" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person163" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Because I have heard, by all Accounts, she was a wicked, vile Creature, and I was afraid of my Life.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did you ever live with one Glass on Tower-Hill?</p>
               <p>Holder. I never lived with any Body there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person164">
                  Ann 
                  Hyam 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person164" type="surname" value="Hyam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person164" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing of the Prisoner, but what I had from 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-person165">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holder 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person165" type="surname" value="Holder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person165" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Prosecutrix. On the 30th of June, the Prosecutrix came to my Lodging, said she wanted to speak with me, and begged I would let her in, she said, she had been a Merry-making with some Friends, on account of her Birth day, that coming over Tower-hill, she met the Prisoner, who asked her, whether she would go and drink a Pint of Beer? Which they did; that they met a Man, and the Prisoner and the Man went up Stairs into her (the Prisoner's) Lodgings, that she desired her to stay, and she would come again presently. That she went into a House on Tower-hill to drink a Pint of Beer, till she came down: She thought she staid a good while, so went up Stairs, and heard a great many Words pass, as if they had differed; that some time after that, she looked into the Room, and saw a Man bleeding very plentifully at the Mouth and Nose. I advised her to go before a Justice and make a Discovery, but she did not go for some Days.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know who this Man was?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person166">
                  Ann 
                  Hyam 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person166" type="surname" value="Hyam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person166" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No: I never saw the Man in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person167">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Portington 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person167" type="surname" value="Portington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person167" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of June, about 10 or 11 o'Clock at Night, the Prisoner came to my House, and asked, if she could lie there; I told her, I could not accommodate her. I asked her, What she had been about? One of her Hands was bloody, her Apron and Neck-Handkerchief a little splashed, she said she had been in a Quarrel ; she desired I would not speak of it, nor take any notice that I saw her, and then went away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Were you never a Witness in any Case for Mrs. Ivers ?</p>
               <p>Partington. I never was that I remember.</p>
               <p>Court. This is a soleman Transaction, pray recollect your self.</p>
               <p>Portington. I cannot say that I was a punctual Witness.</p>
               <p>Court. The Question was, Whether you were not a Witness upon any Occasion?</p>
               <p>Portington. Not that I remember.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Had you never an Oath administred to you?</p>
               <p>Portington. No; I never had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you a Witness for her once in Doctors-Commons ?</p>
               <p>Portington. Yes, once she took me there about some Money.</p>
               <p>Court. Did not they give you an Oath upon this Occasion?</p>
               <p>Portington. I was asked Questions, and laid my Hand upon a Book.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was not you a subscribing Witness to a Will for Mrs Ivers?</p>
               <p>Portington. No; I never was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person168">
                  Edward 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person168" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person168" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw a Man lying dead, with his Throat cut, in a Room up two Pair of Stairs backwards, on Friday, July 2, in that House which was formerly the Blue-Anchor, by the Ditch Side, on Little-Tower-Hill. - I do not know any thing of the Woman.</p>
               <p>[R. Holder called again.]</p>
               <p>Court. You say, Holder, that when you went up Stairs, you saw her holding a Hat under his Chin, and the Blood running into it; in what Position was the Body, was it lying or sitting?</p>
               <p>Holder. It was standing upright, in this manner; [ leaning her Head a little forward] by the Debate there was between them, I suppose he had lain with her, and that she wanted some Money of him, because she said, he was not so good as his Promise.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174207140009"></xptr>Q. Where was you when you saw this?</p>
               <p>Holder. I was at the Landing-place, just by the Door. - The Door was a-Jarr, not open, - There was no Bed in the Room; there was something of Flocks or Feathers lying in an odd manner, and an old Waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw this Man thus bloody, did you hear any struggle between them?</p>
               <p>Holder. No; but she had called him old Rogue, and Son of a B - h.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the Man cry out?</p>
               <p>Holder. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, these People have often been concerned in forging of Seamen's Wills and Powers; I had given an Information against 14 Persons, which was made before Justice De Veil; I am the unhappy Widow of that Rhodes, who was executed on Monday, for being concern'd in these Practices; they have lodged this Indictment against me to take away my Life, to prevent my giving Informations. I have seen so much of the Wickedness of these Things, that I went and made a voluntary Confession; for that Reason they seek my Life; they have threaten'd it several Times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420714-19-person169">
                  William 
                  Wintx 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person169" type="surname" value="Wintx"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person169" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Deputy to Mr King the Coroner. On the 3d of July, I went with my Inquisition to view this Body, in a House by Tower-Ditch; up two Pair of Stairs in a Back-room, there was a Body lying with the Head almost cut off, a Hat full of conjealed Blood, and a Razor all bloody. - There was not one Spot of Blood on the Floor, which makes me conclude the Murder was not committed there. I got a Candle to examine the Floor though it was light enough; but I was willing to be thoroughly satisfied: The Head lay upon a Heap of Rubbish, I turned the Head aside, to see if there was any Blood under it, and moved the Rubbish with my Foot, but there was none, which must have been if he had been murder'd there; they likewise viewed every Room in the House, and could find no Blood in any of them. - I do not think that the Man was murdered in that House, for there must be more Blood come out of a Body than the Quantity that was in the Hat; and the Room did not appear to have been washed lately.</p>
               <p>Coroner. The Man that was murdered sold Sticks upon Tower-hill, his Name was 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-person170">
                  John 
                  Husday 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person170" type="surname" value="Husday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person170" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - he used to lodge sometimes in one House, and sometimes in another, at 2 d. a Night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had made an Information about 12 Months ago about forging of Wills, and there are many that do these Things to wrong Widows and Children; but if it please God I live to come out, I will make a Discovery of all that I know.</p>
               <p>[Holder call'd again.]</p>
               <p>Court. Consider what it is to swear against a Woman when her Life is at stake, why did not you go and give an Information of this?</p>
               <p>Holder. I was afraid of this 
               <persName id="t17420714-19-person171">
                  Mary 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17420714-19-person171" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person171" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , - but I did discover it afterwards. I am a poor working, honest Woman, and can bring People to my Character.</p>
               <p>Court. It is an unreasonable Thing to suppose, that you should see a Man standing up, and bleeding into a Hat, with his Throat cut, and not cry out murder, and give an account of it directly. <rs id="t17420714-19-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420714-19-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
