<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17460409-20">
               <interp inst="t17460409-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-20" type="year" value="1746"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17460409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17460409-20" type="date" value="17460409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17460409-20-off89-c269" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-20-defend314 t17460409-20-off89 t17460409-20-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>157. 
               
                  <persName id="t17460409-20-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17460409-20-defend314" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-defend314" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-defend314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17460409-20-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four Hararen Curtains, a Dimity Petticoat, a Pair of Woollen Breeches, six Silver Tea-Spoons, six Pewter Plates, a Pewter Dish, a Copper Coffee-Pot, a Copper Stew-Pan, a Silk Gown, a Crape Gown, a Looking-Glass, two China Punch-Bowls, a Box-Iron, a Copper Tea-Kettle, a Linnen Sheet, a Copper Sauce-Pan with a Copper Cover, a Camblet Petticoat, and three Blankets; the Property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17460409-20-victim316" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Steward 
                        <interp inst="t17460409-20-victim316" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460409-20-victim316" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17460409-20-victim316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-20-off89 t17460409-20-victim316"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , from his Dwelling-House
            </rs> in <placeName id="t17460409-20-crimeloc90">New Hermitage-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17460409-20-crimeloc90" type="placeName" value="New Hermitage-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17460409-20-crimeloc90" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-20-off89 t17460409-20-crimeloc90"></join>, the <rs id="t17460409-20-cd91" type="crimeDate">13th of March</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17460409-20-off89 t17460409-20-cd91"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17460409-20-person317">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17460409-20-person317" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-person317" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Jame Steward) Are you the Wife of 
               <persName id="t17460409-20-person318">
                  James 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17460409-20-person318" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-person318" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Steward. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your Husband's House?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174604090015"></xptr>Steward. In New Hermitage-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Husband lose any Goods from thence?</p>
               <p>Steward. Yes, my Lord; they were my Husband's to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. When were these Goods lost?</p>
               <p>Steward. They were lost between the last Day of October and the 7th of March.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray in what Manner were they lost? How came you to suspect that the Prisoner took them?</p>
               <p>Steward. Because, my Lord, I left her in the House.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you carry on any Business there?</p>
               <p>Steward. She (the Prisoner) came to lie with me, either in the Latter End of May, or the Beginning of July; a Neighbour brought her to lay with me, and I could never get her away; but I never saw any of her Money. In the latter End of October last I went to Hall, to meet my Husband, as he is a Sea-faring Man; she (the Prisoner) comes in with a Paper in her Hand, and said, I have a Paper come up from Cornwall, to make you easy and myself too. I said, I shall be gone before Saturday Night; and I said to Mrs. Brown, I have serv'd you before now, and oblig'd you; Now will you oblige me, in looking after my House while I am gone, as my Maid is so young; I said, if it suited her Convenience? She promis'd she would. I gave her 10 s. and said, Will that be enough 'till that Time you have your Money? I went away that very Night. The next Day after that I was gone, Mr. Canedy and his Wife return'd, (they had been out of Town, and use to lodge with me) she said to them, the Case was alter'd, and she put the Man and his Wife upon a Flock Bed, and gave them nothing to eat. The Prisoner refus'd to let them have the Bed they us'd to lie on.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you not hear from the Prisoner all this Time?</p>
               <p>Steward. I had two Letters, and no more, and very kind ones they were. When my Husband and I came home, we were surpriz'd to see the House in such Distraction; and she has been an Instrument of making a Difference between me and my Husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Prisoner after this?</p>
               <p>Steward. Yes, and desir'd her to tell me where my Goods were. At last she own my Crape Gown and some other Things were pawn'd, and some carried out for fear of Fire.</p>
               <p>Court. According to the State of Things this appears only to be a Breach of Trust. We believe, good Woman, you have been very much wrong'd, and the Prisoner is open to the Law, but not to a criminal Prosecution.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17460409-20-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17460409-20-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
