<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17421013-11">
               <interp inst="t17421013-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421013-11" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421013-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17421013"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17421013-11" type="date" value="17421013"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17421013-11-off54-c83" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-defend107 t17421013-11-off54 t17421013-11-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>124. 
               
                  <persName id="t17421013-11-defend107" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Heaney  otherwise <rs id="t17421013-11-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-defend107 t17421013-11-alias-1"></join>Ceeney</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-defend107" type="surname" value="Heaney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-defend107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-defend107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , was indicted for <rs id="t17421013-11-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a Silver Watch, val. 5 l. - and a Silver Watch Chain, val. 4 s. the Property of 
                     <persName id="t17421013-11-victim108" type="victimName">
                        Henry 
                        Lane 
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-victim108" type="surname" value="Lane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421013-11-victim108" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17421013-11-victim108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-off54 t17421013-11-victim108"></join>
                     </persName>
                    , in the Dwelling-House
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17421013-11-person109">
                  John 
                  Lemmon 
               <interp inst="t17421013-11-person109" type="surname" value="Lemmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .</p>
               <p>Henry Lane. On the <rs id="t17421013-11-cd55" type="crimeDate">31st of August</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-off54 t17421013-11-cd55"></join>, between eight and nine in the Morning, I was going up Fleet-street, and a Gentleman like Man picked up a Shilling; he said he had found a Shilling, and asked me to drink part of a Pint of Wine, which I accepted of. He went into <placeName id="t17421013-11-crimeloc56">Pope's-Court, in Bell-Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17421013-11-crimeloc56" type="placeName" value="Pope's-Court, in Bell-Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17421013-11-crimeloc56" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-off54 t17421013-11-crimeloc56"></join>; and in this Court we met 
               <persName id="t17421013-11-person110">
                  John 
                  Heaney 
               <interp inst="t17421013-11-person110" type="surname" value="Heaney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; says the Man, who picked up the Shilling, I have found a Shilling, and am going to treat this Man with a Glass of Wine, and desired him to go and take Part of it. We went into a House where there was a little Room in the Yard. They put me into the inner Part of the Room, and the Prisoner was next to the Door; after they had drank some Wine, they began to talk of cutting of Cards, particularly the Prisoner, who went out under a Pretence of buying Cards; but I believe he had them in his Pocket at the Time, because he returned so quick; the Prisoner and the other played, I was prevailed on to bet a Shilling, and I won two Shillings; so this Man who had picked up the Shilling, he cut good Cards, Court Cards; says he to me, Do you cut; I apprehend he had two Packs, for when I came to cut, I cut nothing but Aces and Duces, and the like, and I lost the two Shillings that I had got. Says he, I will venture another Shilling, says I, I have never a Shilling: What, says he, have you no Watch nor nothing to put down? Yes, says I, I have a Watch, so I put my Watch down upon the Table, and cut two or three Times; still the Cards were low, that I lost every Time; I lost two or three Shillings that Way; and please you, my Lord, he took up my Watch and went away with it directly. I went out as fast as I could, but he was gone, and I saw no more of him till about a Fortnight afterwards; as I was coming up Newgate-street I met with him, and one more of his Companions; as soon as ever he saw me, he began to run; I cried out Stop Thief, and caught him before he got to the End of the Street; but the other was a brisk Fellow, and he got off; says the Prisoner, if you will release me you shall have your Watch again. He begged me to go into a Publick-House, and the People persuaded me to let him go in; said they, may be you may have your Watch again; and he said I should have my Watch. So some of the People persuaded me to make it up, and others not to make it up, for if I did he might trouble me; so I would not make it up, but would have him before a Magistrate; he did not care to walk on Foot, but he would have a Coach, and before we got to Guild-Hall, he was fumbling in his Pocket; I was in Hopes I should have my Watch again, but they were two Packs of Cards that he had in his Pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Another Man put down a Ring to answer his Watch. I plaid till it came to Six Guineas, and won his Watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any Body put down a Ring?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes, one of his Companions did to bet with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421013-11-person111">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17421013-11-person111" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person111" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Constable. I was at the Alehouse, while Mr Lane had the Prisoner there in the House, and he said if he would let him go, he would send for the Watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My Lord, this Gentleman has sworn a Robbery upon me, when I won the Watch; and it is very unlikely a Man should be robbed of his Watch at Noon-Day, and not make a Noise.</p>
               <p>Lane. My Lord, I was afraid of my Life, and did not care to make any Noise, for I had heard<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174210130006"></xptr> of some Murders and Robberies at that Time, that I was afraid to do it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421013-11-person112">
                  Martha 
                  Blakesley 
               <interp inst="t17421013-11-person112" type="surname" value="Blakesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person112" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             says she has known the Prisoners two Years, gave him the Character of an honest Man, that he always kept good Hours; that as he was a Watch-Maker, she thought he might have got his Living honestly and truly, without following this Course of Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17421013-11-person113">
                  Frances 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17421013-11-person113" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person113" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave him much the same Character. <rs id="t17421013-11-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-verdict57" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17421013-11-punish58" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17421013-11-punish58" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17421013-11-defend107 t17421013-11-punish58"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
