<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17420224-35">
               <interp inst="t17420224-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-35" type="year" value="1742"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17420224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17420224-35" type="date" value="17420224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17420224-35-off153-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-defend239 t17420224-35-off153 t17420224-35-verdict157"></join>
         
               <p>33. + 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-defend239" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-defend239" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-defend239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-defend239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17420224-35-defloc152">St. Martin Outwich</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-defloc152" type="placeName" value="St. Martin Outwich"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-defloc152" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-defend239 t17420224-35-defloc152"></join>, was indicted with other Persons unknown, for <rs id="t17420224-35-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assaulting 
                     
                        <persName id="t17420224-35-victim241" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Fawdrey 
                        <interp inst="t17420224-35-victim241" type="surname" value="Fawdrey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-35-victim241" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17420224-35-victim241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-off153 t17420224-35-victim241"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's Highway, putting him in Fear, and taking from him a Gold Watch, Value 10 Pounds
            </rs>, <rs id="t17420224-35-cd154" type="crimeDate">Feb. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-off153 t17420224-35-cd154"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person242">
                  Robert 
                  Fawdrey 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person242" type="surname" value="Fawdrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person242" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of this Month, I had been at the Mourning Bush, at Aldersgate, and about half an Hour past twelve in the Morning, I was walking very carefully down <placeName id="t17420224-35-crimeloc155">Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-off153 t17420224-35-crimeloc155"></join>, being a little Lame. I saw nobody in the Street, but very near that Part that is opposite to <placeName id="t17420224-35-crimeloc156">St. Martin Outwich Church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="St. Martin Outwich Church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17420224-35-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17420224-35-off153 t17420224-35-crimeloc156"></join>, a Woman came up to me, and fastened round my Arm; - my Dear! said she, You look like a good-natur'd Fellow, you will give me a Glass of Wine! I, with an Imprecation, bid her be gone. She said, I am sure you will give me a Glass of Wine, and immediately pull'd my Watch out of my Pocket. I cry'd out Watch; and directly the Prisoner said hold of me; - the whole Transaction was not so long as I have been speaking. The Prisoner immediately tripp'd up my Heels, and stood over me, and beat my Right Fore-finger in a terrible Manner. I believe it will appear by the Evidence that I shall produce, that this Man and the Woman were found talking together at Creed-Lane, about 12 o'Clock. I believe it was a Conspiracy between them, in order to meet the first Man they could. and I was the unhappy Victim of their Intentions.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240014"></xptr>Q After you had been tripped up, as you have mentioned, what happened then?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. I call'd Watch! as I had done before, and a Person came up to me, who is the next Witness, 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-person243">
                  William 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person243" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Hind, a Man I never saw before, but fortunately I believe for me, came in to save my Life. When I began to call Watch in this Manner, they both left me: the Woman ran up the Street, and the Prisoner ran down it, and was taken by the next Witness.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q Can you recollect what Hour the Woman met with you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. Between 12 and 1: - I did not meet with her, she met with me, and came forcibly upon me.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was it near a Lamp?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey It was very near the Lamp, and I knew the Prisoner the Moment he was taken.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. I think you say, before the Man came up, your Watch was taken from you.</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. At the very Instant that my Watch was taken away, my Heels flew up, from whence I apprehend, that the Man was behind me.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Had you seen the Man before the Woman came up to you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. No, nor her neither, for the whole Transaction was but half a Minute.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Can you guess how near to 12 or 1 this might be?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. It was so near, that I believe I could say it wanted about a Quarter of one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person244">
                  Wm 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person244" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person244" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Hind. On Tuesday Morning, or Monday Night, I will not say, I came from Mr. Darby's in Stationer's-Court. It struck twelve o'Clock, and then the Landlord according to Custom, turn'd every Body out of the House. - I believe it might be a Quarter after when I left the House. I crossed over the Way to the Corner of Creed-Lane, and while I was standing there, I saw the Prisoner and another Man, with a Woman in a white Cloak and a Velvet Hood. One of the Men, who was a tallish Man, cross'd the Way from her, and when he had got about half a-cross, the Woman call'd, Hog! Hog! I want to speak with you. He then came to her, and they all went down Creed lane together. I went on into Cheapside, where I stopp'd to speak to one 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-person245">
                  Dick 
                  Too 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person245" type="surname" value="Too"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person245" type="given" value="Dick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Watchman, after which, I walked pretty leisurely till I came beyond the Change. The Prisoner and the Woman in the Cloak then passed me. I was not positive which Way they turned, but just as I came to the Corner of Cornhill, by Bishopsgate-Street, there stood a Hackney-Coach just cross the Street. I stopp'd there to make the Coachman drive out of the Way, which being done, I went down Bishopsgate-street; and when I had got 3 or 4 Doors down, I heard a Cry of Watch! Hearing that, I mended my Pace, and there is a great Pair of wooden Gates on the Right Hand side of the Way; and next Door to them, I saw Mr. Fawdrey upon his Back. The Prisoner and the Woman in the white Cloak were then upon him: What (said I) are you going to murder the Man? and as soon as I had said that, the Prisoner turned about, and ran over the Way directly: - he ran one Way, and the Woman another. The Prosecutor said he had lost his Watch, upon which, after I had helped him up, I pursued the Prisoner. He ran about as far as the Pump, and then he turned his Back against the Wall, and asked me what I wanted with him? I told him, the Gentleman said he had robbed him of his Watch, and he must go with me. I brought him over the Way, and as soon as Mr. Fawdrey saw him, he said, that is the Man that knocked me down. We then, with the Assistance of a Watchman, carried him to the Watch-house, and there he denied that he knew any thing of the Matter.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Fawdrey. What Dress was the Woman in that came up to you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Fawdrey. I take it that she had on a Linnen or Cotton Gown, with a light Colour'd short Cloak, and a Velvet Hood.</p>
               <p>Pris. to Hind. Had you any Acquaintance with me before this?</p>
               <p>Hind. I never spoke to him before to my Knowledge?</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. How came you to take such particular Notice of a Man going along the Street, that you can be sure of him when you came to Bishopsgate street ?</p>
               <p>Hind. Because he then had a blue Handkerchief with white Spots about his Neck, and the same Coat on as he has now.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. Was it dark or light when this happened?</p>
               <p>Hind. I can't remember, but there is a Lamp just by the Tavern Door, at the End of Creed-Lane, and another at the Door over-against it.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. What o'Clock was it when you saw them there?</p>
               <p>Hind I believe it was a Quarter after 12, because when the Watch go 12 o'Clock, Mr. Darby always turns the Customers out of Doors, and I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174202240015"></xptr> only staid to pay my Reckoning and finish a Pot of Beer, and then I came away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person246">
                  Daniel 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person246" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person246" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Watchman, confirm'd the Deposition of Palmer Hind, so far as it related to the apprehending the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Thomas Hill, Constable. On Tuesday Morning, a little after one, the Prisoner was brought into the Watch-House. Mr. Fawdrey gave me charge of the Prisoner, for knocking him down, and rescuing a Person who had robbed him of his Watch. I asked Mr. Fawdrey in what Manner this was done, and he related it to me. He told me, he was coming down Bishopsgate-street, and a Woman laid hold of him, and asked him to give her a Glass of Wine: He bid her go about her Business, and he then perceived the Watch taken from him; upon which he attempted to lay hold of her, and immediately the Prisoner knocked him down, or struck up his Heels. That as soon as he recovered himself, he called Watch! and the Fellow then made off, and was pursued by Palmer Hind, who was then coming by, and with the Assistance of a Watchman, the Prisoner was taken. I asked the Prisoner several Questions, and he told me, he was going down on the other Side of the Way, and saw a Man and a Woman upon the Ground. He said, he went over to see what was the Matter, and when the Gentleman cry'd Watch! he ran - for Fear of coming into Trouble.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say that he knew the Woman who was there?</p>
               <p>Hill. No, he pretended that he knew nothing of her.</p>
               <p>It was insisted on by the Prisoner in his Defence, that he had been in Company with two Friends towards St. Giles's, 'till late at Night, and that he came from thence with them only towards Bishopsgate-street; that as he was going on one Side of Bishopsgate-street, he saw a Gentleman and a Woman struggling. That he went away directly, and soon afterwards the Gentleman complained of the Injury, and pursued him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person247">
                  Thomas 
                  Cumber 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person247" type="surname" value="Cumber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday Evening, between 7 and 8 o'Clock, the Prisoner and I were drinking at the Bull Head, in White chapple. He said, he was going into Catherine street, to receive some Money, and desired me to take a Walk with him. Accordingly I did, and then we took our Departure from thence, and directed our Way Home.</p>
               <p>Pris. Q. How long did you stay in Catherine-street ?</p>
               <p>Cumber. I believe we came from thence between 12 and 1: 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-person248">
                  Joseph 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person248" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person248" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with us. We came directly for the City, and we took our Leaves of the Prisoner at the End of Bishopsgate-street, and went towards White chapple. There was nobody at all in Company but we three, and when we parted with the Prisoner, I believe it was about 1 o'Clock, and I saw no more of him that Night. I am a Shoemaker, and live in the Minories; Gibbs lives in White chapple, and I parted with him at the End of the Minories. I have known the Prisoner 20 Years, he is a Butcher, and I have bought Meat of him lately. He does not keep any Shop, but carries it about in a Tray. I never heard no ill Character of him, but he seems to take an industrious Care for his Bread. - I live in Well-Court, just by Mr. Fowler's the Barber's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go into Creed-Lane as you were going Home?</p>
               <p>Cumber. No, I don't know Creed-Lane, but we turn'd down no Lane at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person249">
                  Joseph 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person249" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person249" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Company with Cumber and the Prisoner at a Shop like a Chandler's Shop in Catherine-street: - it was pretty near 9 o'Clock, and we staid there till a little after 12. From thence we came with the Prisoner alone to the End of Bishopsgate-street, and there parted with him. There was no Woman in our Company, and we turn'd down no Street at all till we came to Bishopsgate-street, where we parted with the Prisoner, and went on directly towards Whitechappel. I believe it was then very near 1 o'Clock, if not quite. As to the Prisoner's Character, I have known him 20 Years, and never heard any Body give him an ill Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person250">
                  Thomas 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person250" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person250" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday last about 1 o'Clock, I was coming from the Yorkshire Grey in Gravel-Lane, and just as I was going to cross to Thread-needle-street, I heard a Person say, Stop her, I have lost my Watch! Presently a Woman ran by, as fast as if she had Wings, and I saw another Person like the Prisoner, and he was taken hold of. The Mob then began to gather, and I went Home, and saw no more of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person251">
                  John 
                  Kitchen 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person251" type="surname" value="Kitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-person252">
                  Samuel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person252" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person252" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17420224-35-person253">
                  James 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person253" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person253" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             appeared to the Prisoner's Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17420224-35-person254">
                  William 
                  Hookham 
               <interp inst="t17420224-35-person254" type="surname" value="Hookham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person254" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the Prisoner by Sight a great while. His Character is that of a common Sharper, and in general 'tis very bad. <rs id="t17420224-35-verdict157" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17420224-35-verdict157" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
