<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17411204-5">
               <interp inst="t17411204-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-5" type="year" value="1741"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17411204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17411204-5" type="date" value="17411204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-5-off20-c54" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-defend64 t17411204-5-off20 t17411204-5-verdict24"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17411204-5-off22-c56" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-defend68 t17411204-5-off22 t17411204-5-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>7. 
               
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-defend64" type="defendantName">
                     Esther 
                     Burnham 
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend64" type="surname" value="Burnham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend64" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , of <placeName id="t17411204-5-defloc19">St. Clement Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-defloc19" type="placeName" value="St. Clement Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-defloc19" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-defend64 t17411204-5-defloc19"></join>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-defend68 t17411204-5-defloc19"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17411204-5-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Silver Watch, value 3 l. 4 Pieces of foreign Gold, value 7 l. 4 s. 2 Moidores, and 9 Guineas, from the Person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17411204-5-victim66" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Bowers 
                        <interp inst="t17411204-5-victim66" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-5-victim66" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17411204-5-victim66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17411204-5-cd21" type="crimeDate">Nov. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-off20 t17411204-5-cd21"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-off22 t17411204-5-cd21"></join>. And,</p>
               <p>8. 
               
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-defend68" type="defendantName">
                     Godfrey 
                     Nodder 
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend68" type="surname" value="Nodder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend68" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-defend68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             , for <rs id="t17411204-5-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person69">
                  John 
                  Bowers 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person69" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday Night between 9 and 11 at Night, I was going round the <placeName id="t17411204-5-crimeloc23">Back Side of St. Clement's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-crimeloc23" type="placeName" value="Back Side of St. Clement's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17411204-5-crimeloc23" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-off20 t17411204-5-crimeloc23"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-off22 t17411204-5-crimeloc23"></join>, and I went with a Woman into this Burnham's House. It is a House where they sell Drams, and I thought it was kept by another Person. I dismissed the Woman whom I had with me, and went towards the Fire-side, and turned up the Flap of my Waistcoat, and saw my Watch was there. The Prisoner then desired me to go with her into the Passage just by the Door, and we had not been there above three Minutes before she picked my Pocket of my Watch, and she gave me a Shove and ran into the House. I followed her, and just as I came to the Door, 
               <persName id="t17411204-5-person70">
                  Godfrey 
                  Nodder 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person70" type="surname" value="Nodder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person70" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the other Prisoner, met me, and gave me a push away till she made her Escape. Finding she was gone, and not being willing to lose my Watch, I said in the public Room, I would give any Body a Guinea to have my Watch again, and no Questions asked. Upon this she came down Stairs rectly, and I pulled out my Purse to have Change for Half a Guinea: She seeing my Purse, called me into another Room, and I thinking to have my Watch again, went into the Room with her, and there she picked my Pocket of my Purse and Gold. I missed it that very Minute, and ran after her and caught her. I came to Town on the Sunday Night before, and brought this Money with me, and was pretty much fuddled when this happened. I seized the Prisoner a second Time, and Nodder came and struggled with me, and she got away again. I can't tell what Nodder is; I never saw him before that Night, but I can swear to them both. I saw there was nothing to be done, so I went to call Assistance, and got Mr. Roach and Mr. Sumner to go with me, and with some Difficulty we got into the House. We went into a Room and found the Prisoner, and seeing Nodder's Hat and Wig lying on the Chest of Drawers, we asked her where her Husband (Nodder) was? She said he was gone out, but after we had set a Watch about the House, we went into the next Room, and there was Nodder by the Fire Side. He robb'd his Eyes as if he had been asleep, and 
               <persName id="t17411204-5-person71">
                  Robin 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person71" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person71" type="given" value="Robin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             found the Watch in the Chimney by him. Then they search'd in the Fire Place, and found some 36 s. Pieces, two Moidores, and 3 Guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know they were yours?</p>
               <p>Bowers. I am sure as to the Watch, but it is a hard Matter to swear to the Money. I told the Constable and all of them, what Pieces I had lost before they went to search. These Things were not found upon Nodder, but in the Fire Place by him, and on searching him we found a Purse and some Money in his Pocket. I can't swear that they were mine, but he said he had pawned his Hat and Wig for 2 s. just before.</p>
               <p>Pris. Burnham. Ask him if there were not two Women that came with him, and sat by the Fire Side.</p>
               <p>Bowers. One Woman I brought in, but her I dismissed.</p>
               <p>Burnham. How do you know but that Woman might take your Things?</p>
               <p>Bowers. Because I chang'd my Money after she had been gone some Time.</p>
               <p>Pris. Nodder. Ask him if I mislefted (molested ) him in any Shape, or meddled with him good, bad, or indifferent?</p>
               <p>Bowers. Once I had her in my Custody and he hinder'd me.</p>

               <p>Nodder. Did not I tell him he might go and see if there was any Woman there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040006"></xptr>
               </p>
               <p>Bowers. He said I might go down into the Cellar and see.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person72">
                  Elias 
                  Sumner 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person72" type="surname" value="Sumner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person72" type="given" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Robe maker, and happen'd to call in at this House to see for my Bed-fellow, because I knew he was drunk that Afternoon , and he used to keep Company with a loose Woman that used that House. At Nodder's Desire I sat down by the Fire Side about two Minutes , and the Coachman (Bowers) came and sat down on the other Side of the Fire. He sat about a Minute, and went out again, and Burnham and he were both missing. After they had been out two Minutes, or something more, I heard some Body run up Stairs very fast . There was a Screen by the Fire, and I could not see whether any Body went out with him, but he came in presently, and said she had robb'd him of his Watch. Nodder said there was no Body come in there, Bowers insisted that there was, and upon that Nodder wanted to let him out at the Passage Door to see for her there. Bowers would have it, that she was gone up Stairs, upon which Nodder took a Candle off the Counter, and went up Stairs, but would not let him go into the one pair of Stairs Room, because (he said) they must be gone up higher. I went up to the one pair of Stairs, but Nodder and the Prosecutor went up higher, and when they came down again, the Prosecutor pulled out a Guinea on the Counter, and said he would give it for his Watch. Immediately Burnham came down, and he told her she had got his Watch, and he would give her a Guinea to let him have it again . He called for a Quartern of Shrub, and had Change for half a Guinea: she seeing his Money said, Come hither my Dear, I want to speak with you! Upon which they went backwards , and staid very near a Quarter of an Hour, and then I heard her run out crying, D - ye if I will be served so. He follow'd her, and said she had got his Money. Nodder said, no Body had got his Money; but however I saw the Prosecutor bring her into the House by one Arm, and Nodder and he had a great Struggle, and got her from him. Then the Coachman (the Prosecutor) went out to see for his Friends, and Nodder fasten'd up the Door. I did not care to stay in the House any longer, so I bid Nodder give me a Dram, and let me go out. He was very unwilling to let me go, but at last he did; and when I came out, I saw the Prosecutor and Roach together While we were talking together , I happen'd to see this young Woman that my Shop mate keeps Company with. Nodder had refused to let us in again, so she open'd the Door for us, and when we came in we found the Prisoner Burnham a Bed, and I saw the Watch found in the Chimney, and the Money in the Ashes.</p>
               <p>Burnham . How long has he known me?</p>
               <p>Sumner . I never saw her but once before that Sunday Night.</p>
               <p>Burnham. Did he see me go into any Company with the Coachman ?</p>
               <p>Sumner. No, Nodder came up to me as I sat in the Watch-house, and said, if I would keep silent , his Wife should make me a Present.</p>
               <p>Nodder. Ask him whether I used the Coachman ill?</p>
               <p>Sumner. Yes, he got the Woman away from him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person73">
                  Robert 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person73" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person73" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Lamb-Inn, the Back of St. Clement's, within five Doors of the Prisoner's House, and my Servant being gone to see what was the Matter , I went to fetch him Home, but being acquainted with the Coachman, I staid to assist him. The House was beset with Watchmen, and the Door in the Passage was bolted, but we got it opened, and when we came in, we saw Nodder in the Room below Stairs: He rubbed his Eyes and yawn'd , and ask'd what was the Matter The Prosecutor said, he had been robbed, and on searching the House, I found this Watch on the Edge of a Brick between the Closet and the Chimney, and in the Chimney Corner I found four Broad Pieces, and three Guineas.</p>
               <p>Bowers. This Watch is mine, it was made by one Davis.</p>
               <p>Roach. Nodder stood by me when I found these , and he bid me look in the Fire, so I took the Poker and stirred the Fire, and found two Moidores, and two Guineas more. After I had found the Watch in the Chimney, I began to look for the Money, and Nodder desired to speak with me in private, and he said, If I would disperse the Watchmen, the Money should be forth coming. I told him, we must have it now, but he said, there were some Females concerned in it, and they were the Devil to deal with.</p>
               <p>Burnham. Did not I desire to be stripp'd and search'd?</p>
               <p>Roach. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person74">
                  Samuel 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person74" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person74" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday Evening about eleven o'Clock, or a small Time before, John Bower came to my House, and told me he had been robbed: The Robe-maker (Sumner ) came by at the same Time, and we got him to go along with us. We got two Watchmen to stand and secure the Fore-door, and then a Woman came by that used the House, and by her Means we got in. When we had got in, we went into</p>
               <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174112040007"></xptr>
               <p>the back Room, and found Burnham a bed, and on going into another Room , we saw Nodder sitting by the Fire-side , as if he had been asleep, and he pretended to be ignorant of our Business. We searched about, and at last my Brother found the Watch in the Chimney , and among some Dirt there were four thirty-six Shilling Pieces and some Guineas found . I took particular Notice of them, because Williams took them out , and he being a Stranger, I imagined he might Pocket some .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person75">
                  Arthur 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person75" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person75" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd the above Deposition, with Regard to the finding the Prosecutor's Money .</p>
               <p>Burnham. The Prosecutor came into our House with two Women, and had some Shrub, and changed Half a Guinea for it. They sat some Time, and at last went away together, and some time afterwards he came in again , and charged me with robbing him of his Watch . It is something very particular, that this Man should lose his Watch , be gone from me, and say I robb'd him, and afterwards fuster me to take his Money. I should be glad to know what Freedom there was between us.</p>
               <p>Bowers. There was going to be a pretty deal of Freedom, but I lost it in the mean Time.</p>
               <p>Mary Lane. I live in Peter street, St. James's. I lived with Mrs. Burnham last Summer, and I was in her Family before I lived with her. On Monday last in the Evening, I believe it might be something after eight o'Clock, I saw the Door open, I happened to be coming along, and dropped in there, and saw Mr. Nodder in the Shop. - I knew him before, for he lodged with her when I was her Servant. She keeps a Shop, and sells Liquor , - I don't know what, - common Liquor, - Gin I believe; but however , this Coachman came in, - he had a laced Hat on then, and he asked for one Mrs. Shaw. He was drunk, and two Women followed him in, and one of them sat in his Lap. He went out, and when he returned, he said, he had been robbed, and I am sure the Prisoner was not in his Company a Crum of a Minute. He accused me first, and when Mrs. Burnham came, he accused her; but before he went away, he desired to have a Dram, and be Friends . I know two or three of the People that were there; you, Sir, I knew for one, and this Man in his own Hair was another, and I will take another of you if that be all ( to Roach ) you told me, if I offered to appear you would hang me, and the Beadle of the Parish said the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine the other Woman robb'd Bowers ?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes, I fancy so.</p>
               <p>Q. And left the Watch and Money for some body else ?</p>
               <p>Lane. I can't tell as to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person76">
                  Elizabeth Bett 
                  Burnham 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person76" type="surname" value="Burnham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person76" type="given" value="Elizabeth Bett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived with a Relation of mine at Chelsea , about a Year ago, and I never heard that she wrong'd any Body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17411204-5-person77">
                  Robert 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17411204-5-person77" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person77" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know but little of Burnham , but Nodder I have known about a dozen Years, and never heard any Body accuse him of any Thing of this Kind. He kept a Public-House in Fleet Street a little while ago. - I have heard that he stood on the Pillory , but not till within this Month .</p>
               <p>Roach . Lane was in the House, and behaved in a very insolent Manner, and we desired the Justice to commit her to Bridewell, but he would not commit any Body that might be a Witness for the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Burnham. They said before the Justice, that I should keep my Christmas in another World, for they were determined to hang me.</p>
               <p>Mr. De Viel. These Gentlemen said no such Thing as she charges them with, and Lane was the most impudent Creature that I ever saw, and the Reason I did not commit her, was, because she was to be an Evidence for the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Burnham <rs id="t17411204-5-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17411204-5-punish25" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-punish25" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17411204-5-defend64 t17411204-5-punish25"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Nodder <rs id="t17411204-5-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17411204-5-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
