<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-12">
               <interp inst="t17400903-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-12" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-12" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-12-off76-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-defend118 t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>376. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-12-defend118" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Barton  otherwise <rs id="t17400903-12-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-defend118 t17400903-12-alias-4"></join>Webb</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-defend118" type="surname" value="Barton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-defend118" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-defend118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17400903-12-defloc75">St Paul's Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-defloc75" type="placeName" value="St Paul's Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-defloc75" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-defend118 t17400903-12-defloc75"></join> , was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-12-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               privately stealing a Watch, with the outside and inside Cases made of Gold, val. 10 l. a Chain made of base-metal, val. 5 s. a Stone Seal set in base-metal, val. 3 s. a silver Snuff-box , val. 10 s. and a silver Tooth-pick Case, val. 5 s. from the Person of 
                     <persName id="t17400903-12-victim119" type="victimName">
                        Robert 
                        Moone 
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-victim119" type="surname" value="Moone"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-12-victim119" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17400903-12-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs> . <rs id="t17400903-12-cd77" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-cd77"></join>.</p>
               <p>Robert Moone . I have seen the Prisoner, but as to the Fact , I can't say she took my Things. I was coming home the 29th, or 30th of June last, a little late, and a little in Liquor, - 'twas between 2 and 3 in the Morning, - and as I was going towards my own home, - towards Covent-Garden, a Woman took me up, and carried me to the Jersey Coffee House , in Covent-Garden; one Hyat keeps the House. There I was supply'd with something to drink; which, with what I had drank before, made me more and more in Liquor. After I had drank there, the Woman who pick'd me up, carried me to <placeName id="t17400903-12-crimeloc78">Jones's Bagnio</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc78" type="placeName" value="Jones's Bagnio"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc78" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-crimeloc78"></join>, at the <placeName id="t17400903-12-crimeloc79">Sign of the Turk's-Head</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Sign of the Turk's-Head"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-crimeloc79"></join>, in <placeName id="t17400903-12-crimeloc80">Bow-street, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="Bow-street, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-12-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-12-off76 t17400903-12-crimeloc80"></join>: and there I believe I was put upon the Bed, and being in Liquor, I fell a-sleep; and being a-sleep, - I slept for an Hour, or an Hour and a half, and then I wak'd; and being awake, - I called up some of the People of the House, to tell me where I was. The Keeper of the Bagnio came up, and told me I was at the Turk's-Head Bagnio, in Bow-Street. I informed him I was robbed of my Gold Watch, a silver Snuff-box, and silver Tooth-pick Case. I really can't say I was robbed at the Bagnio, but I will take my Oath, I had them at Hyat's House, the Jersey Coffee House ; for I pulled my Watch out there, and told the Bar-keeper, I was not capable of seeing what a clock it was myself, therefore I desired her to tell me. But missing my Things at Jones's Bagnio as soon as I wak'd, I complained that I had been robbed, but I can say nothing to the Prisoner; I met a Woman who carry'd me thither, - but I can't say it was the Prisoner; Indeed she acknowledg'd when she was before Colonel De Veil, that she was the Woman who was with me that very Morning, - at Hyat's Jersey Coffee House , first, - and then at the Turk's-Head Bagnio, but at the same time that she owned this, she denied the Fact, and said she did not rob me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner . Was no other Woman with you that Night?</p>
               <p>Moone . I don't know of any other Woman being there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw his Things, or touched them, These People that appear against me, have but very indifferent Characters themselves.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-12-person120">
                  William 
                  Horrabin 
               <interp inst="t17400903-12-person120" type="surname" value="Horrabin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person120" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (A. Waiter at Jones's Bagnio ) The Prisoner calls herself Ann Barton, alias Webb. She came in with the Prosecutor about the 30th of June, at the Turk's-Head Bagnio, between three and four o'Clock in the Morning. They asked for a Room; I showe'd them one; and shewing them the Room, they called for a Negus . I served them with it, and then came down Stairs, and left them. In half a Quarter of an Hour the Bell rang, as I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030012"></xptr> thought; so I ran up Stairs, and laid hold of the Knob of the Door, but I could not open it: so I call'd to Moone, and asked him if he rang? No, G - d d - your B - d, go about your Business. Then I went down again, and carried a Bottle of Wine into the Bagnio; and about an Hour after this, I heard the Bell ring hard: upon which I ran up Stairs, and found the Door of the Room, where the Prosecutor was, open. Sir, d'ye call? says I. Where's the Woman that was with me, said he? I told him I could not tell; for he had lock'd the Door, and I could not tell what was become of her. But why do you ask, Sir? Why, (says he) she has robb'd me of my Gold Watch, a Silver Snuff-box, and a Silver Tooth-pick Case, and immediately he fell a stamping about the Room. - Hush! Hush! said I, sometimes Women go out upon necessary Occasions; and I went to the Vault to look for her, but she was not there. Then I came up Stairs again, and bid him be patient; and I hunted about the Room, and about the Bed; but I found only a few Keys, a Corkscrew, and a Bit of Sealing-wax. Why this is not my Watch, says he: No, (I told him) it was not, but he might have had 20 Watches, for ought I knew. - The Prisoner was the Woman who was with him at our Bagnio, and that's all I know of the Matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-12-person121">
                  Francis 
                  Jean 
               <interp inst="t17400903-12-person121" type="surname" value="Jean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person121" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A young Fellow brought me a Warrant, to serve upon the Prisoner, and desired me to go with him to the Crown-Tavern upon Ludgate-Hill . When I came there, there was Mrs Hyat and two Men; one of whom carried me to Sword and Buckler Alley , where I took the Prisoner, and brought her to the Crown-Tavern . We sat a little while, and then Mrs Hyat went and fetched her Husband ; and we set out, in Order to go before a Justice. Mr Hyat and the Prisoner talked together, and he desired she would clear him, and tell whether the Watch was lost at his House, or not. She said, the Prosecutor did not lose it there, but that she took it out of his Pocket, on the Side of the Bed, at the Turk's-Head Bagnio , and had sold the Watch, and the outside Case, at two different Times, for 6 Guineas, to one 
               <persName id="t17400903-12-person122">
                  George 
                  Stacey 
               <interp inst="t17400903-12-person122" type="surname" value="Stacey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person122" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or Stracey , I can't tell which.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask him if 
               <persName id="t17400903-12-person123">
                  John 
                  Hyat 
               <interp inst="t17400903-12-person123" type="surname" value="Hyat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person123" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did not give him two Halfcrowns to swear against me?</p>
               <p>Jean. Upon my Oath I never had a Halfpenny , nor the Promise of a Halfpenny.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr Hyat wrote a great deal upon a Piece of Paper, and wanted me to sign it, but I told him I could neither read nor write, and I refused to do it. Then he told me if I could raise five or six Guineas, he would make it up.</p>
               <p>Jean. When the Prisoner was before the Lord-Mayor, she deny'd the Fact, but she had confessed it to me and Mr Hyat *, as we were coming up Cheapside. Before we went to the Lord-Mayor's, we call'd at Sir 
               <persName id="t17400903-12-person124">
                  William 
                  Biller 
               <interp inst="t17400903-12-person124" type="surname" value="Biller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person124" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, to see if Sir William was in the Way; and at his Office she confessed she took the Things at the Bagnio. This was the 18th of July, in the Afternoon. I believe there was another Person heard her confess, beside Mr Hyat , but I am not certain of that, - upon my Honour I am not.</p>
               <p>* Mr Hyat was in Court, but neither the Prosecutor nor Prisoner cared to have him examined.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I deny it, before Colonel De Veil?</p>
               <p>Jean. My Lord Mayor desired the Prisoner might be taken before Colonel De Veil, as she was taken with his Warrant, and we accordingly carried her before him. She did deny it there, but I told the Colonel, what she had confessed to me at the Office, and as we brought her up Cheapside . For Mr Hyat had bid her confess, in an honest way, that he might get clear of the thing; upon which she fell a crying, and said, she did not know what to do. I am afraid (says she) I shall bring myself into trouble: but after she had wiped her Eyes, she said she would make a true Confession, and she accordingly confessed what I have related . <rs id="t17400903-12-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-12-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
