<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440404-28">
               <interp inst="t17440404-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-28" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440404"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440404-28" type="date" value="17440404"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440404-28-off162-c253" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-defend319 t17440404-28-off162 t17440404-28-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>218. + 
               
                  <persName id="t17440404-28-defend319" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17440404-28-defend319" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-defend319" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-defend319" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             , of <placeName id="t17440404-28-defloc161">St. Paul's Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-28-defloc161" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-28-defloc161" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-defend319 t17440404-28-defloc161"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440404-28-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing thirty-nine shirts, value 25 l. three cambrick aprons, value 1 l. 1 s. eighteen linnen aprons, value 3 l. one fustian gown, value 3 l. one dimitty gown, value 1 l. 10 s. four petticoats, value 1 l. 12 s. two linnen jackets, value 2 s. three linnen waistcoats, value 3 s. four linnen handkerchiefs, value 8 s. two cambrick caps laced, value 2 l. a silk handkerchief, value 2 s. three cloth cloaks, value 3 s. one pair of cambrick ruffles, laced, value 10 s. one linnen cap, value 10 s. one suit of cambrick headclothes, laced, value 5 l. six sheets, value 1 l. 10 s. two linnen bed quilts, value 15 s. one damask table-cloth, value 21 s. four damask napkins, value 4 s. seven diaper table cloth, value 7 s. sixteen napkins, value 1 l. 12 s. six towels, value 6 s. one pair of gold ear-rings, value 5 s. one silver egg, value 5 s. one silver spoon, value 8 s. four silver tea-spoons, value 4 s. two silver strainers, value 2 s. one pair of silver tongs, value 18 d. one pair of silver buckles, value 7 s. a leather case with a knife, a fork, and a silver spoon, value 1 l. 1 s. one pair of velvet muffateens, value 5 s. and a silver snuff box, value 8 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17440404-28-victim321" type="victimName">
                           Ellis 
                           Conliff 
                        <interp inst="t17440404-28-victim321" type="surname" value="Conliff"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-28-victim321" type="given" value="Ellis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17440404-28-victim321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-off162 t17440404-28-victim321"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   , in his dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17440404-28-cd163" type="crimeDate">March 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-off162 t17440404-28-cd163"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440404-28-person322">
                  Mary Ann 
                  Conliff 
               <interp inst="t17440404-28-person322" type="surname" value="Conliff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-person322" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-person322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I kept a <placeName id="t17440404-28-crimeloc164">publick house in the little piazzas Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-28-crimeloc164" type="placeName" value="publick house in the little piazzas Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440404-28-crimeloc164" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-off162 t17440404-28-crimeloc164"></join>. I delivered all my linnen into the care of the Prisoner, who was my <rs id="t17440404-28-deflabel165" type="occupation">barkeeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440404-28-defend319 t17440404-28-deflabel165"></join> - I am lately married, and my husband would not let me stay in the house. When I went, I left the Prisoner in charge of the house, and a cook, and a man servant, with her - I was in the house but two months before I was married, and I have been married about two months - My husband is a lieutenant in a regiment at Jamaica: he is gone into the country to take leave of his friends, before he goes to his regiment. I demanded an account of my things of the prisoner, and she put me off from one day to another for three weeks; and then she said, she could not find them. I owed her a little money, and she said she would give me a little account, if I would pay her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The washerwoman has all the linnen entirely. She owes her four pound fourteen shillings and odd pence; and she owes me eight pound seven shillings and ten-pence. <rs id="t17440404-28-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440404-28-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
