<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17430907-46">
               <interp inst="t17430907-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-46" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17430907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17430907-46" type="date" value="17430907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17430907-46-off237-c356" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-46-defend440 t17430907-46-off237 t17430907-46-verdict239"></join>
         
               <p>421. 
               <persName id="t17430907-46-defend440" type="defendantName">
                  Eleanor 
                  Mackintosh 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-defend440" type="surname" value="Mackintosh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-defend440" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-defend440" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the <placeName id="t17430907-46-defloc236">Precinct of St Catherine's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-46-defloc236" type="placeName" value="Precinct of St Catherine's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17430907-46-defloc236" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-46-defend440 t17430907-46-defloc236"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17430907-46-off237" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-off237" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-off237" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Wilful Murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17430907-46-victim442" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Bryan 
                        <interp inst="t17430907-46-victim442" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-46-victim442" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17430907-46-victim442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-46-off237 t17430907-46-victim442"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by giving him a Mortal Wound, with an Iron Poker of the Value of 2 d. upon the right Temple, of the Length of half an Inch, and the Depth of half an Inch, <rs id="t17430907-46-cd238" type="crimeDate">August 18</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-46-off237 t17430907-46-cd238"></join>. of which Wound he languished in the Parish of St George till the 21st Day of August, and then and there died
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second Time charged on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said Murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-46-person443">
                  Catherine 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person443" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person443" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged with the Prisoner; my Brother, the Deceased, used frequently to come and see me, and upon this Day three Weeks he came between nine and ten in the Morning, and this Accident happened about 4 o'Clock in the Afternoon, during which Time we had three half Pints of Brandy, between the Prisoner, one Mrs Stewart, an Acquaintance of her's, my Brother, and I; I believe my Brother did not drink half a Glass of it. Mrs Stewart laid down upon the Bed, and the Prisoner said, my Brother went to put his Hand under her Petticoats, and he said, I had no Intention to put my Hand under her Petticoats, I had no Thoughts of it; he said he only laid his Hand upon her, and thought no Harm in it. Then the Prisoner began to curse and swear, and called him a great<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070025"></xptr> many Names, and said he had a great deal of Impudence to meddle with any Body in her Apartment, that she was no Companion for him; my Brother said, What is that to you, I will do as I please; the Prisoner made Answer, No, you Rogue, you shall not do as you please in my Apartment, and she took up a short Hearth-Brush, and gave him several Blows upon the Head with it; What, says he, are you in earnest ? Yes, said she, I am, you Dog. Then he took the Brush out of her Hand, and slung it away; then she took up the Bar of the Grate, and was going to knock him down with that; he took the Bar out of her Hand, and threw it away; then she took hold of him by the Hair of his Head, and he endeavouring to get her Hand out of his Hair, scratched her on the Face, and gave her a Push from him, and she fell down backward; then she started up again, took up the Poker, and gave him a dead Stroke on the right-side of the Temple.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she strike him with great Violence or no?</p>
               <p>Collins. She did it designedly to be sure, for she said before the struck him, You Son of a Where. I will knock your Brains out; - it a had she could strike him; the Poker has a little sharp Point, which was wore away with the Fire, and was like a crooked Nail; it run into his Temple so that there was a Hole I could put the Top of my Little-finger into; when he received the Blow he said, I am murdered, and the Blood and Tears ran down from his Face, and so the Tears did from mine. - She knocked him dead down with the Blow, - it was a small Poker, about the Bigness of my Finger, not three Quarters of a Yard long; - he cried out Murder, and I cried out Murder; he bled about half a Pint.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the Prisoner behave?</p>
               <p>Collins. She thought nothing of it, she said, he gave her more than she gave him, and did not Care if she had given him six Times as much; then my Brother and I went away; we had two Pints of Beer at an Alehouse, and he said he would go to his Lodging.</p>
               <p>Jury. Was there no Surgeon applied to?</p>
               <p>Collins. No. my Brother took no Notice of it for two Days - The Deceased was a Glover and Breeches Maker; - he could do no Business after he received that dead Stroke, and did not eat a Morsel, till Death took him, but he drank pretty much Small-Beer and Pump-Water, and that would come up again before it was well down in his Belly: - He received the Wound on Thursday, and was turned cat of his Lodging on Friday Night, and on Saturday Night he got another. - I was with him when he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible when he died?</p>
               <p>Collins. He was a little headful some times, but he came sensible about Half an Hour before his Death, when I got him a Pint of Ale, and rais'd him up to drink it, and after he had drank it, he fell off my Arm like a great Stone, and never spoke afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any Physician or Surgeon?</p>
               <p>Collins. No, he did not mind it for two Days, though the Wound run with Blood and Water, and his Face was swelled as big as three Faces.</p>
               <p>Coroner. The Parish where he died would be at no Charge, and no Surgeon would come near him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-46-person444">
                  Mary 
                  Grant 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person444" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person444" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person444" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He came to my House, on the Saturday Night, between six and seven in the Evening, and said, the Woman that was drinking with me on Tuesday Night, has given me a Blow with a Poker, that has given me my Death's Wound; and when I am dead she will be hanged for me.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-46-person445">
                  James 
                  Flit 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person445" type="surname" value="Flit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person445" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Saturday Night, between nine and ten, I saw the Deceased at Mrs Grant's and he said, Mrs Mackintosh had given him his Death's Wound; he cried out facly, and said, if he could not be blooded he should die in a Minute, that he had a Pain about his Heart, and desired me to lend him a Hand into St Catherines; I went with him to a Barber's Shop and desired him to bleed him; and, he said, it was a Thing of a very dangerous Consequence, and did not care to do it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-46-person446">
                  Mary 
                  Caddy 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person446" type="surname" value="Caddy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person446" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Deceased came to our House on the Saturday Night, when my Mother and I were not at Home; and some of our People took him in; and my Mother was angry, and said, it was hard to bury a Man for one Night's Lodging; the Woman that was with him (his Sister) called us up; I went, and found that he drew his Breath very slow; I said to her, pull him straight, for I thought he was dying; and the Woman cried, and said, he was murdered by one Mackintosh; I got an Officer, and went to take her up: says the Deceased's Sister, you must be pretty sly about it, or she will get away; I left the Officer at an Alehouse, because she should not be apprized of the Thing; I knocked at her Door, and said, Mrs Mackintosh I want to speak to you; she opened the Door, and I thought looked a little surprized at seeing a Stranger; I said, there was some-body wanted to speak with her at the Black-Boy; she said, she would not go; I got within the Door, to prevent her shutting of it; said I, What are you guilty of any Thing that you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070026"></xptr> are afraid of going; may be, I am, said she; I got within the Door, and caught fast hold of her, and cried out for Help; one of the Men at the Alehouse came and took her; says I, you are a vile Jade, you have murdered a Man, and he is now dead at my Mother's House; she said, he would have murdered her - she said, she hit him with a Poker; and that he run to the Grate, and took a Bar off, and hit her with it; and that the twisted the Bar out of his Hand; I cannot be positive whether, she said, she struck him first; she said, he had abused her; and if she had not killed him, he would have killed her</p>
               <p>Capt. 
               <persName id="t17430907-46-person447">
                  John 
                  Jell 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person447" type="surname" value="Jell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person447" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (High Constable) On Sunday Morning, Aug. 21. I heard a Noise in the Square, between six and seven in the Morning, and was informed, that a Woman was taken up; I went to enquire about it, and found the first Evidence in the Cage; I asked the Reason, and they told me it was upon Suspicion of Murder; while I was talking, one of the Headboroughs came with the Prisoner at the Bar; and, they said, This is the Woman that has done the Injury to the Man; I asked her whether she had struck the Man; she said, she had; said I, what did you strike him with? She said, with the Bar of the Grate: then, said I, with that you killed him, for the Man is dead; she clapped her Hands together, in this Manner, having a Child in her Arms, and said, God forbid, and sat herself down, and cried.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Collins made it her brags, that if she did not hang me, she would bring enough that should. -</p>

               <p>Collins. I never declared any thing to that Effect - I never mentioned it; I said, I could not tell what would be done to her, for to be sure she murdered him, and she deserves to be hanged.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She said she had murdered her Husband, and had got seven Pounds for it; and that, she would hang me, if she did not get a Farthing for it. The Deceased gave me thirty Strokes upon my Shoulders, Thighs, and Hips; it is very strange, that a strong Man should take any Thing from such an ailing Woman as I am; he called me a thieving B - h; I said, I never did thieve any Thing in my Life; then he gave me several Blows, and I cried out, to awake these two Women, who were upon the Bed, 
               <persName id="t17430907-46-person448">
                  Sarah 
                  Stewart 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person448" type="surname" value="Stewart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person448" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person448" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and his Sister; his Sister got off the Bed; I was then all in a gore Blood, and he had tore my Cap off my Head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her with her Cap off or bloody?</p>
               <p>Collins. She had not a Drop of Blood upon her, but what came from him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Stewart awoke soon after, and said, Lord! what is the Matter with you; and, he said, bad Luck to you, you Gallows Thief, I will you to Death; and he gave me two Stroke with the Poker, and spit in my Face; I said, You will not serve me as you did the Woman you killed before; and I took the Poker to protect myself, and gave him a Stroke on the Head, but I did not think to kill him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by the Poker?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I took it out of his Hand, at the Time he spit in my Face, and called me thieving B - h.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17430907-46-person449">
                  Frances
                   Jones The
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person449" type="surname" value="Jones The"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person449" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Prisoner's Husband is my Brother; my Husband and I were coming by the Prisoner's Door about one o'Clock, and heard a Cry of Murder; I went in, and saw Obrian, the Deceased, his Sister (Collins) the Prisoner, and Mrs Stewart.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were 
               <persName id="t17430907-46-person450">
                  Catharine 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person450" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person450" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person450" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mrs Stewart?</p>
               <p>Jones. They were both upon the Bed; 
               <persName id="t17430907-46-person451">
                  Catharine 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17430907-46-person451" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person451" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-person451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was very much fuddled.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed between the Prisoner and the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Jones. The Prisoner said, the Man had murdered her; she had her Child in her Arms.</p>
               <p>Q. What Marks were there upon her?</p>
               <p>Jones. She was all over bloody, and could hardly take Breath with that I called him Villain; he called me a great many B - hes, and said, he would give me as much, if I spoke another Word; with that I took the Child, and came away.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to leave them under such Circumstances?</p>
               <p>Jones. Because my Husband would not let me stay; the Deceased being such a vile Fellow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any Marks of Violence upon Bryan ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Not a Mark in the World.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he complain of any Thing?</p>
               <p>Jones. Nothing at all - the Deceased two Days afterwards sent for the Prisoner, and desired to make it up, and said, he bore her no Malice, and would had her have drank with him, but she would not; Collins was there, at the same Time, and desired her not to bear Malice.</p>
               <p>Q. to Collins. Did not you see this Woman two Days after this?</p>
               <p>Collins. This Woman was not within the House all the Time that I lived there; all that she says is false; her Sister has not seen her these twelve Months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you before a Magistrate, to give an Account of this Affair?</p>
               <p>Collins's Examination taken by Justice Richards<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174309070027"></xptr> was read, and agreed with the Evidence she now gave.</p>
               <p>The Justice being asked, what Condition the Prisoner was in, when she was brought before him; the Justice said, he believed, she had twenty Scratches all over her Cheeks and Forehead.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The Deceased and his Sister went on Thursday Night to the Black Boy and Trumpet by the Ditch Side; and they being troublesome when they are in drink, they turned them out of the House; he said, he was followed by a Press Gang, and that they abused him very much; but that he did not mind his being beat, if he had not lost his Hat; and that was the Occasion of his Death.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that his being abused by the Press-Gang was the Occasion of his Death?</p>
               <p>Collins. There is nothing in it; I do not blame her, for endeavouring to save her Life - he was not abused by my Press Gang - I do not know any thing of his losing his Hat.</p>
               <p>Mrs Grant. The Tuesday Night he was at our House, and say there; I did not see him again till the Saturday Night; and then, I told him, I had not Conveniency for him; and gave him 2 d. to get him a Lodging; his Neck was swelled up even with his Chin, and if it had not been for his Voice, I should not have known him - he talked very reasonably.</p>
               <p>Q. to Collins. Where did you go to on Thursday Night, after you had been at the Alehouse?</p>
               <p>Collins. We parted at the End of the Lane; and, he said, he was going to his Lodging; I met him the next Morning, and between six and seven in the Evening; and then, he went to Mrs Johnson's, and lay there (she keeps a Lodging House) Mrs Grant was afraid he should die in her House, and so would not let him come there. <rs id="t17430907-46-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-verdict239" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty, Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17430907-46-punish240" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-punish240" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17430907-46-punish240" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17430907-46-defend440 t17430907-46-punish240"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
