<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17400903-8">
               <interp inst="t17400903-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-8" type="year" value="1740"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17400903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17400903-8" type="date" value="17400903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17400903-8-off54-c75" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-defend86 t17400903-8-off54 t17400903-8-verdict59"></join>
         
               <p>371. 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-defend86" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-defend86" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-defend86" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-defend86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17400903-8-defloc53">St James's Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-defloc53" type="placeName" value="St James's Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-defloc53" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-defend86 t17400903-8-defloc53"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17400903-8-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver Tankard, val. 7 l.
            </rs> the Goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-victim88" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Minton 
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-victim88" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-victim88" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-victim88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-off54 t17400903-8-victim88"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17400903-8-cd55" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-off54 t17400903-8-cd55"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person89">
                  John 
                  Minton 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person89" type="surname" value="Minton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person89" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17400903-8-viclabel56" type="occupation">keep a Publick House</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-victim88 t17400903-8-viclabel56"></join> in <placeName id="t17400903-8-crimeloc57">St James's Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-crimeloc57" type="placeName" value="St James's Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17400903-8-crimeloc57" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-off54 t17400903-8-crimeloc57"></join>. On the 29th of July last, 2 Gentlemen came who were Customers to my House, and called for a Tankard of Beer, in a little Yard before the Door. I served them in a silver Tankard, and when they had drank the Liquor, they called for more; I filled it again, and the Prisoner (a <rs id="t17400903-8-deflabel58" type="occupation">Chairman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17400903-8-defend86 t17400903-8-deflabel58"></join>) using my House, being in the Yard, they asked him to drink. The Gentlemen went away, and left the Prisoner in the Yard; and in an Hour's Time I missed the Tankard. I was in a fright about it, and remembred that no body else had been at the House. By and by, (soon after this) in comes one of the Gentlemen who had drank out of the Tankard; I asked him if he knew any thing of it? He told me it was left with Harry Clark (the Prisoner) upon the Bench in the Yard. So the next Morning I went to the Prisoner's Lodgings, but he was gone out to work; then I went directly to the Pawnbrokers, and desired them to stop it if it should be offered. But hearing nothing of it, I went to the other Gentleman who had been in Company, and he likewise told me, the Tankard was left upon the Bench with Harry Clark. At 8 o'clock the next Morning the Prisoner came to Breakfast, and I asked him about it. He owned it was left with him, - but d - mn your Tankard, (said he) am I obliged to look after it? Do you think I have it? This made me dubious about taking him up; so I advertised it, and was in hopes it would be brought me for the Sake of the Reward. Four or 5 Days after I spake to him again, and told him, I would not expose him, but that I had reason to suspect him. He utterly denied all, and asked me what Business I had at his Lodgings without a Constable ? Why, Harry, says I, I only come to ask you about it, - I hope that every one who comes to ask for you, don't come with a Constable. After all the Enquiry I could make, I could hear nothing of it; so upon the 8th of August I got a Warrant, and took the Gentlemen and the Prisoner before Mr Justice De Veil , who clear'd them, and said he must commit the Prisoner. When the Prisoner heard this, he took me into the Yard, and asked me what I intended to do; and said, he hoped I would not send him to Prison, and declar'd to me that he had not the Tankard. I told Colonel De Veil that I missed him and the Tankard together, and that no soul came to the House, but these People, before I missed it. He desired me (if I could) to put off his Commitment for 2 or 3 days; I told him if he would let me have my Tankard again, I would beg he might be only sent to the Round-House. Then he wanted me to put it off for a Fortnight; and upon my telling him I could not do it, he said he would give me 2 Guineas down, and a Note of Hand for the rest; but upon my relating this Proposal to Colonel De Viel, he told me I must not accept of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person90">
                  Richard 
                  Woodyere 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person90" type="surname" value="Woodyere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person90" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17400903-8-person91">
                  William 
                  Tessbury 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person91" type="surname" value="Tessbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person91" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I went to the Prosecutor's House, and we had a Tankard filled twice, and asked the Prisoner to drink. When we came away, we left the Tankard upon the Bench in the Yard, at a little Distance from the Prisoner, and there was no one but he in the Yard. We did not speak to him to take care of it, for we imagined he would do it, as he drank Part of the Beer, and was one who constantly used the House. About an Hour afterwards I came back to Mr Minton's; he asked me about the Tankard, and I told him I set it down within 5 or 6 Foot from the Prisoner, upon the Bench.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person92">
                  William 
                  Tessbury 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person92" type="surname" value="Tessbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person92" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave exactly the same Account.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr Tessbury if it was left in my Possession?</p>
               <p>Tessbury. It was so far in his Possession, that it was on the Bench in the Yard, where he was sitting, and we thought, as he used the House, that it was left safe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person93">
                  James 
                  Tomes 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person93" type="surname" value="Tomes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person93" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 29th of July , in the Evening, I was call'd off with a Horse-Jobb to Clare-Market : when I went away with the Jobb, I left the Prisoner and the two last Witnesses, drinking out of a Tankard in the Yard. When I came back again, the two Men were gone, and there was no body in the Yard but the Prisoner. My Partner wanting to hang the Horse to a Nail over the Bench where the Prisoner sat; and it being above the Prisoner's Head, my Partner desired him to get up, that he might hang the Horse up. He<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174009030009"></xptr> made no Answer at all; so my Partner spoke to him a second Time, and then he only slid his Backside along the Bench, and leaned his Head on one Side, that we might reach to the Nail. I did not see the Tankard at all; but I heard him acknowledge at the Justice's, that the two Men left it with him, and he offered to pay for it in my Hearing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person94">
                  George 
                  Fewterel 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person94" type="surname" value="Fewterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person94" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , Tomes's Partner, gave the same Account.</p>
               <p>Defence. I own I used this Man's House, and that these two Men had been drinking that Evening in the Yard. I had been drinking myself, and came and laid my self down on the Bench, and these Men asked me to drink out of their Tankard. I drank most of the Beer myself, and gave the Tankard into one of their Hands; then I went to sleep again, and they went away without saying any Thing about the Tankard to me, and there was a Jew there, an ill-looking Rascal, as ever you saw in your Life, that sells Buckles and Studds about the Streets; and if any Man had the Tankard, I must think he had it. I am a Chairman in the Winter, and in the Summer I follow labouring Work, and am a Man that's never idle. At that Time I worked with a Man in Basinghall-street , and at 6 o'Clock I came to this Mr Minton's, and having got my Supper, went to my Lodging in Red-lion-street , about 9 o'Clock. On the Tuesday following, I met a Friend in the City, who told me Mr Minton suspected I had his Tankard, because I did not use his House as usual; therefore I went thither, and called for a Pint of Beer. Mr Minton then told me, he was uneasy about his Tankard, and asked me to go with him before Colonel De Veil to be examined, with these two Men. I told him, I would go Home and put on a clean Shirt, because I did not care to appear as a Bricklayer's Labourer, and that I would come to him in half an Hour. Accordingly I went Home, and cleaned myself, and returned to Mr Minton's ; but the two Men not being come, I waited for them, and at Length we all went before Colonel De Veil. Now if I had had the Tankard, I should hardly have gone with him before the Justice ; I had Time enough to have got off. - I am hired by the Week to carry Mr Copping Williams , and in a Morning I clean his Plate to the Value of some Thousands of Pounds, and I have had more Opportunity to steal his Plate, than this poor Man's Tankard. My Prosecutor is as honest a Man as any in the World, and would not take a false Oath, - but he is set upon it. My Character was never stained before, but now it is out of my Power to get my Bread in England.</p>
               <p>Woodyere. He says he was asleep while we were in the Yard; but he did not sleep, nor appear drowsy at all; but sat as upright as I am now. I believe too that he was not in Liquor: I take it that he was but just come from Work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17400903-8-person95">
                  Sarah 
                  Worthington 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person95" type="surname" value="Worthington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person95" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400903-8-person96">
                  Dorothy 
                  Newington 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person96" type="surname" value="Newington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person96" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17400903-8-person97">
                  Frances 
                  Brocket 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person97" type="surname" value="Brocket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person97" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               <persName id="t17400903-8-person98">
                  John 
                  Wintersham 
               <interp inst="t17400903-8-person98" type="surname" value="Wintersham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the Prisoner a good Character.</p>
               <p>The Prisoner desired Mr Minton might be asked, if he did not go before the Justice, without a Warrant. Mr Minton answered, that he desired the Prisoner to go before a Justice and clear his Character, and offered to pay him for half a Day's Work, because the Prisoner made Words about losing so much Time: upon which he agreed to go, and did so, before the Warrant was served upon him. <rs id="t17400903-8-verdict59" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17400903-8-verdict59" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
