<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17431012-34">
               <interp inst="t17431012-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-34" type="year" value="1743"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17431012"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17431012-34" type="date" value="17431012"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17431012-34-off158-c344" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-34-defend413 t17431012-34-off158 t17431012-34-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>499. 
               
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-defend413" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Newbold 
                  <interp inst="t17431012-34-defend413" type="surname" value="Newbold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-defend413" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-defend413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of London, <rs id="t17431012-34-deflabel157" type="occupation">Porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-34-defend413 t17431012-34-deflabel157"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17431012-34-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17431012-34-cd159" type="crimeDate">13th of June, and at other Days and Times since</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-34-off158 t17431012-34-cd159"></join>, in the <placeName id="t17431012-34-crimeloc160">Parish of St Brides</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Parish of St Brides"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-34-off158 t17431012-34-crimeloc160"></join> did keep a disorderly House, for Lucre and Profit, and for harbouring evil disposed Persons, and Persons of ill. Fame and dishonest Conversation, and for keeping such Company in his House, and suffering them to remain there drinking, scolding, fighting, and making great Noises and Clamours to the Nusance of all the Neighbours, the Breach of His Majesty's Peace, and Contempt of his Laws
            </rs> *.</p>
               <p> * 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person414">
                  William 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person414" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person414" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person415">
                  Arthur 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person415" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person415" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were sworn on the Jury for this Trial, in the Room of 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person416">
                  Joseph 
                  Stead 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person416" type="surname" value="Stead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person416" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person417">
                  William 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person417" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person417" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120048"></xptr>The Prisoner desired his Trial might be put off for some Time, his Witnesses not being come; but it being an Hour beyond the Time appointed for this Trial; and it being the only one left for this Jury to try, the Court was not disposed to give him any farther Indulgence; on Enquiry, there was no one appeared in behalf of the Prosecution. The Witnesses on the Back of the Indictment were three several Times called to come forth, and prosecute; and not answering, the Court was about to discharge the Prisoner; previous to which, however, Mr Recorder thought it requisite to set forth the ill Consequences of permitting such Houses, and to caution the Prisoner to behave better for the future: While he was speaking, Perkins appeared; and during his Examination, the other Witnesses came into Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person418">
                  Jonathan 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person418" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person418" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman belonging to the Court where the Prisoner did live - it is Love's-Court, in the Parish of St. Brides; he lived there about two Years and a Quarter; the House is shut up ++ now; I believe, his Wife left it last Week; he has been in Prison about six Weeks.</p>
               <p>++ It has since been opened: 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person419">
                  Thomas 
                  Paris 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person419" type="surname" value="Paris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person419" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Sarah, his Wife were on the 24th of October committed to Bridewell by Alderman Bernard, for keeping a Bawdy-House there. 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person420">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person420" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person420" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with several other Persons of ill Fame, were at the same Time taken up and committed.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a House did he keep?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He kept a very disorderly House.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he keep a Publick-House?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He sold Gin, and entertained all Sorts of bad Company; there were two Street Robbers tried last Week, that used his House, || Robert Stevens and 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person421">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person421" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person421" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>|| See p. 262. No. 481, 462.</p>
               <p>[The 5th of September was the Day the former Sessions began at Guildball, when the Indictment against the Prisoner was preferred. He was committed on the first of August.]</p>
               <p>Perkins. Stevens has used the House above a Twelvemonth; they both of them used the House all Hours of the Night, with disorderly Women; there were seven or eight disorderly Women used it; it was sometimes kept open till two or three o'Clock in the Morning; I have been many Times called off my Watch to go there; the very Night that he was taken up, I was called there.</p>
               <p>Q. What Company was in the House?</p>
               <p>Perkins. There were four Women, who are now in Bishopsgate Workhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an Account of what you saw there?</p>
               <p>Perkins. I was beating the Hour of One, and met the Constable, who was going there; we went into the House, and found-four Women and four Men; we turned the Men about their Business, but took the Women up.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they doing of?</p>
               <p>Perkins. They were all drinking in the same Room; one of the Men had lost his Handkerchief, and charged them with it; he said, he lost it since he came into the House; he was to have appeared here to Day, but he is not come.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in Liquor, or were they sober?</p>
               <p>Perkins. Some of them were in Liquor, and some were not</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask Newbold how he came to have such Company in his House, or how he came to entertain such People at that Time of Night?</p>
               <p>Perkins. I believe we did, but he made no Excuse then.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he doing of?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He was lying down on a Bench in the same Room, and pretended to be asleep; and when the Man complained that he was robbed of his Handkerchief, he did not take any Notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any Thing of the Women before?</p>
               <p>Perkins. I have known them these seven Years; they were common Women of the Town; they had used the House about a Twelve-month; I was called in there one Night; and they asked me if I would see a burning Shame, and one of the Women stuck a lighted Candle -</p>
               <p>Counc. Let us have no obscene Descriptions.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say for yourself?</p>
               <p>Newbold. He never saw any ill Company in my House in his Life.</p>
               <p>[
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person422">
                  John 
                  Welburne 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person422" type="surname" value="Welburne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person422" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             appeared, and was sworn.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person423">
                  John 
                  Welburne 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person423" type="surname" value="Welburne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person423" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Constable of the Ward of Farringdon.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Newbold, and where he lives?</p>
               <p>Welburne. Yes, he lives in Love's-Court.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a House does he keep?</p>
               <p>Welburne. He keeps a disorderly House.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of his keeping a disorderly House, between June and September?</p>
               <p>Welburne. I have gone my Rounds that way several Times, between June and September; I have called in between two and three in the Morning, and I never went in, but I found a Company of Women, and sometimes Men with them; and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120049"></xptr> have taken them up sometimes, and carried them to the Watch-house, and they have been committed to the Workhouse; I was going by one Day this Month, and there was a Man at the Door, who said, he had been robbed in the Prisoner's House; that he had picked up a Woman of the Town, or the Woman had picked him up, and that he had lost 18 d. and his Handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see in the House at that Time?</p>
               <p>Welburne. I did not go into the House then.</p>
               <p>The Court was informed, that the Prisoner was committed the first of August, so that nothing affected the Prisoner, with regard to this Indictment, but what was done, from the 13th of June to the 1st of August.</p>
               <p>Welburne. The Night the Prisoner was taken up, I went into his House between eleven and twelve at Night; and there was a Man in the House, who said, one of the Women had picked his Pocket of a Handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Man drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Welburne. He was suddled.</p>
               <p>Q. How many Women were there in the House?</p>
               <p>Welburne. There were four Women, and the Man, who said, his Pocket was picked.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the Prisoner doing?</p>
               <p>Welburne. He was swearing and cursing at a very great Rate.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after you were in the House, or before?</p>
               <p>Welburne. It was before I went in; I stood a little Time listening before the Door was opened, for I had a Mind to hear how they behaved - It is a little House, of one Room on a Floor, and it is shut up all Day long like a private House.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen these four Women in the House, between the 13th of June and the 31st of July?</p>
               <p>Welburne. Yes, I have seen the same Women there within those Times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I said to this young Man, that he speaks of, who was in Liquor, that I would have him go Home.</p>
               <p>Welburne. I heard him say to the young Man, he would have him go out, and not stay there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before you went into the House, or after?</p>
               <p>Welburne. It was after I went into the House; I did not hear him say so, while I was at the Door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in Bed, and there were three Constables, and three or four Watchmen.</p>
               <p>Welburne. We never go alone to these dangerous Houses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person424">
                  William 
                  Ballard 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person424" type="surname" value="Ballard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person424" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (a Watchman) said, that he had been sometimes called to go to Newbold's House, but could not speak to any Thing, from the 13th of June to the 31st of July.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person425">
                  Benjamin 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person425" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person425" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman of St Brides.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been at the Prisoner's House, between the 13th of June and the 31st of July?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I believe I cannot bring it within so narrow a Compass as that Time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the House the Night he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I was not at the Prisoner's House the Night he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before that was you in his House?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I was there within a Fortnight before.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of Company did you find there?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I found very indifferent Guests there, almost naked, and drunk, and several of them lying in Closets and Holes.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they Men or Women?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. There were some Men, and some Women; they were very ragged Creatures; and himself was in Bed then, with a black Eye.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any Noise in the House then?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. Yes, I did, or I had not gone in - they were damning their Eyes and Limbs, and swearing away in that black-guard Manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see these Women before?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I never saw them in the Streets, that I know off; they are not fit for the Streets, they are such poor ragged dismal Toads, and drunk; I believe they ply about George-Alley, and by the Ditch Side - I have been there several Times, and the Company used to be much of the same Nature, more or less.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person426">
                  Mary 
                  Levit 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person426" type="surname" value="Levit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person426" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person426" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17431012-34-person427">
                  James 
                  Newbold 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person427" type="surname" value="Newbold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person427" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I live at the Bell in George-Alley, just by the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sort of a House does he keep?</p>
               <p>Levit. He keeps a very disorderly House; when he was taken up, I was then brought to Bed, or I would have gone before the Alderman, to have complained of him - I have heard Company in the House all Hours of the Night, when we are awake - the House was continually disorderly, till the Time he was taken up - they used to make it a House of very bad Language, cursing and swearing, a great deal too much - sometimes till five or six in the Morning.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174310120050"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person428">
                  Catherine 
                  Dorrel 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person428" type="surname" value="Dorrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person428" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person428" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged in the last Witness's House, I have oftentimes heard Outcries in the Night, d - ng their Eyes, &amp;c. and one Night I saw the Prisoner beat two Men out of his House - between one and two in the Morning, - they were two elderly Men. - There are a great many Women that frequent the House; he beats his Wife, and beats the Women all round, and makes them all cry out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person429">
                  Edmund 
                  Sharrock 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person429" type="surname" value="Sharrock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person429" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In June and July I have often gone down the Court where the Prisoner lives, from ten o'Clock at Night till two or three in the Morning, and alway found disorderly People there, some up Stairs and some below; he has got a little By Place in the House, where the Men and Women resort to, - the Company is generally very drunk. - I know them to be common Women of the Town, because I have taken them up as such many a Time. - I have heard such Language that is not proper to be spoken, cursing, swearing, d - ng, and talking of Bawdy, and they frequently behaved in a very riotous Manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person430">
                  William 
                  Winter 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person430" type="surname" value="Winter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person430" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It is a Misfortune to me to live near the Place where the Prisoner lives.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of his Behaviour from the 13th of June to the 31st of July?</p>
               <p>Winter. I cannot speak as to any particular Time, but till the Time he went away; we had frequent Riots and Disturbances; I have heard him say himself, that he kept four Does in his House.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think he meant by the Word Does?</p>
               <p>Winter. Women of the Town, - Creatures who had scarce Rags to their Backs; I have heard Noises all Night long; I have heard too much cursing and swearing, and every thing that is obscene; I have it at my Door every Evening, as soon as it is dark; - the House is like a Hog-sty. They get drunk, and the Men and Women are like Hogs and Pigs lying together; the Place in general is very bad as well as his House.</p>
               <p>Newbold. I go to work at the Water-side, and the Watchmen used to call me up at three or four o'Clock in the Morning, to go to work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person431">
                  Mary 
                  Gilham 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person431" type="surname" value="Gilham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person431" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person431" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew any Thing of the Prisoner, but that he was an honest industrious Lad; - I live at St James's, a Mile and an half from him. - I do not know what he may do now, I never knew him to do so before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person432">
                  Jane 
                  Bradmore 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person432" type="surname" value="Bradmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person432" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person432" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew any Ill of the Prisoner in my Life, - I live at St Botolph Aldgate, - I work at my Needle, and make Waistcoats and Ticken Breeches; his Wife is my own Daughter; I have lain there sometimes. and I never saw any Thing of these Disorders.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lie there in June or July?</p>
               <p>Bradmore. No, I believe I did not.</p>
               <p>Perkins. This is his Wife's Mother, she used to attend the Customers, and serve them with Liquor.</p>
               <p>Bradmore. I never did in my Life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17431012-34-person433">
                  Edmund 
                  Sharrock 
               <interp inst="t17431012-34-person433" type="surname" value="Sharrock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person433" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Since the Prisoner has been in the Counter he told me, if he did not kill me somebody else should, for I should die in my Shoes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never gave him a misbehaved Word in my Life, nor an ill Word. <rs id="t17431012-34-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17431012-34-punish162" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17431012-34-punish162" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17431012-34-defend413 t17431012-34-punish162"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
