<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17440223-8">
               <interp inst="t17440223-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-8" type="year" value="1744"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17440223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17440223-8" type="date" value="17440223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17440223-8-off43-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-8-defend72 t17440223-8-off43 t17440223-8-verdict45"></join>
         
               <p>147. 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-8-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Durose 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-8-defend72" type="surname" value="Durose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-defend72" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , of <placeName id="t17440223-8-defloc42">St. Mary Colechurch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-8-defloc42" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Colechurch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17440223-8-defloc42" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-8-defend72 t17440223-8-defloc42"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17440223-8-off43" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-off43" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-off43" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pound of nutmegs, value 8 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17440223-8-victim74" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Oram 
                  <interp inst="t17440223-8-victim74" type="surname" value="Oram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-victim74" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-victim74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-8-off43 t17440223-8-victim74"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17440223-8-cd44" type="crimeDate">Jan. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17440223-8-off43 t17440223-8-cd44"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17440223-8-person75">
                  William 
                  Oram 
               <interp inst="t17440223-8-person75" type="surname" value="Oram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-person75" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of January in the evening, a Grocer in Fleet-street, asked me, if I had not been robbed, I said, I don't know, he told me, the Prisoner brought a pound of nutmegs to him, and offered to sell them for 18 d. that he told him, it was too little, and the Prisoner said, then give me two shillings; but he would not buy them. The next time the Prisoner came to my house, I challenged him with taking those nutmegs, and bid him bring them again; he protested he had not seen a nutmeg these twelve months; then said I, go out of my house (he is a chocolate-maker, and works for me) for you shall not work for me any more; he said, it was very hard that he must lose his work for a man's saying, that he carried him some nutmegs, and would not go; so<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="174402230005"></xptr> I took him by the collar, and told him I would charge a constable with him; then he begged my pardon, and said he had never done so before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess that he took them?</p>
               <p>Oram. He confessed that he took them out of the cellar in my house, and carried them to a shop in Holborn, somewhere by the Turnstile, and sold them for three shillings, but would not tell me to whom.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I found the nutmegs in the street, and did not know the value of them: I was in liquor, I do not know what I said then.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you found them in the street, what did you do with them?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I sold them to a man, but I don't know his house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss these nutmegs?</p>
               <p>Oram. No I did not miss them, there were 60 or 70 pound weight in a cask in the cellar, the key was left in the cellar-door, and, I suppose, he might go down for some beer, and then take them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any body to your character?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My master will give me a character.</p>
               <p>Oram. Before this thing I took him to be as honest a fellow as any in England, he made a thousand weight of chocolate for me last year, and was to have made a thousand more; he has worked for me five years: he offered to sell the person, to whom he offered the nutmegs, as much chocolate for half a crown a pound, as he would have. <rs id="t17440223-8-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17440223-8-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
