<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570526-13">
               <interp inst="t17570526-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-13" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-13" type="date" value="17570526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570526-13-off70-c112" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-13-defend134 t17570526-13-off70 t17570526-13-verdict72"></join>
         
               <p>226. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17570526-13-defend134" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  <rs id="t17570526-13-deflabel69" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-13-defend134 t17570526-13-deflabel69"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17570526-13-person135">
                        John
                          Williams
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person135" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570526-13-person135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570526-13-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-defend134" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-defend134" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-defend134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570526-13-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 4 l. and 12 d. in money number'd
            </rs>, the goods and money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570526-13-victim137" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Canvin 
                  <interp inst="t17570526-13-victim137" type="surname" value="Canvin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-victim137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-victim137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-13-off70 t17570526-13-victim137"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17570526-13-cd71" type="crimeDate">April 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-13-off70 t17570526-13-cd71"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-13-person138">
                  John 
                  Canvin 
               <interp inst="t17570526-13-person138" type="surname" value="Canvin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of April I was drinking in company pretty late, and when we broke up it was between twelve and one o'clock; I found myself a little in liquor, and did not much care to go home, as the woman of the house where I live was ill, and I did not chuse to disturb her; so I went away from the alehouse, and walked over London Bridge.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the alehouse you went from?</p>
               <p>Canvin. It is in White's Ground, Barnaby street, in Southwark. I went through best part of the city.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Canvin. I live in Southwark.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you go over the bridge?</p>
               <p>Canvin. I walked about to get sober. I walked till I came almost to Whitehall. I had my watch and some money about me. Then I thought I'd turn back again and go through the city, rather than go home over the New Bridge and St. George's Fields at that time of the night. Then I went up into Covent-Garden, and got into Drury-Lane, where I saw this woman at the bar and a companion of her's standing together; they both called to me, and said they wanted to speak with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that companion of her's a man or a woman?</p>
               <p>Canvin. It was a woman. I went over the way to them. The prisoner ask'd me if I'd give her any thing. I said, what shall I give you? She said a dram; there was no publick house open as I saw, so I gave her a penny to buy a dram; she brush'd up to me, and ask'd me if I had a mind to do with her, and what I would give her; I said nothing. I had not much occasion that way. Then she ask'd me if I would give her partner a dram; she said if I would I should have a touch with her. Then she put her hand between the waistband of my breeches and my body. Then I thought she had a mind to pick my watch out, so I put my hand to my watch, and my other hand to where my money was. Then she took hold of my hand and went to put it under her petticoats; while my hand was there I felt my watch go out of my fob.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen your watch before?</p>
               <p>Canvin. That very instant I had felt it in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was the other woman to you?</p>
               <p>Canvin. She was about a yard, or a yard and a half from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it possible for her to take your watch ?</p>
               <p>Canvin. No; she could not reach me to take it: Being conscious the prisoner took it, I challenged her with it, and desired her to give it to me again;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260012"></xptr> she denied it, and said she knew nothing of it; I said I would not lose my watch upon any account. She wish'd several bitter wishes about it. Then I said I would give any thing rather than lose it; she said, what will you give me, will you give me half a crown? I said, yes I would, and took out 2 s. and 6 d. Give it me she said. I said I would, if she would deliver me the watch. She said, she would have the money first, which I would not give her. I said, if she would let me see it, I would give her half the money. She would do nothing, except I would let her have the money first.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she produce it?</p>
               <p>Canvin. No, she did not; I held the money in my left-hand. She stood on the right-hand side of the passage where we were, and I open'd my hand, thinking the sight of the money would induce her to let me have the watch; she catch'd at it, and got a shilling out of my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the watch again?</p>
               <p>Canvin. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you got sober then?</p>
               <p>Canvin. I was a sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Canvin. I am a leather-dresser. There came a soldier up to the entry while I was contending with her, and with his help I got her to the constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she out of your sight in this time?</p>
               <p>Canvin. No, never till I got her to the Round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the other woman?</p>
               <p>Canvin. They both pushed me and intreated me to go into the house up the alley, but I would not. I found I could not keep them both, so I seiz'd the prisoner, and the other jump'd away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess any thing before the justice?</p>
               <p>Canvin. No, she did not; all she said was, I gave her the shilling to have to do with her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-13-person139">
                  Daniel 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17570526-13-person139" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person139" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by the end of the alley, and saw the prisoner and prosecutor pulling and hauling; I asked what was the matter; he told me she had got his watch. I saw him hold the money in his hand, and saw her snatch it out; I help'd to secure her. She carried the shilling in her hand to the constable's house, and in the Round-house she sent for a full pot of purl, to drink the prosecutor's health.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to prosecutor. Do you remember when you put your hand down my breast you said you would give me a shilling?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never put my hand there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This soldier Day is an old thief-catcher; he will swear any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-13-person140">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Basset 
               <interp inst="t17570526-13-person140" type="surname" value="Basset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person140" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the keeper of St. Giles's-Round-house. I remember the prisoner's being brought in there for stealing a watch. I strip'd her from top to bottom, and there was nothing about her; I really know nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no conversation with her?</p>
               <p>E. Basset. No, I had not; I strip'd her quite to her skin, skin and all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>There were other women with him, which he was picking up; I never saw his watch. I deal in Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-13-person141">
                  Mary 
                  Caly 
               <interp inst="t17570526-13-person141" type="surname" value="Caly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person141" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prosecutor, on St. Martin's side in Drury-Lane, with three or four women.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner one of them?</p>
               <p>M. Caly. No, she was not there at that time; but however, as I came out of the court I saw the prisoner and her husband having some words; he was in liquor. She came out. I asked her where I could get a little beer, and she directed me to a night house in Covent-Garden. I went and got a pint, and came back again; when I heard a noise made by this man about his watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prosecutor before?</p>
               <p>M. Caly. No, I never saw him since that time.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prosecutor dressed?</p>
               <p>M. Caly. I believe he was dressed in some white cloaths, not in these he has on now.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What cloaths had you on that night?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I had a darkish ash-colour'd surtout coat on.</p>
               <p>Two other women appear'd for her; one deposed she lived in Wild-street, and had known her twenty years, and never heard any thing amiss of her; the other had known her five years, and had bought old cloaths of her, and never knew any ill by her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570526-13-verdict72" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-verdict72" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570526-13-punish73" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-13-punish73" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-13-defend134 t17570526-13-punish73"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
