<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580405-24">
               <interp inst="t17580405-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-24" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-24" type="date" value="17580405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580405-24-off115-c139" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-24-defend179 t17580405-24-off115 t17580405-24-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>180. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-defend179" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17580405-24-defend179" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-defend179" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-defend179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580405-24-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver pepper-box, value 5 s. and one silver salt-seller, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-victim181" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17580405-24-victim181" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-victim181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-victim181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-24-off115 t17580405-24-victim181"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580405-24-cd116" type="crimeDate">March 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-24-off115 t17580405-24-cd116"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Elizabeth Stevens. My husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17580405-24-person182">
                  William 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person182" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person182" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner came to our house the 23d of March last, and my husband asked him to dine with us. After dinner I was obliged to go out of town about business, and left the pepper-box and salt in the place where they used to stand. The prisoner was in the house when I went out; when I returned, the pepper-box and salt-seller were missing; we suspected the prisoner, and went after him to Thisleworth, and they were found there at the Rose and Crown. I can say no farther than that they are my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person183">
                  James 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person183" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person183" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work for the prisoner's wife that afternoon; I went to a publick-house to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050011"></xptr> get a little drink, and stay'd there till eight o' clock; coming home by the prisoner's gates, we heard a great disturbance in the yard; we was asked to assist a person who was taking the prisoner to the Round-house. Going along the prisoner dropt this silver salt out of his pocket, and I took it up; (produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutrix) I gave it to a man, thinking the prisoner had robbed his wife, or some body of it. The next day, which was the 24th, I went to my labour as usual; when I came to his wife's house, she was gone, the house was shut up, and all business was stopt.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I have known him two or three years.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you worked for him?</p>
               <p>Arnold. Never before this time, and that not him; I worked for his wife; I looked upon her to be my pay-mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does she carry on?</p>
               <p>Arnold. She carries on that of a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not he capable of carrying on business?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I don't know whether he is or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be a man in his senses.</p>
               <p>Arnold. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person184">
                  William 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person184" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person184" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner on the 24th of March, about four in the afternoon, pull this pepper-box out of his pocket. (Produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutrix.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person185">
                  William 
                  Ewer 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person185" type="surname" value="Ewer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person185" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That evening 
               <persName id="t17580405-24-person186">
                  James 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person186" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person186" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I were going home from our labour, we were desired to assist in taking the prisoner to the Cage; the prisoner dropt the salt; Arnold took it up, and gave it me, and desired me to take care of it till the morrow. I kept it till the afternoon the next day, when I heard Mrs. Stevens had lost a silver salt and pepper-box; I gave it to her, and she gave me a shilling to drink.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the prisoner disturbing?</p>
               <p>Ewer. He was disturbing his wife, he wanted to get into the house, and she would not let him, and he had broke the windows.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he was in his senses?</p>
               <p>Ewer. I can't tell whether he was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would have broke his windows if he was in his senses?</p>
               <p>Ewer. He might be a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Stevens. What business is your husband?</p>
               <p>Stevens. My husband is a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your husband and the prisoner acquainted?</p>
               <p>Stevens. They have been acquainted a great many years, and on that account he asked him to dine.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be a man out of his senses.</p>
               <p>Stevens. I look upon him to be a madman really, but I had no acquaintance with him.</p>
               <p>Q. From what do you look upon him to be a madman?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He does not now appear to be in his senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think you do right in prosecuting a mad man for a felony?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I did not know him to be such before.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prisoner. How long have you been acquainted with this woman's husband?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have been acquainted with him five or six years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We are both butchers.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been married?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Almost ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you carry on business now?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have left off my business almost three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you live when you carried on business?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I kept a butcher's shop in Hungerford-market, but I have left it now.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live now?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I live at Thisleworth.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any children?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, we have no children.</p>
               <p>Q. By what means do you live now?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I carry on the gardening business. I purchased a bit of ground for that purpose, and that will maintain me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Stevens. Upon whose evidence was he committed?</p>
               <p>Stevens. It was on my evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your husband?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He is not here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person187">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person187" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable that had the prisoner in charge. I heard him own before the justice, that he took the pepper-box and salt from the prosecutor's house, and he would have signed his own confession, had not the justice told him it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050012"></xptr> would be evidence against him on his trial; then he begged to be excused.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mrs. Stevens charge him before the justice, and swear to the things?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing about his being mad?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person188">
                  Charles 
                  Webster 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person188" type="surname" value="Webster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person188" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about eight years; I always understood him to be a butcher, and that he bought the estate he lives in at Isleworth, at the purchase of four or five hundred pounds.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I gave four hundred and twenty pounds for it.</p>
               <p>Webster. For these two or three years past, I have thought he was a madman in all his actions.</p>
               <p>Q. I should be gled to know, during what period of time, he did any irational act?</p>
               <p>No answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you now swear that man is now out of his senses?</p>
               <p>Webster. I don't see that in him now as I have seen in him before; I have thought him mad for this two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Any particular sort of madness?</p>
               <p>Webster. Wildness.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you used to see him often?</p>
               <p>Webster. I have seen him, may be, once in two or three months.</p>
               <p>Q. For this two last years when you saw him, have you thought him mad?</p>
               <p>Webster. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to any time you saw him mad ?</p>
               <p>Webster. I think, more particular that morning he did this fact, he appeared very wild, and came to my house, was very troublesome, and would not take my answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you mention any other time?</p>
               <p>Webster. I have heard of his breaking his wife's windows, and disputes in the family, and from thence, I judged him very unhappy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person189">
                  John 
                  Alleson 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person189" type="surname" value="Alleson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Boar and Castle; his wife made complaint of him on the 25th of November, and put him into prison. I took him to my house till the 6th of January last. When he has dined at one o'clock, may be, by four, he has declared he has eat nothing for two or three days. He would catch up case knives and run after the servants. Sometimes I have lost my news-papers, once I found ten in his pockets; and sometimes I have found case knives in his pockets. There was a separation between his wife and him, and an agreement made; she was to allow him six shillings per week.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any writing drawn up?</p>
               <p>Alleson. There was; he has often said, while at my house, why did they lay him in that bed, he would lie in his own bed, and all this time he never lay out of his bed, he always lay in one bed; he would fly about, and behave very wild, and at other times he would sit down and cry for two or three hours together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person190">
                  John 
                  Sprigins 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person190" type="surname" value="Sprigins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was at the Boar and Castle, I looked upon him to be out of his senses. Sometimes he would appear very sensible, and at other times quite out of the way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person191">
                  William 
                  Walton 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person191" type="surname" value="Walton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person191" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Watford, and have known the prisoner thirty years; I have observed a visible alteration in his behaviour; I bailed him out of New Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he put there for?</p>
               <p>Walton. For assaulting his wife in November, he came out there before Christmas, and I carried him to the Boar and Castle; there he was very troublesome, and disturbed the customers, so that I was desired to take him away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take him to be in or out of his senses?</p>
               <p>Walton. I take him not to be in his senses. At that time they did not execute the writings, thinking him not capable to sign.</p>
               <p>Q. Are they executed since?</p>
               <p>Walton. They are.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they executed?</p>
               <p>Walton. I believe it to be about three weeks ago; he was bound to forfeit 200 l. if he ever went near her, and two or three days after he went and broke her windows.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you related to him?</p>
               <p>Walton. I am his brother-in-law. When I took him to the Boar and Castle, he would hallow out at the window at night, to know what o'clock it was. We have got him into bed, and in about an hour after he would be hallowing again. I believe he has not been in his senses this two or three years. He has been distressed for want of money, through the marriage settlement upon his wife two or three years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-24-person192">
                  John 
                  Dagnall 
               <interp inst="t17580405-24-person192" type="surname" value="Dagnall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person192" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a meal-man, and lived at Watford-mills. I have known the prisoner thirteen<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050013"></xptr> or fourteen years, he has been out of his senses two or three years, he may answer questions well for two or three hours; yet I know he is mad now.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect any question he has answered in court, that discover him not to be in his senses? I suppose you, as well as the gentlemen of the jury, know for what reason they were asked him?</p>
               <p>Dagnell. He has answered every question well.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you found your opinion upon, that this moment he is mad?</p>
               <p>Dagnell. I don't say now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say he is mad now?</p>
               <p>Dagnell. He has been out of his senses two or three years, so he cannot be in them now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Stevens. Did you dine with the prisoner at your house?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Stevens. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing pass there, that shewed him not in his senses?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Stevens. There was nothing passed, only eating and away. I don't remember a word he said.</p>
               <p>Q. How comes it that your husband is not here?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Stevens. He cannot swear to the marks of the things, and his business prevented his coming.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580405-24-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-24-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
