<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-3">
               <interp inst="t17540530-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-3" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-3" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-3-off9-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-3-defend40 t17540530-3-off9 t17540530-3-verdict12"></join>
         
               <p>307. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540530-3-defend40" type="defendantName">
                  Hannah, <rs id="t17540530-3-deflabel8" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-3-defend40 t17540530-3-deflabel8"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17540530-3-person41">
                        James 
                        Scelley 
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person41" type="surname" value="Scelley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-3-person41" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-3-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-defend40" type="surname" value="Scelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-defend40" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-defend40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted, <rs id="t17540530-3-off9" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-off9" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-off9" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17540530-3-person42">
                        John 
                        Evans 
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person42" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-3-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not yet taken, for that the latter did murder a person unknown, by cutting off his head, and the prisoner was aiding and assisting in the same. ++
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-3-person43">
                  Anthony 
                  Fonseccon 
               <interp inst="t17540530-3-person43" type="surname" value="Fonseccon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person43" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, and being on my stand, with my fellow watchman, in <placeName id="t17540530-3-crimeloc10">Half-Moon-Street, St. George's Hanover-Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-3-crimeloc10" type="placeName" value="Half-Moon-Street, St. George's Hanover-Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-3-crimeloc10" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-3-off9 t17540530-3-crimeloc10"></join>, on the <rs id="t17540530-3-cd11" type="crimeDate">first of May</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-3-off9 t17540530-3-cd11"></join>, somewhat better than half an hour after two in the morning, there came by the prisoner and one 
               <persName id="t17540530-3-person44">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17540530-3-person44" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (as she told us his name was): said Evans, You bitch, I'll make you remember keeping me out till this time of the morning; to which she replied, You vile rogue, this is always your way to use me in this manner. I observed the woman had a bundle in her arms, which she carried as if it was a child; I went up to her, took hold of her arm, and told her I must see what she had got; but she replied, Not you, you scoundrel. Upon this the man immediately took a pistol from the side of his coat, which flashed in the pan by the side of my cheek, but did not go off; then he dropt it and ran away. We took it up, and found it was loaded deep with swan shot. After this I took the bundle from her, and we took her and that to the watch-house. It was a sack, and in one corner of it was a white cloth all bloody; I unfolded it, and there was in it a man's arm, and the testacles of a man; and in the other corner of the sack was a man's head. We asked the woman a several questions, but she varied in her story. Last of all, she said a gentleman gave her sixpence to bring it from Kensington, and also that she had it of the man that got off, at the corner of a lane. We kept her all night, and the next day she said she had it from the Fox and Bell at Knightsbridgeand that a man gave her sixpence to bring it to Leicester-Fields. We took her before the vestrywhere she still continued to be in several stories, and said that her landlady sent her away with some bacon and greens to her husband, who was at work in the country; adding, that the man who got off overtook her, and gave her six-pence to bring this bundle. She said his name was 
               <persName id="t17540530-3-person45">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17540530-3-person45" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he lived in Monmouth-Court. The constable went there, and in the room where one Evans lived he found a child's hand, but the man was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner tell you her landlady's name?</p>
               <p>Fonseccoa. Yes, and she came and contradicted what she said of the bacon and greens.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-3-person46">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17540530-3-person46" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person46" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a watchman that night, and with the other witness at the time he mentions. He confirmed the account given by him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>One Mr. Saundersa surgeon, sent twice for 
               <persName id="t17540530-3-person47">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17540530-3-person47" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the last time he was at home; he went down to his house in Gerard-Street, and I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300004"></xptr> went with him. We went into an entry, and Mr. Saunders and he talked together; he asked him some questions, but it being high stile, I did not understand him. Mr. Evans said he would do it for him, and the other replied. I beg you will not disappoint me. Then he asked me to take a walk with him; we went almost as far as Parson's Green, where we had some beer and bread and cheese; he then sent me to the Fox at Knightsbridge, and he turned up a long lain. I staid about three quarters of an hour, and although he had nothing with him when he went, yet when he came back he brought that bundle, and after he had carried it a little way, he desired me to carry it to Leicester-Fieldsand said I should be satisfied for it. I never saw the bag open till I came to the roundhouse, or knew what was in it; nor do I know where Evans is now.</p>
               <p>The foreman of the Jury. Some of my brother jurymen were upon that vestry, and they were very well satisfied the head was taken out of a church-yard. The trunk was found afterwards.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540530-3-verdict12" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-3-verdict12" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
