<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-36">
               <interp inst="t17500912-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-36" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-36" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-36-off162-c206" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-36-defend277 t17500912-36-off162 t17500912-36-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>543. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-36-defend277" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Keys 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-36-defend277" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-defend277" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-defend277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17500912-36-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-36-victim279" type="victimName">
                           Catharine 
                           Selby 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-36-victim279" type="surname" value="Selby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-36-victim279" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-36-victim279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-36-off162 t17500912-36-victim279"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, one silk purse, value one penny, and two guineas in money, the property of the said Catharine, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-36-cd163" type="crimeDate">August 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-36-off162 t17500912-36-cd163"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-36-person280">
                  Catharine 
                  Selby 
               <interp inst="t17500912-36-person280" type="surname" value="Selby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person280" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of August, about six o'clock, as my mamma, I and my sister Elizabeth were coming to London in a coach, we were stopped <placeName id="t17500912-36-crimeloc164">between Brompton and the Blue Bell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-36-crimeloc164" type="placeName" value="between Brompton and the Blue Bell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-36-crimeloc164" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-36-off162 t17500912-36-crimeloc164"></join> by a single highway-man; he presented a pistol to us, and we gave him our money; I gave him my purse, I cannot tell the quantity of money in it; I can swear to two guineas, there were above that; my sister gave him some money likewise, then he rode off. I was very much surprised, I cannot say who the man was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-36-person281">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Selby 
               <interp inst="t17500912-36-person281" type="surname" value="Selby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person281" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sister to the other lady; I was in the coach at this time, we were stop'd between Brumpton and the Blue-Bell; the man presented a pistol, and ask'd us for our money; I gave him my purse, and I saw my sister give him her's, after that he rode away. I think the prisoner is like that man, but I will not swear to him.</p>
               <p>Henry Green. I was coachman to Mrs. Selby ; I was coming through Brumpton about six o'clock, or rather before, it was before sun set, on the 30th of August, I saw the prisoner on horse back; when I came within ten yards, pointing his pistol to me, he was sitting still, betwixt me and London; he stood till I came up to him, as I mov'd on, he said, if I did not stop he would blow my brains out; I stop'd immediately, he went up to the coach and demanded the ladies money and their watches. I saw the ladies give their purses out of the coach, then he ask'd them for their watches; I heard Miss Selby say, upon her honour she had left her watch at home. He pull'd a mask over his face a little way, but not till after he had demanded the ladies money. After this he rode off, but not fast, towards Brumpton; I am very certain the prisoner is the man. Last Saturday, about 11 or 12 o'clock, I was standing at my own door in Bow-street, Covent-Garden; the prisoner came by between two men on foot; I knew him, I follow'd him up the street considering what was best to be done; after I had followed him some way I laid hold of his arm, and said, sir. if you please I would speak with you; then I said, sir, you are the man that robb'd a coach between Brumpton and the Bell, and you must go along with me to the justice. I spoke to a man that stood at an apothecary's shop door to assist me; the prisoner told me he would go very quietly with me, and desired I would make no noise. We went imediately to justice Fielding's by ourselves, I told the justice's clark that was the man that had robb'd the coach, &amp;c. He told me I must fetch the ladies to swear to what they had been robb'd of; I fetched the footman, he was behind the coach, who as soon as he enter'd the room, said he would swear that was the man. There were no arms found upon him, he was then committed.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-36-person282">
                  Peter 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17500912-36-person282" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person282" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Esquire Selby's servant; I was behind the coach, the 30th of August, when my ladies were robb'd. He confirmed the testimony of the coachman, with this addition, that the prisoner said, your humble servant gentlemen and ladies, when he rode off towards Brampton, after he had committed the robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-36-person283">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17500912-36-person283" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person283" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the prisoner to Newgate, to assist Mortimore and Campbel, the two constables; the prisoner said his name was Keys, and that he lodged at one Esquire Westaby's, in North-Street, Red-Lion-Square ; I took a key out of his pocket, he said it belonged to his chest which was where he lodged. We all three of us went to the Esquire's house, there we found the house-keeper we ask'd her if Mr. Keys lodged there, she said she did ; we ask'd if there was not a trunk of his in the house, she said yes; then we told her he was committed to Newgate for a robbery, and we had got the key to search his trunk. She sent for the Esquire's kinsman, who was the prisoner's bedfellow; when he came they went and shew'd us the chest, we found in it a loaded pistol, a blacksilk mask, and two green purses; I carried them to the ladies and they did not own them. The pistol was produced in court.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The pistol is not offensive but defensive at the Esquire's house where I lodged, there has been attempts made to rob it, so I took the pistol into my custody, the young gentleman and I being bed-fellows, for fear of a surprize in the night; the mask I unfortunately found going home one night, I kick'd against it, I took it up, and when I got home I throw'd it into my chest.</p>
               <p>Deard Shefield and 
               <persName id="t17500912-36-person284">
                  Benjamin 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17500912-36-person284" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person284" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two master perriwig makers, with whom the prisoner had work'd journeywork, gave him a good character, for the time he work'd with them</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-36-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-36-punish166" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-36-punish166" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-36-defend277 t17500912-36-punish166"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
