<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530502-35">
               <interp inst="t17530502-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-35" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-35" type="date" value="17530502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530502-35-off186-c303" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-defend370 t17530502-35-off186 t17530502-35-verdict191"></join>
         
               <p>217. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17530502-35-defend370" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Birmingham 
               <interp inst="t17530502-35-defend370" type="surname" value="Birmingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-defend370" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17530502-35-off186" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-off186" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-off186" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530502-35-victim372" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Wheeler 
                        <interp inst="t17530502-35-victim372" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-35-victim372" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-35-victim372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-off186 t17530502-35-victim372"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17530502-35-viclabel187" type="occupation">infant between 9 and 10 years of age</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-victim372 t17530502-35-viclabel187"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17530502-35-cd188" type="crimeDate">March 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-off186 t17530502-35-cd188"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-35-person373">
                  Richard 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17530502-35-person373" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person373" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to Elizabeth: she is 9 years and four months old the fourteenth of October last, Old Stile. On Shrove-Tuesday the prisoner and I were drinking a pint of beer together, he desired I'd send him 6 d. till Saturday, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is he?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175305020028"></xptr>Wheeler. He is a <rs id="t17530502-35-deflabel189" type="occupation">weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-defend370 t17530502-35-deflabel189"></join>; my wife brought some victuals to the ale-house in <placeName id="t17530502-35-crimeloc190">Brick-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530502-35-crimeloc190" type="placeName" value="Brick-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530502-35-crimeloc190" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-35-off186 t17530502-35-crimeloc190"></join>, and we eat together ; my two children followed their mother to the ale-house; the prisoner took Elizabeth between his legs, and kept stroking of her face; my wife desired her to go home and light a candle, and told her she would follow her; the prisoner said he'd go with the child, and took her by the hand. I thought it was to help her over the kennel, they staid about three quarters of an hour before he came in again; my wife went over to them in about half an hour; but I sat in the alehouse till they came back; when he came, I asked him what made him stay so long; he said he had been with Betty, and she was lighting the fire; we staid together till about the hour of twelve, then we shook hands and pared ; I heard no complaint till nine days after; my wife then going to wash, she found the child's linnen spotted, she began to examine the child what that was upon her shift; after that I looked at the child ; and I sent for a midwife, the child is not well, but is now under the care of a surgeon, who is here to give an account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-35-person374">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17530502-35-person374" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person374" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; my husband and the prisoner were at the ale-house together last Shrove-Tuesday ; he bid me to bring him some victuals over ; I did, my two daughters came over to me, Elizabeth is the eldest ; I bid her go home and light a candle; the prisoner said I'll go with her, you may if you please said I, he had been stroking her face as she stood between his legs before they went, I thought they staid a great while, and I went over to them, and sound them both there, but had no room to suspect any thing then ; on the Thursday was a week after this, I found her linnen soul, it was slibbery like; I asked her whether she blow'd her nose on her shift; she said yes ; at night I examined the child, and found a running upon her; then she said if I would not let her be beat she would tell me; I told her she should not be beat, then she told me.</p>
               <p>Court. You must not say any thing the girl told you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-35-person375">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17530502-35-person375" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person375" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person375" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the younger. My mother bid me go over the way and light a fire; I went, the prisoner went with me; I laid down the bellows, and was stooping to take up the cynders, he took me by the leg, and throw'd me on the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What bed?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. My mother's bed in the same room; he bid me not tell my mother, and I said I would; but when my mother was coming, he said if I told her or my daddy, they would kill me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do to you when he slung you down on the bed?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. He took down his breeches and took out his cockey, and put it to mine; when I cryed out he bid me hold my tongue.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. He did</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing in you?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ill presently after?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you walk about the next day, and do your business as usual?</p>
               <p>E. Wheeler. I did, my mother came to find it out by chance, or I would not have said any thing about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-35-person376">
                  Robert 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17530502-35-person376" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person376" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The child's friends brought her to the London hospital, about five or six weeks ago she was examined by Mr. Hambleton, and Mr. Grindal ; I was by at the time; they both declared she had the foul disease.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion ?</p>
               <p>Bristow. My opinion is the same, that it is a clap.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any thing of violence being used ?</p>
               <p>Bristow. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she been penetrated ?</p>
               <p>Bristow. I believe she had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Could she have that distemper without penetration.</p>
               <p>Bristow. Such an injury cannot be committed without a contract.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530502-35-verdict191" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-35-verdict191" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>But detained to be tried, for assaultin g with an intent to commit a rape, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
