<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-47">
               <interp inst="t17510116-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-47" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-47" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-47-off221-c340" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-47-defend429 t17510116-47-off221 t17510116-47-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>152. 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-47-defend429" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Lloyd 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-47-defend429" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-defend429" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-defend429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510116-47-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 2 l. 2 s. the property of Thomas Cureton, in the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-47-victim431" type="victimName">
                           John Luke 
                           Landon 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-47-victim431" type="surname" value="Landon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-47-victim431" type="given" value="John Luke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-47-victim431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-47-off221 t17510116-47-victim431"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  
               
                  </rs>. <rs id="t17510116-47-cd222" type="crimeDate">Dec. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-47-off221 t17510116-47-cd222"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-47-person432">
                  Thomas 
                  Cureton 
               <interp inst="t17510116-47-person432" type="surname" value="Cureton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person432" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of Dec. about eight at night, four men came to empty the necessary house; my master lives in <placeName id="t17510116-47-crimeloc223">White-lion-yard, Spittlefields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-47-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="White-lion-yard, Spittlefields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-47-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-47-off221 t17510116-47-crimeloc223"></join>; I sat up; between 9 and 10 o'clock my master came to me, and bid me go to bed. I pulled my watch out of my pocket, and hung it upon a nail in the kitchen, and went to bed, expecting to be called up about one, but was not called up till five; then I went into the kitchen to see for my watch, and it was gone. I went and told the person who sat up with those men, it was gone, and he said he knew who must have it; he went to the master's house of those men. We got a constable and searched, and found the watch in the hay-loft, where the prisoner and the other three men were lying. The watch was produced in court, and deposed to, the prisoner did not own to the taking it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-47-person433">
                  Thomas 
                  Mumford 
               <interp inst="t17510116-47-person433" type="surname" value="Mumford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person433" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am fellow servant to the prosecutor. About 12 o'clock on the said night, my master and the others in the house went to bed, and left me to take care of these men. I was either in the kitchen, or with them all the time till about four in the morning, when they had done, at which time I had orders to give them some bread and cheese and small beer: The prisoner had been down in the vault, and he was so weak when he came out he could not stand; I gave him a dram of gin when he was washing himself; he fell down upon the stones with cold; he asked me, if I had any fire below? I told him, no: he then asked me, if he might make a little fire of hay or straw? I told him, no. I seeing him so very cold, let him go down into the kitchen, and I went with him. I had a fire there, but did not tell him so at first; I gave him some bread and cheese and small beer there; he pulled off his shoes and stood by the fire and warmed himself; the others had victuals and drink in another place. I once left the prisoner by himself there and went about ten yards; I was not absent above half a minute or a minute; then the prisoner came from the fire on his own accord, and in a few minutes after they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160025"></xptr> all went away. I thought nothing about the watch; I sat down about an hour, and then I went and called the prosecutor up, and went to bed myself; he went down, and in a few minutes came up again, and asked me after his watch, saying, he could not find it; said I, I am positive who must have it if it is gone, for none but the prisoner had been in the kitchen. I knowing where one of them lived, I went and told him the case, and he and I went together to the prisoner in the hay-loft, where were two or three along with him; the people were up in the stable with their horses; the man went up and said something to them, and came and called me; then I went up; I told the prisoner there was a watch gone, and he must have it; he seemed to be very far from owning it; I gave orders to two or three of the men to see he did not go away till I got a warrant and a constable; we returned and searched the hay-loft, and 
               <persName id="t17510116-47-person434">
                  Jonathan 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17510116-47-person434" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person434" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             found the watch, so we took the prisoner and had him committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-47-person435">
                  Jonathan 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17510116-47-person435" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person435" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up with the persons to search, and I found the watch between two trusses of hay, in Mr. Pocock's hay lost.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>There were five of us at work together in emptying the vault; I was in the vault when they went to eat bread and cheese; they went into the kitchen, and he was up stairs a quarter of an hour; and as soon as we had eat our bread and cheese, we went all home and lay in the hay-loft.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-47-person436">
                  Samuel 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17510116-47-person436" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person436" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years, he is a near relation of my wife's; he came up out of the country, and was some time with me. I never heard any thing ill of him before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-47-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-47-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
