<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590425-10">
               <interp inst="t17590425-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-10" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590425"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-10" type="date" value="17590425"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590425-10-off52-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-10-defend101 t17590425-10-off52 t17590425-10-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>154. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-defend101" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17590425-10-defend101" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-defend101" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-defend101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17590425-10-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the king's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590425-10-victim103" type="victimName">
                           Mathew 
                           Reay 
                        <interp inst="t17590425-10-victim103" type="surname" value="Reay"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590425-10-victim103" type="given" value="Mathew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590425-10-victim103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-10-off52 t17590425-10-victim103"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one guinea and seven shilling in money, numbered
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17590425-10-cd53" type="crimeDate">April 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-10-off52 t17590425-10-cd53"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Mathew Reay. On Monday the 9th of April about 7 in the evening, it might be five or six minutes after; I was going to Kentish-town from London, I observed the prisoner at the bar as I was going along in <placeName id="t17590425-10-crimeloc54">the second field from Totenham-court turnpike</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590425-10-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="the second field from Totenham-court turnpike"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590425-10-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-10-off52 t17590425-10-crimeloc54"></join>; I look'd upon him to be an honest labouring man, having no mistrust of any ill, did not defend myself against him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he going your way, or did you meet him?</p>
               <p>Reay. I met him: he was coming towards London, I bid him a good night, and the moment he past me he knock'd me down, and put his hand to my pocket; I said, I hope you will not kill me; he said, he would not strike me any more if I would not be any worse, it was my money he wanted; he ask'd me, if I had a watch; I said, no; he put his hand in my pocket and took out what money I had, which was a guinea in gold and some silver, between seven and ten shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you down when he took it out?</p>
               <p>Reay. I was: after that he went over the field; as I lay on the ground, I observed him to go to the hedge, and I believe he either went over it, or lay down in the ditch, there I lost sight of him, I did not follow him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner and be sure.</p>
               <p>Reay. I am very sure he is the man; after I recovered I got up upon my feet, and met a man that was going to Highgate, and told him what had happend; he took me back to the Adam and Eve, by Totenham-Court turnpike; I was hardly sensible when that man met with me; but after some time, being at the Adam and Eve, I came to my perfect senses, and desired to be bleeded; they sent for a surgeon, and I was bleeded.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any pursuit made after the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Reay. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250009"></xptr>Q. How came he to be taken up?</p>
               <p>Reay. I gave a description of him to every one that asked me about the affair, both at the Adam and Eve, and also when I went home to Kentish Town that evening, and the next morning; after which Mr Maplethorp and Mr Pantin sent for me to Mother-Red-Cap's, they having seen the prisoner go in there; when I came there, he was gone from thence over the fields towards London, in the way that he knocked me down; so we set out after him. They ask'd me if I thought he was the man; I said he look'd like him, but I could not tell 'till I saw his face; then I went up and spoke to the prisoner, and then said I was sure that was the man that knock'd me down and robb'd me; so we seized him, and brought him to the Adam and Eve.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was he walking when you took him.</p>
               <p>Reay. He was walking towards London.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him, when you say you spoke to him?</p>
               <p>Reay. I asked him if he did not frequent that road pretty often; he said, yes, sometimes. I said I had seen him about that place the last evening, near about that same place, and that he gave me a handsome salute with that stick he then had in his hand, or such another; the other gentleman were behind me, and we said hold of him directly; then I said to him, if you can clear yourself, now is your time to send for your friends, for I'll swear you are the man that robbed me; we staid at the Adam and Eve near two hours, then we took him before Justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your guinea and silver in one pocket?</p>
               <p>Reay. They were.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the person that robb'd you knock you down with?</p>
               <p>Reay. With a stick which he had in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before?</p>
               <p>Reay. No, not as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you apprehend you may mistake one man for another?</p>
               <p>Reay. I do not apprehend I have here.</p>
               <p>Q. You say it was in the second field beyond the turnpike, Which way did he go from you?</p>
               <p>Reay. He went into the corner of the field near the stile.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way is that towards?</p>
               <p>Reay. It is towards Marybone.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you always been certain as to the man, or have you ever mentioned it as matter of belief?</p>
               <p>Reay. No; never as matter of belief, I always said he was the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing found upon him?</p>
               <p>Reay. No, nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever confess it?</p>
               <p>Reay. No, never; he said I was mistaken, he was not the man, one man might be like another.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether he at that time did work over-against Mother-Red-Cap's?</p>
               <p>Reay. Yes, I believe he did; he told me so.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his business ?</p>
               <p>Reay. He is a Bricklayer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person104">
                  George 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person104" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person104" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On the tenth of this instant, April, I was sent for to the Adam and Eve, and was told there was the schoolmaster of Kentish Town had been robb'd, and the man was there. When I came there, Mr. Pantin said there is your prisoner, and there is the staff that I believe he knock'd Mr Reay down with when he robb'd him (producing a mop or hair-broom stick); this is it. I conducted the prisoner to the Justice's; he was committed, and I brought him to Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person105">
                  Thomas 
                  Pantin 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person105" type="surname" value="Pantin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person105" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I spent the Monday evening, being the ninth of this instant, with Mr Maplethorp, the curate of Kentish Town; the prosecutor's maid told me her master had been knock'd down and robb'd, coming to Kentish Town from London. Upon which I went up stairs to see him; he was in bed; I ask'd him how he did; he said his head ach'd a good deal; that he had had a good blow, having been knock'd down on the road. I ask'd him what kind of a man it was that knock'd him down; he described him to me with a loose<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250010"></xptr> white coat on, and an apron tuck'd round his middle; and that he look'd like a labouring bricklayer or a mason. The next morning he gave me the same account very punctually. That day, being the tenth, just before church, I went to Mr Maplethorp and told him what an accident Mr Reay had met with, and described the man, as he had described him to me, that had committed the fact. We went to church together; after which I went with him part of the way to town; he said he should be glad if I would come and meet him, when he came back, between five and six o'clock; accordingly, after business was over, I went to meet him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Pantin. I am a clergyman. I met him between five and six. This was on Tuesday the tenth. Just as I came upon the road, we saw each other; he beckon'd with his hand and ran towards me; when I came up to him, he said, here is a man that answers the description you gave me of the man that robb'd Mr Reay last night; I should be glad if you would step back and call him; the man is gone in at Mother-Red-Cap's, and I'll watch him. I ran back to Kentish Town, and told Mr Reay; he came with me. Mr Maplethorp told us the man was gone out of the house about five minutes; we made haste after him. Mr Maplethorp ask'd Mr Reay, as we came near him, if he thought that look'd like the man; he said he believed he did, but he should know that presently when he saw his face. When we came pretty near him, Mr Reay said I'll go and look in his face, and speak to him, and you will take notice what I say to him, and by that means you will secure him. Mr Reay told the man (which was the prisoner at the bar) he had met him the night before about that place. Mr Reay seized him by his right hand, and I seized the stick, and got it out of his hand; the same which the constable produced, Then we tied his arms back, and carried him back to the Adam and Eve. Mr Reay said positively that was the man, and he would swear to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Pantin. He said, he little thought of this. As soon as we laid hold of him I said I thought he little did. He said I am innocent; and persisted in it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How did Mr Reay describe the man as to his size?</p>
               <p>Pantin. He said he was a lusty man.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner; is he a lusty man?</p>
               <p>Pantin. Yes, he appears so to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he describe his features?</p>
               <p>Pantin. No.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the prisoner said, I little thought of this. If you or I, innocent of an offence, should be charg'd, do not you imagine we should make use of the same expression?</p>
               <p>Pantin. We might. I do not mean that by way of aggravation; the man all along persisted in his innocency.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person106">
                  John 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person106" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met Mr Reay going to Kentish Town on Monday the 9th of this instant April, in the bottom field; he was very much stunn'd and stagger'd a little.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you meet him?</p>
               <p>Edwards. It might be a little better than a quarter after seven o'clock. He said to me, if you are an honest man, I hope you will not hurt me, and told me what had happened. I asked him, if he would go with me to Kentish Town ? he said, he had rather go back to the Adam and Eve. He described the man that had robb'd him: that he had on a whitish frock, and was a tallish man, with his apron tuck'd round him. He was blooded at the Adam and Eve, and came pretty well to himself. After that I went back with him to Kentish Town.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was at work at the half-way houses for Mr Harding, on the 9th and 10th of this instant April, As I was going home to London on the 9th, being Monday night, I was got over all the fields, and met a woman that lives on the same estate that I had been at work upon. At about half an hour after six o'clock I got<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250011"></xptr> home to my landlady's. Soon after, my supper was not quite ready, I said to her, as my supper is not quite ready, I'll go to Mr. Hardings, which I did about seven o'clock. I returned to my landlady, and sat down to supper, and she fetch'd me some beer, and I never went out of the house that night afterwards.</p>
               <p>The Witnesses for the Prisoner were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hickey. I live on Mr Harding's estate, opposite to Mother-Red-Cap's, I take care of his house there. The prisoner is a Bricklayer, he used to work there; I remember his going away from our house that night that this robbery was committed. He went away about six o'clock, to the best of my knowledge, and at his going away he said, he believed he should have a very wet night of it (it rain'd then).</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him with a stick?</p>
               <p>Hickey. No, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this stick (that is the broomstick).</p>
               <p>Hickey. I know nothing of it. I saw no stick in his hand that night, when he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Hickey. I do not know. He went over the fields towards the Turnpike for London.</p>
               <p>Q. How does he dress?</p>
               <p>Hickey. Always like a labouring man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come to his work on the Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Hickey. He did at six in the morning. Then he work'd in the summer-house. On the Monday he was making of arches before the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any signs of suspicion in him on the Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Hickey. No, I did not, on the Thursday night following (the prisoner being then in prison), I met a man seemingly perfectly like him, when I was within three yards of him I thought it was this bricklayer got out of Newgate. It affrighted me a good deal. He had a stick in his hand about a yard long. He said to me, a good night, and I the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you then?</p>
               <p>Hickey. I was coming from Mr Whitfield's tabernacle.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner a diligent man?</p>
               <p>Hickey. He was a very diligent man. When he left work he generally went in at Mother-Red-Cap's for a pennyworth of beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person107">
                  Mary 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person107" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person107" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the half-way house going to Hampstead, in one of Mr Harding's houses. My mother keeps a chandler's shop there; I met the prisoner as he was going to London from his work, on Monday the 9th of this instant April, at about half an hour after six at night, as near as I can tell, just by Totenham-Court turnpike, that is in the fields joining to the turnpike beyond it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I was going home. I had been to London, near the New Church in the Strand, to carry home a nurse-child to Mrs Leeson a Haberdasher there; it was six o'clock when I left the New Church in the Strand; the clock struck just as I was coming away, so I guess I was about half an hour in coming there.</p>

               <p>Q. What time was it when you got home?</p>
               <p>Thomas. It wanted about ten or fifteen minutes of seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the clock strike?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No; but after I heard that the man was taken up, I knowing I had met him the night before, I asked Mrs King, a neighbour, what time I came home, and she said, she could tell the time, which she said was about that time.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after did you hear of the robbery?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I heard of it on the Tuesday, being the day after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner speak to you when you met him?</p>
               <p>Thomas. He asked me if I would turn back and drink with him; this was just by the Adam and Eve, where we met.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person108">
                  Mary 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person108" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person108" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Compton-street: the prisoner at the bar has lodged with me almost two years; he came home on Monday the 9th of this instant, at about three quarters after six o'clock at night, I was going to boil some bacon and greens for his supper; when he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250012"></xptr> came home I told him it was not quite ready; he said, can I go to Mr Harding's and fetch a pail and sieve by that time it is ready; he went and returned I believe a quarter after seven with the things; he eat his supper and never went out of the house after that night, I called him up next morning about five.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr Harding live?</p>
               <p>Lawrence. He lives in the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so exact as to the time?</p>
               <p>Lawrence. I can look out to the clock, and see what a clock it is at any time?</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say you looked at the clock that time?</p>
               <p>Lawrence. I looked at the clock at six o'clock that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the clock at seven?</p>
               <p>Lawrence. No, I could not, then it was candle-light, I heard it strike seven; he was then coming from the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person109">
                  William 
                  Boyde 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person109" type="surname" value="Boyde"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person109" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr Harding: the prisoner worked for him; the prisoner came for a pail and a riddle  much about seven o'clock, I can't say, but that it was a little after.</p>
               <p>
             A sieve with large holes in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your master live?</p>
               <p>Boyde. In the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>Q. What night was this?</p>
               <p>Boyde. It was the night before he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of weather was it?</p>
               <p>Boyde. It was a rainy night; it was darker at seven that night than it is at eight now, being cloudy and raining, my mistress desired me to go and give him the things, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you think it was that time?</p>
               <p>Boyde. I had been out, and coming by Covent-Garden the clock struck six, I told it; I made what haste I could, being wet to the skin; when I came home my mistress bid me go to the fire and put off my cloaths, and after that he came.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is Mr Harding?</p>
               <p>Boyde. He is a Cabinet-maker.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harding. I have an estate over against Mother-Red-Cap's: I have employed the prisoner there several times; he was at work there for me on the 9th and 10th of April instant.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave?</p>
               <p>Harding. He is a very constant worker when he is at work; that very Monday night he had finished a piece of work for me; I went down to him the next day, and left him working; he had told me on that Monday when I was there with him, that he would come to my house in London for a pail. I always looked upon him to be an industrious pains taking man; I have trusted him where I have had goods of value; I can't charge him with taking any thing; I always looked upon him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr Price. I used to employ the prisoner at the bar; I believe I employed him about eight months last summer, while there was business to be done our way.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave ?</p>
               <p>Price. Very well, industrious and honest: he never was drunk during the whole time to my knowledge, I looked upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr Wild. I have known the prisoner ten or twelve years; he has been an industrious man when he had work to do, he had not always work.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he an extravagant or frugal man?</p>
               <p>Wild. I never saw any extravagancy in him; he always bore a good character, that of a good-natured honest working man; and I really believe he deserves that character.</p>
               <p>Mr Watts. I live in Fetter-lane: I have known the prisoner thirty years; I never knew nor heard any harm of him in my life; I believe he deserves the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr Branson. I live at Hampstead: I have known him three years, he has worked for me twice, the first time about six months; he behaved exceeding well; I have trusted him in a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250013"></xptr> great many gentlemens houses; he has worked for me at my Lord Mansfield's; he was always very industrious, and always carried money in his pocket and paid his way; if he was clear of this affair, if he wanted a jobb, I would employ him.</p>
               <p>Mr Buckhurst. I have known the prisoner about three years: he worked for me about a year of that time; he was always very industrious, and never lost any time when he had business; I have trusted him in the best houses in Hampstead; I believe him to be as honest a man as any in the world; if he was discharged from this I would employ him to-morrow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person110">
                  Dorothy 
                  Fenton 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person110" type="surname" value="Fenton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person110" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged at my house three years; he never staid out a night in that time, and always behaved well and honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person111">
                  Christopher 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person111" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person111" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner upwards of three years; I live near where he lodged; he is a very industrious man whenever he has work to employ him; I believe him to be as honest a man as any in England; there is hardly a week but what I see him almost every day.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mackley. I have known the prisoner almost three years, and have employed him when he has been out of work in the winter-time to grind oatmeal for me; I have trusted him in my shop, and never had any suspicion of him; I believe him to be an honest man; was he out I would employ him to-morrow had I it to do.</p>
               <p>Mr Fisher. I have known the prisoner four or five years; he always behaved exceeding well; I never was more surprized in my life, than when I heard he was charged with this thing; I looked upon him to be a very honest man; was he discharged now I would employ him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-10-person112">
                  Thomas 
                  Blunt 
               <interp inst="t17590425-10-person112" type="surname" value="Blunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person112" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner four or five years; he always kept his hours and bore a good character; I believe him to be as honest a man as any in the Court; I do not think there can be an honester; I do not believe he would stop a child of twelve years old.</p>
               <p>Mr Hill. I have known him about seven years; he has always behaved well; I looked upon him to be an honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>Mr Crookshanks. I have known the prisoner five or six years; I have worked for him, and he for me; he has paid me very honestly, and was very industrious; I always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590425-10-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590425-10-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
