<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580405-28">
               <interp inst="t17580405-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-28" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-28" type="date" value="17580405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580405-28-off133-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-28-defend233 t17580405-28-off133 t17580405-28-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>184. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580405-28-defend233" type="defendantName">
                  Esther 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17580405-28-defend233" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-defend233" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-defend233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17580405-28-deflabel132" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-28-defend233 t17580405-28-deflabel132"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580405-28-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 7 s. and 6 d. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580405-28-victim235" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17580405-28-victim235" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-victim235" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-victim235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-28-off133 t17580405-28-victim235"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580405-28-cd134" type="crimeDate">March 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-28-off133 t17580405-28-cd134"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-28-person236">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580405-28-person236" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person236" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17580405-28-person237">
                  Edward 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580405-28-person237" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person237" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17580405-28-viclabel135" type="occupation">we keep a publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-28-victim235 t17580405-28-viclabel135"></join>. I have known the prisoner, I believe, four or five months, her brother and sister boarded at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge her with?</p>
               <p>Smith. While I was talking to a man, she keeps company with, who was with her at my house, she put her hand into my pocket apron, and took out 7 s. and 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober at the time?</p>
               <p>Smith. I was, but don't believe she was.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she took out 7 s.</p>
               <p>Smith. Mr. Torneck took it out of her hand, and we told it; there was 7 s. and 6 d. of it, all in silver. I had halfpence in my right side pocket, and silver in my left.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your husband at this time?</p>
               <p>Smith. He was at that time up in the club-room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-28-person238">
                  William 
                  Torneck 
               <interp inst="t17580405-28-person238" type="surname" value="Torneck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the prosecutrix and prisoner, standing on that side the box the prosecutrix was on. She was leaning over the table, talking with both her hands on the table; she presently said, what is this on my thigh? clap'd her hand down and seiz'd the prisoner's hand, and desired me to lay hold of her hand; I did, and pull'd it from under the prosecutrix's apron. I saw a six-pence, and desired the prisoner to open her hand, she would not; I put my fingers to my mouth and weted them, and strove to screw her hand open, and took out 7 s. and 6 d.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>That afternoon I had my fellow-servant come to see me; when my brother and sister came home to dinner, I call'd for two or three pots of beer. My friend stay'd till towards night with my sister and me; before he came down he said to me, in my sister's room, how do you do, have you spent your fortune? (I having broke my arm, was at my brother's lodging) he said, if you want a little money, I can assist you. I said it would be very acceptable, he made me a present of half a guinea, and treated us with a glass of rum; and when my brother came home from work, he treated him with a pot of beer, after that I sent down for one more; a little after that I came down stairs, and the landlady ask'd me what I would treat her with, I said any<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050018"></xptr> thing that she pleased; we had two pints of hot. She gave me change out of a shilling, when I pulled out my money, this gentleman said it was the landlady's money. I never had a farthing change out of it, the 7 s. was taken from me; he that made me a present of it has been in the country and is not return'd, or he would have been here. I never lived out of the city this fifteen years, and was never disguis'd in liquor in my life.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-28-person239">
                  John 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17580405-28-person239" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner sent for me to come to her when she was in New-prison, to write her a letter, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I keep a little private house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I am a mason.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ellis. She is a cook.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I have known her a year and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character ?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I never heard a bad one of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear a good one of her?</p>
               <p>Ellis. No; I never had but very little acquaintance with her.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. I knew the prisoner when she was cook at the crown tavern, Ludgate-hill, and at the Ax-inn, in Aldermanbury, and the Salutation in Newgate-street. She bore a most excellent character: if I wanted a servant to-morrow I'd take her, I have so good an opinion of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580405-28-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-28-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
