<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-1">
               <interp inst="t17550116-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-1" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-1" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-1-off1-c44" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-1-defend45 t17550116-1-off1 t17550116-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>44. (M. 1.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-1-defend45" type="defendantName">
                     Aaron 
                     Dring 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-1-defend45" type="surname" value="Dring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-defend45" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-defend45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550116-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550116-1-victim47" type="victimName">
                           Jeremiah 
                           Reuben 
                        <interp inst="t17550116-1-victim47" type="surname" value="Reuben"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-1-victim47" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-1-victim47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-1-off1 t17550116-1-victim47"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, and taking from his person 1 s. 6 d. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">Decemb 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-1-off1 t17550116-1-cd2"></join>. *</p> 
               <p>Jeremiah Reuben. On Sunday the 15th of December, I went from London to Barnet on foot, between two and three o'clock. I was between the 7 and 8 miles stone on <placeName id="t17550116-1-crimeloc3">Finchley-common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="Finchley-common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-1-off1 t17550116-1-crimeloc3"></join>, when I saw a soldier walking about half a mile before me. He made several halts till I came up with him; then he said, How do you do, brother-traveler? and asked me how far it was over the common. I said, About a mile, or mile and half. He walked with me about two stones throw. I asked him how far he was going He said, Only over this common. He asked me how far I was going? I said, To Barnet. He seeing the road was clear, took me by the arm, and said, I must have your money. I complained, and said, I was a poor traveler going about fifty or sixty miles, and had not much money. He said, If you don't make haste, I'll stick you, or cut you. Then I pulled out 1 s. 6 d. from my pocket, and some half-pence. He took the 1 s. 6 d. and left the half-pence.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a sword by his side?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. No. He put his hand to his pocket, when he said he would cut me. He turned down the common on the right-hand, and I went on. In about ten minutes I met two men on horseback, to whom I told of my being robbed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160003"></xptr>Q. Was the soldier then in sight?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. No, he was not. There came three men and overtook me in about a quarter of an hour afterwards. I told them of it: I went with them through Whetstone turnpike. There came a Man after me on horseback, and asked which of us had been robbed?</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after the robbery?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. It might be about three quarters of an hour after. The other men told him I had. Then I went back with that man to Brown's-wells; there I found the soldier, which I believe is the prisoner at the bar. He wanted to shake hands with me; but I did not care to do that. The people there said, he of his own accord had told them he had robbed me; and he said so, in my hearing, of several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe, or are you positive, the prisoner is the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. I can't swear positive; I believe he is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-1-person48">
                  Richard 
                  Nusham 
               <interp inst="t17550116-1-person48" type="surname" value="Nusham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person48" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Brown's-wells on Finchley-common; on the 15th of December, between two and three in the afternoon, I was sat down to dinner, some post-boys came from Barnet, and told me a man had been robbed, and that the robber was gone across the common. I, my son, and 
               <persName id="t17550116-1-person49">
                  Thomas 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17550116-1-person49" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person49" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , ran after him, and overtook him, which was the prisoner now at the bar, about half a mile from my house. The post-men rode before, and stopt him; we brought him to my house, and sent for a constable; the prosecutor was fetched back, and I thought the prisoner would have given him his 1 s. 6 d. back again. I heard him say he had robbed a man with a bundle under his arm of 1 s. 6 d. and said, he hoped they would not hang him; but he did not mind being transported.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he soldier's cloaths on then?</p>
               <p>R. Nusham. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did he give you your 1 s. 6 d. there?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a bundle under your arm, when you was robbed?</p>
               <p>J. Reuben. I had a bundle on my stick upon my shoulder.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was not the man that robbed him.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-1-person50">
                  John 
                  Collier 
               <interp inst="t17550116-1-person50" type="surname" value="Collier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner betwixt four and five years, which time he has belonged to the same company with me; he has behaved very well; I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-1-person51">
                  Thomas 
                  Thomson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-1-person51" type="surname" value="Thomson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner these twenty years; he and I were born at Norwich; I enlisted him into the regiment, since which time he has behaved exceeding well; he has been trusted in his quarters to draw beer; I never heard any complaint of him, neither did I ever hear any ill of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
