<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550226-12">
               <interp inst="t17550226-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-12" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-12" type="date" value="17550226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-12-off71-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-12-defend107 t17550226-12-off71 t17550226-12-verdict74"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-12-off71-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-12-defend109 t17550226-12-off71 t17550226-12-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>104, 105. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17550226-12-defend107" type="defendantName">
                  Jaques 
                  De Blancourt 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend107" type="surname" value="De Blancourt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend107" type="given" value="Jaques"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-12-defend109" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lashershang 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend109" type="surname" value="Lashershang"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-defend109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17550226-12-off71" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-off71" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-off71" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one metal watch, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550226-12-victim111" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Baily 
                        <interp inst="t17550226-12-victim111" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-12-victim111" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-12-victim111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-12-off71 t17550226-12-victim111"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said George, <rs id="t17550226-12-cd72" type="crimeDate">Jan. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-12-off71 t17550226-12-cd72"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-12-person112">
                  Martha 
                  Baily 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person112" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person112" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17550226-12-crimeloc73">St. Dunstan's-court, Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-12-crimeloc73" type="placeName" value="St. Dunstan's-court, Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-12-crimeloc73" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-12-off71 t17550226-12-crimeloc73"></join>, and take in washing for gentlemen, my husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17550226-12-person113">
                  George 
                  Baily 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person113" type="surname" value="Baily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person113" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of January last, a quarter before twelve at noon, the two prisoners came up the court; I called out at the window, and asked them what they wanted? I came down stairs, stept to the door, and asked what they would have? I thought they were reading the bill upon the gate, lodgings to let. Lashershang asked if I had a room to let? I said, yes, gentlemen, I have one up two pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. In what language did he speak to you? (He having an interpreter in court).</p>
               <p>M. Baily. In English. He said, can we look at it? I shut my parlour-door with my left-hand, it is near the foot of the stairs; I thought they both followed me: Lashershang followed me a little way up, about ten or twelve stairs; the other called him, and said, come along. I hearing him below, ran down by Lashershang, and found my room-door open, and the watch gone, which was hanging up in the room when I shut the door. I should not have known the other to be the man, but he owned he was with Lashershang, and Lashershang shewed us him when he was taken, When I missed the watch, I turned to Lashershang, and said; where is your friend ? he has robbed me. I left him in my passage, and ran out; and a neighbour was standing at the end of the court, who said there was a man ran by him; then we looked, but saw nobody running: then I went and took Lashershang by the collar, and took him into the public-house; there was a Frenchman that lodges in the court, I desired him to go and talk to him, for he would not speak English: he threw his cloaths about, to show he had not the watch. I said he had it not, but his companion had. We took him before my Lord-Mayor, and was told he was gone to Guild-hall; we came back, and in the Poultry the little man was taken, but I did not see him taken; they were both taken before my Lord-Mayor, and searched, but De Blancourt had been gone an hour and three-quarter: they found nothing of the watch. My Lord-Mayor talked French to them, and explained it to me; for I did not know what they said: I never found the watch again.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the parlour-door locked?</p>
               <p>M. Baily. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Lashershang speak English ?</p>
               <p>M. Baily. Yes, he did, and in the Hole-in-the-wall alehouse after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not you command the prospect of the door when you was on the stairs?</p>
               <p>M. Baily. No, I did not look behind me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it possible for a person to be got out of fight in that time?</p>
               <p>M. Baily. Yes; for when I saw my door open, I turned round, and said to Lashershang, who was on the second stair, or there-abouts, where is your friend? he has robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not said you had been up stairs for some minutes before?</p>
               <p>M. Baily. No, sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-12-person114">
                  William 
                  Acton 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person114" type="surname" value="Acton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person114" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter, and live in Flower-de-luce-court, Fleet-street; the day this watch was lost I was sent for to Mrs. Baily; I came into the Hole-in-the-wall, and saw Lashershang in custody; we took him in a coach to the Mansion-house; going by the Poultry-compter, came by the other prisoner; we were on foot then; this was as we came back from Guild-hall. Lashershang clapt his hand on the other's shoulder, and spoke French to him, and then lifted up his waistcoat, and clapt his hand to his pocket; the little man pushed off directly. There was another man in company with us; I said to him, certainly that is the man that was with him: I pushed after him, and catched him near the Royal-Exchange.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear Lashershang speak English at the Hole-in-the-wall ?</p>
               <p>Acton. No, I did not. I said to the man, when I came to him, your friend wants to speak with you. He said, me go. They desired to be heard in French, and my Lord spoke to them in French, and they both spoke French to him; I could not understand the prisoners; they were both committed. I was before my Lord-Mayor twice after that; they spoke French then; I know nothing that passed there but what my Lord-Mayor told me.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of them make any resistance ?</p>
               <p>Acton. When a prisoner is in safe hands, he may very well go easy.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by pushing away?</p>
               <p>Acton. When a man runs away, that is pushing hard, I think.</p>
               <p>Lashershang's defence.</p>
               <p>I met my companion in Hays's court on the 24th of January; we went together in order to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260009"></xptr> get a new lodging to lodge together; as one did understand the language, we could make shift to get one. In our walk we went to a chymist's, where there was a bill put up; but the lodging did not suit us. We proceeded, and went to where the prosecutrix lives; being there, the woman called to us out at the window, and asked us what we wanted? She came down stairs; I met her about four steps from the bottom, the door being open; I went up after her about half way up the second story, and asked if there were any more? She said, yes. I said it will not do. Then my companion called me down; when I came down I did not see my companion. After she had looked into the parlour she seized me, and went to the end of the alley, to ask if any body had seen the person. She met a man at the last door in the court, and asked him if he had seen a Frenchman go that way? He said, no. I remained with my arms across till her return; and when she came back I went into an alehouse, and was there a quarter of an hour, without knowing what she wanted with me. I said they might search me. They went for a constable, and took me in a coach to my Lord-Mayor. At my coming from my Lord-Mayor my companion came and asked where I had been? and said he had been looking for me. I said I was in the hands of a constable. He said he would go and seek for help for me. As I was going to apply for a friend, I made motion to let the people know that was my companion. They took us to my Lord-Mayor, and searched us, and found nothing but a little money upon us. After having been in prison seven days, my Lord-Mayor let me out to come upon my own recognizance, and now I appear.</p>
               <p>De Blancourt's defence.</p>
               <p>The reason why I went out of the court first was, because I was not within the house but staid without; being got into Fleet-street, I looked several ways for my companion, but could not see him; at last, when I met with him, I rebuked him for having hid himself. He said he was in the hands of the constable; I told him I would get a friend to help him; upon which I was going, and two men pursued me, and said, master! upon which I stopt, and asked them what they wanted? They said, a Frenchman, a friend of mine, wanted me. I said I was willing to go. Then I went back, and we were carried before my Lord-Mayor, and were examined apart in French and English, and what we said my Lord-Mayor was so kind as to give it them in English.</p>
               <p>De Blancourt called 
               <persName id="t17550226-12-person115">
                  Peter 
                  Cacoe 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person115" type="surname" value="Cacoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person115" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his wife, Mr. Brown, Joseph Nichiloe, 
               <persName id="t17550226-12-person116">
                  Charles 
                  Delsonce 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person116" type="surname" value="Delsonce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person116" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17550226-12-person117">
                  Mary 
                  Becket 
               <interp inst="t17550226-12-person117" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person117" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , all which gave him the character of a sober honest man.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17550226-12-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-12-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
