<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-32">
               <interp inst="t17551204-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-32" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-32" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-32-off173-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-32-defend336 t17551204-32-off173 t17551204-32-verdict177"></join>
         
               <p>39. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-defend336" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-32-defend336" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-defend336" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-defend336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17551204-32-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-32-victim338" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Osgood 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-32-victim338" type="surname" value="Osgood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-32-victim338" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-32-victim338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-32-off173 t17551204-32-victim338"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17551204-32-cd174" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-32-off173 t17551204-32-cd174"></join>. He likewise stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-person339">
                  William 
                  Dickson 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person339" type="surname" value="Dickson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person339" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of September, about four in the afternoon, 
               <persName id="t17551204-32-person340">
                  Thomas 
                  Osgood 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person340" type="surname" value="Osgood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person340" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was along with me and others at Mr. Gosler's hetcheling lost in <placeName id="t17551204-32-crimeloc175">Limehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-32-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Limehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-32-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-32-off173 t17551204-32-crimeloc175"></join>; the prisoner at the bar, who was <rs id="t17551204-32-deflabel176" type="occupation">foreman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-32-defend336 t17551204-32-deflabel176"></join>, was there. I saw the prisoner at the bar lay hold of the deceased and give him a push; and by the force of the push he tumbled him down, as he was about a foot within the lost; he then roll'd out, and fell to the ground. The room was about seven foot from the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the push in anger, or in play?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I can't say he was much in anger, but he was much in a passion, or he had never done it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion of his passion?</p>
               <p>Dickson. The reason was, so far as I heard, he desired some of them might go out of the lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased one of the workmen in the lost ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his business there ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I suppose he came to drink a pot of beer with his friends.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any blows or push happen between them, before he pushed him down ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I saw no anger, only that time.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them, when he fell ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I was within 4 or 5 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any angry expressions by Brown ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I heard him say the other had no business in the loft.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased sober, or fuddled ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. He was fuddled, or in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Would that push have flung any body down that was not in liquor ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. What I said I shall say no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing he had push'd you as hard, if you was sober, would that have flung you out of the lost?</p>
               <p>Dickson. He push'd him and he fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a place did he fall in?</p>
               <p>Dickson. A gravelly sort of a place. He said, Oh! Brown has hurt me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether Osgood died, or not?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I never saw him after he fell.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did Osgood come into the lost?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I can't tell to a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been there an hour or two?</p>
               <p>Dickson. No, not so long.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor when he came first?</p>
               <p>Dickson. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do the men go in and out where he fell?</p>
               <p>Dickson. What I have said I shall say no more.</p>
               <p>Court. Consider, you must tell the whole truth.</p>
               <p>Dickson. It is what they call a door.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any ladder there?</p>
               <p>Dickson. There are steps, or else they could not go up.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040033"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-person341">
                  William 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person341" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person341" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the loft at the same time, drinking a pot of beer with the deceased; there were five or six of us, and we drank three full pots. Mr. Brown, who is the foreman of the ground, bid us go away out of the loft. I said, I will go as soon as the last pot is out. He walked down and came up again, and said, I see you are not gone. Mr. Tuney said, If I was foreman, I would take and tumble those scoundrels out of the place. Then Brown came up in a violent passion, and gave the deceased a push; and he fell down flat on his face on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Osgood drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Williams. He was much about half drunk. Brown came in a violent passion and took hold of me next, and said, I'll turn you out after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Williams. I was as sober as I am this moment. I went down and helped to turn the deceased on his back; he could not speak for 5 or 6 minutes; he was blooded in about 8 minutes. I asked him how he was. At last he said, I am very weak, I can't move my head, legs or hands. He was put in a chair and carried home, and died in about 24 hours after the accident happen'd. His private parts were swelled as big as my two double fists.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased a man belonging to that shop ?</p>
               <p>Williams. No, he was not; he and I both work'd at captain Huddy's.</p>
               <p>Q. What business had you there?</p>
               <p>Williams. We went to see a workmate, and to drink with him. Mr. Tuney said to Mr. Brown, I believe you have been the death of the man. Mr. Brown said, he did not care if he had killed him, why did he not get out of the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the deceased for health before this fall?</p>
               <p>Williams. He was as hearty and well as I am at present.</p>
               <p>Q. If the man had been quite sober, would that push have flung him down?</p>
               <p>Williams. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been drinking in this loft ?</p>
               <p>Williams. I believe about an hour and a half, or two hours.</p>
               <p>Q. How many full pots of beer had you in the loft ?</p>
               <p>Williams. We had three amongst six of us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the prisoner at first desire you in a very civil way to go out of the loft?</p>
               <p>Williams. He came up in a violent passion first of all; but he desired us to go out of the loft, when he was below stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer was made by the deceased ?</p>
               <p>Williams. I made answer and said, As soon as the pot is out I'll go out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased make any answer ?</p>
               <p>Williams. I did not hear him make any.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-person342">
                  Thomas 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person342" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person342" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work for Mr. Brown, when these men came to see me. They asked me what I would give them. I said I would give them a pot of beer, and gave them one. When that was out, they asked me to give them another. I said they had been drinking, and I would not. Then I went up into the hemp loft; they follow'd me, and 
               <persName id="t17551204-32-person343">
                  William 
                  Dickson 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person343" type="surname" value="Dickson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person343" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave me a pot of beer; then John Higgs and 
               <persName id="t17551204-32-person344">
                  John 
                  Sandal 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person344" type="surname" value="Sandal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person344" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were another pot of beer. As the last pot was drinking, 
               <persName id="t17551204-32-person345">
                  John 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person345" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person345" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the deceased were wrestling together; Harrison flung him upon the hemp, and he got up and flung the other. Then Mr. Brown the foreman came and asked what that noise was. He was answered, They are playing the rogue. Then he desired them to go out; they said they would as soon as the pot was out. He said, If they did not go out directly he would come and turn them out; then he came and took hold of the deceased's skirts, to put him out, and by the scrambling he fell head over heels.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there steps where he fell?</p>
               <p>Roberts. There were steps to go out at.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it any more than turning them out because they made the men idle ?</p>
               <p>Roberts. That was all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he receive any hurt, when he fell upon the hemp, by the other's falling upon him?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, he fell clean out of his arms.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased in liquor?</p>
               <p>Roberts. He was pretty much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he fall down upon the pavement at once ?</p>
               <p>Robert. He fell half in and half out, and at last he fell out head over heels.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by scrambling ?</p>
               <p>Roberts. He scrambled to save himself from falling out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think, if the push had been given to a man that was sober, it would have pushed him out ?</p>
               <p>Roberts. I can't say it would.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was he from the door, when Brown gave him the push ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040034"></xptr>Roberts. Five or six foot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-person346">
                  John 
                  Spang 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person346" type="surname" value="Spang"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person346" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of September, between four and five o'clock in the afternoon, several people came running to me, and desired I would go to a man that had fell from this hemp loft. I went, and found the man lying on some small bundles of hemp. I examined his head, and found no fracture on his scull. Then I observed the other parts of his body, to see if he had received any injury from the fall. I found none. The deceased complained of a pain in his neck. I opened him. He was so intolerably in liquor that he (raising himself up) said He would bruise me too, not knowing me. I advised them to get the parish chair, and send him home to bed. I gave him diluting liquors, in order to carry off the effects of his drinking. The next morning I visited him again, and found his pulse high, rather from the quantity of liquor than the appearance of any accident. There was a great extension of the abdomen and erection of the penis, which was not caused by a bruise, but the heat of the blood. I apprehend the swelling of his belly and the other symptoms that he had were the effect of liquor, and not the consequence of a fall or bruise, there being no discharge by stool or urine. I used some method to reduce the penis, took an instrument to draw off some water, and ordered him some internal medicines. The people about him, as usual in such unhappy circumstances, were more in a hurry to do what they termed justice, than to give him relief in his disorder. I found they did not provide anything that I ordered, such as water-gruel, broth, and the like; but they rather kept giving him a little wine, under the notion of comforting him. The fever continued, and I visited him again at four in the afternoon, when I found his pulse falling; and he died that night about ten or eleven o'clock.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you search him after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Spang. No, I did not; as he lay in bed, I turn'd him, to see if there was any discharge by stool, when I saw a little extravasted blood or bruise on his loins.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the fall was the occasion of his death ?</p>
               <p>Spang. I do not think it could.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason the body was not opened?</p>
               <p>Spang. I never had application made to me for such a thing; neither do I apprehend, if it had, that it would have given the jury any knowledge of the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the body's being in a state of putrefaction the cause of its not being opened ?</p>
               <p>Spang. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, do you think he died of the bruises, or not?</p>
               <p>Spang. I do not think he did die of the bruises: that is my opinion, upon oath.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you look upon was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Spang. I look upon it, that it was a fever from his excessive drinking.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-32-person347">
                  Edw 
                  Wild 
               <interp inst="t17551204-32-person347" type="surname" value="Wild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person347" type="given" value="Edw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house; but I have cured many that have had white swellings, when they have been deemed incurable. I cure bruises also.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you cure more than you hurt?</p>
               <p>Wild. I do. I saw the deceased. I never went but once to him. I observed him swelled vastly. No bladder was ever blowed up more: his private parts were thicker than my arm. I said, What signifies bringing me here ? His head was very much bruised, and his neck, and so down to his loins. I said, I can give him a little ease: I can let him blood; but he is a dead man. I went home, and met one of the jurymen. He asked me where I had been: I said, I had been to bleed a dead man; for; if he is not dead, he will be dead before night, he being so internally bruised. I never saw a man so bruised in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it you saw him?</p>
               <p>Wild. I saw him about 11 o'clock, on the 17th. He was, from the crown of his head, to his loins, all down his back part, on his left side especially, to bruised, that I never saw any thing in my life like it, some part of his body being as black as my hat.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Wild. I do think, by his bruises, the fall was. I dare say his bladder was burst. I said, How did you get these bruises? It must be wilfully done. He said. The foreman, where he had worked, threw him out at the window. He talked of going to law. I said, You had better think of a future state; for you are a dead man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>About half an hour after 12 o'clock, those people were drinking below; when I came back, I found them drinking in the loft. I went away to the lower part of the ground. Coming back I heard some words: I said, This is not a drinking place; and desired them to come down. After that I went up, and took hold of the deceased's arm, and desired him to go down; he said, He</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040035"></xptr>would go down by and by. I said, If you must drink, then go to a publick house, this is not a place to drink in; and gave him a shove. I turned round to Mr. Williams, and said, I am surprised at your coming where you have no business; you stop all my men from work. What account can I give to my master? I never touched him; I was not within 9 feet of the deceased, when he fell from the lost.</p>
               <p>There were a great many witnesses to his character; but the court thought it needless to call them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-32-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-32-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
