<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-48">
               <interp inst="t17510116-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-48" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-48" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-48-off225-c347" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-48-defend438 t17510116-48-off225 t17510116-48-verdict228"></join>
         
               <p>153. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-48-defend438" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Davise 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-48-defend438" type="surname" value="Davise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-defend438" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-defend438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he <rs id="t17510116-48-off225" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-off225" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-off225" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-48-victim440" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Linter 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-48-victim440" type="surname" value="Linter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-48-victim440" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-48-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-48-off225 t17510116-48-victim440"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault; putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one hat and one perriwig, value 1 s. 6 d. and one piece of cloth call'd a cuff of a coat, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-48-cd226" type="crimeDate">Jan. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-48-off225 t17510116-48-cd226"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-48-person441">
                  Thomas 
                  Linter 
               <interp inst="t17510116-48-person441" type="surname" value="Linter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person441" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bell-alley, Goswell-street. On the 2d. of this month I had been along with one 
               <persName id="t17510116-48-person442">
                  Jane 
                  Easie 
               <interp inst="t17510116-48-person442" type="surname" value="Easie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person442" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person442" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to see after her husband; I went from the Red Bull in Long-lane to the Coach and Horses in Gray's-inn-lane Holborn, then to Field-lane, then to the Castle at the end of Chick-lane ; we had two pints of two-peny; coming from the Castle, the prisoner met us at <placeName id="t17510116-48-crimeloc227">the end of Black-boy-alley in Chick-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-48-crimeloc227" type="placeName" value="the end of Black-boy-alley in Chick-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-48-crimeloc227" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-48-off225 t17510116-48-crimeloc227"></join>; he came directly up to me, and said, d - n your blood, what do you do with my wife? Before I could make him an answer, he struck me with his fist a blow on the side of my face.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Linter. It was about 11 o'clock, my lord; then he struck me another blow under my ear, which fell'd me to the ground. I was striving to get up again, and with his left hand he took hold on the cuff of my coat and gave me another blow, tore off the cuff of my coat, and snatched off my hat and wig; he turned to the woman, and said, d - n you, you are but a woman, I'll not strike you, then he ran away; I cried as loud as I could; he was pursued and taken with the things upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he demand your money?</p>
               <p>Linter. No, my lord, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before?</p>
               <p>Linter. Not to my knowledge, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Linter. It was a very moonlight night, and there was a lamp over a door near us; I knew him directly when I went to the Compter to see him: there were about a dozen called to the door, and I knew him from the rest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-48-person443">
                  Jane 
                  Easie 
               <interp inst="t17510116-48-person443" type="surname" value="Easie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person443" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-person443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was looking for my husband, and coming home along with Mr. Linter about 11 o'clock at night up Chick-lane, the prisoner came to us, and said to Mr. Linter, d - n you, what do you do with my wife? Mr. Linter made answer and said, you scoundrel what is the matter with you; the prisoner knocked him down directly, I saw nothing in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Easie. I am sure, my lord, it was him. Mr. Linter got up again, and the prisoner knocked him down again, and took his hat and wig from his head, and tore off the cuff of his coat and ran away. I cried out stop thief, and murder! he turned round to me, and said, d - n you, I will not strike a woman. He ran away, then I saw Mr. Linter's face was all over bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Linter strike him?</p>
               <p>J. Easie. No, he did not, he fell down between two bulks.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner demand his money?</p>
               <p>J. Easie. I did not hear him demand any.</p>
               <p>Ahra Atterbury. On the 2d of this month, a little after eleven o'clock, I was going into Cow-lane, I heard a voice cry, stop thief; I saw the prisoner run by, and a person at some distance after<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160026"></xptr> him ; I saw nobody else. I immediately ran after the prisoner, and overtook him; just before I overtook him he turned his head about, and said d - n your eyes, I'll d o for you; I laid hold on him and secured him: then the person behind came up, and told me, he had stop'd him twice in Smithfield, and once endeavoured to take his stick out of his hand. I took him to the watch-house, and when the constable searched him, he found a hat, wig, a cuff of a coat, and a pair of buckles upon him; the prisoner said he bought the buckles in the New-market, but we inquired at the place he said, and found it was not so. The things produced in court, excepting the buckles, the prosecutor deposed to.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gillet. The prisoner was brought to the watch house, the 2d of this month, betwixt 11 and 12 at night; and charged with assaulting a man in Smithfield; he had a hat in his hand, and another on his head. I ordered him to be searched, we found this wig and cuff of a coat in his pocket, he was in a great many stories about the hat and wig. We had him before the alderman, and he was committed; we had the things advertized, and the prosecutor came and described the hat and wig, and cuff of the coat, before he saw them, the latter was compared with the coat and it agreed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 2d of this month about 2 at noon I left work in order to go to dinner, from my master's shop in Goswell-street, into the New-market to the sign of the Cooper's-arms ; I staid there the best part of the afternoon. Meeting with two or three young fellows, they inveigled me to stay there till 8 o'clock; after that I took a walk and bought a pair of buckles, and about half an hour after 9 I went up Field-lane; I went home, my master was gone out, I desired my mistress to let me have three halfpence; I went to the New-market again, and had a pint of beer; about this time it was a 11 o'clock; as I was coming up Field-lane, I saw two men going to fight; there were three or four other men there; one of the men came to me, and desired I would hold his hat and wig, saying he'd fight the other. I took hold of them, a mob arose, and the two men went to fighting; and after that, I saw no more of the one or the other. I walk'd up and down the lane for three quarters of an hour. I went into a publick house, and had a pot of beer, having three half-pence, I did not know of before in my pocket. After that I had a halfpennyworth of cheshire cheese to some bread I had in my pocket. Coming up the lane again to see if any body had ask'd for the hat and wig, to let them have it. I can bring people to-morrow to prove me an innocent fellow; I have a very good trade and have no occasion to be tempted to such things.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-48-verdict228" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-verdict228" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17510116-48-punish229" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-48-punish229" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-48-defend438 t17510116-48-punish229"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
