<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-23">
               <interp inst="t17551204-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-23" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-23" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-23-off122-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-23-defend205 t17551204-23-off122 t17551204-23-verdict125"></join>
         
               <p>28. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-23-defend205" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-23-defend205" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-defend205" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-defend205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-23-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     <persName id="t17551204-23-victim206" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17551204-23-victim206" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-23-off122 t17551204-23-victim206"></join>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. He likewise stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17551204-23-cd123" type="crimeDate">Nov. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-23-off122 t17551204-23-cd123"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Civil Tompson. I keep <placeName id="t17551204-23-crimeloc124">the Hat and Ton at Hatton wall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-23-crimeloc124" type="placeName" value="the Hat and Ton at Hatton wall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-23-crimeloc124" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-23-off122 t17551204-23-crimeloc124"></join>; the thing happened in my house; but I saw nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the Deceased?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I did. She was a bad temper'd, drunken woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the man?</p>
               <p>Tompson. A good temper'd man; he will drink sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether he was drunk or sober when the accident happened?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I believe he was sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-23-person207">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-23-person207" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person207" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not know the prisoner or deceased before. That night I and Yarbury lodged at the Hat and Tun. We came in at about nine o'clock, a fortnight ago yesterday; there were people dancing and merry. Presently came in a sidler; the deceased said I will give you a halfpenny if you will play me a tune; he play'd, she danced; after that there were two more women gave him a halfpenny each at last. The Fidler went out. The husband was sitting by (he seem'd to be angry with) his wife; and said she had more need to keep her money to buy some supper. She used many ill words, and said she would do what she pleased. They had more words, and she fell a beating him very much with her double fist about his head. He did not offer to resist; he held his hand up, and once said, I here I kept that blow off. She very much abused him with her tongue, and call'd for gin and beer. She seem'd to be pretty much in liquor. After that she sat down in a box, and he and she had a few ill words, especially from her. She seem'd to aggravate him very much. He asked for the key of his room door, to go home. She said you dog you shall not have it yet, I'll have some more beer before I go; then she call'd for half a pint of beer. He got up and struck her, while the boy was gone for the beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the blow fall ?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I think under the jaw; it was not very severe, but a pretty sharpish blow. She sat on her seat about half a minute, or hardly so long, and then drop'd with her face on the ground, and rowl'd on her back, and made a little noise in her throat, and died.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she drunk at that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040014"></xptr>Tompson. She was pretty full of liquor whilst I was in the house; which was about an hour. She drank gin two or three times; and she seem'd pretty full of liquor when came in. After she had laid some time-her husband came and looked at her; and they said she was very subject to his. They did not struck her dead at first.</p>
               <p>Q. Was is a blow with to much violence, that had she been sober it would have killed her ?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I don't think it would. I do not think he had a design to kill her, any more than I had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has not made any mistake; I can't ask him any thing more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-23-person208">
                  William 
                  Yarbury 
               <interp inst="t17551204-23-person208" type="surname" value="Yarbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person208" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present with the last witness at the Hat and Tun. There was the deceased merry, and in liquor. There came in a sidler; she insisted upon giving him a halfpenny, and she'd have a dance; the sidler play'd to her, and 2 other women joined with her in the dance; at last her husband came in and said she had better keep her money; she said you dog I'd do as I lease; and call'd him cagmag dog, and Welch dog, and struck him. After that she sat down in a box. Her husband had been out, and came in and said you have been drinking gin now; she said she'd have some more beer; he rose up and struck her; she rose up and pitch'd down on her face; he lifted her up, and call'd for some water, and said she is apt to be in fits; he put water on her face, and wiped her face; after some time we perceived she was dead; then they sent for the parish-officer and took him up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-23-person209">
                  Samuel 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17551204-23-person209" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person209" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. I was sent for by the coroner to inspect the body of the deceased. I found a bruise upon her forehead the breadth of half a crown. I cut through it, in order to see if the bone was fractured; there was no injury done to the bone. I likewise examined her jaw, but there was no injury there.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you think she came by her death?</p>
               <p>Chapman. The evidence seem'd not quite certain where the blow was given; and that she was greatly in liquor. The fall might contribute to her death, or the fall itself might occasion her death.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>She has been troubled with fits nine or ten years, and has fell in the streets, and been taken up for dead. Please to call Mrs. Tompson again.</p>
               <p>C. Tompson. She has had several sits. I have seen her in two. I believe her passion threw her into them. I know the man is a lab orious hard working man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-23-verdict125" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-23-verdict125" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
