<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-42">
               <interp inst="t17531024-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-42" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-42" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-42-off191-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-defend306 t17531024-42-off191 t17531024-42-verdict193"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-42-off194-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-defend306 t17531024-42-off194 t17531024-42-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>488. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-defend306" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Thompson 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-42-defend306" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-defend306" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-defend306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that he, <rs id="t17531024-42-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-42-victim308" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Leadbeater 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim308" type="surname" value="Leadbeater"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, five guineas, one half guinea, and fourteen shillings in money numbered, from the person, and against the will of the said John, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-42-cd192" type="crimeDate">August 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-off191 t17531024-42-cd192"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-off194 t17531024-42-cd192"></join>.* </p>
               <p>John Leadbeater. On the 18th of August I was going in a post-chaise to my own house at Barnes, in Surry, I intended to go as far towards home, as the chaise would carry me on this side the water, and about eight o'clock in the evening, in the lane leading to the water side from the Bohemia Head, I saw a person come up to the chaise, there was one Mr. Dell in the chaise with me, and said to the post-boy turn your head the other way, or I will blow your brains out, the chaise then stopt; he then put a pistol into the chaise, and said, give me all you have, or I will blow your brains out, or words to that effect; I gave him five guineas, half a guinea, and six or seven shillings in silver, which I put into his hand; he then demanded Mr. Dell's money, and while he was taking that I was striving to save some little trifle, which the prisoner observing, said, d - n you, don't<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240025"></xptr> trifle with me, for I will search you afterwards, and if you have any thing I'll blow your brains out. I then told him, I thought he had a pretty good booty, and might give us something back again; the prisoner then said, d - n you, I have dropped something, you may take that if you will, the post-boy then got down and found a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person309">
                  John 
                  Leadbeater 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person309" type="surname" value="Leadbeater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As it is in a case of life and death, I will not take upon me to swear that he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it so light that you could distinguish his Face ?</p>
               <p>Leadbeater. I could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person310">
                  James 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person310" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person310" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company and in the same chaise with Mr. Leadbeater, and was going to Kew, we were stopt in the lane that goes from the King of Bohemia's head to Cheswick, by a single highwayman, and I really believe the prisoner to be the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person311">
                  Joseph 
                  Nicoll 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person311" type="surname" value="Nicoll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person311" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the post-boy that drove the chaise when the gentlemen were robb'd, and am sure the prisoner is the man that did it; I had seen him many nights before, and once in a morning he rode round my chaise several times, but never stopt it before. I took particular notice of him the first night.</p>
               <p>Q. How light was it at the time the chaise was stopt ?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. A person might see to read very well at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. I am sure he is the man.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see the prisoner at any other time?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. The first time I saw him was at Hide-Park Corner, about a week before this robbery was committed, he rode overagainst the chaise for twenty yards together, and seemed to take great notice, and when we came just by the half way house to Kensington, he turn'd round and look'd into it: When I came to Kensington he asked me whose chaise it was, I bid him go look.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the chaise at this time?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. There was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he attempt to rob them?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in company with him?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. No, no further than seeing him at four different times before ride by my chaise.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence, but call'd the following witnesses.</p>
               <p>Mr. Moore. I live in the Strand, and have kept the house these nine years, I have known the prisoner near eight months, he work'd for one Mr. Brown, a printer, near St. Martin's-lane in the Strand; I was present when their boy came in on the 18th of August, about six in the evening, from the prisoner with his compliments and thanks to me for some tea and bread and butter my wife had sent him that afternoon ; he came home himself about nine o'clock, he lodged and boarded with me, and never was out of my sight, except when he was at work, and at sleeping time. I can give him the character of a very sober man, one that was never given to any extravagence, and one that always kept good hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him booted ?</p>
               <p>Moore. The most times I ever saw him booted was twice, and both times on a Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. to the post-boy. Did you ever see the prisoner about your chaise on a Sunday?</p>
               <p>Nicoll. No.</p>
               <p>Q. to Moore. Did the prisoner keep a horse ?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, he never did.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Moore. I have known the prisoner Thompson ever since the beginning of last April, he has lodged in our house ever since ; upon the 18th of August we had Mr. and Mrs. Kelly, and Mrs. Mercer drinking tea, the prisoner did not come home, so I sent him some; while we were drinking tea, Mr. Kelly said, when he had done, he would go to Westminster to look at a lodging, and that he would call at Mr. Brown's and take Mr. Thompson along with him. Mr. Kelly went, I desir'd him to make haste home to supper, and Mr. Thompson and Mr. Kelly came home together about nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner booted?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What dress was he in?</p>
               <p>Moore. He had on a brown coat, a light waistcoat, black breeches and stockings.</p>
               <p>Q How came you to remember the day?</p>
               <p>Moore. We was to have gone up the river that day, but it happening to be a wet day we could not go, so we appointed the next day, which was Sunday, and we were obliged to get a warrant to authorize the waterman to carry us, and here is the warrant (producing one) dated the 19th.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time the prisoner lodged at your house, how often did you see him booted?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240026"></xptr>Moore. Twice: he always behaved himself well, and during the time he boarded with us, he never was absent at supper time, unless we were all out together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person312">
                  Richard 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person312" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person312" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 18th of August, my wife and I, and Mrs. Mercer, drank tea at Mr. Moore's, about six o'clock in the evening, the prisoner was not there, but there was some tea sent by Mr. Moore's apprentice to him, I was going to Park-street, Westminster, to look at a lodging, so I said I would call upon Mr. Thompson, and take him with me, which I did, and then it was about half an hour after six o'clock; we went to one Mr. Cane's in Park-street, Westminster, and after we had seen the lodging we went into the Park, and into the Mall, where we met with Mrs. Moore of Maiden-lane, and her sister, we staid some time in the Mall, from thence we made it in our way to see the ladies home: we parted from them about nine o'clock, and we was at home by a quarter after nine; and from the time we went home the prisoner was never out of my sight that night till after eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Miss Cane. On the 18th of August, about seven in the evening, the prisoner and Mr. Kelly came to our house to enquire where he must go to look at the lodging; the prisoner was drest in a brown coat, black waistcoat and breeches, and black stockings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person313">
                  Mary 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person313" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person313" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person313" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 18th of August the prisoner came with Mr. Kelly to look at my lodging, and Mr. Kelly came and gave earnest for it on the 21st.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it they came to look at them ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person314">
                  Mary 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person314" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person314" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot be positive what time it was.</p>
               <p>Miss Simms. I remember Mr. Kelly's coming to my grandmother's to take lodgings, the prisoner at the bar was with him; it was on Saturday the 18th of August after dinner, but I don't know exactly the hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour cloaths had the prisoner on?</p>
               <p>Simms. A lightish brown coat and a silver laced hat.</p>
               <p>Miss Moore. On Saturday the 18th of August, I was in company with my sister in the park, there we met the prisoner in company with Mr. Kelly, at a little after seven in the evening, and parted with them at my own door at nine.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any boots on?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, he had the same dress on that he works in every day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person315">
                  Sarah 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person315" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person315" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Maiden-lane ; on the 18th of August, about seven o'clock in the evening, I was in company with my sister in the park, we met the prisoner and Mr Kelly together, they continued in our company till nine, and parted with us at our own door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-42-person316">
                  George 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17531024-42-person316" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person316" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work at Mr. Brown's the printer, where the prisoner work'd, the prisoner is a compositor, and did not work in the same room that I do: I cannot take upon me to swear whether he was there that day or not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mercer. I am clerk to a banker; on the 9th of June the prisoner at the bar delivered this letter to me, (producing one) which was read to this purport:</p>
               <p>London, Nov. 22.</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>Should the Bearer hereof have Occasion for 20 Pounds, please to supply him with that Sum.</p>
               <p>From your's, &amp;c. Richard and Thomas Dawson</p>
               <p>I asked him whether he would have the money or not, he took up five pounds, and on the 6th of August he took up five guineas more; so that when he was taken up there was nine pounds fifteen shillings he might have had for drawing for; and he had a further recommendation by Alderman Dawson, that I would have supplied him with five, ten, or more guineas.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-42-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for that he, <rs id="t17531024-42-off194" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-off194" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-off194" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-42-victim318" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Dell 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim318" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim318" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-42-victim318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one silver watch, val. 50 s. one steal seal, and four shillings in money numbered
            </rs>, the goods and money of the said James, <rs id="t17531024-42-cd195" type="crimeDate">Aug. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-off191 t17531024-42-cd195"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-42-off194 t17531024-42-cd195"></join>.</p>
               <p>This robbery being committed at the same time, and the same witnesses as in the former trial, he was <rs id="t17531024-42-verdict196" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-42-verdict196" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
