<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-11">
               <interp inst="t17570713-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-11" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-11" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-11-off51-c83" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-11-defend98 t17570713-11-off51 t17570713-11-verdict53"></join>
         
               <p>255. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-11-defend98" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Urlin 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-11-defend98" type="surname" value="Urlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-defend98" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-defend98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17570713-11-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570713-11-victim100" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Urlin 
                        <interp inst="t17570713-11-victim100" type="surname" value="Urlin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570713-11-victim100" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570713-11-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-11-off51 t17570713-11-victim100"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , his father
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570713-11-cd52" type="crimeDate">June 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-11-off51 t17570713-11-cd52"></join>. He likewise stood charged on the coroner's inquisition for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-11-person101">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17570713-11-person101" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person101" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the deceased and prisoner many years, they lived at Harmondsworth. The prisoner work'd by the day, at labouring work.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he do his work as other people?</p>
               <p>Taylor. When he had fits he could not work, he used to fall down in them. I was at the deceased's house (he kept a chandler's shop) on this day three weeks, when the prisoner and he were in the room together. He said Richard was not well, he having had fits for four or five days, but he hoped he'd go to work again soon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Not one word. He was sitting there. I went away and left them, and soon after that I heard he had kill'd his father; I saw his body in the coffin. I was on the jury, of the coroner's inquest.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He was kill'd; his skull was broke, and his face mash'd in a terrible manner; but who did it I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the state of his mind, did you ever know him to do any mischief?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. When he came out of his fits was he as other men?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Not very soon, sometimes not for two or three hours; but at other times he never was ready to answer questions as other men, nor sensible<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130013"></xptr> like other people; he'd say as others said to him, let it be what it would; he'd do things as often wrong as he would right. I never heard he attempted to be mischievous in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he ever had any quarrel with his father?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Never as I heard of; his father was very tender of him. He was a very honest sober man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-11-person102">
                  George 
                  Crips 
               <interp inst="t17570713-11-person102" type="surname" value="Crips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person102" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about fifteen years. Having heard the prisoner had kill'd his father, I saw him and ask'd him where his father was; he said he lay dead on the floor. I saw him lying dead. He push'd a pitchfork through the window at me. Then another man came up. He bar'd the door up so that we could not get in. We burst the door open. He push'd a pitchfork out at the door, and we took it away from him; then he said he had got another ready for us. After that we got on the backside of the house to another door, and broke that open; but he would not let us come in till we had stifled him with dirt. There were people enough to assist when we got upon him. After we had seiz'd him he said nothing at all. The deceased was lying with his brains beat out, and all the prisoner said was, he had kill'd Mr. Nobody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his father ever go by that name?</p>
               <p>Crips. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of any quarrel between this man and his father?</p>
               <p>Crips. No; they always agreed.</p>
               <p>Q. What temper of mind is he of?</p>
               <p>Crips. Not like another man in behaviour, better sometimes than other some. He was out of his mind sometimes in fits, and just as he got out of them.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time he had not fits was he reckoned a man of sense as other men?</p>
               <p>Crips. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-11-person103">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17570713-11-person103" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. When fits are off him, how is he for understanding?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Not like other men.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he of a mischievous disposition?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any quarrel between him and his father?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Taylor. His brains were lying on the floor; his head was cut all to pieces.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-11-verdict53" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-verdict53" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-11-verdict53" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               Acquitted. Accidental death 
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
