<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-6">
               <interp inst="t17520514-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-6" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-6" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-6-off25-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-6-defend43 t17520514-6-off25 t17520514-6-verdict28"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140005"></xptr>286. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-defend43" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Gwilliam 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-6-defend43" type="surname" value="Gwilliam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-defend43" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17520514-6-off25" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-off25" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-off25" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               ripping and stealing 100 lb. wt. of lead being part of a gutter fixed to the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17520514-6-victim44" type="victimName">
                        Squire 
                        Pew 
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-victim44" type="surname" value="Pew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-6-victim44" type="given" value="Squire"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-6-victim44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-6-off25 t17520514-6-victim44"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17520514-6-cd26" type="crimeDate">April 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-6-off25 t17520514-6-cd26"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person45">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Pew 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person45" type="surname" value="Pew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person45" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person45" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is Squire Pew, we live in the parish of <placeName id="t17520514-6-crimeloc27">St. Clements-Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-6-crimeloc27" type="placeName" value="St. Clements-Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-6-crimeloc27" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-6-off25 t17520514-6-crimeloc27"></join> : in the morning about three o'clock on the 25th of April I heard a noise like the falling of pantiles; I thought it was cats upon the place ; when we got up between seven and eight o'clock we found part of the house was stripped and some of the lead gutter taken away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person46">
                  Abraham 
                  Griffinhoofe 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person46" type="surname" value="Griffinhoofe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person46" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Pew: about three in the morning the 25th of April, I heard something ratiling ; I thought it was cats upon the house; we went upon the house between seven and eight and found some of the tyles were taken away belonging to a gutter, I went to the Carpenter that has the care of the houses, to come and get it repaired: he came and the bricklayer with him; we went up about three or four in the afternoon and measured it, as well as we could by the eye, it rained hard, that we was not very exact ; there appeared to be missing about six feet, and there were upwards of six feet left ; they concluded there could not be any thing done to it that day; we went up again about an hour afterwards and found the remainder of it was gone also; the prisoner lodged at the Fountain, which is the next house to it; I was told he was seen to go in at a window. We went to the house and met him at his room door with his key in his hand, all over mortar on his back ; we desired to go into his room, he would not deliver his key to us for some time, at last he did to Mr. Legier, he was then in the street ; I held him whilst Mr. Legier went up into his room and found the lead in a sack; then I went up, and we found the other piece under his bed, we put them together, it made four foot in length, and three in breadth, when together.</p>

               <p>Q. from the Prisoner They searched me and my room, did they find any instrument with which I cut it?</p>
               <p>Griffinhoofe. We found no knife or any thing to cut; the man of the house said, he had lost a hatchet or cleaver with which it might have been done, but we did not find it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person47">
                  Henry 
                  Legier 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person47" type="surname" value="Legier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person47" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Carpenter. The last evidence came to me in the morning, April the 25th, I did not go with him then; he came again in the afternoon, I then went and took the Bricklayer with me: we went upon the place and missed about six feet of lead, part of a putter ; as it rained hard we concluded to let it alone till the Monday, so they set some pans to catch the water; about an hour after he came and told me the rest was gone; there was about twelve foot of it in all; after this they set a person on the top of the house to see if he could see any body; he called out to us, and said, he saw a man go in at a window. We went to the house and the landlord went up with us and opened the garret door on the right-hand-side; then the prisoner was coming out of his own room on the left-hand-side, he was locking the door, we brought him down stairs into the street; there was a little boy, who said, he had seen him on the top of the house, the prisoner's cloaths seemed as if he had had some lead on his back, part of them were all mortar ; we asked him for the key of his room, he would not deliver it at first, at last he did; then we went up and found part of the lead in a sack behind his door; then we locked the door and came down and took him before the justice; after which we came to his room again, and found the other piece under his bed, we laid them together and they matched; one end of the lead was about 3 feet wide, the other about 2 feet 10, each between 5 and 6 feet in length, it tallied with the place on the house where taken from: we searched his room but found no instrument with which it was cut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person48">
                  Thomas 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person48" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person48" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Bricklayer. I was at the Trumpet in Shear-lane drinking, the landlord came down and said it rained in; (Mr. Pew lives the next door to it) I went up into the gutter and missed the lead, the gutter is betwixt that and Mr. Pew's house, I traced the foot-steps by broken tyles into the garret window, I afterwards went into that room, it belongs to the prisoner, that and the next to it in which the lead was found: they measured the place and the lead and they agreed, but I do not know how much the measure was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have lodged in that house a twelvemonth; I have another person lodges with me, he and I got up that morning and went down together and left the key in the door; I had been doing a little job for a master Bricklayer which I work for: I went up for a brush to brush my hat, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140006"></xptr> saw the door open, and brought the key down in my hand. I refused giving them the key till a proper officer was sent for, as my landlord had asked them by what authority they came: I was below at the time they say the fact was done.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person49">
                  Daniel 
                  Keen 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person49" type="surname" value="Keen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person49" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was below with the prisoner on that day, but I cannot say what part of the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home when the men came to search the house?</p>
               <p>Keen. I was, and went up stairs with them, and opened another garret door opposite to his apartment, he came out and locked his door, they laid hold on him; the other door was not locked that is next to it which goes out upon the leads on Mr. Pew's house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he lodged there?</p>
               <p>Keen. I believe on and off about twelve months; for the time he has been there I never knew him to be guilty of any thing of this sort.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his business?</p>
               <p>Keen. He has been a gentleman's servant, since that he has been a Bricklayer's labourer: when they took hold on him, I said, he is my lodger, I don't think he is such a person, but if you take proper means you shall see every thing, then I went to the prisoner and desired him to deliver the key.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person50">
                  Thomas 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person50" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person50" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lay at the last witness's house from the Thursday to the Monday se'nnight after; I lay there on this Saturday with the prisoner, we went to bed much about nine, and arose about five, I can't say I awak'd all night, I never missed the prisoner in the night.</p>
               <p>Q. to Keen. Was there any white on the prisoner's back?</p>
               <p>Keen. There was, according to what I saw, it might be mortar.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-6-person51">
                  John 
                  Starr 
               <interp inst="t17520514-6-person51" type="surname" value="Starr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person51" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five years, he served the late Colonel Warder, I never heard any thing against him, after he left him he went and lived with a Lady in Dover-street, the Colonel gave him a good character to her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-6-verdict28" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-6-verdict28" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
