<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501205-69">
               <interp inst="t17501205-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-69" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-69" type="date" value="17501205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501205-69-off345-c420" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-69-defend559 t17501205-69-off345 t17501205-69-verdict349"></join>
         
               <p>85. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-defend559" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Tombs 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-69-defend559" type="surname" value="Tombs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-defend559" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-defend559" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501205-69-off345" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-off345" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-off345" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one deal box, value 1 s. 5 linen shifts, 5 linen aprons, 8 check aprons one tea spoon, and other things
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-victim561" type="victimName">
                     Jane 
                     Hammond 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-69-victim561" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-victim561" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-victim561" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-69-off345 t17501205-69-victim561"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17501205-69-viclabel346" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-69-victim561 t17501205-69-viclabel346"></join>, <rs id="t17501205-69-cd347" type="crimeDate">Nov. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-69-off345 t17501205-69-cd347"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person562">
                  Jane 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person562" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person562" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person562" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17501205-69-crimeloc348">Fetter-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-69-crimeloc348" type="placeName" value="Fetter-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-69-crimeloc348" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-69-off345 t17501205-69-crimeloc348"></join>, on the 13th of Nov. about 7 o'clock at night, I employed 
               <persName id="t17501205-69-person563">
                  John 
                  Street 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person563" type="surname" value="Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person563" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person563" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to bring a trunk and box to Fetter-lane, from Doctors Commons; there were the things mentioned in the indictment in the box, he lost them and can give some farther account how.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person564">
                  Grace 
                  Fifield 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person564" type="surname" value="Fifield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person564" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person564" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down an Alley in Fetter-lane, right against Mr. Jackman's, Nov. 13. I saw the prisoner take a box up at Mr. Mason's door, next door to Mr. Jackman's, I saw the porter set it down, first upon the step of the door; there was a woman in a scarlet cloak helped the prisoner up with it on his shoulder, as soon as he had got it up he cross'd the kennel, I was just facing him; there were a man and a woman going up the Alley, he said to them have a care, let me come by; I had seen the prisoner at the bar before come out of a house with a creature there, and knew him well; there was a lamp over my head, and our light from our windows; I saw his cloaths, he had on, blew gray cloaths, a brown wigg, and no hat, blew gray stockings, and white flat rim'd buckles, he past by me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person565">
                  John 
                  Street 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person565" type="surname" value="Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person565" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent by the prosecutrix to Doctors Commons, to fetch this box and trunk, I set out from the Commons about a quarter before 6, coming up Fleet-street, there was a man overtook me about the middle of the street, he dropped his stick between my legs which had like to have flung me down; he took his stick up and beg'd my pardon; he ask'd me where I was going with that box and trunk, I said into Fetter-lane: he said I live in the Lane, tell me to whom you are going and I'll tell you the house. I said when I come into the lane I would look into the note; when I got into the lane I pull'd the note out, and said it was to Mr. Jackman's; when I came to the door on this side his house there was a man stood at it, it was shut; another man came to him and said, your servant Mr. Jackman, the man that answered to the name Jackman said to me, young man you have brought the things very right, they are my servant's things who is coming to live with me, adding you brought them from Doctors Commons. Then he ask'd me if he should help me down with them, he laid hold on the box I had under my arm, and I put the other down my self. Then he desired I'd go over the way to the Coffee-house, for his clerk, who he said had got the key; I said I had rather he'd go and I'd stand by the things, he said I had brought them very safe. So I went, and in the mean time the box and trunk were gone, and he also, and I have not heard of the things since.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the man you saw in Fleet-street, is the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Street. I do not know it is.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have witness to prove I was not near the lane all that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person566">
                  Ann 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person566" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person566" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person566" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Chancery-lane, the prisoner has been at sea, he was daily at my house, he was there about half an hour after 6 o'clock that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person567">
                  Thomas 
                  Figg 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person567" type="surname" value="Figg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person567" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person567" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house in Grays-Inn-lane, the prisoner was at my house that night at 7 o'clock, and parted about half an hour after ten; to my knowledge he was not absent all the time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-69-person568">
                  George 
                  Roberson 
               <interp inst="t17501205-69-person568" type="surname" value="Roberson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person568" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-person568" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner that night at a club; he was there about half an hour after 6, and went away near ten.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-69-verdict349" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-69-verdict349" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
