<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560528-32">
               <interp inst="t17560528-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-32" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560528"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-32" type="date" value="17560528"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560528-32-off159-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-defend277 t17560528-32-off159 t17560528-32-verdict163"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560528-32-off159-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-defend279 t17560528-32-off159 t17560528-32-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>213, 214. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-defend277" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend277" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend277" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560528-32-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Shilock 
                  <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend279" type="surname" value="Shilock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend279" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted , for <rs id="t17560528-32-off159" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-off159" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-off159" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that they, on the 13th of March, about the hour of 9 in the night, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560528-32-victim281" type="victimName">
                           Alice 
                           Jones 
                        <interp inst="t17560528-32-victim281" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560528-32-victim281" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560528-32-victim281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-off159 t17560528-32-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17560528-32-viclabel160" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-victim281 t17560528-32-viclabel160"></join>, did break and enter, and steal out thence 8 silk handkerchiefs, value 8 s.
            </rs> the goods of the said Alice. *</p> 
               <p>Alice Jones. <rs id="t17560528-32-viclabel161" type="occupation">I keep a slop shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-victim281 t17560528-32-viclabel161"></join> at the lower end of <placeName id="t17560528-32-crimeloc162">Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560528-32-crimeloc162" type="placeName" value="Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560528-32-crimeloc162" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-off159 t17560528-32-crimeloc162"></join>. My shop was rob'd of 8 silk handkerchiefs, but I knew not the persons till the prisoners were taken up. Shilock was brought to me by three officers, and told me he had rob'd my shop about a week before, along with some of his conforts. I asked him how he did it. He said he drew out a window shutter (shewing me how) then put in a hook at a broken glass, and took out 8 silk handkerchiefs in one piece, and sold them for 6 d. each. I went with them before the justice, where I heard his confession again, and saw him sign it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he broke the glass ?</p>
               <p>A. Jones. I believe the glass was broke before. The prisoner Watts was examined also; I heard him confess he was by when Shilock took the things out.</p>
               <p>James May. I, 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-person282">
                  Thomas 
                  Hale 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person282" type="surname" value="Hale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-person283">
                  Peter 
                  Churgen 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person283" type="surname" value="Churgen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person283" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , being all officers, had warrants for impressing disorderly<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175605280016"></xptr> men. On the 22d of March we went into Cable-Street. We did not see any houses of ill same open till we came to the last house of that sort; I made a stop at the door, and thought I heard somebody coming from the back room to the door, and the bolt and lock drawn back. A woman open'd the door and look'd out. I put in my staff, and she scream'd out. I saw a couple of lads in the room, who got up and ran to the left hand, open'd a door, and went in there. I went after them; where I found a necessary house, and a hole that a man might get into the vault. I put my staff down, then look'd, and found the 2 prisoners. I order'd them out, and they came up. I saw something look red, and got it up. They said, it did not belong to them. Then I ask'd the people of the house if it was theirs. They said, no. I secured them in the watch house, and carried the parcel with me. The next morning came justice Fielding's men, who had got a warrant for 6 men. They desir'd me to let them see the 2 lads we had got. One of them said, these are not the men we want, but they are 2 notorious thieves; let's take out the little one (which was Shilock) and examine him. We did so, and he would not confess for a long time. He said, if you don't confess and impeach Watts, he will impeach you, for he transported his wife, and had like to have done the same by his mother a little time ago. Then the prisoner said he stole the parcel, which were handkerchiefs, in Wapping, at Execution-Dock, and that there was another parcel in the place where he was taken, which the gentlemen did not see. Then I took him before justice Pell, and told his worship what the lad had inform'd me of. The justice desir'd us to go back, and see for the other parcel. We went, and Shilock with us. He went down into the place, and brought a parcel of handkerchiefs, 10 of them blue and white. We went to the justice's with them; then Shilock confessed he had been in company with the prisoner Watts about a month, and that they had committed several robberies, and had rob'd Mrs. Griffith's shop at Execution-Dock of 14 handkerchiefs. The justice desir'd we would take him with us, to shew us the shop. When we came there Mrs. Griffith was crying. We ask'd her what she had lost; she said some handkerchiefs. Shilock confessed also at the justice's that they rob'd Mrs. Jones. We took him there by his direction, and ask'd her if she had been rob'd. Her daughter told us they had lost a great many handkerchiefs some time ago. I ask'd if they had lost any within 8 or 10 days. She said no, at first. Then Mrs. Jones was call'd down, who said she had lost some handkerchiefs out of the window, or else they were sold. The boy said they stole a piece of 8 handkerchiefs. Then the daughter said she missed them, but her mother being ill she did not tell her of them, for fear of disturbing her. Then the boy shew'd us how he drew back the window shutter, putting in a hooked stick at a hole in the window. Then we took the boy to the justice again. Mrs. Jones went with us; there was also Mrs. Griffith. Then both the prisoners confessed the 2 robberies. The confession was taken in writing, and sign'd by the 2 prisoners and the justice. It was read in court, to the following purport:</p>
               <p>'' The voluntary confession of 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-person284">
                  William 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person284" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person284" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , '' taken before me, &amp;c. on the 24th of March, 1756. '' who faith, that about a month ago he got acquainted '' with Shilock at the Glass-house, and '' that last Saturday was three weeks they went together '' to a shop opposite Field-gate, White-chapel, '' and got out of the window two pieces of '' cheque, containing about 20 yards, by taking a '' crack'd piece of glass out of the window, which '' they had sold in Rag-fair; that from time to '' time they had daily gone together on London-Bridge, '' picking of pockets; and on Saturday '' the 13th instant, about 8 or 9 o'clock, they took '' out of a window in Whitechapel 7 silk handkerchiefs, '' that they sold some to Plump for 22 d, '' and others they sold to 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-person285">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person285" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person285" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Elizabeth '' Dolison; that on Thursday the 16th instant, '' about 8 o'clock, they went into Wapping, '' in company with one Arthur, and pull'd back a '' window shutter belonging to a shop near King '' Edward's stairs, and took out 8 silk handkerchiefs; '' that on Friday the 19th they committed another '' robbery, and on the 22d they committed that at '' Mrs. Griffith's. Sign'd by the mark of Watts''</p>
               <p>A memorandum was then read, wherein Shilock says, '' The above confession being read to me, I do '' acknowledge the several facts therein mention'd '' to be true, except that near the Field-gate, White-Chapel. '' Witness my hand (the mark of) James '' Shilock, March 24, 1756.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-32-person286">
                  Thomas 
                  Hale 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person286" type="surname" value="Hale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person286" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560528-32-person287">
                  Peter 
                  Oburgen 
               <interp inst="t17560528-32-person287" type="surname" value="Oburgen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person287" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirm'd the account given by their brother officers, and also seeing the confession taken, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Watts's defence. The constables took Shilock out of the watch-house and put a thing on his thumbs, which squeez'd them till the blood flew out of them, to make him confess; and they gave him liquor and made him fuddled, and then told him they wou'd bring somebody to swear his life away if he did not confess.</p>
               <p>Shilock's defence. They kept me above an hour with the thing on me, and ask'd me if I'd have some gin, but I refused it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175605280017"></xptr>The three constables being all ask'd if they used the method mention'd to extort a confession, all said that he never cry'd out, neither did they hurt him; that the thumb-screw did not continue on him above 10 minutes, for when they determin'd to stay with him, it was immediately taken off, and that they gave him but little liquor, and he was quite sober all the time.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560528-32-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560528-32-punish164" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560528-32-punish164" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-defend277 t17560528-32-punish164"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-32-defend279 t17560528-32-punish164"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[For Watts see the trial of Boswell, No. 73, in this Mayoralty.]</p>
            </div1>
