<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-1">
               <interp inst="t17581206-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-1" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-1" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-1-off1-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-1-defend30 t17581206-1-off1 t17581206-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>1. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-1-defend30" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Newton 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-1-defend30" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-defend30" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-defend30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 30 yards of callimanco, value 39 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                     Joshua 
                     Newson 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Newson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-victim32" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-victim32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-1-off1 t17581206-1-victim32"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581206-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">Nov. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-1-off1 t17581206-1-cd2"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-1-person33">
                  Joshua 
                  Newson 
               <interp inst="t17581206-1-person33" type="surname" value="Newson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person33" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17581206-1-viclabel3" type="occupation">weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-1-victim32 t17581206-1-viclabel3"></join>, the prisoner was my <rs id="t17581206-1-deflabel4" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-1-defend30 t17581206-1-deflabel4"></join>. I missed a piece of callimanco, and by looking I found it concealed: on the 6 of Nov. in the morning it was taken away. I had looked on it every day; then my father, to whom I had told the affair, took him into a room: my father tax'd him with it: he denied knowing any thing of it 2 or 3 times: this I heard. At last he said, if you please I'll go and fetch it, which he did, and said he hoped I would forgive him. (produced in court and deposed to ) Here is my name on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your father live with you?</p>
               <p>J. Newson. No: he lives next door to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-1-person34">
                  Thomas 
                  Newson 
               <interp inst="t17581206-1-person34" type="surname" value="Newson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person34" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to the prosecutor; my son came to me and told me he missed a piece. He, by hunting about, found it concealed. Then I said be sure you see it every day: when he missed it he told me, then I went and took the prisoner into a room, and tax'd him with it. He said take care of my character, I never was a thief. But at last, finding me resolute, he told me he would fetch it, which he did: this is it. The next day he said he would take his oath on the book, never to do so no more. We always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. Mrs. Curtain in White-Chapel, asked me, if we had any callimanco which was very good, I said yes. She desired me to bring it for her to look at it. I asked her what time I should bring it. On the Monday morning I had some yarn to be carried to be scowered at a Dyer's. I looked among the goods, and happened to find this piece. I took it and put it among the yarn, and carried it to show her. I left the yarn at the Dyer's, and carried the piece, but she was not at home; then I carried it to my own house; then I went out with two bills, and left one for acceptance, the other I took the money and brought it to my master, which was 10 l. Then my master's father took me into a room, and asked me what I had done with that piece of callimanco that I had taken away. I said I had carried it to my own house, and went and fetched it, and told my wife if the gentlewoman came, to tell<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060002"></xptr> her the price; and that I should be at dinner. After that, my master and I <note>[Text unreadable in original.]</note> the other end of the town, and din'd a pipe together. After which Lombard-street, where I acceptance for the m I went a the prisoner 18 en he was servant had the business his ut four days before the called upon usual, I been a customer to his master Richardson. asked me if I wanted any thing in his way. said if you have my callimanco of the best sort would see he said he had not, but would some as soon as he had. On the morning following, he brought a black piece of callimanco to my house as I was told, but I was not at home, then he left word he would ca it to his own house, and I might call there d see it. I went over and look'd at it, and asked the price, his wife said 2 s. per yard was the lowest price her husband's master would take. said I thought 22 d. was a good price. She said if you'll be so kind as to go to his master's house may be we might agree.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-1-person35">
                  Mary 
                  Curtain 
               <interp inst="t17581206-1-person35" type="surname" value="Curtain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person35" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-person35" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw him about 10 o'Clock on the Monday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you ever give the prisoner authority to take goods out to sell?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I have given him goods out to sell; but I never gave him authority to take them out without my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him this piece out to sell?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No: I did not. To be sure I confidence in him: I looked upon him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you have been angry at him, had he taken it out and sold it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I should not have liked it; I should have thought he was taking too much freedom.</p>
               <p>
                  <note>[Text unreadable in original.]</note>0 l. and 5 l. 5 s.? out to receive one for acceptance, but d this piece. It was n these bills I missed it, carried for acceptance, he to find the person when it was was the occasion I did not take him after he had been and received that, was on the Wednesday after I missed the piece.</p>
               <p>Q. How many days did it lie concealed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. To the best of my knowledge it was 5 or, that is, it was not in it's usual place.</p>
               <p>Q. Could this removal happen by accident?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No: it could not, it was designed.</p>
               <p>Mrs Richardson. The prisoner served me 11 years as my fore-man, when I carried on the trade as the prosecutor does: I have trusted him to carry out bills: he has received a hundred, or a hundred and 50 l. a month for me. I always found him a faithful servant: I very frequently trusted him to carry out goods to customers: I totally confided in him.</p>
               <p>Mr Smart. I have known him about 7 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Mr. Smart. That of a very honest man, he has come with goods and settled accounts with me many a time. I always found him honest.</p>
               <p>Mr Fleming. I have known him about 4 years, he always behav'd well as far as ever I know or heard.</p>
               <p>Mr Urwin. I have known the prisoner between 4 and 5 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Mr Urwin. A very honest faithful man.</p>
               <p>Mr Bailey. I have known him about 7 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Mr Bailey. He is a very honest hard working man, I never heard to the contrary in my life. I would have trusted him with a 100 l. at any time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
