<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-37">
               <interp inst="t17561208-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-37" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-37" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-37-off187-c241" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-37-defend299 t17561208-37-off187 t17561208-37-verdict189"></join>
         
               <p>42. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-37-defend299" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lawley 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-37-defend299" type="surname" value="Lawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-defend299" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-defend299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17561208-37-off187" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-off187" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-off187" type="offenceSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               indicted on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter; for making an assault on 
                     <persName id="t17561208-37-victim300" type="victimName">
                        Jos.
                         Forrest
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-victim300" type="surname" value="Forrest"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-37-victim300" type="given" value="Jos."></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-37-victim300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-37-off187 t17561208-37-victim300"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , and biting his little finger off, and giving him thereby a wound, of which he died
            </rs>, Nov. 19.* </p> 
               <p>James Dunnel. The deceased told me the prisoner had bit his finger; after which he grew so bad that he was obliged to go to the hospital. I visited him there, and allow'd him a shilling a week.</p>
               <p>Q. When did this affair happen ?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. It was on the <rs id="t17561208-37-cd188" type="crimeDate">13th of September</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-37-off187 t17561208-37-cd188"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it done?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. No, I did not. It was done at our house; the prisoner had been exceeding troublesome, and after the deceased had been with the watch to take him to the compter he came back again.</p>
               <p>Q. What house do you keep?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. It is a publick house, my mother keeps it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner carried to the compter for?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. For breeding a disturbance in our house. He came there about 11 at night on the 13th of September, with his wife and two children; he call'd for a pint of beer, which was drawn him; before he had drank it half out, there was some company in the next box with whom he would interfere; they beg'd of him to keep his own company, but he began to be very troublesome. I being backwards heard a noise. I came into the room and beg'd of the prisoner not to swear so, but to go home. He abused me, calling me Mungrel and half Mungrel, and said it was by such as him that I liv'd, he'd lick me and whip my a - se, and the like, till I was forced to call the watch, which came. I beg'd they'd take that man out of the house. I only desir'd they'd get him out at the door and discharge him, which they did. After that he came in and abused me more than before. Then I went out of his sight, and presently I saw him go out at the door. I went and shut him out, then I went to his wife and beg'd of her to go; she said she would not. Soon after that came a brickbat and broke two panes of glass.</p>

               <p>Q. Who threw that?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. I believe the prisoner did; then I opened the door, and the company ran after the prisoner; he fought his way and clear'd himself all thro' them; full he was not satisfied, he would fight somebody, when a man took upon him to fight him, and did beat him. But before this he knock'd the constable down (he is now so very bad of the bruises that we don't know whether he'll live or not.) I took him by the hair of his head to pull him off the constable. After this battle I understood there was some assistance coming from the watch-house, and hand cuffs to put on his hands. The prisoner lay on the ground, and would not be hand cu'd [then I went to see how my wife did, for she was child and much affrighted; she has since deliver'd of a dead child, and I believe on this account.] made shift to carry him to the compter the deceased was one that assisted, be with the rest, and told me that the p bit several of them and his finger was bit.</p>
               <p>Q Did you see his ?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. No I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which hand was on ?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't the constable ?</p>
               <p>Dunnel. No, I was with him he is so ill he cannot be here;</p>
               <p>Thomas Beech the coroner produced position of Martin, which was taken on the 23d of November. 1756, in the parish of St. Giles's, Cripplegate, on the view of the body of 
               <persName id="t17561208-37-person301">
                  Joseph 
                  Forrell 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person301" type="surname" value="Forrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person301" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>It was read to this purport:</p>
               <p>On the 13th of September, being sent for from home by 
               <persName id="t17561208-37-person302">
                  James 
                  Dunnel 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person302" type="surname" value="Dunnel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person302" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who keeps a publick house, known by the name of Jacob's Well in the parish of Cripplegate Without, he there was given charge of Lawley for breaking his windows, and breeding a disturbance, and that Lawley took hold of the deponent and threw him down, and fell purposely with his knees upon him, so that the people cry'd out he would kill the deponent; when almost pull'd off, Lawley gave him a kick on the right breast, upon which he desir'd his apprentice to fetch a pair of hand-cuffs, and desir'd the deceased to assist him in hand cuffing of him; when he bit his little finger almost off, and likewise bit several others; that the deceased after having<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080026"></xptr> advice was admitted a patient in the hospital, where he had his little finger cut off, that it soon after mortified, and he died on Friday last; and that the deceased declared to the deponent that he believed that Lawley's beating him as aforesaid was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-37-person303">
                  Robert 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person303" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person303" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for from the watch-house to assist the constable that night. I ran there as fast as I could; I laid hold of the prisoner at the bar, and said if you please you must go along with me; he took hold of me and threw me down, I turn'd him, and he bit part of the calf of my stocking off, for which I gave him a plump on the jaws.</p>
               <p>Q Did you see him bite the deceased ?</p>
               <p>Brooks. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased and him engaged ?</p>
               <p>Brooks. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased's finger afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Brooks. I did; the deceased was endeavouring to hand-cuff the prisoner, and there was a scuffle between them. I heard the deceased cry out, d - n the son of a bitch, he has bit my finger off I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How did his finger appear?</p>
               <p>Brooks. He had bit the leader of his finger in two, I could see the bone clear; the flesh was so clean bit away, it look'd as if it was shaved round.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-37-person304">
                  Thomas 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person304" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person304" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the ward, I saw nothing of the fray; this 
               <persName id="t17561208-37-person305">
                  Joseph 
                  Forrest 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person305" type="surname" value="Forrest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person305" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the deceased was very hearty and well before that, and the next time I saw him he said he had had his finger bit, and he thought it would be the death of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say who bit it?</p>
               <p>Dixon. He said this man at the bar; the prisoner also bit another watchman, a piece out of the back of his hand.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nourse. I am a surgeon, and had the care of 
               <persName id="t17561208-37-person306">
                  Joseph 
                  Forrest 
               <interp inst="t17561208-37-person306" type="surname" value="Forrest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person306" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the hospital; I don't exactly know the day he was brought in; this accident happen'd I believe about a fortnight or three weeks before I saw him, he was then only an out patient. I advised him by all means to come into the hospital, that he might be under a more frequent inspection.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you think he might come into the hospital?</p>
               <p>Nourse. I think it is about two months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition did you find him?</p>
               <p>Nourse. I did not find his finger very bad, it was very much inflamed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him to be in a dangerous condition?</p>
               <p>Nourse. No, after he came in his hand was not in a very dangerous condition; but in about a week or ten days after he had a fever, which occasioned a great inflammation in his hand, and so far affected him, that it made if necessary for me to take his finger off, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been in the house before his finger was taken off ?</p>
               <p>Nourse. I believe it was after he had been in the house about a fortnight. I defer'd it longer than my judgement directed me, in compliance to his request. After that all his complaints ceased, and his sore seem'd in a healing condition. I apprehended from the appearance of it that it would be w in a little time; but in twenty four hours, when we did not expect it, his wound being in a healing way, he was siezed with a fever. I remember I had seen him on the Tuesday. and on the Thursday after he was siezed with his fever, which soon took him off.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion was the reason of his death ?</p>
               <p>Nourse. I am quite clear he died of the fever.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that fever was, or was not occasioned by the wound?</p>
               <p>Nourse. Not at all. He was as free as I am from all sort, of complaints. His wound was in a fine way of healing.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion that he died on that bite or wound, or not?</p>
               <p>Nourse. I am clear of opinion that he did not die of that bite or wound.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-37-verdict189" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-37-verdict189" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
