<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530502-9">
               <interp inst="t17530502-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-9" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-9" type="date" value="17530502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530502-9-off32-c56" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-defend73 t17530502-9-off32 t17530502-9-verdict37"></join>
         
               <p>186. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-defend73" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Dunn 
                  <interp inst="t17530502-9-defend73" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-defend73" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-defend73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17530502-9-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver quart tankard, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530502-9-victim75" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Loftus 
                        <interp inst="t17530502-9-victim75" type="surname" value="Loftus"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-9-victim75" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-9-victim75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-off32 t17530502-9-victim75"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said Francis
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530502-9-cd33" type="crimeDate">March 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-off32 t17530502-9-cd33"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Francis Loftus. I <rs id="t17530502-9-viclabel34" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17530502-9-crimeloc35">Hercules behind the Exchange</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="Hercules behind the Exchange"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-off32 t17530502-9-crimeloc35"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-victim75 t17530502-9-viclabel34"></join>, I have sixteen silver tankards in all, we always carry them up stairs when we go to bed; on the 17th of March in the morning I had them all, and at night there was one missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen it since?</p>
               <p>Loftus. I have. (Produced in court broke into four pieces, and another to compare with it, the Hercules ingrav'd on it, with Francis on one side, and Loftus on the other.) I advertised it on the Monday following, upon which I had it again in this condition.</p>
               <p>Elliad Mulling. I am a drawer with Mr. Loftus, the first time I saw the prisoner, was on the 14th of March in the morning, he came between eight and nine, and staid till about half an hour after ten; he came again on the 17th, about half an hour after three, and had a tankard of beer in the kitchen with the cook; one of our boys drew the beer in a silver tankard with a lid; (that which we lost had got a lid.)</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these pieces, is this your master's tankard?</p>
               <p>Mulling. Here is the same name and engraving on it as is on all my master's tankards, and I believe it is my master's property; the prisoner was at that time talking to the cook, saying he had been a mountibank, and had travelled round England, and got a deal of money that way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-person76">
                  John 
                  Allison 
               <interp inst="t17530502-9-person76" type="surname" value="Allison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person76" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Johnson a pawnbroker, the corner of Russel-court, Bridge's-Street; on the 17th of March the prisoner brought the handle and part of the body of the tankard to me to pawn, he asked fourteen shillings upon it, I weigh'd it, and found it weigh'd eight ounces, it was much disfigured, I got a constable, and carried him before justice Fielding, he not being at home, we put him into the watch-house, and advertiz'd the part of a tankard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-person77">
                  Thomas 
                  Nicholls 
               <interp inst="t17530502-9-person77" type="surname" value="Nicholls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person77" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable, I carried the prisoner to the round-house, (justice Fielding not being at home) where he lay till the Monday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-person78">
                  Thomas 
                  Carrey 
               <interp inst="t17530502-9-person78" type="surname" value="Carrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person78" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am watchouse keeper of Covent Garden parish, I set there on nights, on the 17th of March, Mr. Allison and the constable brought the prisoner to the watchouse about ten at night, I lock'd him up in a room; a little time after the beadle of the night and I went up stairs and searched him, and found the other pieces of the tankard in his pockets, that is the lid, the bottom,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175305020006"></xptr> and part of the body; he has acknowledged since, it was Mr. Loftus's property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-person79">
                  Nicholas 
                  Brite 
               <interp inst="t17530502-9-person79" type="surname" value="Brite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person79" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went up in the watchouse with Mr. Currey, to search the prisoner, and found the three pieces he has mention'd, upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I told them I had the rest about me, before they searched me, and told them my wife and mother would find out the man that gave it me to pawn.</p>
               <p>Brite. He said it was a family tankard, and when his wife and mother came, they would own it. I took care to have the pieces below, against they came. They said they knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>Epbhraim Elicock. The prisoner liv'd with me a year, fifteen years ago; I know nothing of him since: he behaved himself well, then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-9-person80">
                  Ann 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17530502-9-person80" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person80" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight or nine years he served his time to a <rs id="t17530502-9-deflabel36" type="occupation">barber and periwig-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-defend73 t17530502-9-deflabel36"></join>; I never knew him wrong man, woman, or child, of the tythe of a pin.</p>
               <p>Eleaner Sherriden. I have known him three years, but have not seen him for a year past. He behaved well and work'd for his bread when I knew him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530502-9-verdict37" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-verdict37" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-verdict37" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not in the dwelling-house
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530502-9-punish38" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-9-punish38" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-9-defend73 t17530502-9-punish38"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
