<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551022-25">
               <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="date" value="17551022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551022-25-off128-c146" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-defend190 t17551022-25-off128 t17551022-25-verdict131"></join>
         
               <p>389. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-defend190" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, <rs id="t17551022-25-deflabel127" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-defend190 t17551022-25-deflabel127"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17551022-25-person191">
                        Caleb 
                        Smith 
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person191" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-person191" type="given" value="Caleb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-defend190" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-defend190" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-defend190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17551022-25-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551022-25-victim193" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Oliphant 
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-victim193" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-victim193" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-victim193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-off128 t17551022-25-victim193"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>; she stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquisition for the said murder, <rs id="t17551022-25-cd129" type="crimeDate">October 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-off128 t17551022-25-cd129"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Mary Perry. I lived servant with Mr. Smith, the prisoner's husband. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person194">
                  Joseph 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person194" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person194" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             served his time there.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade is Mr. Smith?</p>
               <p>Perry. A carpenter. Oliphant <rs id="t17551022-25-viclabel130" type="occupation">work'd journey-work</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-victim193 t17551022-25-viclabel130"></join> there. On the 1st of October last, there was 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person195">
                  William 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person195" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person195" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person196">
                  William 
                  Saint 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person196" type="surname" value="Saint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person196" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Oliphant, the deceased, at work in the shop. I went up there and saw my mistress with a mallet and square in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe what she was going to do with them?</p>
               <p>Perry. I believe she was going to strike the deceased. He held her hand and took them away, and said she should have nothing from that bench; then she went to the other bench and catched up a turning-bit, call'd a stock and bit. Then I went down stairs into the kitchen.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220015"></xptr>Court. Look at this instrument. (It was a stock and bit, commonly call'd a breast-wimble, with a goug, about 5 or 6 inches long; about a quarter of an inch diameter.)</p>
               <p>Perry. It was just such an instrument as this that she took up. Just as I got to the bottom of the stairs, I heard a noise as if something had fell; then I returned into the shop and saw my mistress fallen backwards, and the deceased with he hand on his side, and he reel'd and fell down: he was dead then I believe; I thought he was dead when they took him up, for he never feared.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been gone down before you heard the falling ?</p>
               <p>Perry. It could not be a minute from the time I saw her with the stock in her hand, when I return'd and saw her down. My mistress at that time had not the instrument in her hand; she was push'd backwards, and the tool lay on the shavings in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she take the tool up from?</p>
               <p>Perry. She took it from Downing's bench.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body push her backwards?</p>
               <p>Perry. No; I did not: I only judge the deceased did; he had received the wound at that time. I saw the instrument bloody afterwards; that is, the inside of the iron was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done after he fell?</p>
               <p>Perry. Downing went down and ran for a surgeon immediately; the deceased had on a brown waistcoat, and I saw his shirt bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of your mistress after this ?</p>
               <p>Perry. She went down stairs. I went down for some water for the deceased, and I told her then I believed Joseph was dead; she said, 'Pshaw, I don't believe it, he only shamm'd. After that she went into her chamber; and when the officer was going to have her in the coach to take her away, I asked her what she would have to put upon her head; she said, she was ruin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her head naked ?</p>
               <p>Perry. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen her but that once, from the time she went into the room till she went into the coach?</p>
               <p>Perry. First of all she went down stairs, then up stairs, then into her own chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she immediately go up stairs, when you told her you thought Joseph was dead?</p>
               <p>Perry. No, she did not; but I did not see her go up.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when the officer came?</p>
               <p>Perry. I went up stairs after the officer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he find her?</p>
               <p>Perry. In a back chamber where she commonly laid; the officer was breaking open a chamber-door with an ax, where she was not; and my mistress opened the door where she was, and came out to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what she said to him?</p>
               <p>Perry. I do not. That was the time I asked her what she would have to put on her head.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it you saw them in the shop?</p>
               <p>Perry. It was between two and three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in the shop ?</p>
               <p>Perry. It was but just gone up for the broom when I saw her with the mallet and square in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any words pass when you saw your mistress with the mallet in her hand ?</p>
               <p>Perry. I heard a few words pass before I went up.</p>
               <p>Q. What words?</p>
               <p>Perry. I don't know what words.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they when these words past?</p>
               <p>Perry. They were in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they angry words ?</p>
               <p>Perry. Yes, I believe they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who began to speak?</p>
               <p>Perry. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you describe the square you saw?</p>
               <p>Perry. It was a wooden thing with two sides to it.</p>
               <p>C. Look at this instrument. (It was the mallet.)</p>
               <p>Perry. That is a mallet; she had just such a one in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think she was going to do with the mallet and square?</p>
               <p>Perry. I think she was going to strike.</p>
               <p>Q. If she had both these things in her hand, with which was she going to strike, in what manner did she hold them?</p>
               <p>Perry. She held then as I do; (taking the mallet by the handle, and the thinest part of the square in the same hand, holding the mallet with the head upwards, and the bottom end of the square directed forwards.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take hold of her?</p>
               <p>Perry. He did; and said she should have nothing from his bench.</p>
               <p>Court. Describe how she had hold of the stock.</p>
               <p>Perry. She held it in this manner, ( taking hold<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220016"></xptr> of the handle part of the instrument, with the bit directed forward towards the deceased.)</p>
               <p>Q. In what situation was Oliphant at the time?</p>
               <p>Perry. He was standing before her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you expect she was going to strike him with that instrument?</p>
               <p>Perry. I did not expect any mischief when I went away.</p>
               <p>Council. I think you say you was not absent above a minute.</p>
               <p>Perry. No, I was not. I heard a noise as if something fell, upon which I immediately returned to the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. In what position was the deceas'd, when you return'd?</p>
               <p>Perry. He was standing on his legs, reeling, with his hand on his side.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mistress then?</p>
               <p>Perry. Downing was taking her up when the deceas'd fell.</p>
               <p>Council. Then consequently she fell before he fell.</p>
               <p>Perry. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after this accident, was it that the officer was fetched?</p>
               <p>Perry. I can't tell, indeed. I ran out for my master; but I believe it was less than an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing to hinder your mistress from going out of the house, before the officer came?</p>
               <p>Perry. The street-door was lock'd, as usual, and the key hanging up in its place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention to your mistress of her having struck him with that instrument?</p>
               <p>Perry. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing mention'd to her about it?</p>
               <p>Perry. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person197">
                  William 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person197" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person197" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work'd with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person198">
                  Caleb 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person198" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person198" type="given" value="Caleb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when this accident happened. On the first of October I was at work in the shop; between two and three o'clock, there was 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person199">
                  William 
                  Saint 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person199" type="surname" value="Saint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at work also at my bench, and 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person200">
                  Joseph 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person200" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person200" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at another bench by himself. My mistress came up into the shop from out of the kitchen; she went by me and my partner; we were nearer the kitchen than 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person201">
                  Joseph 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person201" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person201" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was; I heard them have two or three words, it was a very few; I did not take notice what the words were. She fell backwards against my leg as I was at work; I turned round and helped her up as fast as I could; and before I had well got her up, the deceased clap'd his hand on his breast, and fell backwards; I went and took hold of him and held him up, and saw-some blood; I said to my partner, for God's-sake, run, for I fear here is mischief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any stroke given?</p>
               <p>Downing. No, I did not. My partner run for Mr. Tolmin.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he alive when you held him up?</p>
               <p>Downing. I can't say whether he was or not; he never spoke. Then I went to the deceased's father, and after that Mr. Tolmin and Mr. Turpin both came.</p>
               <p>Q. You say there were words; who did they rise from?</p>
               <p>Downing. I don't know who. I took no notice of any thing, till the prisoner fell against my leg.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing in the deceased's hand?</p>
               <p>Downing. No, I did not. Nor nothing in my mistress's hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you account for your mistress's falling?</p>
               <p>Downing. No, I cannot; because my back was towards her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember, on the 29th of September, any words between your mistress and the deceased?</p>
               <p>Downing. I was at work on the 29th of September at night, betwixt eight and nine o'clock, they had some words after we left work; the deceased and I were going out to go home; he went first and open'd the door, and I followed him; there was a stoppage at the door; my mistress was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any words?</p>
               <p>Downing. They were generally quarrelling, but the words I can't give an account of.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any thing in her hand at that time?</p>
               <p>Downing. I don't remember she had any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear her threaten him?</p>
               <p>Downing. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person202">
                  William 
                  Saint 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person202" type="surname" value="Saint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person202" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work in the shop when this accident happened, on the first of October; it was, as near as I can recollect, between two and three o'clock; we have a couple of benches in the shop. I and 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person203">
                  William 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person203" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were at work at one, and Oliphant on the other side at another bench; his bench was farthest from the kitchen than ours is. I saw my mistress come into the shop and pass by our bench.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she speak to you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220017"></xptr>Saint. No, she did not. She went on to the bench where Oliphant was at work; then two or three words pass'd between them, but what they were I can't tell. I was minding my work, he was at one side of the bench near one end, and my mistress at the other end of the bench.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is the bench?</p>
               <p>Saint. It is about 10 foot long. I saw her take up this mallet (here produc'd,) and 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person204">
                  Joseph 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person204" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person204" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came round the end of the bench to her; they were both at different ends of the bench when she took up the mallet; when he came to her they had a sort of a scuffle betwixt the two benches, and the mallet drop'd down between them.</p>
               <p>Q. In what posture did your mistress seem to hold the mallet ?</p>
               <p>Saint. I can't say in what posture; I kept minding my work.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Oliphant lay hold of the mallet?</p>
               <p>Saint. I believe he must think his mistress was going to strike him with it, and he came to rescue it out of her hands.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the next thing you saw, that you can remember with certainty?</p>
               <p>Saint. After the mallet was drop'd, I saw my mistress snatch something from the end of the same bench; it was snatched up as quick as possible.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it?</p>
               <p>Saint. Really I can't tell what it was; it was snatched up as soon as could be; it was done in an instant, and my mistress fell against Downing's legs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe what was the occasion of her falling?</p>
               <p>Saint. I suppose as soon as he received the wound he gave her a shove, or she would not have tumbled backwards. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person205">
                  Joseph 
                  Oliph 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person205" type="surname" value="Oliph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person205" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ant clap'd his hand to his breast, and cry'd, Oh! and gave a reel back, and tumbled down, with his head against the pales, and died. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person206">
                  William 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person206" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person206" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to me, run for a surgeon; I said, Lord, madam, I am afraid you have killed the poor young fellow. Then William Downing was helping Oliphant up.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did she make?</p>
               <p>Saint. I did not hear her make any answer, for I ran directly away for a surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether she attempted to strike with the mallet?</p>
               <p>Saint. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think, by the posture she hold it, she intended to strike?</p>
               <p>Saint. It was done in such an instant of time, it is impossible to give an account of it, except I had stood on purpose to look at it; for I believe from the time of her coming into the shop, and the wound being given, it did not last above a minuet. I ran to Dr. Tolmin's, he was not at home; his son came; 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person207">
                  William 
                  Downing 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person207" type="surname" value="Downing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person207" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ran for another surgeon; but when I returned Oliphant was dead. I believe he was dead in the space of 4 or 5 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to fall against the pales?</p>
               <p>Saint. He fell backwards out of the shop down into the yard. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person208">
                  Young 
                  Mr 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person208" type="surname" value="Mr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person208" type="given" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Tolmin open'd a vein; there came just a drop of blood.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the maid in the shop?</p>
               <p>Saint. Really, I was so affrighten, I can't remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing in Oliphant's hand?</p>
               <p>Saint. No, I did not. Afterwards I saw Mr. Turpin had this boreing-tool in his hand, (here produced) the gouge belonging to it, seem'd a little bloody; the blood seem'd to be: dry'd within-side it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you understand to be so extremely quick?</p>
               <p>Saint. The snatching up this stock and bit; but I can't say that was the thing. Whatever was snatch'd up, it was no sooner done, but my mistress fell within half a moment.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was your mistress to the deceased at the time something was snatched up?</p>
               <p>Saint. They were close together as could be; he was struggling to get the mallet out of her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it snatched up from?</p>
               <p>Saint. It was from the end of his bench.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the place where he and your mistress stood, to the stairs that the maid went down?</p>
               <p>Saint. It is about 12 feet.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Oliphant's bench stand longways or endways in the shop?</p>
               <p>Saint. It does not stand longways.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there stairs that go down into the kitchen out of the shop?</p>
               <p>Saint. There are.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220018"></xptr>Q. Where was the maid at the time your mistress fell?</p>
               <p>Saint. It is possible she might be there, but I did not see her.</p>
               <p>Q. Who fell first, the deceased or your mistress ?</p>
               <p>Saint. My mistress fell first, and he stood reeling, and gave his foot a stamp, and gaz'd at her the space of a moment, and tumbled down into the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your mistress walk towards the deceased with any thing in her hand?</p>
               <p>Saint. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. If she had taken a tool from another place, and not from his bench should you have seen her.</p>
               <p>Saint. It is likely I should have seen it, but I did not think of such an affair as this happening.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a person have seen her take something up, and gone to the head of the stairs, and down stairs, before such time the fall was?</p>

               <p>Saint. No, I believe not, it was in a very small space of time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person209">
                  Andrew 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person209" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person209" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I married the mother of the deceased, one of the journeymen came to our house, and told me, and my wife, he believed Joe was killed. I went immediately for a surgeon, and came to his master's house; as soon as I open'd the street door, I saw Mrs. Smith in the entry much confused. I saw Mr. Tolmin's son bleeding the deceased. I went to Mrs. Smith and said, what cruel thing have you done to my son? she spoke something, what it was I do not know. There were some people in the entry, I charged them not to let any body go out, either backwards or forwards, till I knew which way the murder was committed. She got up stairs and lock'd the door of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Williamson. Because I went up stairs and asked where Mrs. Smith was, and nobody could give an account. I went to the headborough.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go first to see if the door was fastened?</p>
               <p>Williamson. I took hold of several doors, but I did not know which room she was in. When the headbrough came, he got an ax, and began to knock at the door where she was not, my back was against the door where she was at the same time. She opened the door and said here I am. I went into the room and catched hold on her, and said what an evil action have you done, she said I am an unfortunate woman, or a ruined creature, or something of that kind.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Barnet?</p>
               <p>Williamson. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he with you at the time she opened the door, and said here I am?</p>
               <p>Williamson. I do not know that, I believe I told Mr. Barnet to take care of the door, that she should not go out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person210">
                  John 
                  Turpin 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person210" type="surname" value="Turpin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, I found the deceased in a sitting posture, supported by the other two workmen, there was Mr. Tolmin. I said, for God's sake what is the matter? he shook his head, and said, I believe he is dead. The deceased's face on the left side was dirty, and a little bloody. I said, he has had a blow here. I found, upon inquiry, he got that by falling upon the pavement in the yard. I found above, the bench end to be square with the door, and about four foot from it, and by the reel he fell out there into the yard, we concluded that blow on his face could not kill him. Mr. Tolmin said, his shirt is bloody, pointing to his left side, I took my instrument out, and ripped down the shirt; and on the left side, about three inches from the region of his heart, there was a small wound, about a quarter of an inch diameter, like a half-moon or curve. I said, we need not look any further, for this wound is close to the region of the heart. I examined the men if they had seen any instrument near where he fell-from, or on the floor; they all said no. I said that it must be done with a small gouge, but they none of them could give any account that they saw such a thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the maid by at this time?</p>
               <p>Turpin. No, she was not there. I then desired Mr. Williamson to go for an officer. It was very near an hour before one came. In looking up and down the shop. I found upon a bench this instrument, called a stock and bit. I said, Mr. Barnet, I believe, I have found the instrument that has done the mischief. I found the gouge or bit in it, exactly the shape and size of the wound, and to me it appeared bloody on the inside. I first apprehended it was wiped. but upon second confideration I judged the waistcoat had cleaned the out-side of it by pulling it out. I took my knife and scraped the inside, and found it to be dry blood. I shew'd it to Mr. Curtis, with much the same words, but can't say what answer he made; then I wrapt it in a bit of paper, and put<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220019"></xptr> it in my pocket, presently came in Downing and Saint. I asked them if either of them had seen that instrument in their mistress's hand, they said, no, they had not; but upon repeating the question, one of them, I think it was Saint, said, our maid told me half an hour ago the mistress had taken up that instrument. I asked them where the maid was, they said, above stairs. I said, pray call her, they did, and she came down. I said, child did you see your mistress with this instrument in her hand? Said she, I saw the mallet and square in her hand? I said, but did you see her with this in her hand? She said, I saw her with a mallet and square in her hand; I said, the man says you told him about half an hour ago, you saw her with this in her hand. I saw the mallet and square, she said again; and I could get no more. I said, you must tell the truth by and by, for you must be examined about it, though I have no right to examine you. She turned her back and went away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person211">
                  Abraham 
                  Tolmin 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person211" type="surname" value="Tolmin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person211" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, I was there about two minutes before Mr. Turpin came in, I found the deceased lying on the floor in the workshop; on observing some blood on the left side, I desired Mr. Turpin to examine whence that came, there we found a crooked small wound, he passed his probe into the cavity of the chest, and we determined that wound was certainly the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>Court. Describe the wound.</p>
               <p>Tolmin. It was a curve of about a quarter of an inch, or a little better. I believe I staid there about half an hour, and after I was gone, this tool was found. When I saw it, it was exactly as now, a little bloody; and then I thought no other tool could do it but that. (So said Mr. Turpin, upon being asked his opinion.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person212">
                  John 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person212" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the deceased. I am a a carpenter and joiner. I was at work for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person213">
                  Caleb 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person213" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person213" type="given" value="Caleb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that is the prisoner's husband, about two months ago. The deceased and I were making a window frame, at a house at Wapping-dock. The prisoner came in, and was angry with me for helping the deceased, and said, it should not be done. She ordered me to go about my work, which I was about, and Oliphant to go home; he said he would not go home, for if he did he would not make the frame. She bid him go out of that place, he said he would not go out for her, then she took up a hand saw, and held it up to strike him, he got the saw out of her hand, and said he would not stand to be beat with his own tools.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that at your master's house?</p>
               <p>Hopkins. No; it was at Wapping-dock. She ordered him to go home to her house to work, and he refused it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person214">
                  Anne 
                  Cowden 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person214" type="surname" value="Cowden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person214" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the day before the accident happened, between 11 and 12 at noon, I was in my yard, which is next to the prisoner's yard, hanging out my cloaths. I heard something heaving about in Mr. Smith's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner hit the deceased?</p>
               <p>Cowden. No, I did not, the deceased was coming to jump into our yard. He was very much affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he jump into your yard?</p>
               <p>Cowden. No, he did not, but he jumped into a hop-field joining my yard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person215">
                  Hannah 
                  Rasbury 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person215" type="surname" value="Rasbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person215" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have heard a great deal of quarrels between Mrs. Smith and 
               <persName id="t17551022-25-person216">
                  Joe 
                  Oliphant 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person216" type="surname" value="Oliphant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person216" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any threatning declarations of hers?</p>
               <p>Rasbury. No; I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person217">
                  Anne 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person217" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person217" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the deceased. I went to the prisoner in New-prison to inquire into the cause of my child's death.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Williamson. She went there on the first of October, and this was the Friday se'nnight after. I said to her, Mrs. Smith, what induced you to do this wicked thing to my child? She said, she had told her husband, and several other people, but would not tell me. I took her by the hand, and said, O dear, what an unfortunate woman am I! pray tell me where your malice first sprung. She said I'd give all the world he was alive again; if I could but get his life again! what an unfortunate creature am I! I believe I asked her this question over and over again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am intirely clear of the charge laid against me.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person218">
                  John 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person218" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person218" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner at the bar these 20 years, her husband and I are very intimate.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take her to be a woman of a humane or cruel disposition?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220020"></xptr>Hawkins. I always took her to be modest, complaisant and civil. I never saw any thing in her but good-nature and agreeable. I believe her to be a woman of humanity. I have been at her house abundance of times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person219">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarke 
               <interp inst="t17551022-25-person219" type="surname" value="Clarke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person219" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 10 or 12 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live near her?</p>
               <p>Clarke. I do not live a great way off. During that time I have occasionally gone to her house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Clarke. A very civil, inoffensive woman, as far as ever I heard or saw, till this unhappy affair she always bore this character.</p>
               <p>Dr. Glanvil. I have known her very well seven or eight years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is her character that of a good natured or cruel woman?</p>
               <p>Glanvil. I never heard any thing of cruelty or ill-nature by her, I always thought her to be a sober, honest, good, and charitable woman. I never saw to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Mr. Barnard. I have known her particularly well about 15 or 16 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Has her behaviour been humane or cruel?</p>
               <p>Barnard. I happen to live within a few doors of her, and have been conversant with her, and know her general character and behaviour. She is a person of as humane a disposition as any woman I know, one that has relieved poor people in our neighbourhood. She has reliev'd some tenants of mine to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Barnard. It is that of a sober, agreeable woman in conversation, on all accounts.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gibbins. I have known her about 9 years. I boarded in her house about three years, in 47, 48, and 49. I have known her to be charitable in several instances.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her humanity?</p>
               <p>Gibbins. I believe her to be a very humane 'I good-natur'd woman, that is her character, never heard any thing to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hickman. I have known the prisoner about 10 years, I boarded in her house about half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the behaviour of the woman?</p>
               <p>Hickman. Her behaviour and conduct was very agreeable and very comfortable to the whole family. I have said often I should have been glad to have lived in the family longer, if it would have suited my circumstances, when I have gone there since, I have always found her conversation very agreeable.</p>
               <p>Mr. Walden. I have known her 14 or 15 years, and have been frequently at the house. I have done business for them, and they for me. I have eat and drank in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. From your observations, what is the disposition and temper of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Walden. I thought always of her, in every respect, a good woman, a meek, mild tempered woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take her to be a woman of a mild, or cruel disposition ?</p>
               <p>Walden. Far from thinking her a cruel woman, but one that would shudder at the thing.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Chapman. I have known her 20 years, and been intimately acquainted with her. I lived within four doors of her.</p>
               <p>Q. From your observation of her, what is her disposition, humane or cruel?</p>
               <p>Chapman. I always found her humane, and charitable to poor people in distress. That is her general character in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fowle. I have known her very near 20 years.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17551022-25">
                  <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551022"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551022-25" type="date" value="17551022"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY OF LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 22d, Thursday the 23d, Friday the 24th, and Saturday the 25th of OCTOBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VIII. PART II. for the YEAR 1755. Being the Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17551022-25-person220">
                     STEPHEN THEODORE 
                     JANSSEN 
                  <interp inst="t17551022-25-person220" type="surname" value="JANSSEN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-person220" type="given" value="STEPHEN THEODORE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-25-person220" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. DO you live near her?</p>
               <p>Fowle. I am a very near neighbour to her, and am frequently at her house, and am intimately acquainted with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her disposition, cruel or humane?</p>
               <p>Fowle. I always took her to be a very tender-hearted person, and a very good neighbour, very willing to serve any body in distress. I have been an eye-witness to many acts of charity she has done, and that as privately as she could.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Eastop. I have known her 18 years and upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Eastop. I live a little way from her, and have been intimately acquainted with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Eastop. Her general character is a good neighbour, and a charitable woman; I never saw any thing to the contrary, but that of a courteous, good-natured woman. I myself have experienc'd this of her. This is a character she always deserved.</p>
               <p>Mrs Gold. I have known her about 13 years, and have been pretty intimate with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her disposition, cruel or humane?</p>
               <p>Gold. She is a humane charitable woman; I have received of her charity myself. I never heard she was a woman of a cru el disposition.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Boston. I have known her about four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Boston. I live not far from her, and have been very well acquainted with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Boston. She always bore a very good character; she is a very good neighbour, and a person of great humanity. This I have observ'd and known.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Huson. I have known her eight years; I never heard any thing ill of her before this.</p>
               <p>Q. From your own observation of her, what is her general character ?</p>
               <p>Huson. I take her to be a humane woman, that was always my opinion.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551022-25-verdict131" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-verdict131" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-verdict131" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551022-25-punish132" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-punish132" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-25-punish132" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-25-defend190 t17551022-25-punish132"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
