<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510227-51">
               <interp inst="t17510227-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-51" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-51" type="date" value="17510227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510227-51-off258-c425" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-51-defend516 t17510227-51-off258 t17510227-51-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>248. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510227-51-defend516" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Osborn 
                  <interp inst="t17510227-51-defend516" type="surname" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-defend516" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-defend516" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he on the <rs id="t17510227-51-cd257" type="crimeDate">23d of Jan</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-51-off258 t17510227-51-cd257"></join>. <rs id="t17510227-51-off258" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-off258" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-off258" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               about the hour of 12 in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17510227-51-victim517" type="victimName">
                        Eliz.
                         Markham
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-victim517" type="surname" value="Markham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-51-victim517" type="given" value="Eliz."></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-51-victim517" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-51-off258 t17510227-51-victim517"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17510227-51-viclabel259" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-51-victim517 t17510227-51-viclabel259"></join>, did break and enter, with an intent the goods of the said Elizabeth to steal, take and carry away
            </rs>.* </p>
               <p>Eliz. Markham. I live at <placeName id="t17510227-51-crimeloc260">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510227-51-crimeloc260" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510227-51-crimeloc260" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-51-off258 t17510227-51-crimeloc260"></join>; about 12 o'clock at night, the 23d of January my daughter came to my room with a candle in her hand, and said there was some body had broke into the kitchen. I was just got into bed. I said it was the cat, she said she was sure she heard the drawers move as they opened, and somebody stir the fire. I arose and went down and saw nobody; I searched the coal-hole. I went to bed again, and lay till five o'clock next morning. As I was making a fire, I heard a great snoring, I looked into a place<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175102270037"></xptr> where I lay my coals, the place were I had looked in before; there I saw a man's legs as far as his breeches knees. I went out and called a neighbour or two, he was snoring hard when I came back, I took him hold by the shoulders, and when he got up, I found him to be a neighbour's son, the prisoner at the bar, he is about seventeen years of age. I asked him, what he did there? he said two strange men shov'd me in at the window after they had made him drunk. I asked him, what he came there for? he said, to carry away all he could find. A little time afterwards he said one of the men was named Hargrave, and some time after that, he said the other was named Stevens; he owned the same before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what window?</p>
               <p>E. Markham. No, he did not, but I believe I know which window; but I cannot say whether the same window was open or shut over night, neither can I say for certain, which window he came in at ; there was a little wooden sliding shutter to one pane of glass that was open.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he meddled with any thing?</p>
               <p>E. Markham. No, he had not; I missed not any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search him?</p>
               <p>E. Markham. I did not, my lord, he confessed opening the drawers, and shutting them again.</p>
               <p>Q. Where there any things in the drawers, that he could take away?</p>
               <p>E. Markham. Yes, my lord, there were, which he might have put into his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor?</p>
               <p>E. Markham. He was, my lord, I don't know but he may be an honest lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-51-person518">
                  Esther 
                  Markham 
               <interp inst="t17510227-51-person518" type="surname" value="Markham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-person518" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-person518" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am daughter to the prosecutrix; on the 23d of January, about 12 at night, I heard something come slump upon the stairs; I thought it was the cat, and I heard the drawers open in the kitchen, and the fire stir; I went to my mother, she was a-bed, we went down into the kitchen, I opened the drawers and found nothing gone; my mother looked in the coal-hole and saw nobody there, we went to bed again ; next morning about 5 o'clock, I heard my mother come up stairs again, after she had been down, very nimbly out of the kitchen and opened the street door; I asked her where she was going, she said to me hold your tongue, saying, there was a man asleep in the kitchen ; she called two of our neighbours in, I went down stairs, and saw them bring the prisoner out of the coal-hole; I heard my mother ask him, what he came there for? he said two men pushed him in at a window.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the window fastened over night?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-51-person519">
                  Esther 
                  Markham 
               <interp inst="t17510227-51-person519" type="surname" value="Markham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-person519" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-person519" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know whether it was open or shut, he did not wrong us of any thing; there were many things about the kitchen and in the drawers, that he might have taken if he would. I believe he was very much in liquor; I have known him ever since he was a child, he may be very honest for what I know.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-51-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-51-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
