<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-49">
               <interp inst="t17580913-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-49" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-49" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-49-off255-c359" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-49-defend449 t17580913-49-off255 t17580913-49-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>306. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-defend449" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Godden 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-defend449" type="surname" value="Godden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-defend449" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-defend449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17580913-49-deflabel254" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-49-defend449 t17580913-49-deflabel254"></join>, late wife of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-victim451" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Godden 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-49-victim451" type="surname" value="Godden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-victim451" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-victim451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-49-off255 t17580913-49-victim451"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17580913-49-off255" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-off255" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-off255" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               she did feloniously, treacherously, maliciously, and wilfully, kill and murder the said James her husband
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580913-49-cd256" type="crimeDate">June 22.</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-49-off255 t17580913-49-cd256"></join>* </p>
               <p>She stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-person452">
                  George 
                  Higgins 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person452" type="surname" value="Higgins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person452" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged in the deceased 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-person453">
                  James 
                  Godden 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person453" type="surname" value="Godden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person453" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, in a room over where he used to lie; on the 22d of June I heard him cry murder two or three times, about eight o'clock; I went down stairs as fast as I could, the key was on the outside of his door; just as I came there 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-person454">
                  Eleanor 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person454" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person454" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person454" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in, she had been out, (she is a lodger in the same house) we entered the deceased's room both at one instant, I found the prisoner with her left-knee on the right side of the bed, the deceased lying on his back.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he dressed or undressed?</p>
               <p>Higgins. His cloaths were off, and he was in bed, she had her cloaths on, her left hand was upon his neck or wind-pipe as he lay, to hold him down, she had the iron pin of the window in her right hand, held by the little end; (he produced an iron pin or bolt, with a knob at one end, and a key hole at the other, about fourteen inches long) the deceased had hold of the great end with both his hands, endeavouring, I believe, to pull it away from her, and she seemed to endeavour to get it away from him. I ran immediately and took it out of both their hands, and took her away from him. As soon as I had so done, she flew at him again, and catched hold of his right arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side of the bed was she on?</p>
               <p>Higgins. She was on the right side of the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she seem to be in a passion ?</p>
               <p>Higgins. She did, I pulled her away again, and asked him if they had had any falling out, he said none at all, and that he had no sleep all night, and he believed he was then in a slumber, and she had taken the advantage of him. I asked her afterwards if she had struck him, he told me she had struck him two blows with the pin before I came.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her strike him?</p>
               <p>Higgins. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where she had struck him?</p>
               <p>Higgins. He said she had struck him on the head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any wound?</p>
               <p>Higgins. No, I did not at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she by at the time he said this ?</p>
               <p>Higgins. Yes, she was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say in answer to it?</p>

               <p>Higgins. She said nothing at all, I asked her several times her reason for doing of it, but she made me no answer at all; he begged of us to go to Mr. Welch for a warrant for her, we went, he granted one, and we took her before him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased go?</p>
               <p>Higgins. No, he was not able to go; the justice examined her, but she said nothing, neither one way nor the other; he committed her, we came immediately home from the justice's, that is I and 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-person455">
                  Eleanor 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person455" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person455" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person455" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been gone from the deceased?</p>
               <p>Higgins. It was not above two hours at most.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130043"></xptr>Higgins. We found him in his bed; he had sent for an apothecary in the mean time; the apothecary's man was there when we returned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wound?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I did, and saw it dressed.</p>
               <p>Q. How many wound were there?</p>
               <p>Higgins. There was one wound.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep was it?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I cannot say as to the depth of it, he was so spent with his disease, that I believe he had no blood to bleed.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his disease?</p>
               <p>Higgins. He was in a deep consumption, which he had laboured under for years.</p>
               <p>Q. If this accident had not happened, do you think he would have liv'd much longer then he did?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I cannot say that, he was in a weak and low condition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after this?</p>
               <p>Higgins. The next time I saw him was the day before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Higgins. He died that day sennight.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he appear that day?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I could see very plainly that he was dying.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think he was dying of the consumption?</p>
               <p>Higgins. It is what I can scarcely pretend to resolve</p>
               <p>Q. Had you then any discourse with him?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I asked him what he would have done with his wife; he told me as well as he could, that he would have her kept in goal; I told him I saw he was a dying man, and recommended to him to send for a clergyman, he said no more, only signed with his hands for me to say no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not in my senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in or out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Higgins. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she use to be out of her senses ?</p>
               <p>Higgins. There was such talk, but some of the house was of opinion that it was artificial, some otherwise, but that I cannot pretend to determine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-person456">
                  Eleanor 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person456" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person456" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged in the deceased's house, I went into the room just as Mr. Higgins did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard Mr. Higgins's examination?</p>
               <p>May. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Was every thing as he has said?</p>
               <p>May. Yes they were, the deceased desired we would not leave him alone with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any reason why he desired that?</p>
               <p>May. Not in particular, he said he was afraid of his life, and he desired me to fetch Mr. Nichols.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he want with him?</p>
               <p>May. He wanted to send her to the workhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Nichols master of the workhouse ?</p>
               <p>May. No, he is a neighbour, a baker.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Nichols come ?</p>
               <p>May. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Higgins and you stay after Mr. Nichols came?</p>
               <p>May. We did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the deceased say to Mr. Nichols?</p>
               <p>May. He desired he would assist him in getting his wife into the workhouse, he wanted her to be taken from him, that she might not do him any farther damage. He said if the two good people had not come, my brains had been upon the pillow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give any account by what means?</p>
               <p>May. He said his wife had been striking him over the head with the pin of the window, and desired me to shew him the pin.</p>
               <p>Q. What pin was it?</p>
               <p>May. It is the same that Mr. Higgins had in his hand here just now.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by when the deceased said this?</p>
               <p>May. Yes, she was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to it?</p>
               <p>May. She said she would not go to the workhouse, she would go to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that all she said?</p>
               <p>May. That was all I heard her say; after that we went to Mr. Welch's in the manner as Mr. Higgins has said.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the deceased next?</p>
               <p>May. I saw him again that afternoon, after the prisoner was committed, he had been in bed, and I helped him to get up.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was he ?</p>
               <p>May. He was very weak, and was forced to lie down again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the apothecary's man with him then?</p>
               <p>May. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had his head been dressed then?</p>
               <p>May. There was a plaister on his head, but I did not see him dressed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130044"></xptr>Q. In what state of health was the deceased at this time?</p>
               <p>May. He was in a poor state of health, in a deep consumption, he was very much worn away.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him next after this?</p>
               <p>May. I saw him several times, but the last time that I saw him was on the Monday before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week did he die on?</p>
               <p>May. He died on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition was he in on the Monday?</p>
               <p>May. He was very bad, and lay groaning violently.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the body after it was dead?</p>
               <p>May. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. As you lodged in this house, did you take this woman to be mad?</p>
               <p>May. There was some talk of it, but I did not see any mad actions by her.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether he was not dying some time before this?</p>
               <p>May. I did not look upon him as a dying man, he had been abroad the Monday before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think there was any hopes of his recovery before?</p>
               <p>May. He was in a consumption before, but as well as he had been for some time.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether he did not drop down in a sit on the Monday before?</p>
               <p>May. Not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Thomas W oodward. I am a constable; I took the prisoner before the justice, I live just by the prisoner, the deceased said to me, I am glad you are come, had it not been for these two people, (pointing to the two evidences ) my brains had been on the pillow; he desired I would take care of his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. What said she to this?</p>
               <p>Woodward. She was by, but made no answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any appearance of lunacy in her?</p>
               <p>Woodward. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you much knowledge of her?</p>
               <p>Woodward. I did not know her very much, I knew the deceased very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him before his death after this?</p>
               <p>Woodward. I did, I went once, I am not certain to the day, I think it was about three days after this affair, I asked him how he did, he was very ill, and said he hoped I had taken care of his wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-person457">
                  Daniel 
                  Douset 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person457" type="surname" value="Douset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person457" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am journeyman to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-person458">
                  John 
                  Jesterman 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person458" type="surname" value="Jesterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person458" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he has been apothecary to the deceased, and his wife, ever since I have been with him, that is fifteen years, I was sent for to the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you dress his head?</p>
               <p>Douset. No, I did not, I examined it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who dressed it?</p>
               <p>Douset. A person that lodges in the house dressed it by my directions.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that person's name?</p>
               <p>Douset. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a wound was it?</p>
               <p>Douset. There was a bruise on the left side of the head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon it to be dangerous?</p>
               <p>Douset. No, I did not think it a dangerous one, very flight, very superficial, just raised the skin.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the skull fractured?</p>
               <p>Douset. No fracture at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it afterwards?</p>
               <p>Douset. I never went afterwards, finding it so slight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your master go?</p>
               <p>Douset. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the body after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Douset. I did, I examined the part; the coroner sent for me.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a constitution had he?</p>
               <p>Douset. A very broken constitution, quite worn out with sickness, a phthisical case.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you upon your oath think this wound was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Douset. No, I do not think it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing appear upon examination from the wound, as if it was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Douset. No, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What in your opinion was the cause of his death ?</p>
               <p>Douset. He died of his illness, a consumption.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been apothecary to the woman?</p>
               <p>Douset. I have, she has had a scrobatical habit of body for years.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she ever disordered in her senses?</p>
               <p>Douset. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When ?</p>
               <p>Douset. About a month before she gave the deceased the blow, we treated her as such at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she well before this affair happened?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130045"></xptr>Douset. I cannot say whether she was quite or not.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen her before?</p>
               <p>Douset. I saw her between three weeks and a month before.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she then ?</p>
               <p>Douset. Very much disordered in her senses.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether a petition was not filled up for me to be admitted into the mad-house ?</p>
               <p>Douset. Yes, it was for her to be admitted into St. Luke's hospital.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was it drawn by ?</p>
               <p>Douset. I really cannot say.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580913-49-person459">
                  John 
                  Jesterman 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person459" type="surname" value="Jesterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person459" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apothecary, my servant, the last evidence, attended the deceased; I never saw him from the time of the blow, till the time of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been his apothecary?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. I believe about eighteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What a constitution had he?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. A very bad one, I expected his death every winter.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the representation your servant has given, do you think it was owing to this blow on the head ?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. I cannot think it was owing to that, I think it was owing to the distemper, that is a consumption.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the woman at the bar?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever known her disordered in her senses?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. I have for three months before this accident.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before this accident might you have seen her ?</p>

               <p>Jesterman. I believe about three weeks before, she was disordered then; I administered to her then as a disordered person.</p>
               <p>Q. What might her disorder be owing to?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. It was said she was given to drinking, and I believe she was, and that brought the disorder.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Was I not very much disordered in my senses, and they were going to get me into the hospital?</p>
               <p>Jesterman. Yes, she was, and her husband had an order about nine or ten days before his death to get her in; he told me he had got the paper.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never had any quarrel nor any words, and I do not know any reason that could be assigned for doing it.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-person460">
                  John 
                  George 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person460" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person460" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in great Earle-street, about a quarter of a mile from where the deceased w'd, he told me about five days before this affair happened, that his wife was out of her senses, and that she had been a very good, industrious, and honest wife for thirty five years before, and that he had been to St. Luke's hospital to see if he could get her in, for he could not leave her five minutes alone; I have known them this twenty years, they lived very happily together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-49-person461">
                  John 
                  Coombs 
               <interp inst="t17580913-49-person461" type="surname" value="Coombs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person461" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a coffee house in Red-Lyon-square; about a month before this affair happened, I called to see the deceased, they were both sitting in the shop, I asked him how he did, he said in his old way, meaning one day alive, and another dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say so?</p>
               <p>Coombs. He did, he said his wife was worse again, that he believed her brain was turned, for she told him the lodgers had carried the beds and goods out of the rooms, where they lodged, and brought old ones in the room of them, when the things were standing as they did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe her then?</p>
               <p>Coombs. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion of her?</p>
               <p>Coombs. To the best of my opinion I thought her out of her senses then.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the deceased ?</p>
               <p>Coombs. I have known him about ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. How had they used to live together ?</p>
               <p>Coombs. They lived very happily till within this three years, since that they were not so happy as they were before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know of any fighting between them?</p>
               <p>Coombs. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-49-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-49-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
