<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550910-3">
               <interp inst="t17550910-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-3" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-3" type="date" value="17550910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550910-3-off11-c38" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-3-defend41 t17550910-3-off11 t17550910-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>301. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-defend41" type="defendantName">
                     Jonathan 
                     Wigmore 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-3-defend41" type="surname" value="Wigmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-defend41" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-defend41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550910-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               that he a certain pistol loaded with gunpowder and a leaden bullet, did wilfully and maliciously shoot off at 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550910-3-victim43" type="victimName">
                           Duncan 
                           Robertson 
                        <interp inst="t17550910-3-victim43" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-3-victim43" type="given" value="Duncan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-3-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-3-off11 t17550910-3-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17550910-3-cd12" type="crimeDate">May 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-3-off11 t17550910-3-cd12"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person44">
                  Duncan 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person44" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person44" type="given" value="Duncan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of May last, I went out from London with the York coach. I was sitting on the box with the coachman, going over <placeName id="t17550910-3-crimeloc13">Finchly-Common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-3-crimeloc13" type="placeName" value="Finchly-Common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-3-crimeloc13" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-3-off11 t17550910-3-crimeloc13"></join>. There came a man on a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100003"></xptr> bright bay horse, with a small swish tail ; he had on a fustian frock, with a pair of greasy breeches, and his face covered with a black mask, a slouch'd hat, and a black peruke.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he overtake or meet you?</p>
               <p>Robertson . He overtook the coach , and rode up to the coachman on the off-side, and immediately, with a great oath, ordered him to stop, or he'd blow his brains out. The ladies in the coach seeing him pass the window, with a pistol in his hand, and a mask on his face, said one to the other there comes a collector, get your money ready.</p>
               <p>Q. How many passengers were there in the coach?</p>
               <p>Robertson. There were five gentlewomen, and a gentleman of about 50 years of age. The coach stopped. He immediately order'd the ladies to pull down the coach windows , or he'd blow their brains out. One of the gentlewomen said, have a little patience, and we'll give you our money directly. He, with a great oath, said, my business is haste . There was a servant belonging to capt. Paterson asleep in the basket. The robber thought he had got fire-arms about him, and said to him, if you don't come out I'll blow your brains out. I had a pistol in my pocket, being quite new; I took it out; he did not then perceive me; I could not fire it off; I return'd it near my eye to see whether I had got my finger on the guard or the trigger; then he perceived me. Upon seeing it, he said, you rascal come down, or I'll blow your brains out. He rode round the coach, fearing he should shoot the coachman. I said to the coachman, for God's sake get down; which he did. The robber rode round the coach, and swore he'd blow my brains out; and I ordered the robber, as he came round, to fire at me.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you order him to fire?</p>
               <p>Robertson. I thought I should have the better chance to fire last. He would not fire. Immediately I fired at him; and he directly fired at the same time. I did say I hit him; but I can't be certain; I suppose I did. His ball went thro' the right shoulder of my coat and waistcoat, and just graz'd, my shoulder. (He shew'd the hole in his coat, having it on.) Immediately I jump'd from the box, on the near side; and he jump'd his horse over the ditch by the road-side, and turned his horse's head about towards the coach again; I ran round the horses, and attack'd him on the other side, and pull'd out my other pistol; I talk'd much to him; he did not say much; then he shot at me a second time; his ball went just by my body, as I was between him and the coach, and swore he should not rob the coach. That ball graz'd under the coach wheel. Then I said I am your master now; you have got no more powder and ball.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was he at that time to you?</p>
               <p>Robertson . He was about ten yards from the coach, and I was between that and him. Immediately he pull'd out a third pistol, and shot at me a third time. That ball fell into a little puddle of water, and, thanks to God, did not hit me. Then immediately he rode off, and I call'd him many names as he rode. Then I got up on the coach-box, and we went on; and I can give no farther account.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the man that fired at you?</p>
               <p>Robertson. I can't say the prisoner is the man; for I did not see his face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person45">
                  Thomas 
                  Cogdel 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person45" type="surname" value="Cogdel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person45" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There came a gentleman riding after the prisoner, and call'd, Stop highwayman.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Cogdel. This was at East-Barnet . I followed the prisoner to Enfield-Chase . I went up to him, and bid him throw his pistols away; he said, he would not. I bid him throw them away three or four times; at last he said, young man come and take them. I was going up to him; he said, young man stop before you come any further; I did; then he said, will you not hurt me? I said, no; then I was going up to him; he said, stop before you come any further; and added, will you not let any of the others hurt me? I said they should not if I could help it; then he said, come and take them; which I did; there were three of them. (Produced in court, three horse pistols .) We took him to Barnet, to the justice's, and from thence to the sign of the Swan; there he lay all night.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. What time of the day did you take me?</p>
               <p>Cogdel. This was in the forenoon; I can't justly tell the time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person46">
                  James 
                  Lockey 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person46" type="surname" value="Lockey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person46" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of May I was, among others in pursuit of the prisoner from, East-Barnet to Enfield-Chase , where we took him.</p>
               <p>Q. About what time did you take him?</p>
               <p>Lockey. I believe it was about eight in the morning. We carried him to High-Barnet , before<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100004"></xptr> the justice. I did not see him examined there, being obliged to go and get my cloaths I had pulled off in the pursuit. Then I returned, and went to the prisoner at the Swan; there I saw his thigh cut in order to take out a ball.</p>
               <p>Q. What ball?</p>
               <p>Lockey . I shot him before he would be taken, in the pursuit. I saw Mr. Robertson before justice Fielding, and saw him shew the hole in his coat, where he said the highwayman shot him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person47">
                  James 
                  Swale 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person47" type="surname" value="Swale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person47" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 7th of May, about six in the morning, I was at work just by where the York coach was stopp'd on Finchley-Common . I heard a gun go off, and somewhat of a noise with it. I stepped about a yard or two, and look'd over some pales , and saw a man attacking the coach. I heard Mr. Roberson say to the man on horseback, sirrah , you rogue, you villain, you want to rob the coach, and you shall not. You are a highwayman, a thief. I saw Robertson fire once, and the prisoner two times.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Swale . The man that was taken was on the same horse, and I saw him upon the pursuit.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether the man's face was cover'd?</p>
               <p>Swale. I could not; I believe I was 200 yards from him.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he make off?</p>
               <p>Swale. He rode towards Brown's-Wells-Hill , coming towards London.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the horse he rode upon, and his cloaths.</p>
               <p>Swale . It was a bright bay lame horse, and he seemed to be in a darkish sort of a frock, with a hat not cock'd up, and a black wig. I went to my master, and call'd out, there is a man will rob, or has robb'd the coach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him after that?</p>
               <p>Swale . I did in about a quarter of an hour, upon Finchley-Common , making up to a wood.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that man was the man that had left the coach?</p>
               <p>Swale. I am sure he was the same. He went into the wood, and so did I. There were so many people about it, that he was obliged to forsake it, and I met him again on the side of the wood, the same man, and the same horse; then he made away for East-Barnet and Enfield-Chase . I could not run so fast as he rode. Two men on horseback began to follow him from the man hanging in chains on Finchley-Common , and I and the two witnesses that have been examined followed so far as Coney-hatch , and then went back again to my work.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the man when he came round the wood?</p>
               <p>Swale . I was not 200 yards from him; I once was within 50 yards of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were the persons that followed the man?</p>
               <p>Swale . One is 
               <persName id="t17550910-3-person48">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person48" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other 
               <persName id="t17550910-3-person49">
                  John 
                  Newil 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person49" type="surname" value="Newil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I could see them; he kept galloping , and they after him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person50">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person50" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person50" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was facing the man hanging in chains on Finchley-Common , and was shew'd the prisoner, and pursued him to the place where he was taken. There were a great many people round the wood; the man was described to me that had stopped the coach in another sort of a dress than the prisoner had on. He had on a loose brown great-coat , and a whitish wig; he was on a bayish sort of a horse.</p>
               <p>Q. to Swale. Had the man you saw a great-coat on?</p>
               <p>Swale. No; he had not when he left the coach; but when he came out of the wood he had a light loose great-coat on, and a light wig.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that this was the same man you saw before?</p>
               <p>Swale. It was the same horse, and the same size of a man, as nigh as I could guess.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the man's face?</p>
               <p>Swale. I did, when he went from the wood; he had no mask on then.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him before that day?</p>
               <p>Swale . No; I never did to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Swale . I am in the 74th year of my age.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know the horse?</p>
               <p>Swale. The horse had a little swish or wisk tail; a bay horse, and lame; the same that the man rode who attacked the coach.</p>
               <p>Taylor continues. I pursued the prisoner from that place to the place where he was taken. His horse broke his leg at East-Barnet , and we took him on Enfield-Chase . We carried him before a justice at Barnet; after that he was carried to the Swan at Barnet, and had his wound dressed.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part was he wounded?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He was wounded through the hand, and into the thigh.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100005"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person51">
                  John 
                  Newil 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person51" type="surname" value="Newil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person51" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . On the 7th of May I got up about six in the morning ; I was told there was a highwayman in the wood ; the man was described to me; I got my horse, and went.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the man described?</p>
               <p>Newil. To have a lightish sort of a coat on, and a horse with a swish tail. I went into the wood, but could see nothing of him. After I had been there some time, out came the prisoner . I was within sixty yards of him; he was dressed in a loose horseman's coat; he had the frock underneath it, as was described to me, as I imagined , and a grey wig on. I said to 
               <persName id="t17550910-3-person52">
                  William 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person52" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person52" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , that must be the man; we will follow him ; he turned about, and took out a pistol and swore if we followed him he'd blow our brains out. Then we turned back a little way , and followed him again, and went on to a place called Coney-hatch , then through a large wood; and as he was riding up a hill at East-Barnet, his horse broke his leg short in two. I rode and catched hold of his horse, and he jump'd off, and ran down a lane; I rode down after him; I was near him when he was taken. In the whole I believe I was six or seven miles after him; sometimes within an hundred yards of him, and sometimes less.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person53">
                  George 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person53" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person53" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work upon the Common that day, and was told a man had been firing at a coach. I was hewing of timber, and did not hear it. I saw his horse went lame. We pursued, and could track him by a bar-shoe. I also saw the prisoner's horse after he was dead, and he had a bar-shoe on.</p>
               <p>Kinga Brebrook . I saw the man attack the coach, and fire when he left it. I followed him to the wood.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed when he attacked the coach?</p>
               <p>Brebrook. I don't know. He was upon a bright bay horse, with a sort of a swish tail. When I lost sight of him I track'd him by a bar-shoe the horse had. When he came out of the wood again I was standing at the place where he went in.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in the wood?</p>
               <p>Brebrook . He came out I believe in about half an hour. I was in the path-way. I saw his face. He drew out one of his pistols, and carried it in his left-hand. I got out of the path to let him go by.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the same man that you had seen before?</p>
               <p>Brebrook. I can't say it was the same man, but it was the same horse that went into the wood. I followed him as far as Coney-hatch, but was not present when he was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>They have got another witness to call, that the coachman that drove the coach, and the constable.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you may call him, if you please</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Call 
               <persName id="t17550910-3-person54">
                  John 
                  Pooley 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person54" type="surname" value="Pooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he will tell the court the horse the man rode had a cut tail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person55">
                  John 
                  Pooley 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person55" type="surname" value="Pooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drove the York stage when it was stopp'd, as has been mentioned.</p>
               <p>C. Describe the horse the man rode on.</p>
               <p>Pooley. He was on a brown bay horse, with a swish tail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person56">
                  Richard 
                  Doubleday 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person56" type="surname" value="Doubleday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person56" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. Some time after the prisoner was committed we had an affair to settle with the overseers of Enfield parish. As my brother constable and I went there, while we were going along, I said we will call and see Jonathan's horse. We call'd at the sign of the Cat; the horse was in the stable there; he was a bayish gelding, with a black mane and tail, and to the best of my remembrance a cut tail.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at his shoes?</p>
               <p>Doubleday. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how long the tail had been cut?</p>
               <p>Doubleday . I don't.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you acquainted with the circumstance of the bar-shoe then?</p>

               <p>Doubleday. No; I was not.</p>
               <p>Humphry Buckle. My brother constable and I going towards Enfield, we called at East-Barnet on purpose to take the marks and colour of the horse.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Buckle. This was about seven days after the prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before the horse was kill'd?</p>
               <p>Buckle. It was. I saw him; it was a bay horse, with a cut black tail.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was cut?</p>
               <p>Buckle . I suppose it was cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it or was it not cut?</p>
               <p>Buckle . It was, but not that day.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I know that; it had been cut some time before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before?</p>
               <p>Buckle. Some time.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it been cut a week?</p>
               <p>Buckle. Above a week, or a fortnight, or a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100006"></xptr> month either . Here has been many people examined here that don't know a horse from a cow, except by the horns. I get my bread by buying and selling horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I keep a publick house; my character is fairish .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine about the bar shoe?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I know nothing of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person57">
                  James 
                  Lockey 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person57" type="surname" value="Lockey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person57" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . This can't be true. We killed the horse in three days after the prisoner was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That man shot me in the hand, and in the thigh, both at one time.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor looked at the three pistols. I will swear these are the three pistols that were shot off at me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person58">
                  Thomas 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person58" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person58" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner five or six years; he once kept a publick house in Fleet-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>Palmer. He has so good a character, that was he out now, I would lend him a hundred pounds. I never thought him capable of doing such an act as he is charged with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person59">
                  William 
                  Megers 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person59" type="surname" value="Megers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person59" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him ten or twelve years; he has a very good character as ever I heard a man have in my life. I never heard anything bad of him. He has dealt with me for many a pound. He lived in Fleet-lane. I used to look upon him as a man of substance.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Megers . I am a butcher.</p>
               <p>Mr. Porter . I have known him about nine years; he was a very good neighbour, and bore the character of an honest man; I don't believe he would be guilty of shooting at a man; neither will any of my neighbours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person60">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person60" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person60" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I have known him nine or ten years; he always bore a very good character as ever I heard in my life. I looked upon him to be a man of substance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person61">
                  Thomas 
                  Holding 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person61" type="surname" value="Holding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person61" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years; he bears a very good character. I have earned many a pound of him; I don't think him guilty of this fact.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him when he kept a publick house?</p>
               <p>Holding. No; he has not kept a publick house this five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What business has he followed within these five years?</p>
               <p>Holding . I can't say what business he follow'd this last five years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Palmer. What became of the prisoner when he left the alehouse?</p>
               <p>Palmer. When he left the alehouse he married a widow, and she and her mother lived together. They had an estate, and lived on their substance . Since that, he used the Bull-and-Gatter in Fleet-market.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that estate per year?</p>
               <p>Palmer . I have heard it was about 40 l. per year. I know he sold some of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear he was employed in any other way?</p>
               <p>Palmer. No; I never heard what else he was employed in?</p>
               <p>Q. to Holding. In what business have you earn'd many a pound of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Holding. I earned 20 l. of him in my way.</p>
               <p>Q. In what?</p>
               <p>Holding. In scouring cloaths for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-3-person62">
                  Cornelius 
                  Molear 
               <interp inst="t17550910-3-person62" type="surname" value="Molear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person62" type="given" value="Cornelius"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four years last past; he lived in Bell-savage-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a house there?</p>
               <p>Molear. He was a lodger, I believe. I was pretty frequently in his company. I look'd upon him to be a man of a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550910-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550910-3-punish15" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-3-punish15" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-3-defend41 t17550910-3-punish15"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
