<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-45">
               <interp inst="t17570420-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-45" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-45" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-45-off243-c436" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-45-defend519 t17570420-45-off243 t17570420-45-verdict246"></join>
         
               <p>192. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-45-defend519" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Gaul 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-45-defend519" type="surname" value="Gaul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-defend519" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-defend519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570420-45-off243" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-off243" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-off243" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, in a certain field and open place near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570420-45-victim521" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Wright 
                        <interp inst="t17570420-45-victim521" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-45-victim521" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-45-victim521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-45-off243 t17570420-45-victim521"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one pair of silver buckles, value 8 s. one hat, value 1 s. and 3 s. in money number'd, the property of the said James
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570420-45-cd244" type="crimeDate">January 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-45-off243 t17570420-45-cd244"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-45-person522">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-45-person522" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-person522" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming home by <placeName id="t17570420-45-crimeloc245">Pancras</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-45-crimeloc245" type="placeName" value="Pancras"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-45-crimeloc245" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-45-off243 t17570420-45-crimeloc245"></join>, and was stop'd by two men on Sunday night between five and six o'clock, about twelve weeks ago; one of them went to stop me, and I ran away from him; the other then appear'd and threw me down, and kneel'd on my stomach; I could perceive he was in soldiers cloaths, but it was so dark, that I can't swear to the men. He took from me 3 s. and a key, my silver buckles and my hat; one of them said we have got your key, that will be of no use to us. I said gentlemen it is to me, and I hope you'll let me have it again; then one of them put it in my pocket again.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you ever see any of your other things since?</p>

               <p>Wright. No, I have not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did they say any thing to you when you was down ?</p>

               <p>Wright. He that threw me down pull'd a hanger out of his bosom, and said, D - n you, the least resistance your life; they were both together then, and after they had rob'd me they said, D - n you, if you follow us, your life still.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to take them up?</p>

               <p>Wright. The Monday morning after I was rob'd I went to justice Fielding's, and told him the case, and he gave me a paper to go and put it in the news, and after the prisoner and Randall were taken up I was order'd to go to justice Fielding's, where Randall was examined, and the justice order'd me to prosecute.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the prisoner make any confession?</p>

               <p>Wright. No, not as I know of.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-45-person523">
                  William 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17570420-45-person523" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-person523" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I together committed this robbery on Sunday evening, just on this side Pancras.</p>

               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>

               <p>Randall. I can't justly say, it may be about three months, it was a very dark foggy evening, between five and six o'clock I believe.</p>

               <p>Q. Are you sure the prosecutor is the man?</p>

               <p>Randall. I look'd in his face, he seem'd to be a very fresh colour'd man. Gaul went to stop him first, he ran away from him, and I ran and laid hold on him, and threw him down. Gaul came up directly. I took 3 s. out of his pocket, and his hat and buckles; there was a key, which I put in his pocket again, as he was on the ground.</p>

               <p>Q. What did the prisoner do?</p>

               <p>Randall. He stood close by me with his hanger drawn, and said he'd cut his head in two if he made any resistance.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you do with the buckles?</p>

               <p>Randall. We sold them almost by Westminster-Bridge the next morning, and we sold the hat to an old cloaths woman.</p>



               <p>Q. When was you taken up?</p>

               <p>Randall. Six weeks ago next Saturday, and the prisoner was the same night, upon my information.</p>

               <p>Q. How long was this before you was taken up?</p>

               <p>Randall. I can't justly tell.</p>

               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What sort of a night was it when you were rob'd?</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. It was a very foggy night, there has not been it's like this year.</p>

               <p>Q. When the prisoner stood over you did you hear any body say they would cut your head in two?</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. They did say some words, but in my fright I cannot say what.</p>

               <p>Q. Could you distinguish either of their voices?</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. No, I could not so as to know them, not their faces neither.</p>

               <p>Q. to Randall. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>

               <p>Randall. Ever since I have been a soldier.</p>

               <p>Q. Has he always had the impediment in his speech he has now? He stammer'd very much.</p>

               <p>Randall. Not quite so much when I first knew him, but he always had an impediment in his speech.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>

               <p>I know nothing at all of it.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200067"></xptr>Q. to prosecutor. Did you hear the prisoner speak before justice Fielding?</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. No, I only heard Randall say he and another did it.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-45-verdict246" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-45-verdict246" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
