<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-44">
               <interp inst="t17580913-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-44" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-44" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-44-off229-c331" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-defend414 t17580913-44-off229 t17580913-44-verdict234"></join>
         
               <p>301. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-defend414" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-44-defend414" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-defend414" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-defend414" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17580913-44-deflabel228" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-defend414 t17580913-44-deflabel228"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-44-off229" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-off229" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-off229" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing six muslin handkerchiefs, value 3 s. 6 d. two pair of muslin ruffles, value 2 s. 6 d. three linen aprons, thirteen linen night caps, one pair of silk mittens, one pair of cotton gloves, one pair of worsted stockings, sixty yards of linen binding, two ounces of thread, three quarters of a pound weight of tea, two pound of sugar, and 1 s. 6 d. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-victim416" type="victimName">
                     Catharine 
                     Westcome 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-44-victim416" type="surname" value="Westcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-victim416" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-victim416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-off229 t17580913-44-victim416"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580913-44-viclabel230" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-victim416 t17580913-44-viclabel230"></join>, <rs id="t17580913-44-cd231" type="crimeDate">July 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-off229 t17580913-44-cd231"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130038"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-person417">
                  Catharine 
                  Westcome 
               <interp inst="t17580913-44-person417" type="surname" value="Westcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person417" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17580913-44-crimeloc232">King's-head court, Beech-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-44-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="King's-head court, Beech-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-44-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-off229 t17580913-44-crimeloc232"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Westcome. <rs id="t17580913-44-viclabel233" type="occupation">I keep a chandler's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-victim416 t17580913-44-viclabel233"></join>; on the 9th of July my house was broke open; in the morning I was alarmed by a neighbour; I got up and found the window shutter broke, and a box that I used to keep under my counter, was standing upon the counter; and a cupboard by the counter was broke open, my tea and sugar were taken out of my canisters; I missed two muslin handkerchiefs, a pair of silk mittens, a black silk handkerchief, a pair of cotton gloves, a pair of stockings, these were taken out of the box; I missed also two double muslin handkerchiefs, two single handkerchiefs, and one dozen of caps from out of the cupboard; three white aprons, taken from under the counter, and some thread and binding, and about three quarters of a pound of tea, and about two pounds of sugar, and eighteen pence in half-pence from out of the till.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the till left open?</p>
               <p>Westcome. I was never lock'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure all these things were in your house when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Westcome. I am positive they were, which was after 12 being on a Saturday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Westcome. She had a lodging in White-cross-street, and she was very well acquainted with the house, for she was brought up in it, I did not in the least suspect her, but my neighbours told me they saw her with some of my things, and her brother's daughter charged her with some of them on her back. When I took her up I found an apron of mine upon her; (produced in court and deposed to,) she owned before justice Keeling that this was one of my aprons, but said it was brought to her after my house was broke open. Mr. Parrot has some things here, that were in my box, which he found in her room; (produced in court,) two pieces of binding, some fine thread, and two handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. How was your window fastened?</p>
               <p>Westcome. I fastened it with an iron bolt and key, and I found the sash open, and the shutter hanging by one hinge.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine the prisoner has strength sufficient to break it in that manner ?</p>
               <p>Westcome. It needed not a great deal of strength, but I believe she could not possibly do it herself.</p>
               <p>Mr. Parrot. The prisoner rented a room of me in White-cross-street, on the 26th of July, in the morning; I had word that she was going away, I went and seized upon the things that were left; while I was taking an inventory of them, the prisoner's brother, and her niece, and the prosecutrix came into the room; the prisoner, upon seeing the prosecutrix coming into the room, made a frivolous excuse to go down, and then went away; the things mentioned by the prosecutrix I found in the prisoner's room, and the prosecutrix claimed them as her own.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was with Mrs. Westcome with a person that was ill, that person made me a present of the apron, and some caps, because I was so tender of her; I know nothing of the house being broke open; as to the tapes, I deal in needle-work, and buy my tapes at the best hand.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutrix. Did she nurse a person at your house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. She did; it was a relation of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before your house was broke open?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I believe two months before.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure these caps and things were in your house the night before your house was broke open?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I am positive they were.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-person418">
                  Ann 
                  Millington 
               <interp inst="t17580913-44-person418" type="surname" value="Millington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person418" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person418" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 8 or 9 years, I never knew any ill of her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she do for a livelihood?</p>
               <p>Millington. She used to go to service, and when she was out of place then she weaved gimp in the loom.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-person419">
                  Robert 
                  Linsey 
               <interp inst="t17580913-44-person419" type="surname" value="Linsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person419" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from a child, she always behaved very just to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her down to this time?</p>
               <p>Linsey. I have not known her these 3 or 4 years since she has been at service.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-44-person420">
                  Mary 
                  Hurt 
               <interp inst="t17580913-44-person420" type="surname" value="Hurt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person420" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-person420" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 6 months, she lived in the house with me; I never knew any thing amiss of her; but, surely, I did see a quantity of tea and sugar in her apartment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-44-verdict234" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-verdict234" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-verdict234" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-44-punish235" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-punish235" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-44-punish235" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-44-defend414 t17580913-44-punish235"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
