<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-42">
               <interp inst="t17561208-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-42" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-42" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-42-off210-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-42-defend346 t17561208-42-off210 t17561208-42-verdict214"></join>
         
               <p>48. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17561208-42-defend346" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Brannock 
               <interp inst="t17561208-42-defend346" type="surname" value="Brannock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-defend346" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-defend346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17561208-42-off210" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-off210" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-off210" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of leather pumps, value is. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-42-victim348" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Murray 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-42-victim348" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-victim348" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-victim348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-42-off210 t17561208-42-victim348"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17561208-42-cd211" type="crimeDate">Nov. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-42-off210 t17561208-42-cd211"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-42-person349">
                  James 
                  Murray 
               <interp inst="t17561208-42-person349" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-person349" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner worked with me as a <rs id="t17561208-42-deflabel212" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-42-defend346 t17561208-42-deflabel212"></join>
               </p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Murray. I am a <rs id="t17561208-42-viclabel213" type="occupation">shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-42-victim348 t17561208-42-viclabel213"></join>; on the 30th of November he went out about eight o'clock, and return'd about four in the afternoon; he took these two pumps, and put one in each pocket. I followed him and took him with them upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him put them into his pocket ?</p>
               <p>Murray. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say when you charg'd him with them ?</p>
               <p>Murray. I asked him what he had got in his pockets, he said nothing at all. I brought him back to my shop, and from thence to Justice Fielding, and he was committed to New-Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself when he was before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Murray. When he was examin'd there, he own'd he took them.</p>
               <p>Q. In what words did he own it.</p>
               <p>Murray. He said he took the pumps ( the pumps produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came into the shop in the evening, in order to shut it up and take in the goods and things. I had these shoes in my hand, and I went to make water; so I put them under my apron, and he came and said I was going to rob him.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-42-person350">
                  Nicholas 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17561208-42-person350" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-person350" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he was in short coats. I never heard or knew of any thing that touch'd his character; he work'd for me some time. I don't know that ever I had any room to suspect him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Griffith. I am a shoemaker, I have trusted him several times to shut up my shop, and I have some scores of dozens of shoes at times; he might have wrong'd me of many had he been so minded, and I never missed them.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of him now?</p>
               <p>Griffith. I would employ him again was he out of his trouble, to-morrow if the court please.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known him 16 years, in all that time I never heard any ill of him till now.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080032"></xptr>Q. What has been his general character ?</p>
               <p>Witness. That of an honest lad.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you employ him again, was he at liberty?</p>
               <p>Witness. I would in my way.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known him 7 years, I have trusted him, and never found him wrong me of the value of a pin in my life. I would trust him again to-morrow, was he out of his trouble.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I have known him from his mother's arms, he always bore a good character; I never heard any ill of him in my life. I am worth a hundred pounds. I could trust him with it all, was he out of his trouble.</p>
               <p>A Witness. The prisoner has work'd with me about a year. I never missed any thing, or heard an ill character of him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Witness. I have known him 14 years, if I had five thousand pounds I'd trust him with it this minute, was he out of trouble.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I was at the birth of the prisoner, and have known him ever since; his parents died when he was very young. I kept him four or five years; he was very just. I never found any thing deficient by him in my life, nor heard of any thing ill of him before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-42-verdict214" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-42-verdict214" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
