<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-22">
               <interp inst="t17580113-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-22" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-22" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-22-off130-c190" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend229 t17580113-22-off130 t17580113-22-verdict134"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-22-off130-c191" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend231 t17580113-22-off130 t17580113-22-verdict135"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-22-off130-c192" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend233 t17580113-22-off130 t17580113-22-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>81, 82, 83. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17580113-22-defend229" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Sleep 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend229" type="surname" value="Sleep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend229" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-defend231" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Laws 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend231" type="surname" value="Laws"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend231" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-defend233" type="defendantName">
                     Matth.ew 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend233" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend233" type="given" value="Matth.ew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-defend233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17580113-22-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               deceitfully and unlawfully forging and counterfeiting a moidore, being the foreign gold of Portugal, and not current, by proclamation, in this kingdom, against their allegiance, and against the form of the statute
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person234">
                  William 
                  Backhouse 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person234" type="surname" value="Backhouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person234" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17580113-22-person235">
                  James 
                  Sleep 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person235" type="surname" value="Sleep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person235" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             upwards of two months before the accident happen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. He is a <rs id="t17580113-22-deflabel131" type="occupation">jeweller</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend229 t17580113-22-deflabel131"></join>, and pass'd for such; but I know nothing of the manner of his carrying on his trade.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Johnson?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I have known him about two years; he was <rs id="t17580113-22-deflabel132" type="occupation">a publican, but latterly past for a shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend233 t17580113-22-deflabel132"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he keep a publick shep?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Not openly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Laws?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I have known him about eight years; he appeared to carry on the business of a <rs id="t17580113-22-deflabel133" type="occupation">truss-maker, in Birmingham</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend231 t17580113-22-deflabel133"></join>, and I was acquainted with him before I came from thence. I was here about five years before he came. I had a press in my possession, and he and Sleep made application to me for it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. It was about two months before the accident happened. They thought they could manage the dye for a moidore, so I submitted to it. We proceeded, and struck the first impression of a moidore by a cast metal blank.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at the doing this?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Sleep and I were present.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the metal, the manner of preparing it, and by whom prepared ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. In a moidore we weigh'd eighteen shillings in gold.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you call we ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I mean all the prisoners and myself. The next was a composition of silver and copper, I believe about three grains of copper in a moidore, and the rest was silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this prepared?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. At Mr. Laws's house, in Castle-Street, Oxford Market. After the metal was weigh'd it was melted at his house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were concerned in that?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. We all four were.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the house was it done in?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. In the low kitchen, in a crucible, in what we call a Dutch slove. We melted it into blanks in an iron pair of moulds.</p>
               <p>Q. What size was a blank ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I believe they are to be produced. I delivered them up; they were to sit the dye, which is the size of a moidore.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done next?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Then they were filed to the weight; and after they were polished and filed they were corded round the edge, and colour'd by a proper colour. It was a mixture of chymical things that made them of a high colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you weigh them?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. At Law's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the scales with which they were weighed?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I believe I should, was I to see them.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these scales. (A pair of scales produced.)</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I cannot be positive whether they belong to Mr. Sleep or Mr. Laws. These are not the scales they were weigh'd with: I know<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130023"></xptr> Mr. Sleep had a pair which were in Mr. Laws's room, and the weights were made of lead.</p>
               <p>Q. When you had prepared them, where did you strike them ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. We struck them at my house.</p>
               <p>Q When and where did you hitch the edges?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. They were done, before they were colour'd, at Law's house.</p>
               <p>Q Who hitched them?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Mr. Sleep did with a file, which is what I mean by corded.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at the striking them off?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I believe Mr. Laws might be by once; but Sleep and Johnson were always by to assist</p>
               <p>Q What was the manner of striking them?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. The dyes were fixed in the press, and the blank la in; then there were obliged to be two or three at the sly to give the impression; that is, to give them a sufficient squeeze to do it.</p>

               <p>Q. Who get generally did this?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Sleep, Johnson, and myself; Sleep and I were most in it.</p>
               <p>Q Where were the dyes kept?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. In Mr Laws's possession.</p>
               <p>Q Who was at the expence of this ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I believe we were all at part of the expence.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been carrying on this practice ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. As to Mr. Sleep and Mr. Johnson I was but very little acquainted with them, 'till about two months before this accident happen'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did you make at a time?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Forty or upwards; we all had shares. I always took what was my share, and they the same. Every one put in his complement of money to buy the gold, and every one took their proportion of the money.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the dyes?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I had a little trouble on a very innocent affair, on account of a little iron that I bought, and which I was in trouble about Mr. Johnson went to put off a moidore to one Davis, and he was stop'd. After that he went to Laws's house, and told him of it; he took one of the dyes and threw it into the value, and the other they buried in the garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Who first gave information of this before a magistrate ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination</p>
               <p>Council. You seem to have but very slight acquaintance with Sleep.</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you in custody before you made information?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what account?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Upon suspicion of making moidores and halfpence.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in New-Prison?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. Yes. A man took my dyes out of my house, and Mr. Fielding was so good as to admit me an evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you charged with some felony?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What never?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. No, only what I mention'd before; I was accused about some iron.</p>
               <p>Q What, of stealing it?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. No; it was of receiving it, knowing it to have been stolen; but it was proved that I was innocent.</p>
               <p>Q Was you tried for it?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at large when you made information of this affair?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say that Laws was ever present when you struck them ?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I cannot take upon me to say he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose press was it?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. It was mine and another person's that is dead</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you had it?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. We purchased it upwards of three years before I had any connection with the prisoners at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your intent when you purchased it?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. With intent to follow the button business.</p>
               <p>Q. What use did you make of it before you practised with the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I had made use of it in making some half-pence.</p>
               <p>Harry Davis I am a shoemaker. I live in Hanover-Yard, near Great Russel Street, Bloomsbury. To the best of my remembrance the prisoner Johnson came on the 30th of August last to my shop to buy a pair of child's pamps. He asked me the price I told him; we very soon agreed, and he pull'd out a moidore to pay for them. Having had a good deal of trouble in taking some gold too light, I had got me a pair of scales and weights. I weigh'd his piece, and found it was within 9 d.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130024"></xptr> of weight. I was in a little hurry, and pull'd out a guinea, and gave him in change, which he took and put in his pocket. Then I cast my eye upon the moidore, more by accident than otherwise, and I thought it look'd odd. I said, friend, where do you live, I wish this may be a good one; he said just by, and after I had ask'd him two or three times over, he said he liv'd in Chapel street, Oxford Road, to the best of my memory - pray what is your name - Johnson, said he. I sent my boy with it to get it chang'd, and to see if it was a good one. Johnson sat all the time in my shop. The boy return'd, and said it was a counterfeit. Then I asked Johnson if he consider'd the consequence of putting off bad money, and told him it was in my power to stop him. He look the guinea out of his pocket that I had given him in part of the change, and laid it down. I let him go, and he took the piece of money with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person236">
                  William 
                  Marsdon 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person236" type="surname" value="Marsdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Backhouse was taken up by Mr. Fielding's directions, he gave information against many (some not yet taken.) I went with Mr. Chamberlaine the solicitor of the Mint, and I believe about half a dozen constables (I think it was about the beginning of September) to Laws's house in Castle-street, Oxford Market. We had a great deal of difficulty to get into the house. The people denied him, and said he was in the country, but when we did get in, we found him in bed, then they said he was very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he ill?</p>
               <p>Marsden. He might be so for what I know. We searched the house, and in a little back kitchen we found a stove, and in it a crucible (produced in court) the stove seemed to be made of pipe maker's clay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing above stairs?</p>
               <p>Marsden. These files (producing two files ) they appear to have gold in the teeth of them. The solicitor of the Mint, and all of us thought it to be gold. There was a working bench and a paper of these sort of files that had not been used.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing else ?</p>
               <p>Marsden. There was something in the stove that some of them said belong'd to the melting way.</p>
               <p>Q. Who said so?</p>
               <p>Marsden. Backhouse or some of them that were with us.</p>
               <p>Q. to Backhouse. What was that?</p>
               <p>Backhouse. I can't tell what it was.</p>
               <p>Marsden. We found also a pair of scales and weights. After we had searched the house, we lock'd the door, and brought Laws and his son to Mr. Fielding's. He was examined and committed, and the boy was a great deal frighten'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Backhouse examined?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I did. He gave information of a dye being hid in the garden. The boy said he could take us directly to the place, at a border of the garden. Mr. Churchman and I went with the boy, and with an old fire shovel by his direction we dug and found it in a minute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person237">
                  William 
                  Churchman 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person237" type="surname" value="Churchman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is the dye [producing one] which we found in Laws's garden, I have had it in my custody ever since; it will make the impression for one side of a moidore.</p>
               <p>Q. to Backhouse. Look upon this, and give an account what it is.</p>
               <p>Backhouse. This is one of the dyes that we used in my cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person238">
                  Nicholas 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person238" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person238" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of September in the morning a person came and told me he had been in company with a woman at the Sash in Chiswell-Street, who acquainted him that a man lived there who made moidores and halfpence I went there, but miss'd of Backhouse, he being gone to my house in the Tower.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>

               <p>Kemp. I belong to the Mint-office. After he had given his information, we went to Johnson's house on the 9th in the evening, and they said he was gone to Carnaby-market. We went away, and came again to inquire for him, when the people said he had been in bed an hour and a half. As we were suspicious they had before deny'd him, we knock'd a considerable time, at last the door was open'd, when we brush'd into the house and up stairs, where we found him in bed with a woman. Finding nothing in that room, I ask'd him where his work-shop was, and found he was a child's pump maker. I went thither, and found some crucibles (producing them) gold weights and scales, which I have not about me, and a wooden screw press to confine the flasks together, in order to pour the metal in from the crucible, to make the blanks, ( producing it.) I found also sand for moulding, and several instruments made use of in order to make counterfeit money.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect what you know relating to Sleep and Laws.</p>
               <p>Kemp. We went to Laws about one in the morning, we got in with some difficulty, and found some implements belonging to his business. The only thing I have to say about him is, that being asked before Mr. Fielding concerning the moidore dye, he own'd he did repair it for Mr. Sleep, if he died or came into any dilemma about it, and said somewhat<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130025"></xptr> about letting them know something, if they would let him be an evidence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nicholas. I am a moneyer, and belong to the Mint.</p>
               <p>Q. What is a moneyer?</p>
               <p>Nicholas. One that coins money.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this press. (Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Nicholas. I did see it before at Mr. Kemp's. (He looks as it again.)</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a press sufficient to strike moidores?</p>
               <p>Nicholas. Yes, I think it is; I think it may be used with different dyes for any sort of coinage whatever; it is not exactly the same with ours (I am speaking of the press and fly ) but it may answer the same end.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person239">
                  John 
                  Coe 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person239" type="surname" value="Coe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Here is one of the moidores which I took of Mrs. Hust's servant.</p>
               <p>Backhouse. 
               <persName id="t17580113-22-person240">
                  Ann 
                  Grandam 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person240" type="surname" value="Grandam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person240" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             changed this?</p>
               <p>Coe. I did not know it was bad 'till justice Fielding sent to me, he having information of it.</p>
               <p>Sleep's Defence.</p>
               <p>My first acquaintance with Backhouse was through Mr Laws. In regard to what he has said I never shared any moidores with him in my life, nor never made any. Backhouse has not known me above three weeks, from first to the last of my being taken up.</p>
               <p>To Johnson's Character.</p>
               <p>Humphry Spencer. I know Johnson; he lived in my house, and was a shoemaker.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Spencer. He behaved like a very honest industrious man, and always kept close to his work.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since he lived in your house?</p>
               <p>Spencer. It is about two months ago since he quitted it; he was in it when he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any crucibles, or any of these sort of things in your house?</p>
               <p>Spencer. No, never before the search was made; I know nothing of the use of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person241">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person241" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person241" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>E. Davis. He was always very honest, and kept very close to his work; I was with him early and late.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any crucibles, or melting pots in his apartment ?</p>
               <p>E. Davis. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person242">
                  Robert 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person242" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person242" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Johnson about fourteen years, and he once lodged in my house; during that time he was an honest pains-taking man.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he live in your house?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He went from my house about eleven or twelve years ago, to keep an alehouse; the Cock in Old-Street-Square. I have taken money of him, and I never took any that was bad.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him last?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I have not seen him these two years before I saw him last sessions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person243">
                  Henry 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person243" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person243" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these nine or ten years; he has owed me money, and paid me honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Harrison. A very good one. I never heard any thing that was dishonest of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person244">
                  Alexander 
                  Parks 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person244" type="surname" value="Parks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person244" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these ten years, and I always thought him a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person245">
                  Michael 
                  Bilson 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person245" type="surname" value="Bilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person245" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these ten years, down to this time.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him lately?</p>
               <p>Bilson. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Bilson. That of a good husband, a good father, and an honest man. I never heard any thing against his character before this charge.</p>
               <p>For Laws.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person246">
                  James 
                  Bradley 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person246" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person246" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have employed Laws about two years, 'till the time he was taken up. I have trusted him with jewels to the value of fourteen or fifteen pounds. He was always very industrious.</p>
               <p>For Sleep.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person247">
                  Benjamin 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person247" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person247" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Sleep work'd for me about two years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I never heard any harm of him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he done work for you lately?</p>
               <p>Lucas. He has within this year and half, or two years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person248">
                  Edward 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person248" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person248" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He has work'd for me about two years on and off.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>More. I never heard any harm of him before. After he was in custody he returned me about 40 s. worth of things by his wife.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130026"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-22-person249">
                  John 
                  Sansom 
               <interp inst="t17580113-22-person249" type="surname" value="Sansom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these twelve years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>Sansom. I never heard any harm of him before this.</p>
               <p>Sleep and Johnson <rs id="t17580113-22-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Laws <rs id="t17580113-22-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, ( haveing done nothing in London, but is to be tried next sessions by the Middlesex jury.)</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-22-punish136" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-punish136" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-punish136" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend229 t17580113-22-punish136"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend233 t17580113-22-punish136"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-22-punish137" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-punish137" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-22-punish137" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="forfeiture"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend229 t17580113-22-punish137"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-22-defend233 t17580113-22-punish137"></join>
               
                     <note>[Forfeiture of lands and goods. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
