<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530111-34">
               <interp inst="t17530111-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-34" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530111"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-34" type="date" value="17530111"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530111-34-off169-c363" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-34-defend429 t17530111-34-off169 t17530111-34-verdict173"></join>
         
               <p>9 (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530111-34-defend429" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Canniford 
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-defend429" type="surname" value="Canniford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-defend429" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-defend429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17530111-34-off169" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-off169" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-off169" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 40 pair of silver buckles with iron chases, value 17 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17530111-34-victim431" type="victimName">
                     Jacob 
                     Levi 
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-victim431" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-victim431" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-victim431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-34-off169 t17530111-34-victim431"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17530111-34-cd170" type="crimeDate">Nov. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-34-off169 t17530111-34-cd170"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-34-person432">
                  Jacob 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17530111-34-person432" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person432" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of November I sent a box of silver buckles with iron clasps, and they weighed 57 7dwt. chases and all, <placeName id="t17530111-34-crimeloc171">from Hounsditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-crimeloc171" type="placeName" value="from Hounsditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-crimeloc171" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-34-off169 t17530111-34-crimeloc171"></join>, where I live, to the book-keeper at the <placeName id="t17530111-34-crimeloc172">Saracen's Head in Friday-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="Saracen's Head in Friday-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-34-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-34-off169 t17530111-34-crimeloc172"></join>, to go by the coach Exeter.</p>

               <p>Q. Who did you send them by?</p>
               <p>Levi. I sent them by one 
               <persName id="t17530111-34-person433">
                  Mordecai 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17530111-34-person433" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person433" type="given" value="Mordecai"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a servant of mine, who is very ill at home; after that I received a letter from Mr. Coffin, telling me he was surprized he had not received them according to advice.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them since?</p>
               <p>Levi. I have, the box and some of the buckles at justice Fielding's, about a fortnight after I sent them.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Levi. At that time before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>(He is shewn a deal box, and some silver buckles, with iron chases in it.)</p>
               <p>Levi. I can swear to the box, and the buckles are like them which I sent, they are mine to the best of my knowledge, but I don't swear to them, because one buckle may be like another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-34-person434">
                  Richard 
                  Twaling 
               <interp inst="t17530111-34-person434" type="surname" value="Twaling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person434" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my shop the 30th of November, and brought a pair of buckles, which he offered to sell to my wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Twaling. I live under Gray's-Inn-gate, aad keep a cutler's shop. I happened not to be at home at the time; he was to come again, then I was at home, he brought two pair of silver shoe buckles and one of knee buckles ; I was sensible he could not come honestly by them by the price he offered them at, so stopped him and them. I asked him how he came by them, and he told me his father was a labourer at Exeter, and that he had given him about eight or nine pair of such in order to defray his charges up to town; he said also that his father dealt in such things. When I got him to the publick house he confessed how he came by them; he said he lived with Mr. Merryweather, who keeps the Saracen's-Head in Friday street, that he found the box in the yard; them I sent for Mr. Merryweather in order for him to enquire of the book-keeper if there was such a box there directed to go to Exeter; in the mean time he had given me the key of his box, and I went to the place where he had taken lodgings by his directions at a gunsmith's, and searched his box, and found this box with buckles in it, which is here produced; he told me likewise he had sold seven pair of the silver shoe buckles and one of knees to Mr. Baskervile in Fleet-Street; he told me also there were some stopped in the Strand, and that he had sold one pair of shoe and one of knee buckles in Holborn; and when his master came he confessed the same to him, but to the last he said he found the box in the yard, so I detained them there.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pair of buckles did you find in his box?</p>
               <p>Twaling. I found thirteen pair of shoes and four of knees.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-34-person435">
                  John 
                  Belchamber 
               <interp inst="t17530111-34-person435" type="surname" value="Belchamber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person435" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of November this box was delivered to me by Mr. Levi's man.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. I am tapster at the Saracen's-Head in Friday street, and book-keeper to the Exeter stage-coach.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the box after you received it?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. I put it into the warehouse, that is, on purpose for that coach.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it out of the warehouse?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. What, was the prisoner at the inn?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. He was under ostler.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he go away?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. I believe he went away on the Thursday morning following.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the Exeter stage-coach set out from the inn?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. It set out on the Monday morning about five o'clock, being the 27th.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the parcel go with the coach ?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. It did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175301110036"></xptr>Belchamber. I never missed it till such time that the porter came to me on Thursday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the parcel booked?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. It never was a rule to book these things; we never book half what comes for the coach.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>These buckles lay under the dung in the yard broke all to pieces, and I took it up as I was moving of the litter on the Monday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. to Belchamber. Was the warehouse door locked ?</p>
               <p>Belchamber. There is no lock at all upon the door, for has been for this half year.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530111-34-verdict173" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530111-34-verdict173" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
