<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570223-28">
               <interp inst="t17570223-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-28" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-28" type="date" value="17570223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570223-28-off158-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-28-defend331 t17570223-28-off158 t17570223-28-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>122 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570223-28-defend331" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17570223-28-defend331" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-defend331" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-defend331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570223-28-deflabel157" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-28-defend331 t17570223-28-deflabel157"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570223-28-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one gold watch with a gold chain, and three seals set in gold, value 22 l. and one gold ring, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570223-28-victim333" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Banti 
                        <interp inst="t17570223-28-victim333" type="surname" value="Banti"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-28-victim333" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-28-victim333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-28-off158 t17570223-28-victim333"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor was a foreigner, and not speaking English 
               <persName id="t17570223-28-person334">
                  John 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17570223-28-person334" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person334" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sworn interpreter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-28-person335">
                  James 
                  Banti 
               <interp inst="t17570223-28-person335" type="surname" value="Banti"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person335" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am from Florence. I lost my watch with a gold chain, three seals, and a gold ring, which hung to it as a seal.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose it ?</p>
               <p>Banti. In <placeName id="t17570223-28-crimeloc159">the Bavarian ambassador's chapel, by Golden Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570223-28-crimeloc159" type="placeName" value="the Bavarian ambassador's chapel, by Golden Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570223-28-crimeloc159" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-28-off158 t17570223-28-crimeloc159"></join>. On a Sunday, twelve days ago, it was pick'd out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get it again?</p>
               <p>Banti. Yes. Justice Fielding advertised it the day after, who got it, and gave it to me again with the chain and seals, and the boy belonging to the master of the New-prison gave me the ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you saw the prisoner at the bar in the chapel?</p>
               <p>Banti. I saw her when she took my watch, for she was then before me. When I was going up towards the altar, to hear a little better, she presented herself before me. She put her hand to my pocket, and I felt it going. I put my hand down, and immediately missed it. I called out immediately, I had lost my watch. She was going away, and I after her as fast as I could; but the people crouded me, and prevented my going so fast as I would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her from that time to the time Mr. Fielding gave you the watch?</p>
               <p>Banti. No.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the prisoner was not taken in the chapel ?</p>
               <p>Banti. As I was going after her she fell down, a little way from the door, and a gentleman took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she immediately searched?</p>
               <p>Banti. No, not immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the name of the gentleman that took hold of her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230030"></xptr>Banti. No. She was taken from the chapel into the ambassador's house, where the constable was sent for. Then she was taken to the constable's house, after that to justice Fielding's, and after that to the Round-house, where she was searched.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing found upon her?</p>
               <p>Banti. No. The time I was going after her in the chapel, there was a man got betwixt her and me, who prevented my taking her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Banti. His name is 
               <persName id="t17570223-28-person336">
                  Leonard 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17570223-28-person336" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person336" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was she searched at the ambassador's house?</p>
               <p>Banti. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the chapel to hear prayers. There were a vast croud of people. A gentleman spoke in French watch, watch. A gentleman took and brought me into a long room up one pair of stairs. I was searched by two women. An English gentleman told me this man had lost his watch, and charged me with it. Then I was brought to the constable's house, and searched by his wife. Then to the Round house, and there searched again. I was strip'd naked to my shift. Then I was brought to Mr. Fielding's, and his maid searched me in a back place. I know no more of the watch than the child unborn. I had no cloak nor capuchin on.</p>

               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Had she no cloak on?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. When I first saw her she had a capuchin or cardinal on; but when she fell down she drop'd it, and after that disowned it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570223-28-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-28-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was detained by the name of Buxter, otherwise Poulter, otherwise Black Moll, to be tried for returning from transportation, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
