<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571207-38">
               <interp inst="t17571207-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-38" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-38" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-38-off195-c266" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend332 t17571207-38-off195 t17571207-38-verdict197"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-38-off195-c267" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend335 t17571207-38-off195 t17571207-38-verdict199"></join>
         
               <p>47, 48. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-defend332" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Joseph 
                     Wood 
                  , otherwise James Collins<interp inst="t17571207-38-defend332" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-defend332" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-defend332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17571207-38-deflabel193" type="occupation">carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend332 t17571207-38-deflabel193"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-defend335" type="defendantName">
                     Jemima 
                     Wilcox 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-38-defend335" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-defend335" type="given" value="Jemima"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-defend335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17571207-38-deflabel194" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend335 t17571207-38-deflabel194"></join>, were <rs id="t17571207-38-off195" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-off195" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-off195" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               indicted for that they feloniously and traitorously, with certain files and other instruments, one piece of good and lawful money, of the current coin of this kingdom, call'd a guinea, did unlawfully file and diminish, against the statute in that case made and provided
            </rs>, <rs id="t17571207-38-cd196" type="crimeDate">Oct. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-off195 t17571207-38-cd196"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Council for the crown. In order to shew the trade and partnership that the prisoners have been engaged in, we shall first shew to the court and gentlemen of the jury, that Mrs. Wilcox went on the 1st of October, to Mr. Honeywood's, a banker, and paid in 100 l. for which she took up bank notes, and afterwards, it will appear, how they were changed at the Bank.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person336">
                  James 
                  Blackburn 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person336" type="surname" value="Blackburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person336" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am cashier at Mr. Honeywood's. Mrs. Wilcox, the prisoner at the bar, came to our office on the 1st of October, and paid in 100 l. and had five 20 l. bank notes. I have here the numbers and dates, but not the years.</p>
               <p>He read,</p>
               <p>20 l. No. 152 6th of June.</p>

               <p>H 20 l. No. 78 7th of Sept.</p>
               <p>20 l. No. 807 30th of Sept.</p>
               <p>C 20 l. No. 101 9th of August.</p>
               <p>B 20 l. No. 207 26th of Sept.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come frequently to your office?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. She did, and sometimes took notes of the house; but more generally she took bank notes for money which she paid in.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did she bring in common ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. It was generally best part of it gold. Sometimes in 100 l. there might be 10 l. or 11 l. in silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it common in the course of your dealings, to give bank notes in that way?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. Sometimes people desire bank notes, and sometimes our own notes; but to people we do not know, we do not, because it is troublesome; but any people that brought so much silver, might have bank notes.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are bankers as careful, at looking at their money, as the bank of England are?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. We are not quite so, because they will not take them at such a weight; but we could not possibly weigh or object to every piece, but if we see any piece remarkably light we object to it.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call remarkably?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. A 36 s. piece to want 2 s. or 2 s. 6 d. or a guinea to want more than 18 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing a guinea should want 18 d. would you take it?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. We should take it of a customer, but of a stranger we should not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the bank more careful than you?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. The bank, I apprehend, in taking large sums of money, are more careful; they take more at a time.</p>
               <p>Q. What money was that she paid you on the 1st of October?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. There were 81 l. in ports, 11 l. in silver, and the other 7 l. in guineas, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person337">
                  Robert 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person337" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person337" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the bank: I know both the prisoners at the bar. I remember the prisoner Wilcox coming there frequently, but I have paid her but once to my knowledge, which was on the first of October last; on that day between the hours of nine and twelve she presented two bank notes for 20 l. each. I gave her 38 guineas and two shillings, which she received. Not two minutes after came in Mr. Wood with three 20 l. bank notes. He ask'd for ports. I gave him 33 36 s. pieces, half a guinea, and 18 d. which was 60 l. He objected to none, but went away immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the numbers of the notes?</p>
               <p>Bell. No, I did not. We only take the name it is payable to, and the person's name that receives. The numbers are taken in another place.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. I belong to the bank of England.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your employ there?</p>
               <p>Sheefe. When bank notes are paid, they are put in my custody ( He produced some notes.)</p>
               <p>Court. Read the numbers and dates.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. No. 152. June 6.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person338">
                  James 
                  Blackburn 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person338" type="surname" value="Blackburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person338" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That is right.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. H No. 78. September 7.</p>
               <p>Blackburn. That is right.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. No. 807. September 30.</p>
               <p>Blackburn. That is right.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. C No. 101. August 9.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070025"></xptr>Blackburn. That is right.</p>
               <p>Sheefe. B. No. 207. September 26.</p>
               <p>Blackburn. These are the numbers and dates I deliver'd to the prisoner Wilcox, two of them had no letters to them. It is possible there may be some notes of the same numbers some years before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person339">
                  Edward 
                  Lambley 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person339" type="surname" value="Lambley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person339" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Council. This evidence was a money taker in Smithfield, who, while Wood liv'd at Birmingham, used to transact business in town, and was a fit person to indorse bills of exchange for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner Wood's hand writing?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Wilcox's hand writing?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I do. I have seen them both write.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon these five notes, see whose names are to them, and by whom wrote.</p>
               <p>Lambley. The two first have Wood's name to them, his own hand writing. Here is 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person340">
                  Jemima 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person340" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person340" type="given" value="Jemima"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the two next. I believe it is her hand-writing. Here is Wood's name on the next, I believe it to be his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it always usual to write the name on the face of the note?</p>
               <p>Lambley. It is.</p>
               <p>Each of them read in court.</p>
               <p>No. 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person341">
                  C. 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person341" type="given" value="C."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person341" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            101 mark'd Wood.</p>
               <p>No. 801. mark'd Wood.</p>
               <p>No. 152. mark'd 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person342">
                  Jemima 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person342" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person342" type="given" value="Jemima"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>No. 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person343">
                  H. 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person343" type="given" value="H."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person343" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            78. 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person344">
                  Jemima 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person344" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person344" type="given" value="Jemima"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person344" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>No. 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person345">
                  B. 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person345" type="given" value="B."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person345" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            207. mark'd Wood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person346">
                  Matthew 
                  Fretwell 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person346" type="surname" value="Fretwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person346" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the Bank. I know the two prisoners at the bar. I have seen them come to the Bank for money several times. I have, with concern, for many years, observ'd the increase of diminish'd guineas to grow upon us, which made me take particular notice of persons that came. I observed one Bell, who is absconded, and after that Mrs. Wilcox, she came often; at first her appearance was not so genteel as afterwards. She ask'd for ports, which lead my curiosity to inquire farther about her; soon after she came to me. I took the opportunity to ask her where she liv'd, she said by London Wall. I ask'd her who she received the money for, she said for a brother of hers, who negotiated bills of exchange in the country, and was then ill. Upon that I took no farther notice, till one of my brother officers happened to make a mistake with her, and paid her a hundred pounds instead of ninety. She was particularly taken notice of by every one of our sellers. In consequence of this mistake he apply'd to me to direct him where she liv'd. We found she had lodg'd at that place, but was remov'd. I acquainted Mr. Chamberlayne the solicitor of the Mint of it, who desired me to make a discovery of it if possible. It happened that the porter of the Mint was with me the morning Mrs. Wilcox came to receive the money for two of these notes. I said to him, Mr. Kemp, here is Mrs. Wilcox, I wish you would dodge her, to see where she lives, and accordingly he did. He came again and told me where he had seen her go in. On the Sunday after he and I went to remark the place, and saw her and Wood both looking out at a window together, at the house she went to. Then we went to inquire what their characters were, in which we were cautious and tender, fearing our business should be suspected.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this house you saw them at?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. It was in Charles Square, Hoxton. Then we went and informed Mr. Chamberlayne of it. He order'd us to go to justice Fielding, where we had warrants. We went to Hoxton the next morning, with one of Mr. Fielding's officers with us. We went in, and up stairs, I imagin'd there might be other conveniences of manufacturing their work, so ask'd the maid servant if there were any other places that belong'd to them; she said there was a garden at the end of Haberdashers alms houses, where they used to go to, in which were some secret places, which the carpenter told her no body could find out but himself. I was desirous to go directly to rummage this garden, as soon as I had done up stairs.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason of your asking where she liv'd.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. On the account of her asking for ports.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kemp. I am porter to the Mint. I was at the Bank on the first of October, betwixt eight and ten in the morning. Mr. Fretwell was endeavouring to trace some of the notes back, and desired me to stay. After that he came to me, and told me Mrs. Wilcox was just come, and desired me to follow and dodge her, and observe and find out the house where the liv'd. I followed her out. She went under the piazzas, where stood Mr. Wood; she convey'd something to him, I supposed it to be the money she had taken. They talked together some time, and then they both went to Leaden-Hall market. They went round the market a good many times, at last they went to a poulterer's shop and cheapen'd a turkey, they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070026"></xptr> bought it for a crown, and changed a 36 s. piece to pay for it, and order'd it to be sent. I could not hear where. I ask'd a friend I saw there if he knew that poulterer, who said yes; I said, if you'll inquire of him where that turkey goes to, you will oblige me. He said he would, and he would leave a line with his mother, where I might call and receive the paper. The two prisoners went round the market two or three times more, and at the upper end of the market they talked a quarter of an hour. Then he went towards the Exchange. I thought the woman was my mark, so I followed her down Bishopsgate street; she said about a quarter of an hour in a tobacconist's shop, and look'd suspiciously about her, from thence she went to another shop, and cross'd the way; from thence to Shoreditch Church, and led me round to Charles Square, Hoxton. She knock'd at the door as if she was mistress of the house, and was let in. I took notice of the house. When I came back to Leaden Hall Market, that person had left a direction with his mother, that the turkey was gone to Mr. Wood's, in Charles Square, Hoxton. The next day, being Sunday, I and Mr Fretwel well went to inquire after them, and at that same house we saw the two prisoners. Wood was in his night gown, and she was behind him looking out at the window. Then we came back and inform'd Mr. Chamberlayne of it. That evening Mr. Fretwell and I had some intelligence of their using the Star in Aldersgate Street. We went there, and got in company with White. After that we went to justice Fielding, on the 6th of October, that remarkable dark Thursday, and then we went with Mr. Chamberlayne, and some proper assistance, to the house, and up stairs. We ask'd the maid where Mr. Wood lay, she said on the right hand side; we went and knock'd at the door, no body would answer; the door was immediately broke open, bat there was no body there. Then we went to the door on the left hand and knock'd there, Mrs Wilcox said no body was there; we said we wanted Mr. Wood, and burst open the door; one of Mr. Fielding's men went down into the yard, and saw Mr. Wood thro' a back window in his shirt; we in the room rummaged their pockets, and took some gold out of each of their pockets; I think we returned Wilcox all hers again. We took five guineas and a half from her, and five guineas from Wood, out of which we returned him two.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you give her her money again ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. Mr. Fretwell look'd over it, and supposed it to be good, so deliver'd it her again; we kept two guineas and two half guineas of Mr. Wood's, which we supposed to be light.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep their money separately ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. No, I am uncertain who the light money was taken from, for we put it all together. (Two guineas and two half guineas produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Were these weigh'd ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. They were. Here is one, a queen Ann's guinea, wants ten grains, one of George the first, ten grains, that is 1 s. and 8 d. each. The two half guineas want eleven grains each, that is 1 s. and 9 d. each.</p>
               <p>Q. Do they appear to have been fresh diminished?</p>
               <p>Kemp. Mr. Fretwell is the best judge of that, he said they did appear so to him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fretwell. What is your opinion?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I thought then they were lately done, (be takes them in his hand ) and I think so now.</p>
               <p>Q. Give your reason for your belief?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. They seem to have a shining upon them, as if they had not been negotiated; they have a wax, with which they rub them over to dull the shining. These seem to have been fresh and recently done.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. By recently do you understand they have never been in any other hands at all, will not that freshness remain upon them after having past thro' two or three hands?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I can't say really. (The jury look at them. )</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Do you speak of some or all?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I speak of them all.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. Where did you take this money from?</p>
               <p>Kemp. From out of the room on the right hand. After that we open'd the chest of drawers, and found two pair of shears, and a three corner'd file, ( produced in court with gold on the file.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was that drawer lock'd?</p>
               <p>Kemp. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you the key ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I had it of Mrs. Wilcox, I ask'd her for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are these instruments fit for the purpose of diminishing?</p>
               <p>Kemp. They are. We proceeded then to the next room, that is, the left hand chamber, supposed to be Wilcox's room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find Wood?</p>
               <p>Kemp. They were both in the left hand room when the door was broke open; in the other room<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070027"></xptr> were found promiscously lying in a drawer, which was lock'd, in a sort of a chest of drawers, two three corner'd files, a pair of scales, some clippings of gold, and filings of gold, some shears and money, some weight and some light. Here is a quarter of a moidore ( producing one ) it is 1 s. 9 d. too light, it seems to have been fresh taken off.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fretwell. Look at this money.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I saw them before, I remember this 6 s. 9 d. two half guineas and two guineas (he looks at them.) Here is the same freshness on them all, and here is some of the black wax upon the edge of one.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. Did you find any wax ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. We found a piece of wax, and marks of gold on one part of it. ( Produced in court, and examin'd by the court and the jury with the money.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. Did you weigh the gold?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I did, and put it down; he reads, here is a guinea, George the first, wants 13 grains, that is 2 s. 2 d. a George the second wants 7 grains, a George second wants 8 grains, a ditto 8 grains, a ditto 9 grains, a Charles the second 6 grains, a William 4 grains, two half guineas want 14 d. each, a quarter of a moidore wants 14 d. in all eight guineas, two half guineas, and a quarter of a moidore. Here are some gold filings, and some clippings (producing them in the papers) the clipings are supposed to be the clippings of guineas and half guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fretwell. What do you suppose these clippings to be taken from?</p>

               <p>Fretwell. Mr. Kemp and I separated the clipings from the filings, and after that sorted the clippings, because some of the clippings I was sure were from ports, and of the others we were doubtful; some of them I thought by their having a flope upon them might be from guineas. Here is one clipping (taking it between his thumb and finger) that has a diagonal slope upon it, which I apprehend may be from a guinea.</p>
               <p>Council. Then you are certain some are from ports, and doubtful as to others.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. Yes. (The jury look at them. )</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the other paper.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. (Takes it in his hand.) Here are some of these that I take to be from guineas or half guineas. Ever since the year 1745 they have made the letters on guineas and half guineas nearer the edge, and put another sort of an edge upon them. This is what I call a comb turn'd circular. This clipping I believe to be of that sort of guineas or half guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you take all the clippings in the three papers to be from some sort of coin or other.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I do; some I am sure to be from ports.</p>
               <p>Kemp. Here are more clippings (producing some.) These I take to be from ports, which I found also in the same drawer with the rest. (The jury look at the clippings, supposed to be from guineas.)</p>
               <p>Fretwell. Guineas in any reign are with a slant stroke on the edge.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Do you speak from a perfect satisfaction, or is it your belief?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I believe it.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. For instance, are you able to tell the different edges of a guinea from a moidore ?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. Some moidores are the same as the old guineas, but none have the same edge as a new guinea since the year 1745. Some ports have feathers upon them; a 3 l. 12 s. and some 36 s. pieces have.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Can you tell the difference between a moidore and a guinea?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Have you look'd at these through a magnifying glass?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. I have two guineas here of my own; one of the year 1752, and the other before; one is sloped more than the other; they are both George II.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. (He looks at the clipping through a glass.) Now I see the comb larger; I believe this to be from a guinea.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Does it appear to be from an old or a new guinea?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. It appears to be one of the guineas since the year 1745; it has a semicircle thicker in the middle than on the edge.</p>
               <p>Council for crown. Have you seen louis-d'ores ?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I have.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Are you acquainted with the effect that the cutting a piece of gold will make upon the milling; as suppose a piece of money is mill'd strait, and a pair of shears being put to it, cut very thin upon the edge, are you capable to form a judgement what effect it will have upon the metal, so as to alter the form of the milling; because the edge turns up and thickens?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I can naturally conclude there is no effect that the clipping could have to make it not appear as the clipping of a guinea; it may make it bend round, but the edge may plainly be discovered.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070028"></xptr>Kemp. Here are some files with gold on them all ( producing them ) which I found in the same drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you discover besides?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I found in the same drawers, in a lower drawer, four guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Are they diminished?</p>
               <p>Kemp. They are. ( Produced in court)</p>
               <p>Q. to Fretwell. Look at these four guineas.</p>
               <p>Fretwell. One of them appears to be fresh done.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. Have you weighed them?</p>
               <p>Kemp. I have not. There was a secret place in the window, in which was a bundle of letters, which I gave to Mr. Chamberlayne. After this we went into the garden, and broke open the summer-house, in which were a fire place, a closet on each side, a proper board fix'd to work on, and a sash window done up so high that nobody could over look them; the top part of the window came out, and a board slipped up, where were abundance of drawers concealed, in which I found more files and gold meltings, a piece of an ingot, and other gold mix'd with borax; to the left hand was another of these rooms, much in the same manner, and over a cock-loft we found some gold, nine crucibles, a moveable vice, weights, scales, chistel, six files, an old tobacco box with gold filings, a piece of an ingot, and two pair of shears.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the garden and place.</p>
               <p>Kemp. When you go in there is a high walk; the garden is low, and encompassed round. I heard it was done by the prisoner Wood. The door is very strong, and a window with a blind nail'd to it. This hole is the place where we put our hands' up into the cock-loft, where we found crucibles and other things; every thing was concealed. There was a work shop on each side the fire place; one of them, we suppose, was for White to work in.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fretwell. Was you with Mr. Kemp when he found all these things?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. Did the place look like a workshop?</p>
               <p>Kemp. Any mechanical people would have said it was like a place where people had been at work.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Recollect to yourself Mr. Fretwell the piece of clipping, that you are most satisfied to be from a guinea. ( Fretwell takes up a piece, and the jury look at it.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person347">
                  John 
                  Spencley 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person347" type="surname" value="Spencley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person347" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, and was concerned in searching the prisoner's house, at Hoxton, along with Mr. Kemp, Mr. Fretwell, and two or three others. I can say no more than what has been said as to the place and things found, which have been in their custody. When we went first we knock'd at the room door, supposed to be the prisoner Wood's.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you suppose it to be his room?</p>
               <p>Spencley. The maid told us it was his room. We broke the door open, found Mr Wood there, and some implements, as two pair of shears, and some files. After that we went into the other room, and found the guineas, and filings of guineas in a sheet of paper in the drawer. I went with them into the garden, and in a building we found several materials concealed in a cock lost, where we could put our hands up. We came back to the house. After that it was imagined better for me to go back alone to the garden, because White was expected to come to work. I went, and was there alone, but nobody came. I wanting some amusement, being alone, pull'd more of the cieling down, got into the cock lost, and could find nothing but this thing ( producing an ingot) two pair of shears, some files, and some crucibles. Then I came back, and that night I went to his former lodgings in Spital-fields, having a search warrant from justice Fielding. When I came there I ask'd if he lodg'd there, and was told they had not seen him lately, although he had not quitted his lodgings. I asked for his room. They shew'd me his apartments, where was a buroe, of which we asked the landlady for the key, who said, she imagined, Mr. Wood had it. There was another constable along with me. We got a little bit of a chissel that was brought us, and broke the lock open, where we found five pair of shears, some files with gold upon them, and, in the drawer, we found a great quantity of papers, which we delivered into Mr. Chamberlayne's custody, at Mr. Fielding's; some of them are of a very late date, in which Mr. Wood's and Mrs. Wilcox's names are mention'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person348">
                  Susannah 
                  Ingoe 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person348" type="surname" value="Ingoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person348" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Red-Lion-Street. Mr. Wood lodged with me there about a year and three quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he take the lodgings?</p>
               <p>S. Ingoe. He took them this Christmass will be two years,</p>
               <p>Q. Who do they belong to now?</p>
               <p>S. Ingoe. They belong to him at this time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did the lodgings belong to at the time the search was made?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070029"></xptr>S. Ingoe. To him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person349">
                  Thomas 
                  Dun 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person349" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person349" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Old Street, I know there garden at Hoxton.</p>
               <p>Q. Who does the summer house belong to ?</p>
               <p>Dun. To Mr. Wood, the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Dun. I work'd for him in the gardens last May.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they belong to him last October ?</p>
               <p>Dun. They did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you receive money of him for your work?</p>
               <p>Dun. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever receive any that was deficient ?</p>
               <p>Dun. No, nor bad to my knowledge ?</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Dun. I am a gardener.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person350">
                  Edward 
                  Lambley 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person350" type="surname" value="Lambley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person350" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I am a seeds man. I keep an inn now, the Bear and Ragged Staff, in Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know White ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. You know something of the prisoner Wood and White's transactions, do you not ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Wood live at Birmingham once?</p>
               <p>Lambley. He did; my first correspondence with him was through White</p>
               <p>Q. Which did you know first ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I knew White a great many years before I did Wood; White was Wood's agent. Mr. Wood, at that time, follow'd his own business, that of a carpenter, and bought a good deal of timber; they used to have a great many bills transacted in town. The first of it was, White used to borrow a little money of me, about five or ten pounds, for four or five days, or a week. I once borrowed 50 l. of him. He said, at the same time, a gentleman had bought a large quantity of timber in Wales, and wanted me to indorse some bills. I indorsed some, drawn by my brother upon me. I borrowed that 50 l. and suffered him to draw upon me real bills. I accepted them, and by that means, I believe, he got about 400 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean got it?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I mean White; it was money that was raised for the prisoner Wood, White was his agent. This was for some time. Sometimes they paid me pretty well, and sometimes I was forced to pay the money out of my own pocket. Wood's real name is Collins; after he failed in Birmingham he came away, and changed his name.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him write ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I have, and Wilcox too.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to the hand writing of Wood?</p>
               <p>Lambley I can; he has drawn many fictitious bills on abundance of people that were his acquaintance and lived a little in credit, made the bills payable to them, and raised money by that means. I was frequently with Wood at that time. There were some good bills came up from Birmingham, but after he came away there came up very few; afterwards they told me they had got a new trade.</p>
               <p>Q Who told you that first ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. White told me that first; after that Wood told me White and he had consulted about it, and began a good trade.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that trade ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. That was filing 36 s. pieces and moidores, and paring them with shears.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner Wilcox assist in any thing ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. She used to put the money off, pay the bills, and such as that.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this paper, whose hand writing is it ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I really believe it to be Mrs. Wilcox's hand-writing</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her write ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I have; she used to draw as well as the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it that Wood told you of this new trade ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. It w as before he came quite away from Birmingham; he used to come very often to town: it is rather better than two years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay at Birmingham after he told you he had got a new trade ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. About two or three months. I believe, or rather more.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he came to London to reside?</p>
               <p>Lambley. It is about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Wood when he came to town, while he was resident at Birmingham ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I did, and had settled bills to the value of 400 l. when they told me of the new trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Confine your evidence to the fact, that may affect Wood; what kind of correspondence or trade was carried on by him, in which you was concerned ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. They used to clip and file 36 s. pieces and moidores.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070030"></xptr>Q. Did you ever see them clip any ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I have seen them clip both.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Lambley. The first place was in Tokenhouse-Yard, at White's house; then at Wood's lodgings, in Red Lion Street, Spital-Fields; and in the gardens I saw Wood and White both clip them.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you seen them clip money ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I believe it may be about half a dozen times.</p>
               <p>Q. Where, in the garden?</p>
               <p>Lambley. In the summer-house at Hoxton, and in Red-Lion Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know of his living in Charles-Square, Hoxton?</p>
               <p>Lambley. No, I did not; they told me their trade was to be confined to clipping ports; the reason they told me was, that guineas were so dangerous they would not attempt it: I told them if they did I would detect them, if I knew it; but I did agree to assist them with some ports, till I could get my money.</p>
               <p>Q. Here are some of the letters that were found in Wood's lodgings, which are directed to Dixon, who was meant by that?</p>
               <p>Lambley. They used to direct so, in Tokenhouse-Yard, where was nobody of that name; it was White that took them in, and open'd them: all the letters that I saw were directed there.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time they mention'd that new trade, were both of them apprised of the consequence of guineas and ports ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I believe so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-38-person351">
                  Mary 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person351" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person351" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived servant in the house six weeks where Mr. Wood and Mrs. Wilcox lodged.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been often up-stairs there ?</p>
               <p>M. Boucher. I have, and Mr. Wood and Mrs. Wilcox were together; but I never was in their room when they were at work; the door was sometimes open and sometimes shut.</p>
               <p>Q. When you was in the room did you ever observe some part of the room dirty, and the other part clean?</p>
               <p>M. Boucher. Sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any working tools upon the table?</p>
               <p>M. Boucher. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever sent out by either of them to change any money at chandlers shops?</p>

               <p>M. Boucher. Yes, with ports, guineas, moidores, and 6 s. 9 d. pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of them scrupled ?</p>
               <p>M. Boucher. Only one person scrupled taking one.</p>
               <p>Q. What piece of money was that?</p>
               <p>M. Boucher. A 36 s. piece.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chamberloyne. These are the letters that the constable deliver'd to me, which he said he found in Red Lion Street. These I selected out from a great number of letters found there (producing several letters.)</p>
               <p>One of them was put into the hands of the clerk of the arraigns.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lambley. Whose hand writing is this letter?</p>
               <p>Lambley. It is the hand writing of the prisoner Wood.</p>
               <p>It is read in court (dated Birmingham, October 17, 1755, and directed to 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person352">
                  James 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person352" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person352" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the shoe warehouse, in Token House Yard, London) as follows: I would have you send me down a set of tools for the new trade immediately, it will do better here than there. You may give me instructiors sufficient I dare say, therefore think of that; be sure let me know by Tuesday's post if you can send them.</p>
               <p>Another was put into the hands of the clerk of the arraigns.</p>
               <p>Lambley. This is the hand writing of Wood.</p>
               <p>It is read. Dated Birmingham, October 18, 1755. Directed to Dixon, &amp;c. in which are as follows:</p>
               <p>The two bills upon Thorne be sure give him the money on Monday. I would have sent it him, but would have you exercise your new practice upon it first; but be sure don't be covetous, 18 d. is sufficient, and do it well; I hope that will turn out well towards some of the expence.</p>
               <p>Another Lambley deposed to be the hand writing of Wood. dated Birmingham, Nov. 17, 1755. in which was (upon complaining of bills return'd,) You will at last load me with ignominy and the gallows.</p>
               <p>Another Lambley deposed to be the hand writing of Wood. Dated Nov. 22, 1755. In which was: For the sake of the trade no one bill must be unpaid. I have got about 4 l. this week, but gave Ward 20 s. for a 64 l. bill; think the expence, &amp;c. (Then, giving an account of bills, says ) Bill upon capt. Ward, in a particular hand, due Monday, pay that as soon as you get this; if you borrow, give Mr. Hall good money.</p>
               <p>Another Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing. Dated Birmingham, Nov. 20, 1755. After an account of variety of bills sent out of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070031"></xptr> the country, he then goes on: You may get all these bills accepted in half an hour, so you may get them all into cash Monday afternoon, and, then you will have time to do them over against' Tuesday. I have made this week 7 l. 10 s. and have received 150 guineas this week, so judge what you may do; but' don't fail to send by the coach all you have done.</p>
               <p>Another, dated Birmingham, Dec. 2, 1755. Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, in which was: Get good cash ready to pay Ward, get all you can ready, and send me by the coach. For the sake of the practice you must not let any bills be unpaid.</p>
               <p>Another (no date) Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, containing an account of bills, &amp;c. and these words: Be sure don't fail to send to-morrow the breeches and a small file or two, a small punch, a graver, an ingot and a crucible.</p>
               <p>Another, dated Jan. 14. 1756, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, in which was: Give a porter a shilling to get the two forty pounds accepted, and then you may get them into cash by Friday evening, for it must be paid away on Saturday, done or undone; be sure get the gold sold directly. I have pack'd up the gold in three ingots and stuff for your bed, get it run into one, it weighs by gold weights two ounces and three quarters, two penny weights and six grains. So be sure get it into cash Monday or Tuesday; (mentions five bills and says) if you look sharp you may get them into cash by Friday, and make your advantage at night, but upon no consideration, done or undone, let any of these bills be unpaid on Saturday night.</p>
               <p>Another, dated December 17, 1755, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, in which were inclosed three bills: For fear you should not have got the gold into cash on Saturday, or indeed on Friday, I have remitted to you as my letters will shew to last Saturday 2179 l. 1 s. gold, &amp;c. 102 l. 10 s. 3 d. this post 108 l.</p>
               <p>Another, dated Feb 16, 1756, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, with these words: I have made about 5 l. 10 s. to day my self, so I hope I shall have a large cargo for you; be sure be industrious, and take care of all the - , and don't let the Welch bills go back.</p>
               <p>Another, dated Feb. 21, 1756, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing, with these words: Your's I got this afternoon, and am surprised there was no more; mine was ten ounces one half, and yours but nine ounces three quarters, and I have been half my time out. I have seat twenty ounces and eleven penny weights of - which at 3 l. 14 s. comes to 76 l.</p>
               <p>Another, Feb. 22, 1756, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing; with these words: By the coach as I said you have twenty ounces and eleven penny weights, which get cast into one, and get into cash directly; but it is strange to me that you have got but about 27 l. in a month, as you said you had 12 l. the first week, when I do much more myself.</p>
               <p>Another, Sept. 17, no date, Lambley deposed to be Wood's hand writing; with these words. The inclosed take to Mr. Elton's, and desire them to give you guineas for it, perhaps you may make some advantage of the guineas, and then change some of them.</p>
               <p>Council for the crown. We will now produce a letter that relates to Mrs. Wilcox.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chamberlayne. Some papers were taken out of the window at the house, Mrs. Wilcox was in the room at the time. She said they were only private letters that past between Mr. Wood and her, they don't regard the affair, and desired I'd let her have them.</p>
               <p>Another letter produced, which Lambley deposed to be Mrs. Wilcox's hand writing.</p>
               <p>It is read. Directed to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person353">
                  Thomas 
                  Hodson 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person353" type="surname" value="Hodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person353" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the George in Steel House Lane, Birmingham. I went to the garden on Saturday morning by six o'clock, and got some pease, they were very good. I went so soon because: would not see any body, for I thought I was pretty safe so early. I was at home by eight o'clock, and saw no body, but it was as much as I could do to get enough for out dinners.</p>
               <p>Council for crown. There was found among these papers an account, which will be proved to be the hand writing of the prisoner Wood; on one side he charges White, and on the other it is discharged; and it will appear that, between the 28th of December, to the 12th of February following, there were three thousand pounds circulated in this manner.</p>
               <p>Lambley. This is Wood's hand writing.</p>
               <p>It is read:</p>
               <p>The contents were an account of bills received by 
               <persName id="t17571207-38-person354">
                  William 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17571207-38-person354" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person354" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and cash paid; the first side containing an account of bills sent to White, the first dated November 10, 1756, and the last dated January 17th following, amounting to 2242 l. 16 s. 2 d. underneath that, after the total, So when ever the bill due (and to be due Saturday, as advised of) is paid, he should have in hand (if all the bills<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070032"></xptr> sent were got into cash 64 l. 12 s. 8 d. that makes another total of 2307 l. 8 s. 10 d. Then he goes on with bills returned, which makes the total in January 13th, 2909 l. 18 s. 10 d. This is the increase on the first total.</p>
               <p>On the other side the account is of cash and bills to answer these bills; the first article thereof is January 11, and ends February 11, and amounts to 2307 l. 8 s. 10 d. Then there are five more bills added, which makes the total 2319 l 9 s. 10 d. Then come four more articles: </p>
               <p>l. s. d.</p>
               <p>The first is bills - 0</p>
               <p>Gold - 6</p>
               <p>The 23d ditto - 0 0</p>
               <p>The 24th ditto - 13 6</p>
               <p>Q. from Wood to Lambley. Did Mr. Wilcox carry out money for you ?</p>
               <p>Lambley. I have known her carry out money for you; she has for me, no doubt of it.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence, but left it to his council, to ask what questions he thought proper.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blackburn. Can you take upon you to swear these are the sirings of guineas ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q Whether any man can. from little bits like these, be able to speak precisely whether they are the borders of guineas or other money ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I apprehend the gentlemen of the Mint are better judges of it than I.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever made observations on the edges of money ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I have frequently.</p>
               <p>Q. Does more money go through the people's hands at the Bank than your's?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I believe more money goes through our hands than of any one teller at the Bank.</p>
               <p>Council for crown. Can you swear there are not the clippings of guineas ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Can any man say whether they are not?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Have you any belief about in one way or another?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. My belief, perhaps, may affect the prisoners.</p>
               <p>Council for crown. Upon what do you ground your belief ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. One of them, I think, may be from half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Council for crown. What is your reason ?</p>
               <p>Blackburn. Because it is smaller.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners to Fretwell, Can you tell whether these are the clippings of guineas or half guineas ?</p>
               <p>Fretwell. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. I, as your council, would advise you to rest the case on the evidence, as it now stands</p>
               <p>Wood <rs id="t17571207-38-verdict197" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-verdict197" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17571207-38-punish198" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-punish198" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend332 t17571207-38-punish198"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-38-defend335 t17571207-38-punish198"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Wilcox <rs id="t17571207-38-verdict199" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-38-verdict199" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
