<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-14">
               <interp inst="t17501017-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-14" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-14" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-14-off74-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-14-defend143 t17501017-14-off74 t17501017-14-verdict77"></join>
         
               <p>632. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Matth.ias 
                     Nichols 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-14-defend143" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-defend143" type="given" value="Matth.ias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-14-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17501017-14-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Foscue 
                        <interp inst="t17501017-14-victim145" type="surname" value="Foscue"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-14-victim145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-14-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-14-off74 t17501017-14-victim145"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway of one linen bag, value 2 d. and twelve pennyworth of halfpence
            </rs>, <rs id="t17501017-14-cd75" type="crimeDate">September 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-14-off74 t17501017-14-cd75"></join>.</p>
               <p>[The prisoner desired each witness might be examined apart, which was accordingly done.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-person146">
                  Thomas 
                  Foscue 
               <interp inst="t17501017-14-person146" type="surname" value="Foscue"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person146" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of September, about three o'clock in the morning, I was coming to London with a load of turnips; about <placeName id="t17501017-14-crimeloc76">half a mile on the other side Paddington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-14-crimeloc76" type="placeName" value="half a mile on the other side Paddington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-14-crimeloc76" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-14-off74 t17501017-14-crimeloc76"></join> I met the prisoner, who stopped me and bid me stand; afterwards he stopped the horses, and said he must have my money; I said, friend, I have but a few halfpence to pay the turnpike; he said if I stirred an inch<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170011"></xptr> he'd shoot me dead, and put the stick up to my breast; then he put his hand in my pocket and took my bag out, and asked me if that was all; I said it was; then he said, I'll have your coat, and struck at me with this mop-stick, which the witness had in his hand</p>
               <p>Q. What was in your purse?</p>
               <p>Foscue. There were twelve pennyworth of half-pence.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough to discern the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Foscue. It was dark, I could not see him above a pole before me; I took this stick to be a pistol; he went to fetch a blow at me, I put my head down, and he struck so fierce at me his stick went out of his hand, and my hat and that went away together; then I took hold of him, and threw him down; then Robert Hargood came to my assistance, we bound him with his hands behind him, and brought him away to Paddington : there we charged a constable with him; we staid there till about 7 or 8 o'clock. At this time two milkmen came up. The constable has the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-person147">
                  Robert 
                  Hargood 
               <interp inst="t17501017-14-person147" type="surname" value="Hargood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person147" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on the top of the cart that the prosecutor drove. The prisoner came up to him and said, d - n you, stand, and give me your money. Foscue said he had but a few half-pence ; then the prisoner d - d him and said, I'll have your coat, or I'll shoot you dead (I think he said he'd shoot him dead three times over) then Foscue called out to me; I came down to his assistance, I did not know which was uppermost; but when I came to them the prisoner was underneath; we secured him, and took him to Paddington. The prisoner said nothing daunted him more than when Foscue called out to me; we charged a constable with him, searched him, and found a knife in his pocket, but neither the bag nor money. Here is a witness here who went back to the place and found the bag and a vial, which the prisoner owned; he said the stuff in it was to black the stick and make it shine like a gun. The prisoner desired I would hang him up without carrying him any farther, saying, he knew he should be hanged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his hand in the prosecutor's pocket?</p>
               <p>Hargood. It was too dark to see that; we carried him before justice Fielding, and he was committed. When he was at the house at Paddington, he said if that blow had hit Foscue he'd never have known who hurted him.</p>
               <p> - Price. I went back with a candle and lanthorn to the place where he was taken, not far from Paddington. The prisoner had had some flower in his bosom, for by tumbling about it came out and lay upon the ground, near which I found the purse and four-pence halfpenny; there were two farthings among it. I found likewise a vial, which the prisoner owned to be his, in which he kept oil for his piece, he being a soldier. The purse was open.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Was your purse open?</p>
               <p>Foscue. It was, my lord.</p>
               <p>Price. It was found near the three mile stone: there was too much dust and gravel in the road, we could find no more money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-person148">
                  Henry 
                  Quinn 
               <interp inst="t17501017-14-person148" type="surname" value="Quinn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person148" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough at Paddington, I was called out of bed to the Green Man in Marybone parish ; the prisoner was delivered into my custody, I searched him and found a long case-knif upon him; I asked him what he did with the pistol he had stopped the man with; he answered with a nod towards his stick, his hands being tied behind him, that is my gun; I asked him about the money, he denied it, but at last said, I am certain, if you go and look in the road, you'll find the bag and money too. When we were at Paddington the prosecutor was complaining how he went to strike at him; the prisoner made answer, if that blow had hit you, you had never been here to have told who hurted you. The bag was shewn to the prosecutor, and he swore to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-person149">
                  Richard 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17501017-14-person149" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person149" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of September, about three o'clock in the morning, I was going to my cows that lie at grass at Kilbourne, I had my man and a great dog with me; I heard a cart stop in the road, and by hearing some words I thought the cart was in the ditch; we went on and heard words increase; said I, it is either a cart in a ditch or a robbery. I heard one say get down, get down, he says he'll shoot me, so we ran on; when we came there the soldier was down, and crying out for mercy. I asked what was the matter; the countryman said, this man has robbed me, telling me the same he has here. I bid them take him to Paddington, and charge the constable with him. I thought the soldier had drank a little that morning; he desired they would not use him ill, and said, he would not run away, saying, he knew he should be hanged, and wanted them to hang him up then. He said his life was a misery to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I live at the Turk's-head near Clerkenwell-green; my father lives at Kingsbury-green in Middlesex; I was going to see him. I set out between 12 and one in the morning, I was a small matter in liquor; I had a piece of link in my hand to light myself as far as Marybone, there<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170012"></xptr> it went out. I went through Paddington, and between that and Kilbourne in the road I met this man, and push'd against him; he struck me; I made a return as soon as I could; that mop-stick I had in my hand to keep me from falling; in the fight I lost that bottle out of my pocket, and the man said he lost his money. I am as innocent of robbing the man as the child unborn, I was much beat and abus'd. Said I, you had better hang me outright, than use me so. They said, they did not fear hanging me for the reward.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-14-person150">
                  Robert 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17501017-14-person150" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person150" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about six years, he bears the character of an honest man in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-14-verdict77" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-verdict77" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17501017-14-punish78" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-14-punish78" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-14-defend143 t17501017-14-punish78"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
