<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-13">
               <interp inst="t17581206-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-13" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-13" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-13-off65-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-defend114 t17581206-13-off65 t17581206-13-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>15. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-defend114" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Zechariah 
                     Holford 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17581206-13-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-defend114 t17581206-13-alias-2"></join>Alford</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-defend114" type="surname" value="Holford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-defend114" type="given" value="Zechariah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-defend114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-13-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 60 yards of silk ribbon, value 4 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-victim117" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Bennett 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-13-victim117" type="surname" value="Bennett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-victim117" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-victim117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-off65 t17581206-13-victim117"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581206-13-cd66" type="crimeDate">Nov. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-off65 t17581206-13-cd66"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-person118">
                  James 
                  Bennett 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person118" type="surname" value="Bennett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person118" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17581206-13-viclabel67" type="occupation">keep a haberdasher's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-victim117 t17581206-13-viclabel67"></join> at the <placeName id="t17581206-13-crimeloc68">corner of Tooley-street, London-bridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-13-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="corner of Tooley-street, London-bridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-13-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-off65 t17581206-13-crimeloc68"></join>, on the 3d of November the prisoner came into my shop, about 10 or 11 in the forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you known him before?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. Yes, I had; he had dwelt with me before, my young man served, I was in the back shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him come in?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. No, but I observed him when he was in; I perceived a little sort of a catch he made use of with his hand, as he was dealing with my young man.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other customers there at the time.</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. No, there were not. My young man served him with two or three sorts of ribbons.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by this twitch with his hand?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. It was a little sudden move of his hand, which gave me to conjecture he had a design to take something, that occasioned me to go into the shop; then came in other customers, but still I watched him. As I served them, I observed my young man had two drawers out, one near the prisoner, and the other near my young man, on the counter; I saw the prisoner had two or three pieces in his hands, done up in rolls as they usually are; one of which he dropt short of the drawer which was near him, the other he put into the farther drawer; my young man and he were opposite each other with the counter between. This I saw was done quick, by that dropping into the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060011"></xptr> wrong drawer, gave me a suspicion that he had a design for that piece (it was pink coloured). I went then upon the stairs, as if going up stairs, and looked through the bannisters on the top of the stairs: the bannister twists round and comes part over the shop, so that I had a good view of him and the drawer; I saw the piece of pink colour'd ribbon lying on the top of the others; I saw the prisoner look round him, and make another twitch, and instantly the pink ribbon was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his hand in the drawer ?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. I did, but it was done so instantaneously, that I cannot say how.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was there of it?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. I believe there were about 18 yards of it; I then went up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go up when you saw it gone?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. I was in some little manner of fright, and there I consulted another of my servants about what was best to be done. We concluded it proper to send for a constable, I sent for one, when I came down again, the prisoner was buying in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner buy any?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. Yes, he bought some sattin ones. Presently came in the Constable, Mr Adamson whom I sent for him, my father, and a neighbour. My father laid hold on one of the prisoner's arms, and I the other, and we took him into the back shop; there the prisoner shuffled with the arm that my father had hold on, and had got 4 pieces from his cloaths somewhere, into his hand.</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. Was the piece of pink any one of them?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he bought any of them?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. No, he had not. The 4 pieces produced. Then I desired he might be searched, and I walked away at the time; I having to my servant mentioned the piece of pink coloured.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say about the four pieces?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. He said these I'll pay for, in broken English, or was going to pay. The pink piece produced. This the constable took out of his pocket, but he is gone into the country. Here are the other witness that saw him take it out; it contains 18 yards, I have great reason to think this is the same piece that I saw thro' the bannister. There was but this one of this quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. How much do all these pieces contain?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. About 60 yards; they are all my property.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your young man's name that was serving him?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. His name is 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person119">
                  Charles 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person119" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person119" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself before the Magistrate?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. He said he had paid for some, and was going to pay for the rest.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the prisoner dealt with you some time before?</p>
               <p>J. Bennett. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the quantity of money he paid you this time?</p>
               <p>Bennett. No.</p>
               <p>Q. You mentioned four pieces in his hand: were they concealed?</p>
               <p>Bennett. He had nothing in his hands, when we laid hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. How could he have secreted those pieces without your seeing him?</p>
               <p>Bennett. I was not observing him all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear of 1 l. II s. being paid for those ribbons?</p>
               <p>Bennett. I think he laid out about 26 s. at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what quantity of ribbons were sold him?</p>
               <p>Bennett. No: I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person120">
                  Samuel 
                  Bevar 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person120" type="surname" value="Bevar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person120" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Bennett. Not by name I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you declare to any body, you believed the prisoner had paid for the pink ribbon.</p>
               <p>Bennett. No: never.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the charge you made against the prisoner, when you carried him before my Lord-Mayor?</p>
               <p>Bennett. I laid the case open to my Lord the same as I have here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-person121">
                  Charles 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person121" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person121" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apprentice to Mr Bennett: the prisoner at the bar came into the shop, I think on the 3d of November, and ask'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060012"></xptr> to see some ribbons; he usually came once or twice a week; I show'd him some: I open'd two or three drawers, and cut him several six yards, in a quantity to the amount in the whole of 1 l. 11 s. and three half-pence. There were none larger than six yards; I remember there was one of two yards and a half, being a remnant; he paid me the money, and the three half-pence I bated; after that, he desired to see some black ribbon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any pink among the quantity you sold him?</p>
               <p>Cook. No: there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the prisoner take any?</p>
               <p>Cook. No: I did not. I observ'd my master go up stairs and come down again, and Mr Adamson went out. I was still showing him the black ribbon; presently came in my master's father, the constable, and a neighbour. My master laid hold on one of the prisoner's hands, and his father the other, and carried him backwards; but by the time they got him into the back shop, he had struggled, and got one had loose, there I saw four pieces in it: the same that my master produc'd here. My master desired he might be search'd, and went out: then the constable pull'd out a piece of pink ribbon from out of one of the prisoner's pockets. It was a great pocket, which he had by the side of a horseman's coat. He looks at it. This is it. It is my master's property.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not sold him that ribbon?</p>
               <p>Cook. No: I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say about the four pieces in his hand?</p>
               <p>Cook. He said, I'll pay for them; but this piece of pink he said he had paid for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he paid you for any of those goods here produced?</p>

               <p>Cook. No: he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. How much of it is there?</p>
               <p>Cook. Here is near sixty yards.</p>
               <p>Q. What is it worth?</p>
               <p>Cook. We cut them all at 6 d. per yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before my Lord-Mayor?</p>
               <p>Cook. I was: the prisoner said the same there, as at our shop; that he had paid for the piece of pink, and intended to pay for the four other pieces. After we had sent for a coach to go before my Lord-Mayor, he begg'd he might not be prosecute, and that he would pay him for all this ribbon what my master desired; he said he had a wife and some small children, and hoped on their account he would not prosecute him.</p>

               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you conclude, that when a person is charged with an offence of this sort, he would much rather pay for these pieces of ribbons than be prosecuted?</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you make up the several items ?</p>
               <p>Cook. He bought some at 5 s. and 9 d. and some at 5 s. and 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you make up the sum of 1 l. II s. and three half-pence, without this piece of pink?</p>
               <p>Cook. If I was to put that to it, it would make much more: I can't recollect all the several pieces that he bought.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cut him two yards, and four yards, at 5 s. and 6 d. per dozen?</p>
               <p>Cook. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cut him four pieces at 5 s. and 9 d. a dozen?</p>
               <p>Cook. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cut him three pieces at 5 s. and 9 d. a dozen? Cook. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Then that sum total amounts to 1 l. 2 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any more you cut him?</p>
               <p>Cook. I cannot: neither should I those, had they not been mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Then this piece of pink, if it came to 8 s. 7 d. 1/2 would make it amount to I l. II s. I d. 1/2.</p>
               <p>Cook. He neither bought nor paid for that piece of pink. I cannot recollect the things he did buy: he and I cast them up and he paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put it in writing?</p>
               <p>Cook. I did it with a pencil on a piece of waste paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that paper? that would have been material.</p>
               <p>Cook. I did not preserve it. I can speak as certain as to the pink, as if I had preserv'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you name any piece of ribbon he bought of you, that makes up the money 1 l. II s. and three half-pence, without including that pink?</p>
               <p>Cook. I cannot. I can be so exact as to say<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060013"></xptr> he never did buy above six yard in one piece of me.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a coat had he on?</p>
               <p>Cook. He had a great coat hung loose on his shoulders, with his arms not in his sleeves.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put the parcels in that coat pocket that he paid for?</p>
               <p>Cook. No: they were all lying on the counter at the time they took him from that counter.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say the goods he bought came to I l. II s. and three halfpence?</p>

               <p>Cook. I can.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-person122">
                  Thomas 
                  Adamson 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person122" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person122" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the back shop with Mr Bennett when the prisoner came in.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Adamson. I am journeyman to Mr Bennett. We had often suspected the prisoner before; and Mr Bennett said he seem'd to shuffle about as if he had a mind to take something. Some time after Mr Bennett call'd me up stairs, and told me he saw the prisoner convey a piece of pink ribbon some where, but could not tell where. I told him he had bet ter send for a constable, so I went for one of the Bridge constables. My master and his father took the prisoner by each arm, and took him into the back shop; there I saw four pieces of ribbon in his hand, and another piece of pink colour taken from out of the prisoner's pocket; he had nothing in his hand when they first laid hold of him, and when he had wrench'd one hand from them, then I saw the four pieces in it; the prisoner said he had paid for the pink, and the others he would pay for. I know he never us'd to buy any more that 6 yards in one piece, and there were eighteen in that pink piece.</p>
               <p>Q. Can he speak English so as to be well understood?</p>
               <p>Adamson. He has been in England many years, and can speak well enough to be understood; I have known him some time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-person123">
                  Edward 
                  Bennett 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person123" type="surname" value="Bennett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person123" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My son the prosecutor let me know, that the prisoner at the bar had taken a piece of ribbon. I went out of my shop into his; there I took hold of the prisoner's right hand, and my son took him by the left; he ask'd me what I did that for; I told him he had got some of my son's property about him. We led him into the back shop; he had then nothing in either hand; he prayed for his hand at liberty; I had had him by it I believe for the space of a minute. I thought I might let it go, as there were a number of us; this was after we got him into the back shop; the moment I got it at liberty, he throw'd it like under his great coat, and brought out four pieces of ribbon, and laid them on the counter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him put his hand under his great coat?</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. I plainly did: he said he would pay for them; he would give 3 l. 12 s. for them; I desired the constable to search him; he put his hand into the prisoner's pocket, and pull'd out this pink piece of ribbon, and my son had before told me, he saw him take a piece of pink ribbon.</p>
               <p>Q. Which pocket was it taken from?</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. I cannot say that: I have had it in my custody ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say for himself?</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. He said he did not intend to steal them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say about the piece of pink?</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. He said he had bought that.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with him before my Lord-Mayor? E. Bennett. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the accusation against him?</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. It was for all the pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether any man in the world would not rather pay 3 l. 12 s. than be prosecuted, if they were not worth but 30 s.</p>
               <p>E. Bennett. This was not accidental; he had them secreted.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I have dealt with the prosecutor two years, I pay him ready money, and sometimes he gives me credit 'till I come back again, then I pay him; I had those four pieces in my hand, the piece of pink I paid for, so put that in my pocket. I had my coat hanging loose on my shoulders, as the young man had brought me a glass of brandy, I saw them come behind me, and they took me backwards, and then before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-13-person124">
                  Samuel 
                  Beaver 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person124" type="surname" value="Beaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person124" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am deputy corn-meter for the city. I remember Mr 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person125">
                  Bennett
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person125" type="given" value="Bennett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the prosecutor<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060014"></xptr> and I had some discourse together about these pieces of ribbon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever give you any account about this piece of pink ribbon?</p>
               <p>Beaver. The prisoner sent to my house to desire me to go to Mr Bennett to mitigate the matter, and to take a friend or two along with me. I went with another or two, and sent for Mr Bennett, who came over to the 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person126">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person126" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person126" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to us; I was desirous to know how it happened; Mr Bennet said he had dealt with the prisoner two years, and he believed he had taken about an hundred a year of him, and never scrupled him, 'till within these three quarters, of a year, but could not observe any thing that he took 'till this time, that he secreted himself upon all-fours on the stairs, and then saw him take this piece of pink, and that he did not miss any more; that he went down and got an officer and assistance, and apprehended him, and shov'd him into a little room; that the prisoner had some pieces in his hand, which he did not see in his hand when apprehended.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Mr Bennett say to you the piece of pink was paid for?</p>
               <p>Beaver. That was paid for.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you that?</p>
               <p>Beaver. Mr Bennett - I think.</p>
               <p>C. Speak the truth.</p>
               <p>Beaver. Upon my word I can't be positive of that.</p>
               <p>The prisoner then called 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person127">
                  Joseph 
                  Stains 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person127" type="surname" value="Stains"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person127" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a hatter and hosier at Aldgate, who had known him 10 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person128">
                  John 
                  Callahan 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person128" type="surname" value="Callahan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person128" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a publican, who had known him between 2 or 3 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person129">
                  John 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person129" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Whitechapel, who had known him 3 or 4 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person130">
                  Walter 
                  Murphey 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person130" type="surname" value="Murphey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person130" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of ditto, who had known him between 3 and 4 years. Mr Keiting of ditto, who had known him between 2 and 3 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person131">
                  Roger 
                  Macmahone 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person131" type="surname" value="Macmahone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person131" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him between 4 and 5 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person132">
                  William 
                  Fillingham 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person132" type="surname" value="Fillingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person132" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who keeps the George Inn in Whitechapel, who had known him about 8 months. Nathanael Kelley, who had known him 7 or 8 years. 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person133">
                  Henry 
                  Fry 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person133" type="surname" value="Fry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person133" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him between 5 and 6 years. And 
               <persName id="t17581206-13-person134">
                  Henry 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17581206-13-person134" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person134" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Fenchurch-street, who had known him upwards of 2 years. Who all spoke well of his character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-13-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-13-punish70" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-punish70" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-13-punish70" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-13-defend114 t17581206-13-punish70"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
