<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-39">
               <interp inst="t17531024-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-39" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-39" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-39-off175-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-39-defend255 t17531024-39-off175 t17531024-39-verdict178"></join>
         
               <p>484. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-defend255" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Bunce 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-39-defend255" type="surname" value="Bunce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-defend255" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-defend255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17531024-39-off175" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-off175" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-off175" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-39-victim257" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Chavace 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-39-victim257" type="surname" value="Chavace"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-39-victim257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-39-victim257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-39-off175 t17531024-39-victim257"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, he stood charg'd on the Coroner's inquisition for the said murder, <rs id="t17531024-39-cd176" type="crimeDate">August 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-39-off175 t17531024-39-cd176"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person258">
                  Claud 
                  Chavace 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person258" type="surname" value="Chavace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person258" type="given" value="Claud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased was my son.</p>
               <p>Q. How old was he?</p>
               <p>Chavace. He would have been fourteen years of age had he lived till the 4th of November. I live in May-fair-market, am a Chairman in the winter, and labourer in summer. I was at work upon a scaffold on the 28th of August, there came word to me, by two chairmen, that there was a boy kill'd in the park, and that it was said it was my son. They had carried him to St. George's hospital at Hide park Corner, I went there, and found it to be my son; he was laid in bed in all his bloody things. I spoke to him, but he gave me no answer. I saw the blood running down his head, then the chairmen took me to the place where they took him from in the park, it was about fifty or sixty yards within <placeName id="t17531024-39-crimeloc177">Grosvenor-gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-39-crimeloc177" type="placeName" value="Grosvenor-gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-39-crimeloc177" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-39-off175 t17531024-39-crimeloc177"></join>, between the walnut-trees and the gate, where lay some blood on the ground. I enquir'd how he came by his hurt, but could not hear any thing of it. I went on the Wednesday to see him, and was told he had spoke, and had told several people that the park-keeper had beat him. I went to Mr. Fielding for a warrant to take up the prisoner on suspicion, but the justice would not grant a warrant, except I would bring the man that heard the child say so; then I went back to the infirmary, and the doctor that examin'd the child said, possibly the child may come to his senses, and might tell who hurt him, and that it would be better not to take him up till we saw whether he would live or die.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the child speak after this?</p>
               <p>Chavace. Yes, I did several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible at any time do you think ?</p>
               <p>Chavace. I believe he was not rightly in his senses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person259">
                  Jane 
                  Chavace 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person259" type="surname" value="Chavace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person259" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My child received his hurt on Tuesday the 28th of August, and on the Thursday following I was standing by him some little time, I thought I found him partly sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Chavace. It was about two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you judge him partly sensible?</p>
               <p>Chavace. By his knowing me and calling me mother. I asked him what ail'd him, but he made no answer. I asked him who beat him, he answered, Pray mother give me a little tea and I'll tell you. I gave him a little tea, and asked him again, he said, the park-keeper struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention his name?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell at what gate he stood?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No, he did not. I asked him where he was hurt, he said on his back.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he describe any place else?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No, he did not; then he repeated the same words again, saying, the park-keeper beat him, and pray mother do you take care of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his head was very much hurt?</p>
               <p>Chavace. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him how he came by that wound on his head?</p>
               <p>Chavace. I did not, his senses were with him but a short while at a time; when he was sensible he'd cry for mercy in these words, Pray forgive me, that staff is too big; oftentimes he said so.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. You said at first setting out, you thought him<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240015"></xptr> partly sensible; did not you think him partly insensible?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No, I did not, that was the only time that I counted him sensible for so long a time together.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not judg'd insensible from the time he came into the hospital to his death.</p>
               <p>Chavace. At times he was sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you look upon the child to be sensible, at the time he said, Pray forgive me, that staff is too big.</p>
               <p>Chavace. I did imagine he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there ever a staff in the room?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you done any thing to him?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you affrighted him?</p>
               <p>Chavace. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you look upon him to be in his senses, when he asked you forgiveness?</p>
               <p>Chavace. He said, pray forgive me; he did not say mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person260">
                  Catherine 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person260" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person260" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd in Upper Brook-street, and kept major Burton's house, a little after eight o'clock in the morning, on the 28th of August, a gentlewoman passed me, and told me she saw a man beating a boy; she was very uneasy, and went down Brook-Street, and I into the park, the minute I went into the park, I saw the boy lying on his face, I thought him to be dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabout did he lie?</p>
               <p>Wells. He lay under the walnut-trees just by the park-keeper's house, I turn'd him on the right side and he groan'd; he seem'd not to lie easy, so I turn'd him on his face again. After that I turn'd him on his back again, and wip'd the blood and froth out of his mouth. I ask'd him who had beat him, but he could not speak. I look'd round the park and could not see any body. I saw the park-keeper's house door was shut, but the windows above and below are all open. I went to the house, and spoke to Mr. Turner, the master at the gate, and asked him where his servants were, and where the parkkeeper was, but he made no answer. I told him a boy lay dead in the park, but he made me no answer to it. I went down to my husband, and came back again, there the boy was then, and two women washing him with heartshorn and water, and a gentleman gave some people some money to carry the boy to the infirmary: I saw him no more till after he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the woman here that gave this information ?</p>
               <p>Wells. No, she is not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person261">
                  William 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person261" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person261" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a patient in the hospital, and lay in the room where the deceased did. I heard his mother ask him who beat him; he said the park-keeper, that he struck him over the back: I also heard him say, Pray, Sir, forgive me, that stick is too long.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take him to be in his senses then ?</p>
               <p>Parker. I took him to be more in his senses then, than at any other time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before he died?</p>
               <p>Parker. I can't tell how long?</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17531024-39-person262">
                  Jane 
                  Chavace 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person262" type="surname" value="Chavace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person262" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When did he die?</p>
               <p>Chavace. He died on the Tuesday fortnight after he received his hurt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person263">
                  William 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person263" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the testimony of the last witness, being by at the time, with this addition, that this was about a fortnight before he died.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person264">
                  Robert 
                  Hardyman 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person264" type="surname" value="Hardyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person264" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was riding on my mare in the park at that very time, about a quarter past eight o'clock in the morning, a boy was in the walnut-tree, I saw the prisoner at the bar with a pole, which he held much about over his head; but as for striking him I did not see that: The boy said, Pray don't strike me, for God Almighty's sake don't strike me any more. This I saw as I was galloping along; but I did not see the boy afterwards.</p>

               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I live in Hanover-square, and am a piece of a coachman. I look after some equl page belonging to my lord Powis, who is now abroad, I take care of his chariot and harness, and the steward's mare. I was on her at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Mr. Fielding on this occasion?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you attend there?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. Because I did not care to bring myself into a preminary about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you first tell it to?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I told it to a chairman last Sunday in a publick-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know that it was advertised that a chairman's son was found murdered in Hyde-Park ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240016"></xptr>Hardyman. I can neither write nor read.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear that a child had been kill'd in the park?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I never heard it till last Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how came that to be a reason that you did not talk of it, fearing being brought into a preminary?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I never heard of it till last Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear you saw this, that day the boy was kill'd?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I can't say what day, I know it was in August, and after I came home with my mare and was rubbing her down, I heard a boy was gone to the hospital, and that the park-keeper had knock'd him out of a walnut-tree; upon my word I don't know what day of the month it was, and I have been out of town since that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before ?</p>
               <p>Hardyman. I have known him three or four years, he is the park-keeper's servant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person265">
                  William 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person265" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being committed to New-prison for perjury on this account, was, by the desire of the prosecutor, brought into court, and also his mittimus, which was first read to this purport:</p>
               <p>He being charged with being guilty of first making information against the prisoner, charging him with giving an account of many Circumstances, tending to prove the prisoner guilty of the murder of the deceased; and he since had declared before justice Fielding, that all he had said was false, and that he committed perjury when he said the same.</p>
               <p>S ign'd by Justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person266">
                  William 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person266" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person266" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am between fifteen and sixteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know about the boy's being kill'd?</p>
               <p>Warner. I know nothing of it. I was a little in liquor, and having a heard others talk of it, I told my landlady, and they took me before the justice; after that I came to consider it was a sad thing to take a man's life away.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you said about it?</p>
               <p>Warner. I had taken on oath that I knew of it; but after that I went and told them I had taken a false oath, for which I am very sorry, and hope God will forgive me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner committed upon your oath?</p>
               <p>Warner. He was.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say, but called the following witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person267">
                  John 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person267" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person267" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the master or keeper of Grosvenor's-Gate, the prisoner is my servant ; on Tuesday morning the 28th of August, about eight o'clock, I was sitting at work below stairs in a room that looks into the park, the window was open, there came a man to me and told me thro' the casement, that there was a boy killed in the park. I said, I can't help that; he asked me were Richard was, meaning the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that person?</p>
               <p>Turner. He was a servant belonging to Mr. Spinneys ; said I, Richard has been gone with his linnen to wash about twenty minutes; he usually carried it once a week.</p>
               <p>Q. How long does he commonly stay when he goes with his linnen ?</p>
               <p>Turner. He commonly stays two hours, his sister washes for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Then what time do you judge he went out ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I believe he went out about twenty minutes before eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does his sister live?</p>
               <p>Turner. She lives in Portland-street, beyond Chandois-square; the way there is from my house through Grosvenor's-gate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him go out?</p>
               <p>Turner. I did, with his bundle in his hand, and a cane.</p>
               <p>Q. What does he do with his staff at such times.</p>
               <p>Turner. He lays that down sometimes within, and sometimes without the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it his nearest way to go by the walnut-trees ?</p>
               <p>Turner. No, that would be almost the length of the park about.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he return that day.</p>
               <p>Turner. He returned about ten o'clock. The prisoner has been my servant about two years: when he came to me, he said, he very seldom worked with his chair on a Sunday (being a chairman) and desir'd I would give him leave to go to church as usual; I did; he has continued that practice ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he for natural temper ?</p>
               <p>Turner. He is the best behaved man I ever had, he is not swearer or drunkard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Catherine Wells talking to you that day.</p>
               <p>Turner. No, my lord, I do not; it has slipp'd my memory if she did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240017"></xptr>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17531024-39-person268">
                  Catherine 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person268" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person268" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Is this the man you talk'd to, that gave you no answer?</p>
               <p>C. Wells. It is; he was pulling hair to pieces. I put my head in at the window, and said, sir. where are all the park-keepers gone, here is a boy lies murdered in the park ! he made me no answer to any thing I said ; in about twenty minutes after, I and a footman went to the window ( this was as I came back) and the footman spoke to Mr. Turner ; then his answer was, he knew nothing about it.</p>

               <p>Q. to Turner. What did you do upon this?</p>
               <p>Turner. I saw nothing of the accident to the boy. After I was told it, I went just out at the door and saw a croud of people. and it shocked me, then I went in at the door again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person269">
                  Robert 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person269" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person269" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The day the boy was murdered I rode into the park by eight o'clock; I saw the prisoner going from Crosvenor's Gate, he was then about twelve yards from the gate with a bundle in his hand, going toward. Tyburn.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a staff in his hand.</p>
               <p>Carter. No, he had not; I went into the park, and over the place where the boy was murdered; there was no boy there then; when I came back he y there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Carter. I do very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person270">
                  John 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person270" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Golden-lion door, which is opposite to Grosvenor's Gate, a little before eight o'clock. I saw the prisoner with a handkerchief, and something in it like linnen, in his hand, and a cane in the other; he went under the wall towards Tyburn: about half an hour after eight o'clock I went into the park, and saw the deceased lying on his back, between a post and a wallnut-tree; there was a man with two horses and a boy with one; the man called to me and desired I would help the boy up. I assisted him and undid his stock-buckle and collar; there were ten or twelve drops of blood, I can't say more or less, upon the ground; there was a cut on one side of his head were the blood came from: there were two pieces of bread and butter lay behind his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible ?</p>
               <p>Mills. No, he was not. When I came into the park was the first of my hearing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mills. Six or seven months.</p>
               <p>Q. to Turner. How many servants do you keep ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I keep only the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do the other keepers keep servants?</p>
               <p>Turner. They do ; but they attend their own gates.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Bunce. I am sister to the prisoner at the bar: I remember the 28th of Aug. when the accident happen'd to the boy. I wash for my brother, and live in Portland-street, Oxford Market.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from Grosvenor's Gate.</p>
               <p>Bunce. I believe it is about a mile; my brother's usual way is to bring his linnen once a week to be washed: he brought it that very 28th of Aug. when he came in it was turned of eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How much after eight?</p>
               <p>Turner. I believe it was not quite half an hour, or about twenty minutes past eight.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay with you ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I believe he might stay half an hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person271">
                  Sarah 
                  Ducey 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person271" type="surname" value="Ducey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person271" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner almost five years. I lodge in the house with his sister. I remember the day this lad got his death in Hide park. I saw the prisoner twice that day; he came about a quarter after eight in the morning, the second time was at about half an hour after eight; he had nothing but his cane in his hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person272">
                  Lucas Everard 
                  Greenhead 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person272" type="surname" value="Greenhead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person272" type="given" value="Lucas Everard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am assistant apothecary and belong to St. George's hospital; I remember the deceased being brought in there. I attended upon him, for my own satisfaction, sometimes every day, and looked upon him to be in a state of delirium all the time; that I can venture to say.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person273">
                  Thomas 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person273" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person273" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pupil at St. George's hospital. I remember the lad's being brought there. I attended and dressed him all the while. I never saw him sensible in the least.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person274">
                  John 
                  Cotton 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person274" type="surname" value="Cotton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person274" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a year and a half, he is a very honest, good-natured, humane man, I saw the boy alive in the park that day and I joked with him; he said nothing to me; I went about my business: he was eating bread and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cotton. I did not, neither going nor coming.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the park was the boy?</p>
               <p>Cotton. He was near the wallnut-trees.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this you saw him?</p>
               <p>Cotton. It was five minutes after eight in the morning, the clock had struck eight as I came to the wallnut-trees.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there nobody at the gate?</p>
               <p>Cotton. There was not, and the lodge door shut.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person275">
                  James 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person275" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person275" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember that day the boy was killed, there was nobody but I and another soldier walking together: I saw the boy fall out of a wallnut-tree.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Davis. I had never seen the prisoner then in my life. There were two gentlemen riding by, one on a black horse, the other on a gray one. one of them smack'd his whip; we conceived that assrighted the boy and made him fall down: he got up again and ran towards the gateway and fell down again.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was between eight and nine in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to the boy when you saw him fall the second time ?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, we never staid to look, we took no money at all, but went on.</p>
               <p>Mr. Parker. I have known the prisoner for some time, he is an honest, sober, industrious man, as any in England.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he could be capable of killing a little boy for getting a few wallnuts ?</p>
               <p>Parker. Far from it, he was one of the most humane men towards Children.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17531024-39-person276">
                  Andrew 
                  Chedwick 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person276" type="surname" value="Chedwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person276" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I have known the prisoner seventeen or eighteen years, he is a very honest, careful, and sober man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he would go to kill a lad for getting up into a wallnut-tree ?</p>
               <p>Chedwick. I believe him very far from it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-39-person277">
                  Peter Abraham 
                  Mozear 
               <interp inst="t17531024-39-person277" type="surname" value="Mozear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person277" type="given" value="Peter Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner, I believe, a dozen years ; I have a very good opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be of so inhuman a disposition, as to murder a boy in a wallnut-tree for getting a few wallnuts.</p>
               <p>Mozear. I don't think he would; I remember he once told me he left off being a chairman, because he would have the Sunday to attend divine worship.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-39-verdict178" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-39-verdict178" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
