<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591024-9">
               <interp inst="t17591024-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-9" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-9" type="date" value="17591024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591024-9-off35-c68" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-9-defend87 t17591024-9-off35 t17591024-9-verdict38"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591024-9-off35-c69" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-9-defend89 t17591024-9-off35 t17591024-9-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>306, 307. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17591024-9-defend87" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Tucker 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend87" type="surname" value="Tucker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend87" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              and 
               
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-defend89" type="defendantName">
                     Andrew 
                     Deering 
                  <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend89" type="surname" value="Deering"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend89" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-defend89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17591024-9-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one shagreen watch, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-victim91" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Pardoe 
                  <interp inst="t17591024-9-victim91" type="surname" value="Pardoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-victim91" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-victim91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-9-off35 t17591024-9-victim91"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17591024-9-cd36" type="crimeDate">October 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-9-off35 t17591024-9-cd36"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-person92">
                  Anne 
                  Badderley 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-person92" type="surname" value="Badderley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person92" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person92" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am laundress to Mr. Pardoe's lodgings in Lincoln's-Inn; he was out of town, and his chambers were repairing. I brought his watch from the chambers for security. When I came home Mr Tucker was in the tap-room; he said he was the 7th son of a 7th son. I lodge at <placeName id="t17591024-9-crimeloc37">the Castle in Portugal-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17591024-9-crimeloc37" type="placeName" value="the Castle in Portugal-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591024-9-crimeloc37" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-9-off35 t17591024-9-crimeloc37"></join>. He was curing of people. I having a bad breast, my landlady said, he may do you good. He told me also, if I believed in God he could cure me. I said, I did believe in God. I put my stomacher on one side for him to touch it with his hand. He said he must touch my stomach, and he put his hand farther. Then he said, I must turn three times round to the sun, which I did. I soon miss'd my master's watch out of my bosom: it was a shagreen watch with a gold dial plate.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had it in your bosom when the prisoner undertook to cure you.</p>
               <p>Badderley. I am sure I had, and when I took him up he owned he had it. And when I took up the other prisoner, who is a soldier, he own'd he had had it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Deering present at the time you lost it.</p>
               <p>Badderley. No, he was not in that house then. I have since been told, that the prisoner Tucker is a madman, and has been in Bethlem 3 or 4 times.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>


               <p>Badderley. He has been a Cheesemonger, and kept a shop in the Fleet-Market. I took him before Mr Fielding, there he own'd he had the watch, and that he took it from me; and there the soldier owned he had it from Mr. Tucker, but I never got it again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-person93">
                  Thomas 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-person93" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person93" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a soldier. I came into my quarters at the Castle and Falcon in Holborn, about 6 in the evening, on a Saturday, about a fortnight ago, I do not know the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I lost the watch last Saturday was se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Rice. There the two prisoners were drinking together: I sat down in the next box to them, they ask'd me to drink. Deering handed the pot to me over the table; I drank, and gave him the pot again. Tucker took a watch with a yellow dial-plate, with a shagreen case, and a packthread string out of his pocket, the glass fell; he took it up, and in striving to get in again he broke it, he having his breeches on with the wrong side outwards, went to pull them off to turn them. (He pretended to be out of his senses.) Deering said, let me hold the watch 'till you turn your breeches. Tucker gave him his watch to hold. He was about ten minutes in turning his breeches: in the mean time Deering ran out of the tap-room<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175910240008"></xptr> into the street with the watch. Tucker looked up and said, Is the man gone with my watch. I ran directly after him, but he had made his escape, and I could not catch him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing hanging to the packthread?</p>
               <p>Rice. Only a key. The madman then said, it was not his own, but it was a gentlewoman's which he had in cure with a sore breast, and he would buy a silk string to it, and bring it to her again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Badderley. Describe the watch. -</p>
               <p>Badderley. It had a gold dial-plate, shagreen-case, with a packthread, and only a key.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rice. Did you see it open?</p>
               <p>Rice. I did not.</p>
               <p>Tucker's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have nothing to say in the affair; I have had the misfortune to be out of my senses several times.</p>
               <p>Deering's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in that house on Saturday was se'nnight, and Tucker came in after I was there; I never saw him before, he sat down in a box and called for beer, and pulled out this watch and opened it, and looked at it, and was for taking it to pieces; he ran his thumb through the glass and broke it; it fell down, he picked it up again, but could not fix it in again: then he said to me, Here, do you take it. I took it in my hand, there were several people asked him how he came by it; he said a lady he was courting gave it him; they asked to look at it, and handed it from one to another, and I never saw it since I delivered it out of my hand, neither did I run away with it.</p>
               <p>For Tucker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-person94">
                  Richard 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-person94" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person94" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Tucker about 10 years, he was a cheesemonger, a man of worth, but by unavoidable misfortunes was reduced; he has been out of his senses many years: I myself have known him to commit several acts of lunacy, going about preaching; sometimes almost naked, pretending to cure people. My father has an estate in Hertfordshire, out of which he pays Tucker about 10 l. per year: he came to me some time ago, and desired I would get him into St Bartholomew's Hospital, his legs were swelled; I got him in, he was so outragious there, that the people could hardly tell what to do with him; after he was cured he went down into the country, and then came up again to our house, and seemed tolerable well, and we settled with him; this is about three weeks ago; he went away as we thought to Hertfordshire, we gave him a written order to a woman there to let him have a Guinea if he wanted it. I have often met him in the streets dressed in the same manner he is now*, telling people he could cure all deceases, if they believed in Abraham, Issac, and Jacob, by only licking them: on the Tuesday or Thursday before he was taken up, I saw him in Morefields with a great crowd about him; he said to the people, What do you trouble me for, I am going home? he went towards Bethlem Hospital, and the people followed him, they admitted him in from the people at the gate, knowing him very well; there I found he was known by many of the disordered people walking about, as well as by the servants belonging to Bethlem; of my own knowledge, I do not know that ever he was confined there; but I went yesterday to the steward, who let me take extracts from the book, and I find he has been confined there three or four times. He produced a paper. This is a true copy of what I found in the book, I went and examined it with the book afterwards, and here is the steward's name to it, testifying it to be a true extract; he went in there in the year 40, and continued there till the year 43; he is certainly out of his senses, and here are others that can prove the same.</p>
               <p>* His coat was buttoned behind, and rags tied about his legs.</p>
               <p>For Deering.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-person95">
                  Thomas 
                  Osman 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-person95" type="surname" value="Osman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person95" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Deering upwards of a year. I keep an alehouse, I have trusted him to draw beer and take money for me by night and by day, he never wronged me to my knowledge; I look upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-9-person96">
                  Ann 
                  Osman 
               <interp inst="t17591024-9-person96" type="surname" value="Osman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person96" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last witness. I have trusted Deering with 10 guineas at a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175910240009"></xptr> time, and to draw beer for me by night and by day, and with the house when I have gone out; he never wronged me of any thing that ever I knew of.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17591024-9-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-9-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
