<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511204-7">
               <interp inst="t17511204-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-7" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-7" type="date" value="17511204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511204-7-off36-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-7-defend77 t17511204-7-off36 t17511204-7-verdict40"></join>
         
               <p>7. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511204-7-defend77" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Booth 
                  <interp inst="t17511204-7-defend77" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-defend77" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-defend77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511204-7-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17511204-7-person78">
                        Nathaniel 
                        Wilks 
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person78" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-7-person78" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-7-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the <rs id="t17511204-7-cd37" type="crimeDate">28th of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-7-off36 t17511204-7-cd37"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511204-7-victim80" type="victimName">
                           Steven 
                           Pile 
                        <interp inst="t17511204-7-victim80" type="surname" value="Pile"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-7-victim80" type="given" value="Steven"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-7-victim80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-7-off36 t17511204-7-victim80"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and steal out thence thirty-four calves skins, value 8 l. two linen checque aprons, and one pair of pumps
            </rs>. *.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-7-person81">
                  Steven 
                  Pile 
               <interp inst="t17511204-7-person81" type="surname" value="Pile"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person81" type="given" value="Steven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17511204-7-crimeloc38">Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-7-crimeloc38" type="placeName" value="Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-7-crimeloc38" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-7-off36 t17511204-7-crimeloc38"></join>, am a <rs id="t17511204-7-viclabel39" type="occupation">currier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-7-victim80 t17511204-7-viclabel39"></join>, on the 28th of September I lost the Goods mentioned. The skins were hanging in my shed, which is like a brewer's shed, the pumps were in my work-shop underneath the shed, the two checque aprons were hanging upon a line in the yard. The boards of the shed were broken to get in.</p>
               <p>Q. Does this shed belong to your dwelling-house?</p>
               <p>Pile. It is part of it, it joins to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you go out of your house into it, without going into the yard?</p>
               <p>Pile. The door opens into the yard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-7-person82">
                  James 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17511204-7-person82" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person82" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to me when I was in my bed, in Cross-lane joining to Holbourn in Star-court; he told me he could get such goods, and that he could make money of them presently; when he brought me there, they were all removed; this was in the beginning of September; after that he came again on the 28th, when the place was full of goods; we went, and one 
               <persName id="t17511204-7-person83">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Wilks 
               <interp inst="t17511204-7-person83" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person83" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with us; there is a thoroughfare that goes from Holbourn into a back-street, out of which place we got into the prosecutor's drying room by breaking a board, and from thence down into the shop; then we opened the door by breaking the lock, and went out into the yard, there was a light in a one pair of stairs room. We took away the leather, 36 skins, 3 linen aprons that hung on a line betwixt two houses, we took a pair of pumps from out of the workshop. As the watchman came by that back place, we fastened the door fearing he should knock against it; when he was gone by, we went with the goods to my apartment; we sold three of the skins, and the rest of them were taken again by the prosecutor. They were to have been sold to a man that buys all manner of stolen goods, where the prisoner lodged. He wanted me to let him have them for a tenth part of the value ; so we quarrelled, and so the affair came out; the constable heard us quarrel, as<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175112040006"></xptr> he came by. So the next morning the prisoner divulged the whole to him; the constable took us both up, if they had not been wet, we should have sold them all.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Pros. What goods did you find again?</p>
               <p>Pros. I found 2 dozen and eight of them in this evidence's room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-7-person84">
                  Thomas 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17511204-7-person84" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person84" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; on the 2d of October, the prisoner came to give me information of the robbery, and asked me if a Neighbour was not robbed of some leather? he said they were to be found at either Davis's, or Wilks's; and wanted to know, if there was a reward if the person was cast. Then I went with the prosecutor and found 2 dozen and eight calf skins, and one coloured apron. The prisoner did not say he was in the robbery, but that the reason of his coming was upon a quarrel.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It is all false they have sworn.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511204-7-verdict40" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-7-verdict40" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
