<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-9">
               <interp inst="t17590912-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-9" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-9" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-9-off62-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-9-defend113 t17590912-9-off62 t17590912-9-verdict64"></join>
         
               <p>255. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-9-defend113" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Marlow 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-9-defend113" type="surname" value="Marlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-defend113" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-defend113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17590912-9-deflabel61" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-9-defend113 t17590912-9-deflabel61"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17590912-9-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four half guineas, and 20 s. in money numbered, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590912-9-victim115" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17590912-9-victim115" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-9-victim115" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-9-victim115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-9-off62 t17590912-9-victim115"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17590912-9-person116">
                        Frances 
                        Dunn 
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person116" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-9-person116" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-9-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, widow, July 22.*</p> 
               <p>Thomas Davis. I live in Rose-street, Covent-Garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does 
               <persName id="t17590912-9-person117">
                  Frances 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17590912-9-person117" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person117" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             live?</p>
               <p>Davis. She keeps a lodging-house in <placeName id="t17590912-9-crimeloc63">Orange-Court, Drury-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-9-crimeloc63" type="placeName" value="Orange-Court, Drury-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-9-crimeloc63" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-9-off62 t17590912-9-crimeloc63"></join>; I happened to have a bad lodging there.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she sell liquor?</p>
               <p>Davis. No: but I had a woman there in her apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. What woman?</p>
               <p>Davis. A woman that I call'd in that was passing by the door?</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Davis. I am a Taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. What business had you there?</p>
               <p>Davis. I wanted a lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was it that you call'd her in?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was in the morning; I wanted to lie down.</p>
               <p>Q. What woman was it you call'd in?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was 
               <persName id="t17590912-9-person118">
                  Mary 
                  Marlow 
               <interp inst="t17590912-9-person118" type="surname" value="Marlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person118" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the gentlewoman at the bar; she went up stairs with me; I trusted her; and told her what money I had.</p>
               <p>Q. How much had you?</p>
               <p>Davis. I had four half guineas, seven half crowns, and some other silver; the half crowns were in my coat pocket, and my half guineas in my fob.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk or sober when you went into that house?</p>
               <p>Davis. I was middling; I can't say I was quite drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to get in liquor so early in the morning.</p>
               <p>Davis. I had been up drinking all night, and could not get into my quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened to you after you was there?</p>
               <p>Davis. I told her not to rob me, because I knew her before; I paid for my bed and went to bed and nobody was with me but she; and when I awaked she was gone, and my money also.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you awake?</p>
               <p>Davis. I slept about three or four hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you laid your cloaths?</p>
               <p>Davis. I had laid my breeches under my head, and my cloaths about my face upon me; when I awak'd, I cry'd to my landlady, what is become o f the woman that was along with me; here she is, said she, and the prisoner came up along with her; she ask'd what was the matter with me; I said, I was robb'd; she took three half crowns out of her pocket, and was putting them down her bosom; I could take my oath they were mine; and she was shifting the gold under her apron-string; and two bullies broke into the house, and came up and broke one of my ribs, and my landlady saved my life, or they would have murdered me and robb'd me of what I had about me; they and she all made off together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get any of your money again?</p>
               <p>Davis. I got only the three half crowns out of her bosom?</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know those three half crowns were your's?</p>
               <p>Davis. I have had them some time; they were remarkable pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. What marks had they?</p>
               <p>Davis. One of them was a Queen Anne's half crown; but what business had she to shift them out of her pocket into her bosom if they were not mine.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120011"></xptr>Q. When did you take her up?</p>
               <p>Davis. I took her up about six weeks after she robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she robb'd you; you say you was asleep?</p>
               <p>Davis. Nobody robb'd me but she I am sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-9-person119">
                  Frances 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17590912-9-person119" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person119" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This man ask'd me if he could have a lodging for six-pence, and said he would lie by himself in particular; I said, yes, you may, and for less money if you chuse it; he said, he had been at the next door to ask for his wife; I ask'd him who she was; he said, 
               <persName id="t17590912-9-person120">
                  Mary 
                  Marlow 
               <interp inst="t17590912-9-person120" type="surname" value="Marlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person120" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said, when was you married to her? he said, last Christmas; I said, you are mistaken, she never was married; he said, she was, and he had been to ask for her, and she was not come home; after that she came in; he sent for some beer and was reading the news; then he said, this woman shall see me go to bed, and nobody else; I said, take care, master, that your money is safe that you have got about you, pray show your money if you have any about you; he said, he had not a farthing of money but six-pence; out of which he was to pay for his bed and pot of beer; she went up stairs and made no longer tarry than to see him in bed and back again; he remained there 'till four in the afternoon; he awak'd and call'd for me; and said, where is that woman that lay with me; what, your wife, said I; then I went down to 
               <persName id="t17590912-9-person121">
                  Bridget 
                  Mears 
               <interp inst="t17590912-9-person121" type="surname" value="Mears"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person121" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and saw her, and said, your husband is awake you must come up to him; she went with me to him; I lock'd my street door; he said, she had taken his money; I put my back against the room door, and said, if you have his money pray deliver it to him; she took something out of her pocket and dropp'd it down into her bosom; then I said, now you foolish man if it is your money go and get it; when he got them from her they were almost as black as a hat; she call'd out, murder, murder; in came two men, one of the men kick'd him; he said, he broke one of his ribs; she got away, and the two men laid him on on both sides, and got to his pockets and wanted more money; I put my arms about him, and said, you notorious wretches you shall not touch him, my life shall go for his.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>He brought me up into the room with him, and said he had but a shilling for me and sixpence for the bed; I took it, and we laid down on the bed; he said, he would go to sleep; after that I came down stairs and gave Mrs Dunn the six-pence for the bed and went out.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-9-verdict64" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-9-verdict64" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
