<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590530-4">
               <interp inst="t17590530-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-4" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-4" type="date" value="17590530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590530-4-off19-c53" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-4-defend58 t17590530-4-off19 t17590530-4-verdict22"></join>
         
               <p>181. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17590530-4-defend58" type="defendantName">
                  
                     James 
                     Dun 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17590530-4-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-4-defend58 t17590530-4-alias-1"></join>Roberts</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-defend58" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-defend58" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-defend58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17590530-4-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a bill of exchange, with the name J. Hazard under-wrote, dated Apr. 12. 59. drawn on Mess. Honywood and Fuller, to 
                     <persName id="t17590530-4-person60">
                        James 
                        Roberts 
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-person60" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-4-person60" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-4-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , or order, for the sum of One hundred pounds; and publishing the same, well knowing it to have been falsly made and counterfeited, with intention to defraud 
                     <persName id="t17590530-4-victim61" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Johnson 
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-victim61" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-4-victim61" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-4-victim61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-4-off19 t17590530-4-victim61"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-4-person62">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17590530-4-person62" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-person62" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was formerly my <rs id="t17590530-4-deflabel20" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-4-defend58 t17590530-4-deflabel20"></join>. <rs id="t17590530-4-viclabel21" type="occupation">I keep a musick shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-4-victim61 t17590530-4-viclabel21"></join> in Cheapside. He quitted my service about three years ago last February, and went into the navy, and has been at sea 'till within six or seven months. He had not served his time out, and for his wages included, and other accounts, he owed me about 70 l. About the 14th of April last he call'd upon me to make me satisfaction, and gave me this bill of exchange, producing one; it is for 100 l. this was at a Coffee-house. I went home, and gave him a bank note of 30 l. by way of change. I sent my apprentice at the same time to Mr Honywood, to know if it would be paid when due. My young man returned, and said, they told him it was not a good bill; so I sent for a constable and he was committed. I then desired him to return me my bank note, this was at Burton's Coffee-house, Cheapside, he return'd me my note.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say upon that?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He said, he did not intend to defraud me; he was obliged to go down to Portsmouth, being Purser of a man of war. He had been in town some time, endeavouring to get a sum of money due to him in the navy, to the amount of 300 l. and upwards, and that he was disappointed, and that he had wrote that bill for fourteen days, on purpose to get the sum of 30 l. to take him down to Portsmouth.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175905300006"></xptr> He intended when he got there, to get leave to return to London, where he was certain of receiving the money before this bill became due, and he intended to come to me and take up that bill, and pay me the whole 100 l. He had arose by his merit from a secretary's clerk, to be purser to the Fortune Sloop. I had reason to believe he had money due from the Navy-office, he has since paid me my 70 l. and I know not, but if I had not sent about the bill, he might have returned according to what he declared, and have paid me my money before the note had become due. I cannot say, that I believe he intended to defraud me of that money. He was five years with me, and was extream diligent, and was as good a servant as ever lived, 'till he took a fancy to the seas, then he was restless and uneasy. I have heard Admiral 
               <persName id="t17590530-4-person63">
                  Hawke
               <interp inst="t17590530-4-person63" type="given" value="Hawke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-person63" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's secretary say, he behav'd so well, that he preferr'd him to be chief clerk in his office.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that secretary now?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I believe he is now with the Admiral in the Bay.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590530-4-verdict22" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-4-verdict22" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
