<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-27">
               <interp inst="t17501017-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-27" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-27" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-27-off132-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-27-defend249 t17501017-27-off132 t17501017-27-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>645. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-27-defend249" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Fletcher 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-27-defend249" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-defend249" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-defend249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-27-off132" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-off132" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-off132" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 10 guineas, and 2 s. and 6 d. the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17501017-27-victim251" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Wittnell 
                        <interp inst="t17501017-27-victim251" type="surname" value="Wittnell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-27-victim251" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-27-victim251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-27-off132 t17501017-27-victim251"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17501017-27-person252">
                        George 
                        Carlow 
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person252" type="surname" value="Carlow"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-27-person252" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-27-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17501017-27-cd133" type="crimeDate">May 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-27-off132 t17501017-27-cd133"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-27-person253">
                  Thomas 
                  Wittnell 
               <interp inst="t17501017-27-person253" type="surname" value="Wittnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person253" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been merry-making with a ship-mate; coming home between twelve and one, between the 6th and 7th of May, the prisoner picked me up in Cable-street, and carried me into Carlow's house; she asked me to go to bed; I said, yes; accordingly she got a Candle, and we both went up stairs: said she, pull off your cloaths; I laid my cloaths on the bed, and my breeches under my head; we both went to bed immediately; after that I went to sleep. I had 10 guineas, and half a crown in my pocket, when I went into the room; I had told it that very same evening; I awaked between 4 and 5 o'clock, and look'd about, and found the prisoner was gone. I put my hand under the pillow, and felt my breeches, but the purse and money was gone; then I went to feel in the right hand pocket, and the half-crown was gone; so I had nothing but 3 or 4 pennyworth of halfpence left; I told the man of the house of it, he was much affrighted, and said he would not rest till he found her; he found her two days after, she was carried before Justice Manwaring, and sent to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Why was she not tried before now?</p>
               <p>Wittnell. The evidence was out of the way, and I was very ill; so I could not find the bill before; she was then discharg'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get your money again?</p>
               <p>Wittnell. I never saw purse or money since; after I got well, and a little money, I thought proper to take her up, to do myself and my country justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk at this time?</p>
               <p>Wittnell. I was not, nor near it.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination, he said, he was coming from Ratcliff Cross at this time; that he did not fall in with any other company; that Carlow never applied to him since, about the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-27-person254">
                  Mary 
                  Proby 
               <interp inst="t17501017-27-person254" type="surname" value="Proby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person254" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 4th or 5th of May I lay in the same room, up two pair of stairs, with the prisoner, and prosecutor; but I was in another bed, and went to bed after them; when he was asleep, 
               <persName id="t17501017-27-person255">
                  Mary 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17501017-27-person255" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person255" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             awak'd me; she took the man's shoe in her hand, and shew'd me the buckle, and said, she thought that was her property; she wanted me to take the watch. She laid the watch down, and the shoe, and did not take the buckles; she said she was a-dry, and ask'd me to go with her, which I did, as far as White Lyon-street, almost a quarter of a mile from Carlow's house; she shew'd me a little purse, tied with two strings, with 5 guineas, and a new half crown in it; she said, if he did not pay her, she'd make bold to pay herself; and told me, as I was bare of cloaths, she would take me to Monmouth-street, and buy me a gown.</p>
               <p>On her cross Examination she said, she never saw any harm in Carlow's house; she had seen men and women go to bed together there; that since this affair there has been a prosecution against the house, for a disorderly one; that Carlow apply'd to her, to be an evidence now; and that the prisoner had been an evidence against Carlow, in the other prosecution.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-27-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-27-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
