<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540424-55">
               <interp inst="t17540424-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-55" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-55" type="date" value="17540424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-55-off293-c391" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-55-defend492 t17540424-55-off293 t17540424-55-verdict295"></join>
         
               <p>292. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540424-55-defend492" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-defend492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17540424-55-deflabel292" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-55-defend492 t17540424-55-deflabel292"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17540424-55-off293" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-off293" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-off293" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540424-55-victim494" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Adams 
                        <interp inst="t17540424-55-victim494" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-55-victim494" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-55-victim494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-55-off293 t17540424-55-victim494"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540424-55-cd294" type="crimeDate">April 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-55-off293 t17540424-55-cd294"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person495">
                  Robert 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person495" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person495" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of April a little after seven o'clock at night I called at the house of Mr. Troy by the Horse Guards; he said, will you please to walk in here, here is nobody here but a gentlewoman of my acquaintance, when I went in there was a pint of wine, and the prisoner at the bar was the woman that was there: she said, I must have a little punch for I cannot drink two-penny; I staid till I cannot tell whether it had struck 8<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240031"></xptr> or not; she drank punch with Mr. Troy, but I drank none: I believe a little before eight I went out to go home; Mr. Troy said, Mr. Adams, as you are going to Westminster I should be obliged to you, if you would conduct this lady towards her lodgings; I asked her whether she would go the park or street way; she said the street way, and then took me by the arm; I never saw her before in my life. We walked very softly together, with her arm under mine; we went on till we came to Abington Buildings, on the other side of the Abbey; she then asked me what o'clock it was; I pulled my watch out, there were two lamps at a door, but I could not see exactly; but said, I believed it was much about nine: I put my watch in my pocket again. I was not got three doors from that place, but she took me round the waste, and said, sir, you shall not go any farther, I am going to College-Court; and she kist me, and I her. I just went from her, a very moment, five or six steps homewards, but happening to put my hand to my breeches I mist my watch; I turned round and ran after her to the end of College-Street, but could not see her; I ran down College-Court, but saw nothing of her. I then went past my own door and through the park to the house of Mr. Troy: I said to him, for God's sake tell me where this gentlewoman lives, for she has got my watch; he said, he did not know where she lodged, but he would see where she lodged; he said, there was one person went home with her he believed could tell me where she lived, his name is Coningham, in Long-ditch; we then went with his son-in-law through the park: when Coningham came down stairs he was to shew us the way to where she lived; and I got a warrant and constable, and we all went to her lodgings. If she had gone there at first, I must have heard her knock at the door, for I went by it after I had lost my watch. We knockt at the door, and it was opened; we asked for her, but was told she was gone to bed; the woman went to shut the door, but I clapt my foot to it and insisted on seeing her; she came out then, and said, Mr. Adams what is the matter? I said to her, you have got my watch; she denied it three or four times; I then served the warrant on her, upon which she burst into tears, and said, don't expose me, and asked me the price of the watch; I said it cost me 7 l. but now it was not worth high so much; she said, I will give you any thing for it. The gentleman who goes for her husband came in, in a great flurry, and calling me aside, asked me what it was worth; he proffered me money; I told him I could not take money. She was taken to the constable's house, the justice being gone to bed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been that day?</p>
               <p>Adams. I had been with Mr. Troy doing business for him that day, we dined in St. Martin's-lane; he took me to appraise some goods for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Adams. I drank only two glasses of wine at Mr. Troy's, that is all, at seven at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know the prisoner is the wife of an officer in the army?</p>
               <p>Adams. I never saw her before; when I went to have the indictment drawn up, I was asked her husband's name; I said, I did not know that; he said, then I will put her down widow.</p>
               <p>Q. You know since that she is wife of an officer in the army, don't you?</p>
               <p>Adams. I have been told so.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see what it was o'clock, when you pulled out your watch?</p>
               <p>Adams. I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you think she had your watch ?</p>
               <p>Adams. When we parted she put her hands round my waste.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it possible for this woman to take the watch out at that time?</p>
               <p>Adams. I don't know how it was; I mist it presently, I don't know how she did it?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive her hand at your fob?</p>
               <p>Adams. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not possible this watch might have slipt down putting it into your fob?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240032"></xptr>Adams. I am quite sure it did not. She took hold on me all the way, except there was a post, then she would come up to me again and take me by the arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stop any where?</p>
               <p>Adams. We never stopt at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go to her husband next morning?</p>
               <p>Adams. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you then ask him to pay you the value of the watch and you would trouble him no more about it ?</p>
               <p>Adams. No, he proposed to pay me; the gentleman proffered to give me any money, I said, I did not care to do it; he said, I will indemnify you; this he said several times in his own room. I went to my attorney, who was not at home, but his partner was; he told me not to do it, saying, it was a felony.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink where you went to appraise the goods?</p>
               <p>Adams. Mr. Troy was in the room almost all the time, we drank none there, after that we went to dine; there were five or six more with us.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you drink then?</p>
               <p>Adams. There were three or four full pots of beer and some punch, it stood us in no more than 6 d. each.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were you drinking there?</p>
               <p>Adams. About two or three hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober at that time?</p>
               <p>Adams. I was as sober as I am this moment.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mr. Troy?</p>
               <p>Adams. Eight or ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be an honest man?</p>
               <p>Adams. I believe he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he would send you home with any body that would pick your pocket if he knew it?</p>
               <p>Adams. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell me how that kissing was?</p>
               <p>Adams. She turned herself round three or four doors after I had looked at my watch, and said, you shall go no farther, and clasped me round the waste.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had your watch at that time?</p>
               <p>Adams. Was I dying this moment I am sure it was then in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the man that produced the watch?</p>
               <p>Adams. I never saw it till to day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in Parliament-street that night ?</p>
               <p>Adams. I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person496">
                  Peter 
                  Thom 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person496" type="surname" value="Thom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person496" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person496" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable that took the lady up on the 22d of this month. Between nine and ten at night Mr. Adams came to me, and I went with him and Mr. Troy to College-street, Westminster, to her lodgings. Mr. Adams went and knocked at the door, I was about two doors off at that time: when the door was opened, they said, she was gone to bed; then he asked if the captain was at home, they said, he was gone to bed; then I heard a gentlewoman at the door, who said to Mr. Adams, what would you have? he said to her, madam, you have robbed me of my watch; she said, I don't know any thing of it; he told her he had a constable there to take her up, and if she did not let him see it he would serve a warrant upon her; she said, she knew nothing of it: he then charged me with her. I took her and brought her to my house: we afterwards put her in the Round-house for that night. Mr. Adams said the same the next morning as he did over night.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she go freely along with you?</p>
               <p>Thom. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Adams sober, or not?</p>
               <p>Thom. I was not sober myself therefore cannot be a judge; but this I know very well, the justice said he was sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person497">
                  John 
                  Troy 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person497" type="surname" value="Troy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person497" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person497" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the sutling house by the horse-guards : I believe between six and seven that night the lady came into my house; she staid a little while, I asked her what she would drink; she said, she liked a little warm punch; I ordered the boy to make 18 d. worth, and we sate and drank it out : whether Mr. Adams<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240033"></xptr> drank any or not I cannot say; I had drunk too much. They both talked of going home about nine; I said to Mr. Adams, this lady lives somewhere about College-street, I should be obliged to you if you would see her home; he said, with all my heart: they went out together, and in about twenty five minutes he was back again, and said, who did you send me home with, she has picked my pocket of my watch? He was in a violent passion, and wanted me to go and get it; I said, this can never be; he said, it is so. I went with him to the constable's house, and told him that one Coningham knew where she lived, and that he lived in Long-ditch; we went there, and he told us he would go and shew us the door, for I had sent him home once before with her. They went and got a warrant; and then he went along with us to the woman's house in College-street; he shewed us the door; I desired him to stand a little back and let me talk to her: I knocked, and a woman came to the door, I asked her for Mrs. Hudson; the woman said, she was gone to bed; then Mr. Adams put his foot in at the door to keep it open, and said, I must and will see her to night: after that the prisoner came out of a room into the passage to the door, and said, what is the matter Mr. Adams? he then challenged her with having his watch; she then came out at the door, I believe she was in the very same habit she is now; then the warrant was served, and they took her to the constable's.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what past there ?</p>
               <p>Troy. I do not, I had been drinking too much, I went home to bed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Troy. About a year and an half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her husband?</p>
               <p>Troy. I believe he is a commission officer, lately come from 
               <persName id="t17540424-55-person498">
                  Nova 
                  Scotia 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person498" type="surname" value="Scotia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person498" type="given" value="Nova"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person498" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I never saw him till last Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come to visit your wife that day?</p>
               <p>Troy. I believe she came to visit me.</p>
               <p>Q. During that year and an half's acquaintance, did you ever hear a bad character of her?</p>
               <p>Troy. No, none, till this thing happened; till then I always looked upon her to be an honest woman and a gentlewoman.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Adams been in your company that day?</p>
               <p>Troy. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you drank that day together ?</p>
               <p>Troy. We had three or four pots of beer, more or less, and some punch where we dined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he drink any thing at your house ?</p>
               <p>Troy. Yes, some wine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he disguised in liquor?</p>
               <p>Troy. I must beg to be excused, I cannot resolve it; I was so far gone myself I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any thing of value about your house ?</p>
               <p>Troy. I have a great many things of value.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever miss any thing after she had been at your house?</p>
               <p>Troy. I never did to my knowledge; I have discounted notes for her which came from abroad.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear a bad character of her?</p>
               <p>Troy. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prosecutor ?</p>
               <p>Troy. Fifteen or sixteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>

               <p>Troy. It is that of a very honest man; I have employed him several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner come out as soon as you asked for her?</p>
               <p>Troy. No, she came out when Mr. Adams insisted upon seeing her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240034"></xptr>Q. Have you had any conversation with her since that evening?</p>
               <p>Troy. Yes, I went to see her in the Gate-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she desire to come to an accommodation?</p>
               <p>Troy. I know her husband said he would give the value of the watch rather than have his wife brought to disgrace.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Troy. He said, I'll pay you for the watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person499">
                  Robert 
                  Conningham 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person499" type="surname" value="Conningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person499" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person499" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday was three weeks I was desired to go home with the prisoner from Mr. Troy's about nine o' clock; by which reason these people came to me to enquire where she lived ?</p>
               <p>Q. Was you robbed, or attempted to be robbed by her?</p>
               <p>Conningham. I was not. I conducted them to the house, and they knocked at the door; when it was opened they asked for Mrs. Hudson, they said, she was gone to bed; presently afterwards she made her appearance, when Mr. Adams insisted on seeing her, and then the constable took charge of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Adams sober then ?</p>
               <p>Conningham. I did not perceive him to be drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say ?</p>
               <p>Conningham. She said she knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any resistance or hinder them from searching?</p>
               <p>Conningham. No, she desired to be searched, I think it was at the constable's house; she said Mr. Adams don't be so cruel, I will be searched, I never was accused of any such thing, I always lived in credit.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she behave when you went home with her.</p>
               <p>Conningham. She behaved like a gentlewoman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person500">
                  James 
                  Eves 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person500" type="surname" value="Eves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person500" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person500" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday night between nine and ten o'clock I went into Mr. Troy's house, where I saw the prosecutor under a great deal of uneasiness, saying, he had lost his watch; and desired Mr. Troy to go along with him to ask for the gentlewoman; and said, she had stole his watch; this was about a quarter after nine: I went with them, and was by when the door was opened; they said, she was gone to bed; they asked the question again, they said the same: Mr. Adams said, I must see her and insist upon seeing her, and immediately out she came, seemingly in a flutter, and said, oh! Mr. Adams, is it you? he challenged her with having the watch; she denied it utterly; he said, I have a warrant against you, if you don't give it me again I'll serve it; she said, I know nothing of the watch, help me God, were the words she said; then the warrant was executed; and we all went to the constable's house, where a valuable consideration was offered several times, but he refused it, and said, give me my watch, give me my watch.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say, if he could not go on with the prosecution, you would assist him with ten guineas?</p>
               <p>Eves. No, I did not, not about the prosecution.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it about?</p>
               <p>Eves. It was not about this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. What affair was it?</p>
               <p>Eves. I did not offer him ten guineas upon my oath, or any money at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person501">
                  George 
                  Troy 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person501" type="surname" value="Troy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person501" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Troy's at the sutling-house, he is my uncle; after the gentleman and Mrs. Hudson were gone, she came back to our house and asked for her muff, saying, she had left it behind her in the chair.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after she went out with Mr. Adams?</p>
               <p>Troy. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Troy. A little after nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it, after she went out, before she came back ?</p>
               <p>Troy. I imagine it was about ten minutes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240035"></xptr>Q. When she came back had she any muff on her hand?</p>
               <p>Troy. No, she had not, she went and took it out of the chair; then she asked for my uncle, he was gone out, and she went away directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person502">
                  Daniel 
                  Squib 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person502" type="surname" value="Squib"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person502" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be at Mr. Thom's house drinking in a room; about ten o'clock came in some company, and went into the fore room; I went into the fore room to hear what it was about, and they had brought Mrs. Hudson in; there she said, she would sooner give double the price of the watch than go to prison, or go under the scandal of it: she desired her husband to be sent for; he came in and wanted to know what they detained his wife for, and said, he was a justice of the peace and an officer; he took Mr. Adams aside, and asked him what value he put on it; he said, it cost him 7 l. though it now is not worth the money, perhaps not half so much: he said, if she would let him have the watch, may be he should never trouble her any more; and he said the same as she said, that he had rather pay double the value of the watch than she should go under the scandal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-55-person503">
                  Zachariah 
                  Peirce 
               <interp inst="t17540424-55-person503" type="surname" value="Peirce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person503" type="given" value="Zachariah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-person503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found the watch in Parliament-street, at near nine o'clock last Monday evening, it lay with the glass upon a stone, in the road where you walk, it was not going then; but when I came home it was wound up and went.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to be dropped?</p>
               <p>Peirce. To me it appeared to be laid there, for it had received no damage, with the glass undermost.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see it plain?</p>
               <p>Peirce. It was just between two lights, very plain.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it lay in the dirt?</p>
               <p>Peirce. No, it lay in a very clean place.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it between your finding it and winding it up?</p>
               <p>Peirce. I went only to Peter-street and back again, there was a gentleman with me who saw me pick it up; when we had wound it up we set it by our watches; it was about a quarter after nine at that time by ours.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540424-55-verdict295" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-55-verdict295" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
