<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-27">
               <interp inst="t17561208-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-27" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-27" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-27-off136-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-27-defend230 t17561208-27-off136 t17561208-27-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>31. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17561208-27-defend230" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Golding 
               <interp inst="t17561208-27-defend230" type="surname" value="Golding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-defend230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-defend230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17561208-27-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 4l. 11s. in money number'd  Joseph Harison, in the dwelling house of the said Joseph
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-27-cd137" type="crimeDate">Nov. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-27-off136 t17561208-27-cd137"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-27-person231">
                  Joseph 
                  Harison 
               <interp inst="t17561208-27-person231" type="surname" value="Harison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-person231" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17561208-27-crimeloc138">Royal Oak a publick house, near St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-27-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Royal Oak a publick house, near St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-27-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-27-off136 t17561208-27-crimeloc138"></join>. A two months ago I lost two crown pieces and being, surprised, I examined a little boy thinking he might take them for play pieces; but found he knew nothing of them. A few days after that I missed a guinea There were 4 l in silver in another place. I told that over, and in a little time after I missed a guinea out of that. After that I told it again, and found it reduced to 26 s. and 6 d. Soon after it was reduced to 19 s. and 6 d. This last was on the 17th of November. I told the affair to an acquaintance, named Clark, and that I suspected the prisoner to be the man, and wanted to catch him. On Friday the 1th of November, in the afternoon, the prisoner came into the kitchen for a pint of beer. He sat down, and seem'd to sham drunk, pretending to go to sleep.</p>
               <p>Q Why did you suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Harison. Because he had lately flash'd his money about and he was known not to be in work, nor had been for a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to come often to your house?</p>
               <p>Harison. He used to come about 2 or 3 times in a week. After he had lain with his head down on the table some time, he remov'd from the kitchen into the drinking room, and slept there till about a quarter after seven; then there came a gentleman in, and the prisoner seeing me busy with him, he made his move. I had given my daughter a charge to mind him; presently my daughter deliver'd a candle into my hand, and said he is gone up stairs. I went and followed him up; there was a key in my room door where I lie. I said I am certain I have a thief in the room, but I can't see him. I call'd up Mr. Clark immediately, and said to him the thief is in the room, but he is invisible; but looking under my bed, there I found the prisoner. I took him by the heels and pull'd him out; he at first look'd very pale, after that he began to be impudent; said I, are not you a villain to offer to ruin a family in this nature; said he, I have got nothing of yours, you can't hurt me; you must send for an officer, you are not to detain me here yourself. I sent for an officer immediately, and we examined his pockets, but found nothing but 6 d. and a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080018"></xptr> half-penny upon him. He was taken before the justice, where he own'd he let himself into the room, and hid himself under my bed; and that the key which I found in my room door, was the key of his lodging room door.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he give you when you charg'd him with taking your money?</p>
               <p>Harison. He always deny'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your money kept?</p>
               <p>Harison. It was kept in a cabinet in that room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep that cabinet always lock'd ?</p>
               <p>Harison. I did, but I observed it lately to be alter'd and spoil'd very much, and the escutcheon almost pull'd off and scratch'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with altering the lock before the justice?</p>
               <p>Harison. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing about him that would open the cabinet lock?</p>
               <p>Harison. We found no key, only a hook.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 19th of November last (having used the prosecutor's house three or four years) I went in there very much in liquor; he said I call'd for a pint of beer, whether I did or not I don't know; he said I laid my head down on the kitchen table, but I can't say whether I did or not; I know after I had been in the kitchen I stumbled in going into the tap room, where I laid my head down in a box; after that I went up stairs and open'd the door with my lodging room key, and thought I was at my own home.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you try that key of his, whether it was the prisoner's lodging-room key or no?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As I was going to lie down the gentleman came up stairs, and said he had got a thief, which put me in my senses almost. I out of surprise ran and hid myself under the bed; he said he had got the thief, and laid hold of my legs and pull'd me out. I was search'd, and they found but 6 d. and three half-pence about me; they took me to Justice Welch three times. I never saw any thing of the prosecutor's money, nor never knew where he put it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-27-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-27-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
