<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-50">
               <interp inst="t17570914-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-50" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-50" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-50-off308-c469" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-defend566 t17570914-50-off308 t17570914-50-verdict312"></join>
         
               <p>358. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17570914-50-defend566" type="defendantName">
                  Rebecca 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17570914-50-defend566" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-defend566" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-defend566" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17570914-50-deflabel307" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-defend566 t17570914-50-deflabel307"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-50-off308" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-off308" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-off308" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one dimity petticoat, value 2 s. four pair of pockets, value 2 s. one muslin apron, value 1 s. one muslin half handkerchief, six napkins, five linen caps, two lawn tuckers, one laced lawn handkerchief, one laced ruff, two pair of laced lawn ruffles, four pair of cotton stockings, and one pair of silk stockings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-50-victim568" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-50-victim568" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-victim568" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-victim568" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-off308 t17570914-50-victim568"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17570914-50-viclabel309" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-victim568 t17570914-50-viclabel309"></join>, <rs id="t17570914-50-cd310" type="crimeDate">Aug. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-off308 t17570914-50-cd310"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-50-person569">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-50-person569" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person569" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person569" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner commenced <rs id="t17570914-50-deflabel311" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-50-defend566 t17570914-50-deflabel311"></join> to me about two months ago. I kept her out of charity. Before she had liv'd with me more than two years; I was to give her 8 l. per year. She had the care of all my effects. I had been continually losing for above half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose.</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. I lost a dimity petticoat, four pair of pockets, two pair of laced ruffles, a laced handkerchief, a laced ruff, two lawn tuckers, five caps, one muslin apron, four pair of stockings, one pair of silk ones, six napkins, and a plain handkerchief. I suspected the prisoner, she having a private lodging of her own. I got a warrant, and search'd for them near Turn Stile, by Little Queen Street, where I found several things.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by when you search'd.</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No, she was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first miss the things you have mention'd.</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. Three weeks ago last Tuesday. I went home and brought her to town directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What home ?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. She was at my country lodgings at Lambeth. I asked her after several things, mentioning them by name. She said she knew nothing of them. I brought the bundle with me, and said they were in that bundle. I shew'd her them, but she denied taking all but the dimity petticoat. I carried her before a justice of the peace; all she said in excuse was that I had given them to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give them to her?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you a lodging on this side the water?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. I lodg'd at Mr. West's in Duke-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she live with you there in the capacity of a servant or a companion ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140058"></xptr>E. Hambleton. In the capacity of a servant, and did every thing I bid her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she use go abroad with you?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she use to dress better than ordinary at such times?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. Very likely she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you use to lend her cloaths to dress in?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No. I might have lent her something when she went out along with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she continue with you before she left you the first time?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. Above a year.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she continue in these private lodgings ?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you send for her when she came to you again ?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No, she came of her own accord.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she continue with you the second time of her coming ?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. She continued with me to this time; it was then that I bargain'd to give her 8 l. per year.</p>
               <p>Q. During this last time did not you use to go out with her?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. She walked out with me in the country as I kept but that one servant.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Douglas in Covent Garden ?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she use to go with you there?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you lend her cloaths to go there?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No, never. She attended me at Mr. Douglas's two days when I lay in.</p>
               <p>Q. During the last time she liv'd with you, did continue at these private lodgings?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. No, she did not, she continued with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know she had private lodgings all the time she liv'd with you last?</p>
               <p>E. Hambleton. I don't know that she had, I believe she had a lodging where she put her things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-50-person570">
                  John 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17570914-50-person570" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person570" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person570" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Hambleton lodg'd at my house, the prisoner was her servant.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of her lending her servant Quarts.</p>
               <p>West. I never trouble my head about those affairs.</p>
               <p>Spencer. I had a search warrant to search the prisoner's lodgings, at Mr. Flannerkin's in Turn-Stile. I found she had two boxes lock'd up in his room; she very readily let me have the key of the closet, and we opened the two boxes, where we found the things that Mrs. Hambleton swore to before the magistrate, and the prisoner acknowledged them to be Mrs. Hambleton's in the coach going along, six napkins and some other things (produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutrix.)</p>
               <p>Constable. Mrs. Hambleton brought her into my liberty in a coach; when we came into Westminster, I said it is needless to deceive you any longer, I have a warrant against you for such and such things, and desir'd her to acknowledge, and told her Mrs. Hambleton would be more favourable to her. She did acknowledge the taking the petticoat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Hambleton promise her not to prosecute?</p>
               <p>Constable. No, but she promised to be favourable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was hir'd as a servant to this lady; she took me to Enfield to keep her house, with a gentleman that she kept company with, where she continued with him till New-Market races; after which they had some words and parted. She sent me to London, to another gentleman that she kept company with; some time after that gentleman (who kept her) and she quarrel'd; she was ill, and I was sent to Enfield to bring up part of her linen. I brought six china saucers pack'd up in linen at a time, till I brought all her things away. She went to live with another gentleman, and he and she could not agree. They parted, and she, wanted money. I lent her two 36 s. pieces, and three guineas. She paid me when she was with another gentleman, and discharg'd me, and said he would not allow me to be in his presence I parted with her in good will. She soon pack'd up her cloaths and came to London, from Hampshire, where she went with her gentleman. Then she gave me caps, handkerchiefs, a bed gown, ribbons, and other things. Then she was to go and keep a captain's house in the country; after that she went to live at Mr. Douglas's, and the night before she sent a boy home with a bottle of shrub, and desir'd me to put it by. Then she dress'd me in a gown of her's, and desired me to go with her to Vaux-Hall, when four gentlemen came and took her in a boat; I went, and return'd with her to her own house. The next morning she went to Cuper's Gardens. The next day we went to Mr. Douglas's, and some men abused us as we went along the Bishops walk at Lambeth. I carried a bundle of cloaths for her,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140059"></xptr> and left her in company with a gentleman; after I took a lodging I was two or three times a day at her house; she has made me pull off my petticoat and put on a clean one of her's to walk out with her, and every thing was in my possession, so that I might put on what I would.</p>
               <p>Court. What is this to the purpose; can you give an account how you came by these things charg'd upon you ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She got the constable and broke open my box, and when she could find nothing of her's, then she swore to what she had lent me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. West. I live near Lincoln's Inn Fields. I have known Mrs. Hambleton between two and three years, and the prisoner going on of two years. She was a hir'd servant to Mrs. Hambleton when she came from France, and frequently went out with her, and used to be dress'd very often with Mrs. Hambleton's cloaths. She had the keys of the drawers, and the care of every thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-50-person571">
                  Mary 
                  Forrister 
               <interp inst="t17570914-50-person571" type="surname" value="Forrister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person571" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person571" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I once liv'd with Mrs. West as a hir'd servant, I left her in January of February two years ago; Mrs. Hambleton liv'd there then. She came there as a widow lady from out of the country. I have frequently seen the prisoner dress'd in Mrs. Hambleton's cloaths, and said this Mrs. Hambleton dresses her maid in fine cloaths. When they went out they did not appear as mistress and servant, but as companions; you could scarce know mistress from servant; the mistress used to wear the cloaths first, till they were a little soil'd, then the maid used to wear them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-50-person572">
                  John 
                  Hines 
               <interp inst="t17570914-50-person572" type="surname" value="Hines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person572" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-person572" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. West, in Duke-street. I remember Mrs. Hambleton's lodging there and the prisoner. The prisoner used to go out dress'd with Mrs. Hambleton frequently in her cloaths.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-50-verdict312" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-50-verdict312" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
