<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520914-9">
               <interp inst="t17520914-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-9" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-9" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-9-off48-c70" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-9-defend86 t17520914-9-off48 t17520914-9-verdict51"></join>
         
               <p>408. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-9-defend86" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Manning 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-9-defend86" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-defend86" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-defend86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17520914-9-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, val. 40 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520914-9-victim88" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Stevens 
                        <interp inst="t17520914-9-victim88" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-9-victim88" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-9-victim88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-9-off48 t17520914-9-victim88"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privily and secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520914-9-cd49" type="crimeDate">Aug. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-9-off48 t17520914-9-cd49"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-9-person89">
                  James 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person89" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person89" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of August, near ten at night, going from Charing Cross to St. James's House, I was walking in <placeName id="t17520914-9-crimeloc50">St. James's Park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-9-crimeloc50" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-9-crimeloc50" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-9-off48 t17520914-9-crimeloc50"></join>, with my left hand towards the grass plat, I saw some people quarreling together. I stopp'd, and seeing a bench, sat down. It was very moonlight; the prisoner was sitting there on my left hand. He turned his face, and made a little jostle near me, and gave me a little touch upon the elbow. I turned about to look at the people; for I thought it was to liften to what the people said. Then I felt him twitch the string of my watch. He then ran away, and by moonlight I saw him fall on his hands. I came up to him, and as soon as he recovered, he called, Jack, Jack, Jack. I saw a man at a distance, who did not come to him, but turn'd about and saw 
               <persName id="t17520914-9-person90">
                  Edward 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person90" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person90" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and desired him to assist me. He seized him by his left hand; and when we had brought him to St. James's guard-house, he turned about and took me by my cloaths. I ask'd him what he meant, and the serjeant desired me to feel in my pocket; for may be, he had put the watch in it, going through the passage into St. James's court. I felt in my pocket; but it was not there. About the middle of the passage he dropped the watch, betwixt the serjeant and me. I saw it drop, and the serjeant took it up. We then went into the guard-house, and he was not out of my fight from the time he was taken till we had him in the guard-house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say about it?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He said I attempted to rob him. The watch produced in court, and deposed to by the maker's name, and the lining. I felt it as I sat by him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I sit by you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. This is the very man that was sitting by me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-9-person91">
                  Edward 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person91" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person91" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In the month of August I had been at Westminster. Coming back again, about five minutes after ten at night, the prosecutor was about ten yards from the seat where he said he had been robbed of his watch, and said the man was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175209140007"></xptr> gone under the wall. I said I would assist him, and followed him. The prisoner was walking pretty smartly. When I came up to him I seized him by his left arm, and led him away towards the guardroom. Going through the passage under the princess Amelia's room, I saw him put the watch out of his right hand into his left, and saw part of the case and seal, so as to distinguish it to be a watch. I immediately said, You villain, you have the watch; he let it fall on my foot, and from thence on the ground, and broke the glass; the case flew open. I took them up and put the watch and case into my waistcoat pocket, and never pulled them out till I came before the justice, between ten and eleven o'clock, and there delivered it to 
               <persName id="t17520914-9-person92">
                  Edward 
                  Linn 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person92" type="surname" value="Linn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person92" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-9-person93">
                  Edward 
                  Linn 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person93" type="surname" value="Linn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person93" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for to the guard room to Justice Lediard. This watch was by the last witness delivered to me, and I have had it ever since.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went with a friend that lives at Fulham. We parted in the park, and he went towards Buckingham Gate. As I was returning, this prosecutor was sitting on a bench, with another fellow in a lightish coloured coat, very close together. The man got up first, and the prosecutor then stood by himself. He crossed the way upon me, and said to me, Did you sit by me? I said, No, honest friend. He said he had lost his watch; and I answered, You scoundrel, I know nothing of it. He then went to this serjeant, and told him that I had his watch, and he came and laid hold on me. I never saw his watch, or sat down by him, as there is a just God in heaven.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-9-verdict51" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-verdict51" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-verdict51" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>. * </p>
               <p>* See No. 87 in Sir 
               <persName id="t17520914-9-person94">
                  Richard 
                  Hoare 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person94" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person94" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and No. 142 in Sir 
               <persName id="t17520914-9-person95">
                  Henry 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17520914-9-person95" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person95" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-9-punish52" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-9-punish52" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-9-defend86 t17520914-9-punish52"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
