<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-28">
               <interp inst="t17550515-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-28" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-28" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-28-off134-c199" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-defend252 t17550515-28-off134 t17550515-28-verdict138"></join>
         
               <p>236. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17550515-28-defend252" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Bowyer 
                  , otherwise Scampy<interp inst="t17550515-28-defend252" type="surname" value="Bowyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-defend252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-defend252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-28-off134" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-off134" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-off134" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silk capuchin, value 20 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-28-victim255" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Grant 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim255" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim255" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550515-28-viclabel135" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-victim255 t17550515-28-viclabel135"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-victim257 t17550515-28-viclabel135"></join>, from the person of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-28-victim257" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Miller 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim257" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim257" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-victim257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , privately and secretly from his person, <rs id="t17550515-28-cd136" type="crimeDate">May 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-off134 t17550515-28-cd136"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-28-person258">
                  Edward 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17550515-28-person258" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person258" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been in Kensington-gardens with a young lady from Norfolk in the afternoon on Sunday the 4th of May; she had given me her capuchin to put in my coat-pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her name?</p>
               <p>Miller Her name is Grant; coming by <placeName id="t17550515-28-crimeloc137">Fleet-bridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-28-crimeloc137" type="placeName" value="Fleet-bridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-28-crimeloc137" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-off134 t17550515-28-crimeloc137"></join> my pocket was picked of it, but I neither saw or felt it done; Mr. Mansel came to me as we were coming up towards Ludgate, and asked me if my pocket was not picked? I felt and found it was of the capuchin; I was for stopping to try if we could see the person that did it, but the young lady was not willing; so we walked up to the end of the Old-bailey; then Mr. Mansel stopped us again, and said, if I was willing we might put his wife, who was with him, and the young lady with me, into a house, saying, he would be lurking about and we might take him, adding, he should know the man if he could see him; so the two women went in to an acquaintance's house of his, and he and I had not gone down past three or four doors from the Old-bailey corner towards Fleet-bridge before he said that was the man, pointing to the prisoner, he was very remarkable, having got a dog wig on, that is such as some coachmen wear. I went up and seized him by the collar, and begged assistance of people that were coming by, so we secured him; we carried him to a tavern at the bottom of the hill; then we sent for the two women; the prisoner said he was in hopes to be forgiven, and said, if he was hanged or transported the lady should have her capuchin again, and accordingly he sent a person for it, who returned with it; he begged very hard for forgiveness; the cloak was laid down on the table, the lady would not touch it. We sent for a constable; she would have taken her oath to the capuchin.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the lady?</p>
               <p>Miller. She had taken a place in the Norfolk-coach, and was obliged to go on the Friday morning, (the capuchin produced in court).</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the same which was picked out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Miller. It is very like it; but one may be like another, so I will not swear to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this that which the prisoner sent for and was brought in by his order?</p>
               <p>Miller. It is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-28-person259">
                  George 
                  Mansel 
               <interp inst="t17550515-28-person259" type="surname" value="Mansel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person259" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was following the gentleman and the lady he speaks of, about half an hour after eight that night; I saw the prisoner and his companions meet them, the prisoner turned very short and slipped in betwixt my spouse and I, and the gentleman and lady; I observed him as he followed them make three attempts to pick the gentleman's pocket, and when we got just by the Fleet-market I saw him pick Mr. Miller's pocket, but of what I can't say; I saw something drawn out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour did it appear to be of?</p>
               <p>Mansel. It appeared to be black; after the prisoner had done it he went down towards the Fleet-market, and his companions with him; I ran up to the gentleman and asked him what he had lost?</p>
               <p>Q. What companions had the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mansel. He had a girl about twelve years old and a short man along with him, they seemed to walk pretty fast; I told Mr. Miller I had seen his pocket picked, he clapped his hand down, and said, he had lost a capuchin; I told him I saw the man run down towards the Fleet-market that took it, and I am positive of knowing him again; I was so near him I could have taken him in the fact, but was fearful of his companions. I said I would go along with him to help take the man if he would get some assistance, they went still before me; I thought it a pity to let the opportunity slip; I ran to him again when<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150027"></xptr> they were at the Old-bailey end, and persuaded the lady to let us try to take the man, so we put my wife and her into a house; and as we were turning down from the Old-bailey we saw the prisoner coming up Ludgate-hill; we got two or three people to assist us, and took him, and carried him into the Fountain tavern; then we sent for the women, and the lady pleaded she wanted to go into the country the next morning, and it would be a great disappointment to go without the capuchin; the prisoner then supposing he should have a pardon if he produced it, consented to send for it, and said, whether he was hanged or transported she should have her capuchin again; I believe there were a dozen people heard it, he sent a person for it and it was brought and put into the constable's hands, the lady would not take it, and when the prisoner saw her determined to prosecute, he took it up himself, and said, if he must be prosecuted for it, he thought it was his property, but the constable took it from him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this capuchin, can you take upon you to say this is what was taken out of Mr. Miller's pocket?</p>
               <p>Mansel. I can't say that, but I heard the lady say it was her capuchin.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-28-person260">
                  John 
                  Tustin 
               <interp inst="t17550515-28-person260" type="surname" value="Tustin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; about ten o'clock that night I was sent for to the Fountain tavern on Ludgate-hill, the capuchin lay on the table, there was the lady, Mr. Miller, and this gentleman sitting by; the lady said that was her capuchin, I told her she must appear next morning, the prisoner said, I am likely to suffer for it, I think it is my property, and he took it up, I took it out of his hand, and said, if you'll give me leave I'll keep it till the affair is decided; and I have had it ever since in my custody.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming along by the Fleet-market, and picked up this capuchin, and carried it home to my washerwoman; after that I came to go up to my horses on Ludgate-hill, this man took hold of me and three or four more, and took me to the Fountain tavern; after we had been there about a quarter of an hour, the lady said she had lost a capuchin; I said, I had picked up one, and if they would send a porter they might have it; they sent out for a porter, when he came, I told him to go to such a place, and desire the people to send the capuchin I brought and left there; the lady said, young man, I am sorry for you, as I have got my capuchin again you may go about your business, but that gentleman would charge the constable with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-28-verdict138" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-verdict138" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550515-28-punish139" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-28-punish139" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-28-defend252 t17550515-28-punish139"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
