<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-20">
               <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-20-off95-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-20-defend184 t17570713-20-off95 t17570713-20-verdict97"></join>
         
               <p>266. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Cane 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20-defend184" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-defend184" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-defend184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570713-20-deflabel94" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-20-defend184 t17570713-20-deflabel94"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570713-20-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               publishing as true a forged and counterfeit bill of exchange
            </rs> to this purport:</p>
               <p>'' <rs id="t17570713-20-cd96" type="crimeDate">May 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-20-off95 t17570713-20-cd96"></join>, 1757,</p>
               <p>'' One month after date please to pay to Mr. '' 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person185">
                  John 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person185" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person185" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order, the sum of 46 l. for value '' received, as per advice,</p>
               <p>JONATHAN MORE.''</p>
               <p>It was laid a second time for uttering as true a forged indorsement, by the name of 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person186">
                  William 
                  Bosworth 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person186" type="surname" value="Bosworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person186" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the back of it.</p>
               <p>Also a third time for forging the name Isaac Lane to an order at the bottom of the bill, to this purport, '' Pay when due, Isaac Lane,'' and for publishing the same, well knowing it to have been forged, with an intent to defraud Hinton Brown, and Co.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person187">
                  Charles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person187" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person187" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with Mr. Isaac Lane for many years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen him write?</p>
               <p>Smith. I have, very often.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this bill of exchange, the name Isaac Lane under the order.</p>
               <p>Smith. This name I verily believe is not his writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you with certainty say it is, or is not his writing?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am very near as well acquainted with his hand writing as my own. I am of opinion this is no more his hand writing than it is mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person188">
                  John 
                  Pett 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person188" type="surname" value="Pett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person188" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller to Mess. Hinton Brown and Co. I am perfectly well acquainted with Mr. Isaac Lane's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any of his hand-writing about you?</p>
               <p>Pett. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the name Isaac Lane upon this order.</p>
               <p>Pett. This is not Mr. Lane's hand-writing. (He produces a paper with Mr. Lane's name on it.) This is his real hand-writing. (The jury and bench examine the two papers together.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Smith. Look at this paper (that which Mr. Pett produced.)</p>
               <p>Smith. If I had had an order for 500 l. on this I should have paid it, but the other I should not.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call this paper now in question?</p>
               <p>Smith. It is a forged order to pay the bill of exchange; it is in the usual form of an order.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pett. When did you see this bill of exchange?</p>
               <p>Pett. The prisoner at the bar came to our house on the 14th of June last, and tender'd this bill for the payment of 46 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are the partners?</p>
               <p>Pett. Hinton and 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person189">
                  James 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person189" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person189" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was another young man received the bill out of her hand, and delivered it to me, it being my proper business to pay the money.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Pett. His name is Foster. I saw her deliver it to him. Immediately after I read it, and considered the contents, I turned to the prisoner, and told her it was a forged bill; upon that she declared if it was a forgery, she was intirely innocent of it, for she received it in a post letter, either that or the proceeding day, and produced the letter, which is in my possession.</p>
               <p>Q. What mark is upon it?</p>
               <p>Pett. There is the Portsmouth mark upon it. I immediately carried the bill and letter to Mess. Brown, who were then at dinner, and told them my opinion of it; the woman waited in the shop till I return'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she an opportunity of going away in that time?</p>
               <p>Pett. There was no restraint laid upon her as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you declared your opinion to her in the shop before?</p>
               <p>Pett. I had publickly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not leave direction with the other person in the shop to stop her if she offer'd to go away?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130019"></xptr>Pett. No, none at all. Mr. Brown came and told her it was a forgery, and she told him the same as she did me. During the time they were in conference, an acquaintance of Mr. Brown's came in, an officer was sent for, and she was taken before my Lord-mayor. I remember upon her being ask'd in Mr. Brown's compting-house who she received it from, she said she did not know the person that wrote the letter. Mr. Brown or somebody observed that it was something extraordinary she should receive a letter with a bill in it, to send down wines, and receive a reward for her trouble, without knowing the gentleman. She reply'd, as she was in a very public way, a great many gentlemen used her house that she might know, but could not recollect them.</p>
               <p>Q. What way is she in?</p>
               <p>Pett. She keeps wine vaults in Tavistock-court, Covent-Garden, and when before my Lord mayor she made the same reply as at Mess. Brown's. She was that evening sent to the Poultry Compter for farther examination. The next day she was brought before my Lord-mayor again, I and Mr. Isaac Lane were present. She made the same answers then to every particular, I don't remember she varied in any circumstance.</p>
               <p>Q. When you told her it was forged, did she shew any signs of hesitation or guilt?</p>
               <p>Pett. I perceiv'd no visible alteration in her, and she constantly persevered in the same story.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the letter?</p>
               <p>Pett. This is it, and this is the case (holding them in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did she give it into your hand voluntarily?</p>
               <p>Pett. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have not had more bills brought you by other people, in the same kind of writing, drawn on the same person?</p>
               <p>Pett. There have been several. There was one brought some time before this was, and another the day after.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Bridge in Johnson's Court?</p>
               <p>Pett. I do. He brought that the day after she brought this.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any inquiry after a person at Portsmouth, that is supposed to be the drawer of this bill?</p>
               <p>Pett. Upon Mr. Bridge being stopt, he declared his innocence, and that he received the bill in a post letter that same day, sign'd 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person190">
                  William 
                  Bosworth 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person190" type="surname" value="Bosworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person190" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He was ask'd if he knew such a person. He said some months before there was a gentleman that pass'd by that name.</p>
               <p>The letter read to this purport.</p>
               <p>Directed to Mrs. Cane, at the French Wine Vaults, Tavistock-Court, Covent-Garden, London.</p>
               <p>'' On board the 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person191">
                  Unity 
                  Guinea 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person191" type="surname" value="Guinea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person191" type="given" value="Unity"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             man at Spithead.</p>
               <p>Dear Madam,</p>
               <p>As I have not at present an opportunity of coming to town, should esteem it as a favour, if you would get the inclosed note paid, which you may do by applying to Mess. Hinton Brown and Co. Bankers, in Lombard-street, who will pay the money on seeing the note, which I beg you'll do. You must write your name on the back under my name.</p>
               <p>I beg you'll accept of a guinea for the favours I received from you, when in town. Pray give my respects to Betty and Polly, and tell them I'll pay them a visit as soon as possible, for I don't think I shall stay long on board this Guinea ship.</p>
               <p>If you think fit, send me a dozen of wine, and deduct the money out of that you receive.</p>
               <p>I remain, dear madam, Your friend and humble servant, 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person192">
                  William 
                  Bosworth 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person192" type="surname" value="Bosworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person192" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>The Portsmouth post mark, and 13th of June, on the back of the letter.</p>
               <p>The Jury compare the letter and the bill.</p>
               <p>Q. did she take any money?</p>
               <p>Pett. She did not. She presented it for payment.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ask for the money?</p>
               <p>Pett. No, but that does not admit of a doubt. I have paid a great many thousand pounds without speaking a word to the persons that brought the bills, or they to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not know it was forged, the bill and the letter came together. Neither do I know the person that sent it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person193">
                  Sarah 
                  Copping 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person193" type="surname" value="Copping"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person193" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Reynolds's, a taylor, in Long Acre. I get my living by doing plain work. Mrs. Cane sent for me on the 13th of June, at night, to read a letter for her; she could not make it out:</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person194">
                  Sarah 
                  Copping 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person194" type="surname" value="Copping"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person194" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person194" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (She takes the letter and case in her hand.) This is it, here is a direction on it of my writing. She desir'd I'd write a direction on it, she then intending to send the letter, and not go herself.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gentleman in the house when you came there ?</p>
               <p>S. Copping. No, not one. The next day between eleven and twelve I was there again, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130020"></xptr> heard a gentleman read it over. She said she had a letter out of the country, and she could not tell who it came from, but she said she thought it was from some gentleman that had used her house.</p>
               <p>The jury desir'd she might write the same words in court, which were wrote on the letter for a direction.</p>
               <p>She wrote the same, viz.</p>
               <p>To Mess. Hinton Brown, and Co. in Lombard-street.</p>
               <p>The jury compared them, and found the hand writing agree.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you write that direction on the back of the letter for?</p>
               <p>S. Copping. For the porter to carry it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you frequently at Mrs. Cane's house?</p>
               <p>S. Copping. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe in the reading the letter the names of Miss Betsey and Miss Polly: Were there such persons in the house at that time?</p>
               <p>S. Copping. There were two Betsey's, but never a Polly. There had been a Polly in the house, but she had been gone three months</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person195">
                  William 
                  Bosworth 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person195" type="surname" value="Bosworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person195" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>S. Copping. No, I do not. There are a great many people come to the house, and he may have come among the rest, but I do not know any body of that name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person196">
                  Joseph 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person196" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person196" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a hosier and hatter, I live at the corner of Tavistock-Row. Mr. Price came to me, and told me Mrs. Cane had just shew'd him a note that came in a letter from Portsmouth, but she did not know any thing of the person, but imagined he had been at her house; and he ask'd me if there was such a person as Hinton Brown. He said it was drawn on a person at Wapping, and that it was very odd. I told him that was frequently done. He went and fetch'd the note, and it seemed to me to be a fair note.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this note ?</p>
               <p>Harris. This is the same note. He said she intended to go for the money. I said she might send a porter, for they will pay it directly. She came afterwards to me, and ask'd my advice. She said she would go and receive the money herself, and said the reason of her going was, that she was to send the money down to Portsmouth by the stage, and was to have a guinea for her trouble, so one journey would serve for the whole.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Harris. I can't say, but it was about the 14th or 15th of June. After that I was sent for to Mr. Brown's, and was before my Lord may or with her. She gave the same account there as she had done to me in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Price?</p>
               <p>Harris. He is out of town, and I believe he was so at the time of the subpaena being taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the letter?</p>
               <p>Harris. No, I did not. She said she received one, and that she did not propose to send any wine down. I did not see the note in her custody.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bridge. I received a letter from Portsmouth, with a draft in it, directed to Mess. Brown, in a frank.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you receive it?</p>
               <p>Bridge. I believe it was three weeks or a month ago last Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it frank'd by?</p>
               <p>Bridge. I forget now, because I gave it to Mr. Brown's teller.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this?</p>
               <p>Bridge. I believe this is it. I went on the Wednesday, the day after I received it, to receive the money. The letter was sign'd Bosworth. I took it to be one capt. Bosworth, that used to come to my house with capt. Murray.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Bridge. I keep the Cocoa-tree in Johnson's-Court, Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this draft. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Bridge. This I take to be the same hand writing as Mrs. Cane's is.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mess. Brown pay you the money?</p>
               <p>Bridge. No, I was stop'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that Bosworth owe you any thing?</p>
               <p>Bridge. No, Nor I never had any dealings with him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the letter directed to you?</p>
               <p>Bridge. To Mr. Bridge, Johnson's Coffee-house, Johnson's-Court, Charing-Cross, from on board the 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person197">
                  Unity 
                  Guinea 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person197" type="surname" value="Guinea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person197" type="given" value="Unity"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             man, Spithead.</p>
               <p>The letter read to this purport.</p>
               <p>'' May the 10th, 1757.</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>I should take it as a particular favour, if you'll receive the cash in the inclosed bill, which you may receive of Mess. Hinton Brown and Co. Please to send it by the coach, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Your friend, 
               <persName id="t17570713-20-person198">
                  William 
                  Bosworth 
               <interp inst="t17570713-20-person198" type="surname" value="Bosworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person198" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to believe that capt. Bosworth wrote this letter?</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17570713-20">
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 13th, Thursday the 14th, Friday the 15th, and Saturday the 16th of JULY.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-first Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VI. PART II for the YEAR 1757. Being the Sixth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble MARSHE DICKINSON, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1757.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17570713-20-person199">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17570713-20-person199" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570713-20-person199" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Bridge. NO, I am far from believing he did now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pett. Who presented this to you?</p>
               <p>Pett. Mr. Bridge did, who was detained, and has given bail.</p>
               <p>Bridge. I went down to Portsmouth, and was there four days; I inquired at all the offices, and got every officer's name there, by sea or land. I got the names out of the books of admiral Broderick.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a ship call'd the Unity?</p>
               <p>Bridge. There is, but no such name belonging to her. I have received since a letter from a friend of mine (the surgeon on board the Alcide ) who says he made all the enquiry he could, and could find no such name. I went to the inn where the stage-coach puts up, but found no such person. I have found, by inquiring at the War-Office, that capt. Bosworth has been gone eight or nine months to America, as a captain in lord Loudon's regiment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-20-verdict97" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-20-verdict97" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
