<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-31">
               <interp inst="t17541023-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-31" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-31" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-31-off153-c163" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-31-defend216 t17541023-31-off153 t17541023-31-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>497. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-31-defend216" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Martin 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-31-defend216" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-defend216" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-defend216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            . <rs id="t17541023-31-deflabel152" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-31-defend216 t17541023-31-deflabel152"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17541023-31-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silk handkerchief, val. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-31-victim218" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Austin 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-31-victim218" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-victim218" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-31-off153 t17541023-31-victim218"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17541023-31-cd154" type="crimeDate">Oct. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-31-off153 t17541023-31-cd154"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Jos. Oarm. I am constable of Bridge-ward; last Friday was fortnight two of our watchmen brought me this prisoner about 10 at night, they said, it was for robbing 
               <persName id="t17541023-31-person219">
                  Robert 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17541023-31-person219" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person219" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of his handkerchief, and that they had found it upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Oarm. She said he gave her the handkerchief in order to lie with her; he said he had no such thoughts. I examined the watchmen whether they found them in any such position; they said no, nor was there any likelihood of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-31-person220">
                  Robert 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17541023-31-person220" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person220" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was walking by <placeName id="t17541023-31-crimeloc155">St. Magnus Corner</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-31-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="St. Magnus Corner"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-31-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-31-off153 t17541023-31-crimeloc155"></join>, last Tuesday was fortnight about 10 o'clock at night, I had my handkerchief in my hand; the prisoner immediately snatched it out of my hand, and asked me if I would go down amongst, the pipes along with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ask you that before she had took your handkerchief or after?</p>
               <p>Austin. It was after she had snatched it out of my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you said to her, or she to you before she snatched your handkerchief ?</p>
               <p>Austin. Nothing at all; I told her if she would not give me my handkerchief again I would charge the watch with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe this woman, if she had had a mind to have rob'd you of your handkerchief, would have ask'd you to go along with her?</p>
               <p>Austin. I did not know what she meant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take her for a woman of the town?</p>
               <p>Austin. Yes, but I did not know where the pipes were.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think she intended by it?</p>
               <p>Austin. I think she intended to keep my handkerchief, and for me to go along with her. When I said I wou'd charge the watch with her, she said to another woman that was along with her, Don't leave me, Nan. I call'd the watch; then the said she did not care, and I should go to the watch-house too.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Austin. I was sober.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to have your handkerchief in your hand?</p>
               <p>Austin. There had been a parcel of fellows came by, and they had shoved me in the mud, and I was wiping myself.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the say when you charg'd the watch with her?</p>
               <p>Austin. She told the watch I had given her the handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He gave me the handkerchief to lie with me; he cannot deny it except he swears wrong. Did I not go along with you and you us'd me as another man does a woman, and after you came from the pipes you call'd the watch.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know where the pipes are; what he says is intirely false.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-31-person221">
                  Stephen 
                  Stroud 
               <interp inst="t17541023-31-person221" type="surname" value="Stroud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person221" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A little after 10 o'clock, I was upon my duty, the prosecutor call'd, watch, I went to him; he said, this woman has rob'd me of my handkerchief. I took the woman and brought her to the watch-house, and said to Austin, friend, you must go along with me too.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Stroud. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>Stroud. She said he gave her the handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That watchman never saw me in his life.</p>
               <p>Stroud. She is a very bad woman; we have had her in custody divers times. We have carried her to the Counter, to London Work-house, and to Bridewell; she goes by the name of Irish Peggy in the night-time.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times can you swear you have seen her?</p>
               <p>Stroud. I can swear I have seen her 10 times. In the seven years I have been there I believe we have had her in the watch-house ten times.</p>
               <p>Q. How often in the last three years?</p>
               <p>Stroud. I can swear to half a score.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have not been in London three years.</p>
               <p>Stroud. She was three months or thereabouts in London Work-house about a year ago.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He did give me the handkerchief indeed to lie with me, and he did lie with me, and gave it me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230019"></xptr> afterwards: he never spoke a word to me after that till he came to the watch-house. Then he began to rail against me like any thing. There were two other watchmen heard him say he gave it me to lie with me, and they would not let them come here.</p>
               <p>Oarm. The prisoner is one of the most notorious whores we have in the whole ward.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had a witness, but she is gone, to prove I am an honest woman, and work hard for my living.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-31-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-31-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
