<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-22">
               <interp inst="t17570914-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-22" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-22" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-22-off131-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-22-defend249 t17570914-22-off131 t17570914-22-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>(L.) 322. 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-defend249" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Boyd 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-22-defend249" type="surname" value="Boyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-defend249" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-defend249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-22-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one wooden trunk, cover'd with leather, value 5 s. one suit of men's cloth apparel, value 40 s. two linen waistcoats, value 20 s. six ruffled shirts, value 3 l. five neckcloths, value 5 s. four holland night-caps, value 2 s. nine pair of worstead stockings, value 18 s. one silver laced hat, value 10 s. two pair of drawers, value 12 d. two full suits of silk women's apparel, value 3 l. two linen sacks, value 30 s. three petticoats, value 20 s. nine muslin handkerchiefs, value 12 d. five pair of ruffles, value 4 s. two linen aprons, value 5 s. ten linen caps, value 4 s. two pair of silk stockings, value 4 s. one pair of silk gloves, value 6 s. ten night-caps, value 6 s. and six pocket handkerchiefs, value 5 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-victim251" type="victimName">
                     Edmund 
                     Francis 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-22-victim251" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-victim251" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-victim251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-22-off131 t17570914-22-victim251"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17570914-22-cd132" type="crimeDate">August 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-22-off131 t17570914-22-cd132"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-person252">
                  Edmund 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17570914-22-person252" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person252" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I hired a hackney coach, and I, my wife, and another woman were in it. I order'd the coachman to fasten the trunk, with the things mention'd in the indictment in it, to the coach behind, and ordered him to drive me to the Saracen's-Head in Friday-Street, from the Strand. The trunk with all in it was gone before we came to St. Paul's Church.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard of any of them again?</p>
               <p>Francis. The prisoner at the bar was taken and brought before my Lord-mayor, and I have got the greatest part of my things.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he there charged with stealing these things?</p>
               <p>Francis. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he make?</p>
               <p>Francis. I have forgot his answer. I think he said he found the trunk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-person253">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17570914-22-person253" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person253" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar came to my shop on Tuesday night the 2d of August.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140016"></xptr>E. Wood. I live in Field lane, and keep a sale shop; he ask'd me if I would buy some shirts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before ?</p>

               <p>E. Wood. I never saw him in my life before to my knowledge, nor since till now.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd ?</p>
               <p>E. Wood. He had a laced hat on. I took him to be a footman. I said to him, let me see them. I look'd at them, and said, these are too good for left off shirts.</p>
               <p>Q. Are any of the goods in court?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Here is a laced hat, and a pair of stockings. (producing them ) these were in the trunk with the rest of the things. I was inform'd I need not bring the whole of them here. This hat was on the prisoner's head, and the stockings on his legs when taken, they are my property. I have been at Holland since the trunk was lost.</p>
               <p>E. Wood. I ask'd the prisoner if the shirts were his own, he said they were, and that to tell me the truth he was a lieutenant, that he was come away for debt out of the country, and was going to sea, and if I did not think well of it. he could shew me his protection if I could read. He shew'd me a paper, I read in it, Edmburgh, Alexander Robertson discharg'd, dated 1755. I ask'd him what it was. He said you do not understand these things, and took it out of my hand. I ask'd him whether these shirts came by the coach or waggon, he said by the Chester waggon, and it put up at the Bull Inn, Holbourn. I asked him what he would have for them; he said 4 s. a piece.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of them?</p>
               <p>E. Wood. There were three of them I agreed to give it. I gave him a guinea to give me change, he said he had no change, but he had a few more things that he could spare, and he'd go and fetch them, and said I might let it alone till he came. So he left the guinea with me, and said he had left his box in a cellar, and it was open. I said, what but just come to town, and leave a box in such a manner, why did you not go to an inn; he said he did that to save charges. He went away, and return'd with a great trunk on his head, big enough to hold two or three people. He put it down in the shop, and took out six shifts, two waistcoats, and I think one pair of drawers, six handkerchiefs, two of them were border'd with red. He took up one, and ask'd me if I ever saw such a one before, and said his brother at the Indies made him a present of them. He took out some neckcloths and some stockings. Then he pull'd out some womens cloaths. I said what have you got womens coaths. He said do you think I have not got a wife I said how came you not to bring her with you. He said she was not far off, she is at the Bull Inn. I said I will not touch them till you bring her here, I am afraid you have strip'd her, and left her behind you He ask'd 41 s. for six shifts, three shirts, two waistcoats, and two pair of ruffles. I began to be very much surprised, having nobody with me, and it was almost ten o'clock at night. I went over the way to a Barber's shop, and knock'd at the door, but they were all gone to bed. Then I thought I would give the prisoner but part of the money, and so I bid him come again in the morning. So I gave him a guinea, and bid him come again for the rest. He wanted me to let him leave the trunk there, I would not permit that, it having been left at a cellar unlock'd, and if any thing had been taken out, I might be blam'd; so he took it away with him In the morning I went to see if the things were in any paper, but saw nothing of it. Then I went to the Printer of the Daily Advertiser. I left three shillings to have it put in, but the paper being full, he said it could not be in till the Friday; this was on the Wednesday. The next morning I found in the Advertiser a trunk lost, the size of this. Then I went to the prosecutor as directed, and told him the same as here, and was glad to deliver him the things I had bought.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-person254">
                  Robert 
                  Thornber 
               <interp inst="t17570914-22-person254" type="surname" value="Thornber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person254" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Black Bull in Holbourn. I was smoaking a pipe with my friend, and in came a porter with a large trunk, a little after eleven at night, on the 3d of 
               <persName id="t17570914-22-person255">
                  August 
                  He 
               <interp inst="t17570914-22-person255" type="surname" value="He"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person255" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked me if a gentleman could have a lodging there. I said yes, if there were nobody but himself; he put the trunk on the floor; then came in the prisoner, who wanted change for a guinea. I chang'd it, he gave the porter 6 d. The porter ask'd him to make him drink, then he call'd for a full pot of beer; he eat some buttock of beef, he was very hungry. He had a pair of new shoes on, and these stockings here produc'd, a very dirty shirt, and this laced hat (thinks I this is some post chaise affair) I began to ask him questions, first what countryman, - Chester, - how did you come, - by the coach, - how far have you come to day, - twenty miles, - that stage must run fifty or sixty miles a day, - I came by a coach, - where did you put up, - at the Plume of Feathers, - there is no such inn as I know of. Then he said it was at the Blossom Inn. I said, why did not you stay there all night. He said he came to see<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140017"></xptr> some acquaintance, a hair merchant in Holbourn. Then he said he was going to sea, on board a letter of marque. I was very busy with him, and found him in a great many stories. I ask'd him if he came thro' St. Alban's, he said he din'd there; I said that is above twenty miles from London. I said I am afraid your shirt will not suit my sheets, they are rather too white for you; I should be afraid to lie with you, fearing I should catch something; said he, I have ruffled shirts in the trunk. Then he open'd it, and pull'd out a large ruffled shirt; thought I, that was never made for you. I look'd in and saw a suit of cloaths trim'd with gold I ask'd him why he did not clean himself before he came to town. Then I look'd and saw a petticoat, said I what do you wear petticoats too; then he ask'd me if I was going to rob him. I said no. Then I told him I should keep him till I knew how he came by that trunk. Then I sent my tapster to the watch house, but there was no constable. Then I went and knock'd up Mr. Stanton, a constable, who came with me. I charged him with the prisoner, upon suspicion of stealing the trunk and things. Mr. Stanton charg'd me to assist, and we took him to the Compter; the trunk was advertised next morning. Then we took the prisoner and things before my Lord mayor, who sent for the prosecutor from St. Mary Hill; the gentlewoman had an inventory of all the things.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you see this evidence before my Lord-mayor?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did.</p>
               <p>Thoruber. My Lord committed the prisoner to Newgate, we attended him thither, and there left him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-22-person256">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17570914-22-person256" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a coachman to a common hackney coach. I took the prosecutor up at the Bell in the strand, at the back of the New Church.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I came then from Bristol.</p>
               <p>Taylor. He order'd me to make the trunk secure behind the coach. I took and bound it fast thro' the handles, and tied the rope with two knots; when I came against the toy-shop in St. Paul's Church yard, I ask'd a man how the trunk was behind, who look'd, and said you have got never a trunk there. I got down and saw it was gone.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stanton. I am a constable. I was sent for to Mr. Thornber's house; there was the prisoner with a large trunk. The prisoner said the things in it were his property; I said if they were, he could tell us what they were. He mention'd some things, and we took them down. We said are there not more things, he said some things not material. When we came to examine them, we found fifty more things than he had mention'd. There was a good suit of cloaths that he said was made for him. We made him put them on, but they were too long for him; he said his father order'd them to be made so because he was growing.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Stanton. About twelve o'clock; there were two razors we took out of his pocket ( producing them )</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. These are none of mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I found this trunk betwixt St. Paul's and Ludgate, about eight o'clock. I came from Westchester, my father lives there. I am a <rs id="t17570914-22-deflabel133" type="occupation">hair curler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-22-defend249 t17570914-22-deflabel133"></join> by trade. I never found such a thing before, I would have been glad to have sold them all.</p>
               <p>Q. to Taylor. What time of the night was it when you missed the trunk from behind the coach?</p>
               <p>Taylor. It had not gone seven.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-22-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-22-punish135" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-22-punish135" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-22-defend249 t17570914-22-punish135"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
