<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-32">
               <interp inst="t17500912-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-32" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-32" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-32-off145-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-32-defend248 t17500912-32-off145 t17500912-32-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>539. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-32-defend248" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Watson 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-32-defend248" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-defend248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-defend248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17500912-32-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-32-victim250" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Loveless 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-32-victim250" type="surname" value="Loveless"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-32-victim250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-32-victim250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-32-off145 t17500912-32-victim250"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one silver watch, value 40 s. from his person and against his will did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-32-cd146" type="crimeDate">Sept. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-32-off145 t17500912-32-cd146"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-32-person251">
                  John 
                  Loveless 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person251" type="surname" value="Loveless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Friday night between 11 and 12 o'clock, I was coming from Ratliff Cross; I had been there at a boat-builder's; a little dog follow'd me into the street; I turn'd myself round to drive him in again; I heard a voice say your money this moment, or else you are a dead man. I was not got above three or four steps from the door; I turn'd round and star'd the man in the face; and thought somebody joak'd with me, being pretty well known in the neighbourhood. I saw his face plain, but had I not taken him that night, it may be I might not have known him again. I started back when I saw a hanger in his hand; he gave an offer at me. He came up to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120015"></xptr> me again, and put his hand to my pocket, and took out my watch, and said, if I stirr'd he would murder me; then he put his hand into my breeches pocket, and took out a paper which was only a direction to a gentleman in Red Lion Square. Then he walk'd off quietly, and I walk'd after him; upon recovering my spirits, I cry'd out stop thief. There was a public house open'd ; they heard the cry ; there was a man I knew, one 
               <persName id="t17500912-32-person252">
                  John 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person252" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I desired him to run after him, saying there he is, and pointed to him. Tanner ran, and two men push'd out at the ale-house, the duke of Cumberland's head. Where is he? said one of them. Said I, that is the man. Said they, let him run to the d - l, we'll have him. Turning down at a corner, one of them struck up his heels. I came up and took him by the collar, and said this is the man. He never had been out of my view then. One of them wrench'd the cutlass out of his hand; it was drawn. I desir'd Mr. Tanner to take particular charge of him; he was the person I knew. We search'd the prisoner, and he had not the watch about him. We found the sheath of the hanger under his coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-32-person253">
                  John 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person253" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person253" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday night last, between eleven and twelve o'clock, I was at my mother's house; I heard stop thief call'd out; I open'd the door and saw the prosecutor, he said, he was just now robb'd; I ran and he ran, I saw the prisoner before me about twenty or thirty yards, and running by the Duke's head there came out two men; I said to one of them, I am tired, do you run; they ran and got him down, (I lost fight of the prisoner once, then I was a little behind Mr. Loveless ) I came up in about half a minute, the hanger was then took out of the prisoner's hand, and about six or seven persons about him, one 
               <persName id="t17500912-32-person254">
                  Thomas 
                  Fitzer 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person254" type="surname" value="Fitzer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person254" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had hold of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-32-person255">
                  David 
                  Service 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person255" type="surname" value="Service"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person255" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Duke's head; Thomas Fitzer was along with me; we heard a voice cry stop thief, this was about half an hour after eleven o'clock; he and I ran and pursued the prisoner, and came up with him in about three minutes; 
               <persName id="t17500912-32-person256">
                  Thomas 
                  Fitzer 
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person256" type="surname" value="Fitzer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was first, the prisoner made a stroak at him with his cutlass, and Fitzer knock'd him down with his fist, and I took the hanger out of his hand. Mr. Loveless came up in a minute, and said, that is the man that robb'd me of my watch, so he was taken to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Loveless. The watch was found in the street, with the glass broken, and brought to the watch-house by some person, I know not who.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming from Blackwall; I met that gentleman going along, as I had pass'd him, he said stop thief; I ran to the top of the lane and fell down, so one person said, you are the man I believe. The prosecutor said before the justice, he could not swear to me; and when the justice said I must be the man, then he did swear to me.</p>
               <p>Loveless. After I had given the same account I have here, I saw his ancient father, who was very much troubled, then I was willing the prisoner should go about his business; and I did say, is it not possible one man should be like another in the dark? a body may be mistaken ; but I was as certain to the prisoner as I am now.</p>
               <p>There were nine witnesses spoke well, as to his character in what they had observed of him, since he returned from the East-Indies with Admiral 
               <persName id="t17500912-32-person257">
                  Boscawen
               <interp inst="t17500912-32-person257" type="given" value="Boscawen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-person257" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's fleet.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-32-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17500912-32-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-32-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-32-defend248 t17500912-32-punish148"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
