<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560528-2">
               <interp inst="t17560528-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-2" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560528"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560528-2" type="date" value="17560528"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560528-2-off7-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-2-defend43 t17560528-2-off7 t17560528-2-verdict10"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175605280004"></xptr>175 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-defend43" type="defendantName">
                     Girolamo 
                     Ferri 
                  <interp inst="t17560528-2-defend43" type="surname" value="Ferri"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-defend43" type="given" value="Girolamo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560528-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 9 holland shirts, value 40 s. I pair of muslin ruffles, value 5 s. 1 gold ring set with 15 diamonds, value 10 l. and 1 gold ring set with an amethyst
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-victim45" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Ricciarelli 
                  <interp inst="t17560528-2-victim45" type="surname" value="Ricciarelli"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-victim45" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-victim45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-2-off7 t17560528-2-victim45"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560528-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">March 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-2-off7 t17560528-2-cd8"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The prisoner and prosecutor being both foreigners, an interpeter was sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-person46">
                  Joseph 
                  Ricciarelli 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person46" type="surname" value="Ricciarelli"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person46" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was my <rs id="t17560528-2-deflabel9" type="occupation">valet de chamber</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560528-2-defend43 t17560528-2-deflabel9"></join>; on the 8th of March I lost a number of shirts, I can't tell exactly how many.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you lost to the number of nine?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. I am. I lost a pair of muslin ruffles, a gold ring set with 15 diamonds, and an amethyst ring. On missing the rings, I taxed the prisoner with taking them. He said he had them in his pocket, and took them out and delivered them to me; then charging him with taking my shirts, he owned he had taken and pawn'd them. We sent accordingly, and the pawnbroker produced them; (the rings produced in court, and deposed to.) I carried the prisoner before a magistrate, where he confessed the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give the prisoner directions to pawn the shirts?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. No, I never order'd him to carry any thing to pawn; I once gave him two louisd'ors to change, which he did, and I had them back again.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the prisoner been your servant?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. He has been my servant four years and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bring him into England with you?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. I did, from Germany.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he deliver your rings upon your asking for them?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or no he was not intrusted with your goods?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. He was, with every thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give a reason why he pawned the shirts?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17560528-2-person47">
                  James 
                  Cammel 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person47" type="surname" value="Cammel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person47" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. I do, he is my footman.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether he and the prisoner have not at different times pawned things for you, by your orders?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. No, I do not remember any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you missed the shirts before you charged the prisoner, or the prisoner told you he had pawn'd them before you charged him with taking them ?</p>
               <p>Ricciarelli. I never look'd into the things till he was taken up, and then he own'd he had pawn'd them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-person48">
                  Thomas 
                  Harrache 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person48" type="surname" value="Harrache"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person48" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of March, about eleven at night, I came home, and heard the prosecutor's servant had robbed him; he lodged in my house. I examined the prisoner myself, who own'd he had pawn'd ten of his master's shirts. I was present before the magistrate, where he owned the same, and also his taking the two rings. The prosecutor is first singer at the opera.</p>
               <p>Jr. Watson. I am a pawnbroker. One Dr. Griffin pledged two shirts and a pair of ruffles with me, at two different times, in November and December; after that, the prisoner came to me with Dr. Griffin, and claimed them as his property; produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-person49">
                  Thomas 
                  Parshal 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person49" type="surname" value="Parshal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person49" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner pawn'd 8 shirts with me; produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I put these shirts in pawn, because my master owned me two months wages; he told me he had no money, but bid me do what I could with the goods, and said he would pay me when he had his benefit.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-person50">
                  James 
                  Cammel 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person50" type="surname" value="Cammel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person50" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an interpreter, and live servant with the prosecutor. The prisoner once came out of my master's room, and brought me two double French louisd'ors, desiring me to go and get two guineas upon them, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they worth?</p>
               <p>Cammel. They are worth about forty shillings each.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pledge or change the louisd'ors?</p>
               <p>Cammel. I pledg'd them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Crawford. The prosecuter has sometimes apply'd to me to advance money on his note before it was due; I know he has wanted money generally before it was due.</p>
               <p>Lazarus Bartovalle. The prisoner brought me 2 double French louisd'ors by order of his master, and I lent him 2 guineas upon them. I have sometimes lent the prosecutor 10 guineas, sometimes 6, and often paid the coach for him. He often wanted<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175605280005"></xptr> another, but he always paid me when he took it. I have known the prisoner from his first coming to England; his master did not use him like a servant, but more like a companion. I have dined with his master and him together; he always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560528-2-person51">
                  Joseph 
                  Cap 
               <interp inst="t17560528-2-person51" type="surname" value="Cap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person51" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he has been in England, which was in the year fifty-four. I look upon him to be a very honest man. I have heard the prosecutor give him a very good character, I have dined with them both at one table. He used him as a companion and not as a servant.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jackson. I have known the prisoner 12 months; he always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Willer. I have known him 10 or 12 months; I never heard any ill of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hall. I have known him about 2 years; I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tilley. I have known him 4 or 5 months; I have trusted him alone in my shop, where there were many jewels and other goods, and he never wrong'd me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560528-2-verdict10" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560528-2-verdict10" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
