<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-22">
               <interp inst="t17590912-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-22" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-22" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-22-off135-c179" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-defend224 t17590912-22-off135 t17590912-22-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>269. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-22-defend224" type="defendantName">
                     Nicholas 
                     Randall 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-22-defend224" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-defend224" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-defend224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17590912-22-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               that he, with a certain gun loaded with gun-powder and leaden shot, which he had, and held in his right-hand, did unlawfully, wilfully, and feloniously, of malice aforethought, shoot of, at, and against 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590912-22-victim226" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hampton 
                        <interp inst="t17590912-22-victim226" type="surname" value="Hampton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-22-victim226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-22-victim226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-off135 t17590912-22-victim226"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   
                     <rs id="t17590912-22-viclabel136" type="occupation">the younger</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-victim226 t17590912-22-viclabel136"></join>, the said John being in the king's highway
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590912-22-cd137" type="crimeDate">Aug. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-off135 t17590912-22-cd137"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>John 
               <persName id="t17590912-22-person227">
                  Hampton
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person227" type="given" value="Hampton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person227" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger. I live at <placeName id="t17590912-22-crimeloc138">Turnham-Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-22-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Turnham-Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-22-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-off135 t17590912-22-crimeloc138"></join> with my father: the prisoner lives just by.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Hampton. I am upwards of fourteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hampton. He is a <rs id="t17590912-22-deflabel139" type="occupation">beggar</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-defend224 t17590912-22-deflabel139"></join>, and has a little house there, and a garden a little distance from it; about a month ago last Sunday I was at play with other boys in the road on the Green, we were talking, not at play.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>Hampton. It was a great way from his house, about a quarter of a mile; he has a garden; he has two pear-trees, a damason-tree, and two or three apple-trees in it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near were you boys to his garden?</p>
               <p>Hampton. It has been measured; it is 70 yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any of you boys been in his garden that day?</p>
               <p>Hampton. No, not as I know of; I was but just come from work.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Hampton. This was about 4 in the afternoon; the prisoner stood in his own garden, and shot through the hedge at us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him?</p>
               <p>Hampton. We did not, but we saw the gun move; he put it into the hedge, at one place, and then at another.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he point the gun?</p>
               <p>Hampton. He pointed it towards us, but he could not fix it at the first place; so he went to another place, and shot off directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he hit.</p>
               <p>Hampton. He hit 
               <persName id="t17590912-22-person228">
                  William 
                  Denny 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person228" type="surname" value="Denny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person228" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the leg, and knock'd another boy's hat off his head, and another through the lappet of his coat, and he shot me just in the sight of my left eye, and blinded that eye.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner stand at the time ?</p>
               <p>Hampton. He stood on the inside of his own garden.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been there?</p>
               <p>Hampton. I believe we had been there about an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. How many boys were there of you?</p>
               <p>Hampton. I believe there were a dozen of us.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they bigger or less then you?</p>
               <p>Hampton. They were all bigger than I am, except one.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any of you spoke to the prisoner that day?</p>
               <p>Hampton. No, neither of us had; I had not seen him that day before he shot.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you been doing before that day?</p>
               <p>Hampton. I had been at work at a farmhouse, in helping to do the horses.</p>
               <p>Q. During that hour you had all been there together, had neither of you been in his garden?</p>
               <p>Hampton. No; in that time we had neither of us been near his garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he call to you before he shot ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120025"></xptr>Hampton. No, he never spoke a word before he shot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Hampton. No, not 'till the people came to him; then he said, he would shoot any body after he shot us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go near his garden afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Hampton. We had our eye and leg dressed before we went that way again; I believe that was a quarter of an hour before we went up to his ground, then he was just coming out of his garden into the street: his house is not by his garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing to him then ?</p>
               <p>Hampton. No, I did not; the gentlemen ask'd him, how he could do so, to hit this lad just in the eye, and another on his leg. He answered, he would shoot any body that went to touch him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the gun pointed towards you boys both times?</p>
               <p>Hampton. It was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-22-person229">
                  Q.
                   John Hampton
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person229" type="surname" value="John Hampton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person229" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person229" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. The evidence that has been examined is my son; I was at home that Sunday. They sent for me when the accident was done. When I came to the place where it was done the prisoner had loaded his gun again, and said, if any body offered to meddle with him he would shoot him.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you said to him?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. I ask'd him how he could do so?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether your son had been in his garden?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. No, I do not know that he had. I went for a constable, and when I came back again they had got him in custody; and bringing him from his garden. He had got his gun with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is he?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. He begged at the pissing-place going to Brentford.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say before the justice?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. He said but little there: he was hardly examined there at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Has your son lost the sight of his eye?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. He has. (There was a cloth about it, that it could not conveniently be seen.) There is a shot in his head now, the Surgeon says. We brought him out of St George's hospital yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any marks of shot in his face?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. No; there were shot taken out of the other boy's leg.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them taken out?</p>
               <p>Hampton, sen. No. I have seen the shot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-22-person230">
                  Richard 
                  Blake 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person230" type="surname" value="Blake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person230" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live about midway between where the boys were shot, and the prisoner's garden. I was standing in my yard, looking over my gate.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the place where the prisoner shot, to the place where the boys were playing ?</p>
               <p>Blake. It is 70 yards, I measured it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in your yard?</p>
               <p>Blake. I had been there upwards of an hour, and had seen the boys at play there upwards of an hour. I saw the prisoner come to his garden, and I heard him swear, as he walked along, that he would shoot the boys.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he say this to?</p>
               <p>Blake. He said that to himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any of the boys been in his garden that afternoon?</p>
               <p>Blake. I can't say none of them had not been in at all; but none of them had been in that afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him put the gun through the hedge?</p>
               <p>Blake. I saw him put it through the hedge and fire: he shot one boy in the eye, he fell to the ground; and another in the leg.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Blake. I was within about thirty yards of him. I saw him charge the gun immediately after he had shot, and he swore he would shoot any body that should attempt to take or meddle with him. There happened to be a Surgeon coming by; we told him what had happened; he insisted upon our taking the prisoner up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he point the gun at any body, when he said he would shoot any body that should attempt to meddle with him?</p>
               <p>Blake. Yes, he did. The Surgeon was so enraged, that he ordered him to come out of his garden; and there came a great many people about him. When he came out we followed him 'till he came to his own door at his house, which is better than a quarter of a mile.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120026"></xptr> There we would not let him go in, but got his gun from him, which was then loaded, cock'd and primed. A long gun produced. This is the gun.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the charge drawn?</p>
               <p>Blake. It is not.</p>
               <p>Court. Take it out, and draw the charge.</p>
               <p>Blake. (He takes it out, and returned with some large duck shot in his hand.) These I drew out of the gun, and after that some powder. The Surgeon took some such shot as these out of the other boy's leg; the boy is here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-22-person231">
                  Jane 
                  Inglefield 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person231" type="surname" value="Inglefield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person231" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Blake; I was at our own gate, and saw the old man go to the garden with his gun in his hand. He said he would shoot the boys when he came up to his garden. He said he saw three boys in it. I went and looked, and there were none in it. I told him there were no boys in it; and he damned me, and said, he would shoot me if I said ever a word more to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. But I saw three boys go out.</p>
               <p>Inglefield. The boys were 70 yards from his garden when he shot at them; I saw him point the gun through the elder hedge and shoot three boys.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it as soon as he got into the garden?</p>
               <p>Inglefield. No; he had been in the garden, I believe, about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do that time in the garden ?</p>
               <p>Inglefield. Nothing, but put the gun 3 or 4 times through the hedge, to see for a proper place where to shoot it off.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he point the gun?</p>
               <p>Inglefield. Always towards the boys; I saw him fire it; it hit Hampton in the eye, and 
               <persName id="t17590912-22-person232">
                  William 
                  Denny 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person232" type="surname" value="Denny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person232" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the leg. After that he charg'd the gun directly, and said he would shoot any body that came up to him. There were several of us that went up to him in a few minutes after the gun went off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see either of the boys dressed.</p>
               <p>Inglefield. I saw the Surgeon take three shot out of 
               <persName id="t17590912-22-person233">
                  William 
                  Denny 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person233" type="surname" value="Denny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person233" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             immediately after he was shot.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are the shot?</p>
               <p>Inglefield. They are not here.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these shot (the same that were drawn from the gun).</p>
               <p>Inglefield. They were just such as these. The boys two mothers asked him how he could do such a thing, as to shoot the children? he swore he would shoot them through the body too, if they said a word. He said, he had not hurt them, for it was nothing but a little sparrow shot. This he said to all of us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-22-person234">
                  John 
                  Croft 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person234" type="surname" value="Croft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person234" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable. The gun was delivered to me on the 12th of August before the justice; it was then loaded, and I kept it loaded in my possession ever since, 'till it was drawn here.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know it was then loaded?</p>
               <p>Croft. Because I put the rammer down and found it so. I was charged with the prisoner at the bar, and he went very quietly along with me, and said, he did not shoot the boys.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>These chaps here, whatever they say, I had never fired upon them, nor nothing like it, but they came, and said, they would knock the old son of a bitch down. The boys have robbed my ground of as many goods as I could have made 20 s. of, and more. These are the honest people, that would have you believe to be so honest. 
               <persName id="t17590912-22-person235">
                  James 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17590912-22-person235" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person235" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and told me, he saw the boys in my garden.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-22-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-22-verdict140" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty. <rs id="t17590912-22-punish141" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17590912-22-punish141" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-22-defend224 t17590912-22-punish141"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>. Recommended
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
