<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561020-39">
               <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561020"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="date" value="17561020"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561020-39-off180-c206" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-defend277 t17561020-39-off180 t17561020-39-verdict184"></join>
         
               <p>438. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17561020-39-defend277" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Jonathan 
                     Hirst 
                  , otherwise, <rs id="t17561020-39-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-defend277 t17561020-39-alias-6"></join>Johnson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-defend277" type="surname" value="Hirst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-defend277" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-defend277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17561020-39-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17561020-39-victim280" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Brudenell 
                        <interp inst="t17561020-39-victim280" type="surname" value="Brudenell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561020-39-victim280" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561020-39-victim280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-off180 t17561020-39-victim280"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17561020-39-viclabel181" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-victim280 t17561020-39-viclabel181"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one gold watch, value 10 l. and 2 s. 6 d. in money number'd, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561020-39-cd182" type="crimeDate">Oct. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-off180 t17561020-39-cd182"></join>. *</p> 
               <p>Robert Brudenell. I was going home in my chair on Tuesday morning the 5th of October, between one and two o'clock; I had not been very well, and was asleep, but the chair being set down (in <placeName id="t17561020-39-crimeloc183">Berkley Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39-crimeloc183" type="placeName" value="Berkley Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39-crimeloc183" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-off180 t17561020-39-crimeloc183"></join> ) it awaken'd me, when I found a pistol at my head.</p>
               <p>Q. How many men did you see?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. I saw only the man that hold it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know him?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. I can't say that the prisoner is the man; the first words I heard were, '' Your cash, '' your cash.''</p>
               <p>Q. Who said that?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. The man that held a pistol to my head, in a low voice. I did not rightly understand him, and said hey, hey, or something like it, being but just awake. He then used some rash words to make me make haste, and the first thing I gave him was my watch.</p>
               <p>Q. What watch was it?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. A gold one.</p>
               <p>Q. What might you value it at?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. At about ten pounds, it was an old one; he took it, and then asked me for my cash, when I took my purse out of my pocket and slip'd it under me, and gave him my loose silver, which I think was about five six-pences. Then he put down the top of the chair, and bid the chairmen go on. I saw the foremost chairman standing about ten yards from me, and the hindmost told me afterwards he was standing behind with a man who held a pistol at his head. When I thought they were got clear from the chair I desired to be let out.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any servant with you?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a light or a dark night?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. The moon was just getting down, rather dark than light.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever your watch again?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200020"></xptr>Brudenell. No; the prisoner said that on hearing a pistol go off he threw it into a pond. I pursued and overtook one of the men; there were some watchmen with me. The person we pursued snap'd a pistol at me, and after that fired again and missed me, but kill'd a watchman about ten yards behind me; it was a very narrow escape.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that watchman's name?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. His name was Crowder. This is the pistol [producing one] that was fired.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the watchman live afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. He died in less than half an hour. Upon that pistol's being fired I told the person I would shew him no mercy, and slack him twice with my sword. Then he surrender'd and desired to be carried before a justice. After I had taken the pistol from him I was conducting him to the watch house, and going along met colonel Brown and captain West, who went thither with me. I set the person down in a chair, when he directly said to captain West, I hope captain West you'll take care of me. I found also he knew me, but not my name; he said he had seen me mount guard many a time.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that man?</p>
               <p>Brudenell. He was a soldier. Captain West asking him what his name was, he said his name was Browning, and that he belong'd to col. Parker's company. Being asked which Parker, he said colonel 
               <persName id="t17561020-39-person281">
                  George 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person281" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person281" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked him who was with him in the robbery; he said that was a soldier also, but would not tell his name. I asked him where he lived; he said he did not know, but that he always met him near Lincoln's Inn Chapel, and that they went to rob together in Berkley-Square or thereabouts, but the other would never let him know where he lived. One of the two chairmen swore before the justice, that the man who shot the watchman was the man that held the pistol to my head.</p>
               <p>Council. We have the two chairman here, but don't apprehend it material to call them, the robbery being so fully proved.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-39-person282">
                  John 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person282" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person282" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am high constable of Westminster. Mr. Fielding desired me to go down to New-Prison to see the man that was stab'd. On Tuesday in the afternoon, about five or six o'clock, I went. He was alive, but died about seven. After some talk with him he told me his accomplice's name was Hirst, but went by the name of Johnson, and that he was concerned with him in that robbery, and he lived in a court by Lincoln's Inn; which I found afterwards, was Bishop's Court. He could not tell the name of the court. He told us if we went to a coffee house at the corner, the people would direct us to the house. We went, and were directed. We inquired for him, and was told he was gone into the country. Browning said, he had a pistol, which was fellow to that which was taken upon him. Upon finding some letters in his buroe, there was one directed to Mr. Newton. We applied to him, and he carried us to several different lodgings. At last we went to the Barnetstage, and found he was gone in it, to Potter's Bar, in Hatfield road. On searching his lodgings we found these purses ( producing six or seven) I and Mr. Newton went to Potter's Bar on Wednesday in the afternoon, to the house of (I think) one Warner, a private house. There we found the prisoner at the bar. Mr. Newton told me that was the man, so I secured him. I put my hand in his pocket, and pull'd out this pistol. It was loaded. ( Producing one, and the two pistols being compared and examined by the jury they appeared to be fellows.) I charged him, and he said he'd surrender. There was his wife sitting by him. We pinion'd him, and brought him that night to justice Fielding's and there he made a confession. I was present and saw him sign it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he sign it freely ?</p>
               <p>Barnes. Mr. Fielding said to him two or three times before he sign'd it, Mr. Johnson, if you sign this, you are signing your death warrant; I'd have you confessed what you'r about, for your confession you can't ritrect.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it read over to him?</p>
               <p>Barnes. It was; I heard it, and also before that I heard him make it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this agreeable to the confession you heard him make ?</p>
               <p>Barnes. It is.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17561020-39">
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561020"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-39" type="date" value="17561020"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY OF LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD BAILEY, On Wednesday the 20th, Thursday the 21st, and Friday the 22d of OCTOBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Thirtieth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VIII. PART II. for the YEAR 1756. Being the Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1756.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. DID he sign it voluntarily?</p>
               <p>Barnes. He did.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport:</p>
               <p>The examination and voluntary confession of 
               <persName id="t17561020-39-person283">
                  Jonathan 
                  Hirst 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person283" type="surname" value="Hirst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person283" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , taken before me, one of his majesty's justices of the peace for the county of Middlesex, 
               <persName id="t17561020-39-person284">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person284" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person284" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; October 6, 1756.</p>
               <p>'' This examinant faith, that on Monday last, '' being the 4th of October, he met one Thomas '' Browning, by appointment, by Lincoln's Inn '' Fields, in order to go and commit robberies; '' that they went to Berkley-Square, betwixt the '' hours of twelve and one, and there they attacked '' a gentleman in his chair, from whom this examinant '' took a gold watch and some money. '' Soon after he heard the report of a pistol, but '' has not seen Browning since.''</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-39-person285">
                  Richard 
                  Hoye 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person285" type="surname" value="Hoye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person285" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the chairmen, who was carrying captain Brudenell (I was behind) Two men came up to rob him in Berkley-Square. One of them held a pistol to my head.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he near enough for you to observe who it was?</p>
               <p>Hoye. It was the man that is dead, named Browning. I can't say any thing to the other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was in such a great confusion when I was taken that I knew nothing what I said. I unfortunately belonged to the army, and had deserted, and I had this pistol determining not to be taken till I could get friends to make it up to return to the regiment again; and under these unhappy circumstances, and withall my wife being big with child, they persuaded me to make confession, but I know nothing at all of the robbery.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-39-person286">
                  Ann 
                  Leichley 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person286" type="surname" value="Leichley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person286" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great many years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>A. Leichley. As good as a character as ever I heard in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him on the 4th of October?</p>
               <p>A. Leichley. He and his wife lodg'd with me eight months, but I believe I did not see him that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he left you?</p>
               <p>A. Leichley. I think he went away last Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-39-person287">
                  Catharine 
                  Horsey 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person287" type="surname" value="Horsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person287" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>C. Horsey. I always heard a very good one. I lodged in the house part of the time he did with the former witness.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you lodge with her now?</p>
               <p>C. Horsey. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of him on the 4th or 5th of October last?</p>
               <p>C. Horsey. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-39-person288">
                  Mary 
                  Prislow 
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person288" type="surname" value="Prislow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person288" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner in his apprenticeship.</p>
               <p>Q. To what trade?</p>
               <p>M. Prislow. A grocer.</p>
               <p>Q. When did that apprenticeship end?</p>
               <p>M. Prislow. It ended six or seven years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave?</p>
               <p>M. Prislow. He behaved himself very well. It was in Scarborough.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known any thing of him for three or four years last past?</p>
               <p>M. Prislow. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If the captain will speak for me he knows no ill of me.</p>
               <p>Captain 
               <persName id="t17561020-39-person289">
                  Bradenell
               <interp inst="t17561020-39-person289" type="given" value="Bradenell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-person289" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the same regiment he does, but not the same company; I know nothing good or bad of him. I have little or no knowledge of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561020-39-verdict184" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-verdict184" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17561020-39-punish185" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-39-punish185" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-39-defend277 t17561020-39-punish185"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
