<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-43">
               <interp inst="t17560915-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-43" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-43" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-43-off221-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-43-defend337 t17560915-43-off221 t17560915-43-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>374. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560915-43-defend337" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17560915-43-defend337" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-defend337" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-defend337" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17560915-43-deflabel220" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-43-defend337 t17560915-43-deflabel220"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-43-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one 36 s. piece of gold
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-43-victim339" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Howel 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-43-victim339" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-victim339" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-victim339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-43-off221 t17560915-43-victim339"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560915-43-cd222" type="crimeDate">July 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-43-off221 t17560915-43-cd222"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-43-person340">
                  Catharine 
                  Howel 
               <interp inst="t17560915-43-person340" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person340" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is William, and we live at the Crown and Scepters, in Charles-Street, Covent Garden. I delivered three thirty-six shilling pieces to 
               <persName id="t17560915-43-person341">
                  Samuel 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17560915-43-person341" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person341" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my servant, to go out and get changed. After he had been out some time he sent for me to the place where the prisoner was. He desired I'd take the two, and said he was rob'd of one by the prisoner. He delivered one changed, and the other not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it he sent for you to come?</p>
               <p>C. Howel. It was in a court just by <placeName id="t17560915-43-crimeloc223">Catharine-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-43-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="Catharine-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-43-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-43-off221 t17560915-43-crimeloc223"></join>. He was standing in the street, to keep the prisoner from coming out at the door. I went to see for a constable, and when I returned I met him and the prisoner, and her acquaintance, coming to go before the justice. She ask'd her friend what she should do? The other answered, d - n you madam, we'll Bury him. Before the justice the prisoner own'd she had the piece of money in her hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-43-person342">
                  Samuel 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17560915-43-person342" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person342" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mrs. Howel. She sent me to get three thirty-six shilling pieces changed. I went in at the Peacock, the corner of Exeter Street, and ask'd the mistress to give me change for one. She said, she could not. Then the prisoner took it in her hand, and said it was a counterfeit, and swore I should not have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150025"></xptr> it. She flung it upon the table to chink it, and then took it up and put it into her pocket. She had a pewter plate in her hand, and swore if I offer'd to touch her she'd cut me down with it. I laid hold on her arm (she had lost blood that day) and it fell a bleeding, so I let her go. She went out, and then into her own house in Catharine-court, near White-Hart Yard; I followed her, and sent mistress word that I was rob'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the landlady of the house see her take it?</p>
               <p>Turner. She saw her fling it down on the table, but she said, she could not swear she saw her take it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the landlady hear all the conversation between the prisoner and you about it?</p>
               <p>Turner. She must hear all that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the prisoner stay in that house after she had got it?</p>
               <p>Turner. I believe about fifteen minutes. When I took the prisoner to the justice the woman of the house was sent for, and she swore she saw the piece of money flung down on the table, and I swore the prisoner took it up. She was committed to New-Prison for farther examination.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went into that house to carry a pewter plate, when this man happened to be there, drinking a pint of beer. He ask'd for change for a thirty-six shilling piece, and said I had got the piece. Mrs. Pratt (the woman of the house) said, she never saw any thirty-six shilling piece he had. Here is a watchman can give an account how he wanted to swear this piece upon another.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-43-person343">
                  Thomas 
                  Buckle 
               <interp inst="t17560915-43-person343" type="surname" value="Buckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person343" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a soldier now, but then was a watchman in the parish. I happened to be at justice Fielding's when the prisoner and prosecutor were there. The prisoner wanted to get a warrant against him for scandal, in saying, she had rob'd him. After she was committed, he said to me, Buckle, you have known me some years; I said, yes, so I have. He said, if you'll go down to Mrs. Pratt's I'll treat you with a pot or two. We went down, and he call'd for a pot of beer. Then in came a woman. He took hold of her by the arm and charged me with her (he thought I was watchman then, but I was not ) and said, you are the woman that took my 36 s. piece.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that woman's name?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I don't know that; we took the woman to justice Fielding's. The people at the door said, he had committed one already, what would he do more? and kick'd him from the door. He said to me the woman that is committed is not the woman that took the piece of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-43-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-43-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
