<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-3">
               <interp inst="t17550515-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-3" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-3" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-3-off11-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-3-defend49 t17550515-3-off11 t17550515-3-verdict13"></join>
         
               <p>210. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-defend49" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Watson 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-3-defend49" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-defend49" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-defend49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 4 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550515-3-victim51" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Bristow 
                        <interp inst="t17550515-3-victim51" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-3-victim51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-3-victim51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-3-off11 t17550515-3-victim51"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said Thomas, <rs id="t17550515-3-cd12" type="crimeDate">March 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-3-off11 t17550515-3-cd12"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person52">
                  Anne 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person52" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person52" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red-house, an alehouse in Thames-street; I am now a widow, my husband was buried last night. I lost a tankard on the 3d of March last.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Bristow. I have seen him at my house four or five times; about four o'clock in the afternoon on the 3d of March he came in and called for a tankard of beer. I bid the boy go and draw it, which he did, and put it before him, he staid till about six o'clock. I had been up to my husband, who was then sick, and when I came down he was moved to another box, and the tankard standing before him, and in about ten minutes time a person spoke to me on the left-hand-side, I turned my face that way, in the mean time I saw the prisoner give the door a violent jirk; I said that fellow had taken away the tankard; I ran out after him into the street; I met a young man that is now in court, I said, Dick, Run after that fellow, for he has taken away my tankard, I saw him run up Harp-lane, he ran after him, but could not overtake him. Having some knowledge of his wife, I, with two friends, went and found the house where he lived, and took him about two in the morning, I took him before the justice, he owned he was in my house but denied having the tankard. I advertised it, and Mr. Dyer came and said he believed his man had bought such a tankard, and he had got it at home. I went to his house, this was on the Wednesday evening, after advertising it on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person53">
                  William 
                  Keys 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person53" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person53" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I called at 
               <persName id="t17550515-3-person54">
                  Thomas 
                  Bristow 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person54" type="surname" value="Bristow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person54" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house on the 3d of March in the evening, and saw the prisoner there with his back towards the Fire; a little after that Mr. Bristow came and said he had lost a tankard, the prisoner was then gone out of the house; after that Mrs. Bristow came in out of the street, and said, that very man that was talking with you by the fire-side has ran away with my tankard. On the next morning Mrs. Bristow desired me to go to St. Martin's Round-house to see if I knew the Man again, I went, and found him to be the same. I went with him before justice Cox, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person55">
                  Charles 
                  Tilley 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person55" type="surname" value="Tilley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person55" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came presently after the tankard was missing, Mrs. Bristow desired I would go along with her to see for the man, we found him in bed at a house in Russel-court, we took him to justice Cox, the justice asked him what made him run away with the tankard? he said. he ran away because he had not money enough to pay his reckoning; he owned he had the tankard in the house, and left it there on the table.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person56" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Dyer, a silversmith in Lombard-street; the prisoner brought this tankard (produced in court) on Monday the 3d of March about six in the evening, and I bought it of him.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I lost it about five minutes before six by my dial.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150004"></xptr>Newman. I believe I bought it after six.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you buy it for?</p>
               <p>Newman. I gave him 5 s. 3 d. an ounce; it came to 5 l. 2 s. 3 d.</p>
               <p>Q. When he came to you did he look to be in a flurry?</p>
               <p>Newman. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you look upon plate when they bring it to sell?</p>
               <p>Newman. I saw the name upon the bottom, but I did not suspect he came dishonestly by it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. This is my Tankard, here is 
               <persName id="t17550515-3-person57">
                  William 
                  Winter 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person57" type="surname" value="Winter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the Red-house, Thames-street, London, engraved on the bottom of it, and T. A. B. on the handle; we bought that and other plate of Mr. Winter when we came into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this new or old sterling.</p>
               <p>Newman. It is old sterling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person58">
                  John 
                  Eadin 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person58" type="surname" value="Eadin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Red-house on the 3d of March, and saw the prisoner there, he was by himself when the tankard was lost, but I did not see him take it; I saw he had a tankard or a pot before him; it was missed before the door was shut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-3-person59">
                  Richard 
                  Wadbrook 
               <interp inst="t17550515-3-person59" type="surname" value="Wadbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person59" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing about two doors from the prosecutrix's house, I heard the door open and saw the prisoner run away. I had seen him in the house but a very little before; I was gone out to get me some victuals for my supper.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Wadbrook. As he is now; Mrs. Bristow said, Dick, Run after him, he has got my Tankard; I ran after him but could not take him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the house but I had no money, and I went home; I saw nothing of the tankard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-3-verdict13" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-verdict13" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550515-3-punish14" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-3-punish14" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-3-defend49 t17550515-3-punish14"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
