<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-39">
               <interp inst="t17510703-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-39" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-39" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-39-off180-c295" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-39-defend371 t17510703-39-off180 t17510703-39-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>452. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-defend371" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Troop 
                  <interp inst="t17510703-39-defend371" type="surname" value="Troop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-defend371" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-defend371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17510703-39-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     <persName id="t17510703-39-victim372" type="victimName">
                        George 
                        Bartholomew 
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-victim372" type="surname" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-39-victim372" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-39-victim372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-39-off180 t17510703-39-victim372"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510703-39-cd181" type="crimeDate">June 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-39-off180 t17510703-39-cd181"></join>. He stood charged on the coroner's inquisition for manslaughter. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person373">
                  Jane 
                  Bartholomew 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person373" type="surname" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person373" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of June my husband was brought home in a coach, and never spoke after; he was put to bed, and there died between four and five the next morning. He was bruised in every part from head to foot, not a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030026"></xptr> place in him was free, his private parts also; he was as black as a negro. He was robb'd also, for he carried out five 36 s. pieces, and five guineas, and he had but half a crown and 5 s. 6 d. in his fob when he was brought home, and the other has not been heard of since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person374">
                  Thomas 
                  Prince 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person374" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person374" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of June I and the deceased met together, and went to the other end of the town in Long-acre. He paid a young man there 12 or 13 s. then we went to the <placeName id="t17510703-39-crimeloc182">Crown alehouse in Compton-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-39-crimeloc182" type="placeName" value="Crown alehouse in Compton-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-39-crimeloc182" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-39-off180 t17510703-39-crimeloc182"></join>. He and one 
               <persName id="t17510703-39-person375">
                  Harry 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person375" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person375" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had some words. I went out and staid about a quarter of an hour, and when I came in again they were at high words. Mr. Troop took a shilling out of his pocket and insisted upon fighting for it, but it was some time before the deceased would take notice of it; at last he covered it with another, and went out to fight. One 
               <persName id="t17510703-39-person376">
                  George 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person376" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person376" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the money up, and we went into the fields. There were eight people or upwards against him and I. The deceased and the prisoner fought, fair boxing, what we call so, about twenty minutes : the deceased fell on his side, and before I could get him up all the company turned to the right hand and left us to ourselves. There were two men to assist me in carrying him to the White Hart in Windmill-street, Tottenham-court Road, where he never spoke above a word or two, which was to ask us to carry him to the vault, which we did, but brought him back as he went. I got a coach and put him in it, but he never spoke a word afterwards. I myself was used very ill, and suffered as much as he, save losing my life. I lay senseless on the ground some time, I believe five or six minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business in that house?</p>
               <p>Prince. We went there thinking to see some of my old shopmates.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person377">
                  John 
                  Doller 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person377" type="surname" value="Doller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am betwixt sixteen and seventeen years of age. I saw a mob, and went up to them, where I saw the deceased and prisoner fighting. I saw blows on both sides, but no desperate ones on either, and several falls. I saw the deceased lie down and shake hands with the prisoner after the battle was over.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they both fall?</p>
               <p>Doller. They did both in their turns.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased fall the last time?</p>
               <p>Doller. No, I did not, my lord; I went with the deceased to the White Hart, and help'd to wash his face, it being all over blood. I heard him ask to go to the vault, which was all he said. I went for the coach, and Mr. Prince desired me to go in the coach with him home, which I did, but he did not speak all the way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person378">
                  Thomas 
                  Bugden 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person378" type="surname" value="Bugden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person378" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of June I was at my work in Marybon-fields. I saw two men going to fight, they were all strangers to me but our own fellow workmen. I saw the two shake hands twice before they went to it; they fought about twenty five minutes. I had not an opportunity of seeing the whole of it, but I saw two falls, once the prisoner fell upon the deceased with his knee in his guts, which the company cry'd out shame on; but they fought a long time after that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person379">
                  Thomas 
                  Tipping 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person379" type="surname" value="Tipping"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person379" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. I saw the deceased the night he came home. I inspected the body after he was dead, and found a puncture on the right scrotum. I open'd his body by the desire of the jury, but did not open his skull; the parts of the body were all found and well, only putrified by the extravasated blood. There were some external bruises, but none but the fracture had gone far in: there was a large contusion on the scrotum; his head was contus'd violently, and there were two great wounds upon it. I imagine the fracture was owing to the fall, as it seem'd to be done by the round end of a stone about the breadth of a shilling, which fracture I look upon to be the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The first of the engagement was at the King's Head, the deceased and Prince came into company both very much disguised in liquor; they called for six pennyworth of rumbo; the people let them have it; then they called for another; they would not let them have any more; then they called for a pot of beer ; I offered to go away, they both insisted on my staying; Prince lent the deceased two shillings; the deceased said afterwards he had not got it; words ensuing, they threw the beer about the house; then the deceased gave him half a crown, Prince gave him sixpence out of it; then the deceased fell upon me about this money I saw him borrow, and said I ought to be beat, and he would lick me; then Prince went to the door about three minutes and returned again; then the deceased pulled out a crown, and said he'd fight me for it; then he took a handful of silver and threw it upon the table, and said he'd fight me for it to a shilling; then I said I'd fight for only a dozen of beer, so we went to fight for that shilling; 
               <persName id="t17510703-39-person380">
                  George 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person380" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person380" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             held the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person381">
                  George 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person381" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person381" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and three more were at the King's Head; we were on one side the house, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030027"></xptr> Prince, the prisoner, and the deceased on the other; they had some words so as to come to fighting, I cannot tell what about; we begged they would be easy and not fight; they continued wrangling some time; at last they were to fight for a dozen of beer, the money was put down, I took it up; they wanted to fight in the house, the people desired them to be quiet; then they agreed to go and fight in the field; they went and many with them, there they stripped and shook hands (they had both shook hands several times in the publick house before, and declared no animosity ) a lemon was bought and divided, and each of them had half to suck before they began; I took up the deceased's clothes, and called out for a friend of mine to take care of the other's; they fought as near as I can guess about half an hour; a great many falls they had on both sides, sometimes one uppermost, sometimes the other; they both received blows, but the falls were a great deal worse than the blows, after the battle was over the deceased lay along on the ground; I lifted him up, he desired me to let him alone; I helped to put on his shirt and waistcoat; Prince came up and said, take care of your friend; then I came to my company and went back to the house where it first began; there I delivered up the two shillings, and the prisoner spent one of them. 
               <persName id="t17510703-39-person382">
                  Charles 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person382" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person382" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the last evidence with this addition, the two men were so drunk, that as they went to strike at each other they missed their blows, and sometimes pitched on their heads or fell any way; and 
               <persName id="t17510703-39-person383">
                  Thomas 
                  Prince 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person383" type="surname" value="Prince"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person383" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in assisting his friend, got one eye almost knocked out, and there were so many strangers came about that he and others were afraid to go high almost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person384">
                  John 
                  Beard 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person384" type="surname" value="Beard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the above account with this addition (that they had three set-to's while fighting)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person385">
                  James 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person385" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person385" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the field before the deceased was stripped, I saw them shake hands, they seemed to make a stagger back; said the other, let us shake hands again, they did; then they set too, very drunk; after they had fought a minute, or a minute and half, one of them lay down, he was taken up and set too, they fought the space of another minute, then there was another fall; there came a parcel of fellows from making bricks, I believe there were 20 of them, and said, you will not leave yet; the prisoner seemed sick one time and lay down, these people by main strength got them up again and set them too like two cocks, and made people afraid to attempt to part them; I don't think any blow that was struck could cause any contusion or fracture.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-39-person386">
                  Charles 
                  Colwell 
               <interp inst="t17510703-39-person386" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person386" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the first that came into the field; I gathered the loose bricks that lay about and threw them at a distance, and cleared a place to fight in; the ground was dry and prodigious hard; when they first engaged the prisoner made a blow at the deceased, and retired I believe near ten or twelve yards, staggered and fell; the deceased followed him up and waited for his getting up again; my opinion is that by this means they might get amongst more brickbats, and by the fall he might receive his damage.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-39-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-verdict183" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-39-punish184" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-punish184" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-39-punish184" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-39-defend371 t17510703-39-punish184"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
