<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-19">
               <interp inst="t17581025-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-19" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-19" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-19-off91-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-19-defend168 t17581025-19-off91 t17581025-19-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>342. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-19-defend168" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-19-defend168" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-defend168" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-defend168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17581025-19-deflabel90" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-19-defend168 t17581025-19-deflabel90"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17581025-19-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two cloth cloaks, value 2 s. one linnen apron, value 1 s. two linen shirts, value 12 s. one muslin neckcloth, and one silk bonnet
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-19-victim170" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-19-victim170" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-victim170" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-victim170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-19-off91 t17581025-19-victim170"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581025-19-cd92" type="crimeDate">Oct. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-19-off91 t17581025-19-cd92"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-19-person171">
                  Jane 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17581025-19-person171" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person171" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person171" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is Thomas, I took in this woman at the bar out of charity, I was very ill in bed and sent her for my linen, she took my cloak and bonnet and went away with them, and the linen.</p>
               <p>Q. What linen?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. Two shirts and a neckcloth.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you send her?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. To the people whom I wash for.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take your apron and bonnet?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. I did, she took my apron from off a chair by my bed side as I lay on the bed, I took her before the sitting alderman yesterday, and he ordered me to take my bonnet from off her head, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she take the bonnet from?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. That was taken from off a nail by my cloak.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your linen again?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. A pawnbroker has got one of my shirts, but he will not deliver it without an order of court.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. He lives by the Cock alehouse in the corner near Ludgate-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner own she pawned it there?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your cloak and apron since?</p>
               <p>J. Williams. No, she has sold them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-19-person172">
                  William 
                  Lamb 
               <interp inst="t17581025-19-person172" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person172" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Great Sheer-lane, the prosecutrix washed for me; she had called on me and said she should send the prisoner to Chancery-lane, to one Mr. Grace for his linnen, and then she should call upon me; accordingly the prisoner came, I let her have one soul shirt and a neckcloth to carry to the prosecutrix's to wash. The maid of the house gave them her in my sight, at the same time the prisoner said, she had got Mr. Grace's shirt in her apron.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-19-person173">
                  Mary 
                  Malone 
               <interp inst="t17581025-19-person173" type="surname" value="Malone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person173" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-person173" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner take the bonnet, cloak, and apron out of the room, and never ask for them; she never brought them back, and Mrs. Williams never saw her till yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bid her not take them at that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250015"></xptr>M. Malone. No, I did not, I thought she was too honest to keep them, she did not return with them again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>She bid me take them and put them on; I belong to St. Michael's Wood-street, and the churchwardens have given her a crown to prosecute me, because I am troublesome to the parish.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Had you any conversation with the church-wardens of St. Michael's Wood-street, about the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear she was troublesome to that parish?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I know she has a sore leg, a very bad one.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see any of the churchwardens?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yesterday, but he did not say any thing to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever desired to prosecute the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever receive any money of any one to prosecute her?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never did, nor the value of a pint of small beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor no promise?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear that she was likely to become troublesome to the parish?</p>

               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lend her the cloak, apron, and hat?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not, I only bid her go for the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever lend her them?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I have lent them to her, but not then at that present time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-19-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-19-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
