<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520219-36">
               <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520219-36-off173-c261" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-36-defend327 t17520219-36-off173 t17520219-36-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>170. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-defend327" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Girdler 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-defend327" type="surname" value="Girdler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-defend327" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-defend327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17520219-36-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520219-36-victim329" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Roberts 
                        <interp inst="t17520219-36-victim329" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520219-36-victim329" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520219-36-victim329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-36-off173 t17520219-36-victim329"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, 15 s. from his person, and against his will did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17520219-36-cd174" type="crimeDate">Jan. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-36-off173 t17520219-36-cd174"></join>. +</p>
               <p>William Roberts. On the 17th of January coming from Westminster to Kensington, where my master lodges, about seven in the evening, in the <placeName id="t17520219-36-crimeloc175">foot-path betwixt Hide-Park-corner and Knightsbridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="foot-path betwixt Hide-Park-corner and Knightsbridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-36-off173 t17520219-36-crimeloc175"></join>, the prisoner stood under the wall, he came out upon me with a brace of pistols, and said deliver your money or I'll blow your brains out; I told him I was but a poor servant, and had none, he said little or much I'll have it: he claped one pistol in his bosom, and searched my pocket with that hand, holding the other to my breast, he took my money which was 15 s. I counted it before I came from Westminster; I turned from him, and on the other side of the way was, I suppose, a companion of his: he came across the way, and asked the prisoner, what he had got? the prisoner said but little, the other said D - n him I'll have his hat and wig: I ran, and got off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough for you to discern him so as to be certain to him?</p>
               <p>Roberts. The moon shone as bright as it could shine, he had a very black beard at that time, as he has now; his shoes were slit up the sore parts, I described him to my fellow-servants at Kensington, dressed as he is now: if I was not positive, I would not swear for a world.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a cap on?</p>
               <p>Roberts. He had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This cap I have on I had of the person that was tried yesterday for stealing the mahogany, I never had it on before.</p>
               <p>Roberts.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be publish'd in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17520219-36">
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 19th, Thursday the 20th, Friday the 21st, Saturday the 22d, Monday the 24th, Tuesday the 25th, and Wednesday the 26th of February.</p>
                  <p>In the 25th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. BEING THE Third SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble 
                  <persName id="t17520219-36-person330">
                     Thomas 
                     Winterbottom 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-36-person330" type="surname" value="Winterbottom"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520219-36-person330" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520219-36-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER III. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Roberts. IT was not that worsted cap he has on, he had on a leather cap when he robbed me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes, I have had a leather cap a great while.</p>
               <p>Roberts. 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person331">
                  James 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person331" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person331" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person332">
                  Alexander 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person332" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person332" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and asked me to describe the man, saying, they had seen such a man drinking at the Wheatsheaf at Kensington: on the 27th 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person333">
                  Alexander 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person333" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person333" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me and told me, he was there then. I went directly, there was the prisoner sitting, I knew him immediately, I left Allen and another man, to keep him safe till I called a constable, who came with me: he was delivered to him, and we took him before a Justice; but he would own nothing; he wished he could have his will of me: there he was searched, but had no arms found upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-36-person334">
                  Alexander 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person334" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person334" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of January, about half an hour after six in the evening, the prisoner was drinking at the Wheatsheaf, where I lodge; he said I must just go a little beyond the court-gate, and I'll return and pay you for the two pints of two-penny; he went, but did not come back that evening; this was on a Friday; on the Saturday morning 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person335">
                  James 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person335" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person335" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into the Wheat-sheaf, and said to me, do you hear of the robbery committed last night, saying, it was Counsellor 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person336">
                  Fleming
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person336" type="given" value="Fleming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's groom, and that the groom had described him by having a blue jacket, a leather cap, a slit in one of his shoes, and one swell'd leg: I went to the groom, and he described him as before-mentioned. I told him, if he'd come with me to the Wheatsheaf, I could produce the man according to his description of him; when we came there, we staid till about ten o'clock; he not coming as usual, we sent the landlord to see if he was in his lodgings ; we found he had paid for his lodgings, but he did not lie there that night; we heard no more of him till the 27th, then I had been at London, and upon my return, I found him sitting in the box under the dial at the Wheat-sheaf, about six o'clock in the evening; then I went and found the prosecutor, and brought him along with me; as soon as he saw him, he said, that is the man; I'll sware to him; then I took him by the hand, and 
               <persName id="t17520219-36-person337">
                  Andrew 
                  Andrea 
               <interp inst="t17520219-36-person337" type="surname" value="Andrea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person337" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             stood behind me while the prosecutor and Bond went for a constable; when he came, we delivered the prisoner to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Allen. I have several and several times in our house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you saw him first ?</p>
               <p>Allen. The first time is about nine weeks ago; I remember he then said he was come from Yarmouth, and had been robbed by a German: I once gave him a pair of old shoes ; he said he was going down to Bristol to his mother; but instead of that he was still in Kensington ; he said after that his mother lived at Reading, and he has been gone sometimes for a fortnight together, and sometimes for a day or two.</p>
               <p>The prisoner bad nothing to say.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520219-36-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520219-36-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-36-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-36-defend327 t17520219-36-punish177"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
