<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560115-29">
               <interp inst="t17560115-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-29" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-29" type="date" value="17560115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560115-29-off137-c288" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-defend346 t17560115-29-off137 t17560115-29-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>91. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560115-29-defend346" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Thornton 
                  <interp inst="t17560115-29-defend346" type="surname" value="Thornton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-defend346" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-defend346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560115-29-off137" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-off137" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-off137" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560115-29-victim348" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Gresham 
                        <interp inst="t17560115-29-victim348" type="surname" value="Gresham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560115-29-victim348" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560115-29-victim348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-off137 t17560115-29-victim348"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>; he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17560115-29-cd138" type="crimeDate">Dec. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-off137 t17560115-29-cd138"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Edward Squires. On a Thursday, but a little time ago, I believe it was in Dec. between 4 and 5 in the evening, I came down into the hall in <placeName id="t17560115-29-crimeloc139">Newgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560115-29-crimeloc139" type="placeName" value="Newgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560115-29-crimeloc139" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-off137 t17560115-29-crimeloc139"></join>; I saw the prisoner at the bar-begging at the grate; he gave a violent push against the deceased 
               <persName id="t17560115-29-person349">
                  Thomas 
                  Gresham 
               <interp inst="t17560115-29-person349" type="surname" value="Gresham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person349" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , without any provocation as I saw. I heard not a word from either of them; the deceased fell on his back, and the back part of his head against the wall; he lay there about ten minutes, and was taken up by one Townshend (belonging to the same ward which he did) who carry'd him to his barrack, where he lay 'till he expired.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the grate when he was there first?</p>
               <p>Squires. I was but can't say the hour he came on to beg.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the prisoner live after this?</p>
               <p>Squires. I believe he lived about 4 or 5 days, but I never heard him speak a word after this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after he was dead?</p>
               <p>Squires. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. How often did you visit him in the time of his illness?</p>
               <p>Squires. Three times.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Don't you know of his receiving a fall before that ?</p>
               <p>Squires. I do not know of a fall before that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-29-person350">
                  Margaret 
                  Smout 
               <interp inst="t17560115-29-person350" type="surname" value="Smout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person350" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down stairs with a candle in my hand, the Thursday before Christmas day. Mr. Thornton was begging at the door, but what he said I cannot tell; I heard nothing said by either just then. Gresham went a few steps from the door and came to it again, and Mr. Thornton gave him a punch in the stomach, and said G - d d - n you get away; the deceased came to it again, then the prisoner came up to the deceased, gave him a push and push'd him down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that push with one hand or both?</p>
               <p>M. Smout. I cannot say; he fell down on his back with his head against the wall.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>M. Smout. He died on Christmas-eve.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after he was dead?</p>
               <p>M. Smout. I saw him when he was laid out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-29-person351">
                  Abraham 
                  Dent 
               <interp inst="t17560115-29-person351" type="surname" value="Dent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person351" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased was a messmate of mine; about a quarter of an hour before he left our ward I had got a pot of beer, he ask'd me to let him drink; he drank, and then went down into the common hall; in about a quarter of an hour, one Townshend, another messmate of ours, and I, were called; we did not know for what, but went into the common hall, where we were told our messmate was lying on his back, and were desired to take care of him; he lay with his head against the wall, and could not speak. I helped him up upon Townshend's back, who carried him to his bed, and laid his body in it with his feet out; in about half an hour after, we heard him groan very much; the last witness's husband said, he did not think it proper to let him lie alone, then we went and put him quite in bed, and covered<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150028"></xptr> him over; we sat up with him that night and try'd to feed him with a pewter spoon, and he bit it almost in two; the next day we try'd the same; the 3d day we sent for Mr. Blackden a surgeon, who came; I had cut the hair from off the back part of the deceased's head, the surgeon lanced the place; there was a great deal of corrupted blood came out. Mr. Akerman came and said he was very sorry we did not let him know of this before; he sent him wine and sack-whey, which I gave him as he wanted it: the day before he died he came to his senses; as I was feeding him with sack-whey, he beg'd I wou'd give him the cup in his own hand, and said, I pray God to restore me to my former health and I'll pray for you; I have something particular to say to you. At that time I was called out; after I came in again, he said, pray sit down, I want to speak to you: then he said, liquor has indeed been my ruin. These were all the sensible words he spoke.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether he had not a fall some time before that in the ward, and lay for dead, and even lost his hearing?</p>
               <p>Dent. He had a fall before that by another man, and never had his hearing till his death; I was present when he had the fall.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before ?</p>
               <p>Dent. That was near a month before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he well recover'd of that?</p>
               <p>Dent. He was, in all respects, except his hearing; he eat and drank, and appeared as usual.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you believe I did it to hurt the man or no?</p>
               <p>Dent. I was not by when it was done, but don't think he intended to hurt him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Blackden. I am a surgeon; on the 22d of December last, a messenger came to me from Newgate, and informed me that a poor debtor had had a fall, and had not spoke-since; I went and found a man lying on his back, senseless and speechless. I found a swelling on the back part of his head, and suspecting the skull to be fractured, laid it open to the skull, and found it fractur'd; I dress'd the part and took my leave of him: this was about 2 in the afternoon. On the Monday I waited on him again about 7 o'clock, and thought him somewhat better. On Tuesday, between 7 and 8 I went again; the person that sat up with him told me he had taken some sack-whey in the night, and had spoke something; I went to him that same evening again, and found him dying.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you take to be the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Blackden. Undoubtedly that fracture on his skull.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend that fracture could be done a month before?</p>
               <p>Blackden. No, it could not; it was a new fracture.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The deceased came down to the gate, calling me ram's-head, goat's-head and buck's-head. I said, Prithee Mr. Gresham, let me alone, if you will not let me alone to beg, beg for yourself. I thought he came with an offer to strike me; I clap'd my hand upon his shoulder and pushed him from me, that he should not strike me. I had no more intention to hurt him than I have to hurt your lordship now; he went from me about 3 or 4 yards, and stagger'd, and fell; if he had not been in liquor he cou'd not have fell.</p>
               <p>Mr. Akerman. I asked the evidences that saw it, they both told me it was not a blow, but a shove. The deceased had but one hand (which I observe the witnesses have not mentioned) or possibly he might have saved the fall.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to Dent. Am I of a quarrelsome disposition, or otherwise ?</p>
               <p>Court. If you can't answer that question without hurting the prisoner, you had better say nothing.</p>
               <p>Dent. I have done, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560115-29-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-verdict140" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560115-29-punish141" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-punish141" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-punish141" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-defend346 t17560115-29-punish141"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560115-29-punish142" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-punish142" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-29-punish142" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-29-defend346 t17560115-29-punish142"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
