<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-21">
               <interp inst="t17541023-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-21" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-21" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-21-off95-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-defend133 t17541023-21-off95 t17541023-21-verdict99"></join>
         
               <p>486. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-21-defend133" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Gentery 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-21-defend133" type="surname" value="Gentery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-defend133" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-defend133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17541023-21-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17541023-21-victim135" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hawkins 
                        <interp inst="t17541023-21-victim135" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-21-victim135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-21-victim135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-off95 t17541023-21-victim135"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and stealing out there two silver watches, val. 6 l.
            </rs> the goods of the said John, <rs id="t17541023-21-cd96" type="crimeDate">Aug. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-off95 t17541023-21-cd96"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-21-person136">
                  John 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17541023-21-person136" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17541023-21-crimeloc97">Middle row, St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-21-crimeloc97" type="placeName" value="Middle row, St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-21-crimeloc97" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-off95 t17541023-21-crimeloc97"></join>; and <rs id="t17541023-21-viclabel98" type="occupation">deal in hardware</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-victim135 t17541023-21-viclabel98"></join>, I lost two silver watches out of my window the last execution day at night; they were taken from off a nail.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watches taken away?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. No, they were both hanging in my window; there was a steel chain to one, and a catgut to the other. I had an occasion to go up stairs, upon which I locked the door and went up, and, at my coming down (not having been gone above two minutes) I found the sash was forced up, and the watches gone, and that some pencils and other things had fallen out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the sash fastened down?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. It was not properly fastened down. I had put in a nail to fasten it down, but it was too little for the gimblet hole. That night I went to justice Fielding's, and advertised the watches, but never heard any thing of them, till irish Ben turned evidence, which was about 6 weeks after. Then I heard one of them was at a pawnbroker's in Chiswell street. The prisoner was taken up; he then owned they had sold the other watch to a Jew in Angel court, Devonshire square. I went there but the Jew was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-21-person137">
                  James 
                  Erwin 
               <interp inst="t17541023-21-person137" type="surname" value="Erwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person137" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Chiswell street, and am a pawnbroker. On the 20th of August, my father and I were in the shop, the prisoner brought this watch, (producing one) and pawned it to my father for two guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Erwin. I have many times, I have known him three years, he had pawned the outside case of this watch to my father on the sixth of Aug. for 3 s. 6 d. and fetched it out in three or four days.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Look at this watch, do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do, this is one of the 2 I lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-21-person138">
                  Benjamin 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17541023-21-person138" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person138" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the justice, there the prisoner had made an information against me for several things.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of taking this watch?</p>
               <p>Harper. I went once to call him, he lodged at one 
               <persName id="t17541023-21-person139">
                  Kate 
                  Horn 
               <interp inst="t17541023-21-person139" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person139" type="given" value="Kate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I asked him to get up, he said he had got a watch in his pocket, marked with two fives and a one; I said, where did you get it? he said in St. Giles's, and after that he said at Hawkins's, at a stick shop in St. Giles's, and shewed me the house, as we were walking that way, and took out a hammer, and said, this is the hammer with which I wrenched the window up.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he tell you this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230009"></xptr>Harper. It was about a week after the last execution.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this watch.</p>
               <p>Harper. He takes it and opens it. This is the same watch, at that time the glass was loose, and he told me it was advertised; that it was advertised in a wrong name. About two days after I asked him if he would sell it, he said, yes, I will; then he asked me to go with him to a pawnbroker, a little man in Chiswell street I went and staid at the door while he went in and pawned it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hawkins. Do you keep a stick shop?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. I have a row of sticks stand for sale at my door.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you value the watch at?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. At 3 guineas, I value them both at six pounds.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Irish Ben told justice Fielding that I got the watch of a suckey cull, please to ask the pawnbroker about it.</p>
               <p>Erwin, to the question. I did hear the evidence say, that the prisoner told him he had it of a suckey cull, and Mr. Fielding said, Ben, what is the meaning of that word? his answer was, he could not tell.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>About three weeks ago I left work about nine at night - and went to the George alehouse, in Broad St. Giles's. I sat drinking there about an hour, going home at the end of Middle Row, a man came pushing against me, and pushed me down. I said, what do you mean by that? he said, don't be angry; I said you are a scoundrol for your pains; he said, let's drink together, so I went with him to drink. In about half an hour after we were there, he pull'd out a watch. I said, what is it o' clock? he said it was about a quarter after 10. I thought it strange to see such a poor ragged man with such a watch. I said to him you'll get yourself in some damage if you are seen with this, for he did not look as if he was used to wear a watch; he was in liquor, he came home with me to my own door; then he said, do you live here? I said yes; then he said, I wish you could help me to a chap for my watch, I said I cannot to night; he said if you'll take care of it I'll come on the morrow, and go along with you and sell it; so he delivered it to me, and I never saw him since, or before. I wore it in my pocket a fortnight.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nash. I am a coachmaker, the prisoner worked with me about 5 weeks, till he was taken up he behaved very well with me.</p>
               <p>Justice Olney. I have known him about fifteen months. I am a coachmaker, he worked with me that time, he behaved extremely well, I never missed any thing the time he was with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What might he earn a week ?</p>
               <p>Olney. He earned a guinea a week.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to part from him?</p>
               <p>Olney. Because business fell off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-21-person140">
                  Thomas 
                  Oliver 
               <interp inst="t17541023-21-person140" type="surname" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person140" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house, I have known him 11 or 12 months, he used my house, he paid honestly and honourably, and behaved very civilly.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hust. I have known him about twelve months, he lodged at my house about half a year, he bore a very honest character, he paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-21-verdict99" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-verdict99" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-verdict99" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-21-punish100" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-21-punish100" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-21-defend133 t17541023-21-punish100"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
