<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-47">
               <interp inst="t17510523-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-47" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-47" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-47-off248-c344" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-47-defend438 t17510523-47-off248 t17510523-47-verdict251"></join>
         
               <p>401. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-defend438" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Byton 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-47-defend438" type="surname" value="Byton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-defend438" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-defend438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17510523-47-off248" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-off248" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-off248" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging an acquittance for the payment of five guineas, to this purport, Receiv'd of Capt. 
                     <persName id="t17510523-47-person439">
                        Henry 
                        Byton 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person439" type="surname" value="Byton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-47-person439" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-47-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   5 l. 5 s. for wages and all other demands, by me, <rs id="t17510523-47-cd249" type="crimeDate">August 30, 1749</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-47-off248 t17510523-47-cd249"></join>, 
                     <persName id="t17510523-47-victim440" type="victimName">
                        Jahn Badesta 
                        Morisca 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-victim440" type="surname" value="Morisca"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-47-victim440" type="given" value="Jahn Badesta"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-47-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-47-off248 t17510523-47-victim440"></join>
                     </persName>
                  ; with intent to defraud
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person441">
                  Francisco 
                  Marisca 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person441" type="surname" value="Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person441" type="given" value="Francisco"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being <rs id="t17510523-47-viclabel250" type="occupation">an Italian</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-47-victim440 t17510523-47-viclabel250"></join>, and not able to speak intelligible English, Solomon Carolina was sworn interpreter.</p>
               <p>F. Marisca. Jahn Badesta-Marisca is my brother; in my own country we are partners, but not here; we have been separate two years. He is shew'd the receipt, &amp;c. This name is not my brother's hand writing, it is not at all like his.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, he did not know when he saw it last, but then he said it was not his brother's writing; it was shewed him by Mr. Long, who came of his own accord and produced it. He had known the prisoner above three years, and came mate from Naples to London; that it was the evidence's own ship; that he had arrested the prisoner for his ship; which is here; that he never sold him his ship, but put him on board only as captain of the flag, that is, to make it an English vessel, and sail under those colours, to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230034"></xptr> protect us from the Algerines ; but that when he came here, he made the evidence sign a thing contrary, as he did not understand the English tongue; that the sailors were to receive their wages from him, not the prisoner, and that the prisoner has never return'd the ship to him; that his brother, the prosecutor, was to receive wages from the prisoner; and that when his brother came to Carolina there was a false assignment made.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person442">
                  Mary 
                  Herne 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person442" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person442" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person442" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She is shew'd the receipt. Look at the name, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>M. Herne. I don't think this is the writing of 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person443">
                  John
                   Badesta Marisca
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person443" type="surname" value="Badesta Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person443" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am acquainted with his hand writing. and have seen him write often; here is a receipt which I saw him write, and here is a note of hand of his. Produc'd in court and compar'd. The prosecutor lodg'd with me in the whole a year and a half.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person444">
                  Andrew 
                  Herne 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person444" type="surname" value="Herne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person444" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am acquainted with John Badesta Marisca's hand writing. He is shewed the receipt. The name here is not his hand writing, or like it.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. How do you write John in Italian?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is wrote Jahn.</p>
               <p>Mr. Long. The first time the prisoner became known to me was on the 9th of September, 1749, when I usually saw him in some mix'd company in a tavern : about a week after that he told me he had been arrested in the borough court by one of his mariners, the prosecutor, for a debt of 25 l. for wages, tho' he owed him nothing, and that he was determined to try the suit; that one 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person445">
                  James 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person445" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person445" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the officer; that he had been arrested for that debt a few days before by the same officer, but had paid it, and got a discharge. I search'd to find where the suit was commenc'd, and found it was in the Marshal's court: soon after there was a Habeas Corpus brought to remove the suit to the King's bench; before bail could be put in, he was arrested for 400 l. upon bond, which he had given to Gayton as a security and a mortgage at the suit of Gayton on the 6th of October, before the term. He sent for me to advise with me what should be done, and disclos'd to me, that the ship had been forcibly taken from out of his custody by the mortgagee: a few days after, a commission of bankruptcy was taken out against him by Gayton. I petitioned for him to my lord chancellor, and it was superseded. There was a neglect to put in bail in the Martial's court, and a procedendo was issued upon that occasion; so he deliver'd to me Guy's receipt, as evidence of the payment of it, upon which I was obliged to have recourse to a bill of equity, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person446">
                  James 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person446" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person446" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I arrested Capt. Byton several times, at the suit of John Badesta Marisca. He is shewed a receipt. This is all my hand writing ; that sum was paid, and I gave him that receipt on the day it bears date, Sept. 4, 1749, it is for 5 l. 9 s. which, with 6 l. 6 s. were paid before in full, from such a time to such a time. The contents mentioned here are true, as far as I know; it was for wages due at that time. It is read.</p>
               <p>Receiv'd of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person447">
                  Henry 
                  Byton 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person447" type="surname" value="Byton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person447" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 4th of Sept. 1749, on account of 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person448">
                  John
                   Badesta Marisca
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person448" type="surname" value="Badesta Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person448" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 5 l. 9 s. which, with 6 l. 6 s. paid to the said 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person449">
                  John Badesta 
                  Marisca 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person449" type="surname" value="Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person449" type="given" value="John Badesta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , is in full for all wages due from the 12th of August, 1748, to the 13th of June, 1749.</p>
               <p>Sign'd, 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person450">
                  James 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person450" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person450" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Long proceeds. The prisoner gave me instructions to file a bill under his hand where the parties lived, in order for subpoena, and likewise so much of his case as was necessary for this bill. In the paper be says, there was money due for wages, and when I came home he arrested me, and I paid him, as by the receipt by 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person451">
                  James 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person451" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person451" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I prepared a bill, sued out the subpoenas, and served them; he takes no notice of any receipt in full of all demands, but observes that Badesta had arrested him for 25 l. for expenses laid out for the ship; to which, says he, I never gave him orders; nor he never did, I declare, but has perjur'd himself by his affidavit. When I had drawn the bill from these instructions, I went to him, and said, if there is no other demand from this man, how came you to take this particular receipt of wages due from such a day to such a day; and likewise told him, if he should swear any other demand, then the bill in chancery would be of no use to him. He said, that that receipt was at his own desire; but, said he, I have a receipt in full besides. Then I told him, it was necessary he should bring me that, for I would not file the bill without it. He was then in prison, it being Hillary term, and the suits on the bail bond, I was forced to bring four writs of error, to prevent the ship and things being taken in execution. I believed the ship to be his own at that time, she being re-delivered by my lord chancellor's order. He was delivered out of prison by me, I think, about the latter end of Feb. and being vacation time I desired he would get me this receipt. (I had great compassion upon him at that time, believing him to be highly injured, and sent him to my house in the country for relief.) I think in the May following he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230035"></xptr> brought me this receipt in question to my house in the country, for my instruction, that discharged him of all demands Marisca had upon him. There was a witness's name to it then: I made this observation to him, how came this to be dated in full the 30th of May, 1749, when this receipt from Guy the officer was dated the 4th of Sept. if you had paid him in full of all demands the 30th of August before? He looked much confounded, and could give no reason. Said I, I observe every word is your own hand writing, as I had seen him write twenty times, i.e. the date and body of it, and I also observed the date to be in different ink, but as to the hand of 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person452">
                  John
                   Badesta Marisca
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person452" type="surname" value="Badesta Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person452" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I knew nothing of it. Then I cast my eye on the witness's name to the receipt, saying, who is this? He answered, he is a man that lived on the other side the water. I desired him to bring him to me, but he told me he was at sea, and he could not tell where. Said I, this is another misfortune, for if this case is tried, you must prove him dead or produce him; and while I was looking at some other papers, he took this note from off my escrutore, and cut off that person's name, saying now here is no witness, here is part of the letter T lost. I reproached him much for it, and told him I never could make use of it, not being in the condition it was when I first saw it; then I had a suspicion of him, and made inquiry, as the other evidences have related.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I leave it all to my council, I have nothing to say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person453">
                  James 
                  Menington 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person453" type="surname" value="Menington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person453" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person454">
                  John Badesta 
                  Marisca 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person454" type="surname" value="Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person454" type="given" value="John Badesta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and have seen him come to the captain and ask him for money, and the captain has let him have money several times ; the ship always went by the name of Capt. Byton's ship. I have known him a little better than three years, and have such confidence in his honesty, that I could trust my life in his hands.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Menington. I have known the captain about three years, he came to lodge at our house, and bore the character of as honest a man as any in the world; he used frequently to be paying money to this Marisca.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-47-person455">
                  Susannah 
                  Farris 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person455" type="surname" value="Farris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person455" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person455" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the captain about five months; my husband was a prisoner in the king's bench with him; about the 3d or 4th of this month 
               <persName id="t17510523-47-person456">
                  John Badesta 
                  Marisca 
               <interp inst="t17510523-47-person456" type="surname" value="Marisca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person456" type="given" value="John Badesta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came there, and asked for the prisoner's landlady. As she did not care to see him, I went to him instead of her, and he told me there, he never should have done this thing, had it not been for Mr. Long: he said also, if Capt. Byton would raise him 50 l. he would go away to France; and that the captain was a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak this in English?</p>
               <p>S. Farris. He did, I heard it from his own mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Is what this evidence relates true?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never spoke a word in English there; I talk'd to a man that was a Greek, and I talk'd in Greek; it was the 27th of April, and I have not been there since that time, neither did I say the prisoner was an honest man. I don't remember I saw this woman there; I saw two women there who said something to me, but I did not answer, neither did I say any thing about 50 l. to the Greek.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-47-verdict251" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-verdict251" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-47-punish252" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-47-punish252" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-47-defend438 t17510523-47-punish252"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
