<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-37">
               <interp inst="t17521206-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-37" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-37" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-37-off183-c237" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-37-defend306 t17521206-37-off183 t17521206-37-verdict187"></join>
         
               <p>44. (M.). 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-defend306" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Lee 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-37-defend306" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-defend306" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-defend306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17521206-37-off183" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-off183" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-off183" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-37-victim308" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Hartley 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim308" type="surname" value="Hartley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim308" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , thirteen 36 shilling-pieces, one guinea, one half guinea, and 50 shillings in money numbered, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-37-victim310" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Waters 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim310" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim310" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-37-victim310" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , widow, in the dwelling house of the said Elizabeth
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-37-cd184" type="crimeDate">November 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-37-off183 t17521206-37-cd184"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Waters. I live in <placeName id="t17521206-37-crimeloc185">Sun-Tavern-Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-37-crimeloc185" type="placeName" value="Sun-Tavern-Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-37-crimeloc185" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-37-off183 t17521206-37-crimeloc185"></join>, the prisoner was recommended to me by a woman as a <rs id="t17521206-37-deflabel186" type="occupation">carpenter and joyner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-37-defend306 t17521206-37-deflabel186"></join>, to mend some houses which I have upon a lease; he was at my house last Friday was se'nnight, between six and seven at night; I went cut and left him there; I believe I d id not stay above a quarter of an hour; and when I return'd I found him where I left him, sitting in a chair; he staid but a little time after, and seem'd to be in a great frustration. He went away and bid me a good night, and ask'd me if I should be at home on the morrow; the next morning, going to get some tea and sugar for breakfast, I miss'd the goods mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose ?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. Thirteen 36 s. pieces, a guinea and a half in gold, and about 50 s. in silver, my property, and a silver watch, value 3 l. 10 s. which was in my custody to sell, the property of 
               <persName id="t17521206-37-person311">
                  William 
                  Hartly 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person311" type="surname" value="Hartly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person311" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; they were in a wooden box together on the top of my drawers, in my parlour; the box was not taken away, but the things were taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them last?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. I told it over the morning before. My kinsman 
               <persName id="t17521206-37-person312">
                  Jacob 
                  Shipton 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person312" type="surname" value="Shipton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person312" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came, and I told him I had lost all I had in the world; and that I told it yesterday morning; I said it must be the prisoner, and gave him a shilling to go in pursuit of him: he was taken on Friday last at the Red Lion, by Pelican Stairs. At first he denied knowing any thing of either watch or money; then I desired he might be search'd, and there was found upon him one 36 s. piece, half a guinea, and 12 s. in silver. After some time he confess'd that he did the fact; at first he said a milkwoman had taken the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this ?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. This was before we went to the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he confess?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. He confess'd that he took the money and watch, that he had hid them on the top of the teaster of his bed; and if I would forgive him he'd send for them; I sent, and there were found ten 36 s. pieces, half a guinea, 12 s. in silver, and the watch; they are here in the hands of the constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Who heard this his confession?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. Mr. Tetherly, Jacob Shipton, and another man; he said he had spent the rest, which is about 10 l. in four days.</p>
               <p>Court. If you have as much back again as you mention, there is not 10 l. missing.</p>
               <p>E. Waters. He said he had a great deal of money besides.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you promise to forgive him upon his confessing it ?</p>
               <p>E Waters. I did not promise him, if he'd confess I would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060024"></xptr>Q. from the prisoner. Did not she promise me, if I'd pay her the sum of 19 l. she'd give me no farther trouble, before the three evidences?</p>
               <p>E. Waters. I said I'd forgive him, but I did not say I'd not prosecute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-person313">
                  John 
                  Knot 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person313" type="surname" value="Knot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person313" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the prisoner, and was by when he confessed he took the money and watch; we sent for it by one 
               <persName id="t17521206-37-person314">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person314" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner said to him, if he'd go and look upon the teaster of the bed, he would find nine 36 shilling pieces. He had one found in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prosecutrix promise not to prosecute him?</p>
               <p>Knot. I heard no such word.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-person315">
                  William 
                  Knot 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person315" type="surname" value="Knot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person315" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came to the prisoner just after he was taken, and heard him confess he took the money out of the prosecutrix's house; there were nine 36 shilling pieces and the watch fetched from off the head of the bed; he had another 36 shilling piece, a half guinea, and 12 shillings in silver found upon him. He desired she would make it up with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she promise him not to prosecute him?</p>
               <p>Knot. She said she would not hurt him if she had her money again, nor prosecute him in any shape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-person316">
                  Jacob 
                  Shipton 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person316" type="surname" value="Shipton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person316" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the prisoner was taken ; I heard him confess, and was one of the men that went for the money as he directed; we found nine 36 shilling pieces on the bed's teaster at a house in St. Catharine's, Wapping. 
               <persName id="t17521206-37-person317">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person317" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person317" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she promise she'd not prosecute him, if he'd confess, in your hearing?</p>
               <p>Shipton. She promised him she'd not hurt a hair of his head if he'd confess, and said she'd not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-person318">
                  Arthur 
                  Fetherly 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person318" type="surname" value="Fetherly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person318" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer, and was concerned in taking the prisoner; we were directed to the house where he lodged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him confess?</p>
               <p>Fetherly. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make him any promise beforehand?</p>
               <p>Fetherly. She said, before he confessed, if she could have her money again, she would not hurt a hair of his head, which she repeated to him several times; I had a search-warrant and searched his chest, where I saw many good things, but he was not there then; I said, no doubt but the man will come again, for he'll not leave these things. Presently he came into the house, so I took him into custody and had him some hours ; when he confessed he produced what he had about him and sent for the rest; he had one 36 shilling piece, and they brought nine more, which are here. He produces ten 36 shilling pieces, one half guinea, and twelve shillings in silver.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was recommended to the prosecutrix to court and marry her by an acquaintance of her's, and was entertained by her with all manner of acceptance as such; I was in the house from time to time, and did several odd jobbs for her about the house. Ask her, whether she did not deliver that watch to me on the 9th of December when we had a rabbit for dinner, as a token of love.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutrix. You hear what the prisoner says; what say you to it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He never proposed such a thing; he never made love to me, neither did I ever give him a watch. He was recommended to me as a shipcarpenter and joiner. The first day I ever saw him he was talking he wanted to buy a watch, and this watch being given into my care to sell, I shewed it him, but he only wound it up and delivered it to me again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask the constable what she said in his hearing about my courting her.</p>
               <p>Constable to the question. When I had him in custody the prosecutrix was asked, whether ever he put the question to her about marriage, and she said, no; but at last she said, I told him if he was a man suitable to my years, I should like him very well.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say about the watch?</p>
               <p>Constable. She said she gave the watch to him to wind it up; then I ask'd her whether she received it again of him, she said yes.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-37-person319">
                  Stephen 
                  Sprigg 
               <interp inst="t17521206-37-person319" type="surname" value="Sprigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person319" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the public-house where the prisoner was in custody, I heard the prosecutrix say to him, if she could have her money back again she would not hurt a hair of his head; she desired the people to speak to him and tell him the same; I spoke to him myself, and told him the same words, after which I left them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-37-verdict187" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-verdict187" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-37-punish188" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-37-punish188" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-37-defend306 t17521206-37-punish188"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
