<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520625-51">
               <interp inst="t17520625-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-51" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-51" type="date" value="17520625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520625-51-off219-c300" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend388 t17520625-51-off219 t17520625-51-verdict222"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520625-51-off219-c301" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend390 t17520625-51-off219 t17520625-51-verdict222"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520625-51-off219-c302" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend392 t17520625-51-off219 t17520625-51-verdict221"></join>
         
               <p>383, 384, 385. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-defend388" type="defendantName">
                     Moses 
                     Moravia 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend388" type="surname" value="Moravia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend388" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-defend390" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Manoury 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend390" type="surname" value="Manoury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend390" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-defend392" type="defendantName">
                     Solomon 
                     Carolina 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend392" type="surname" value="Carolina"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend392" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-defend392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17520625-51-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               conspiring together (with 
                     <persName id="t17520625-51-person393">
                        Samuel 
                        Wilson 
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person393" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-51-person393" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-51-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , since dead) to procure 
                     <persName id="t17520625-51-person394">
                        John 
                        Misson 
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person394" type="surname" value="Misson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-51-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-51-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , master of the ship Elizabeth and Martha, to sink and destroy the said ship with intent to defraud the insurers
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520625-51-cd220" type="crimeDate">December 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-off219 t17520625-51-cd220"></join>. *</p>
               <p>James Lundin. I have been a seaman 27 or 28 years. John Misson came to me July or August last, and asked me if I would be concerned in part of his vessel ; I said I was not in a capacity so to do; he then said, in case I could get any money he'd give me a bill of sale for half of her, and make it of a larger value than the whole vessel, which he did; it was made in the fleet to me with my giving a note of hand to Misson for so much money whenever I got it to repair her. Then one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person395">
                  Isaac 
                  Kendal 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person395" type="surname" value="Kendal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person395" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for he knew which way to raise money upon it. He brought me acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person396">
                  John 
                  Manoury 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person396" type="surname" value="Manoury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person396" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this Kendal ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person397">
                  John 
                  Kendal 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person397" type="surname" value="Kendal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person397" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             worked in the India house in the warehouse. I gave this bill of sale to him ; the note which I gave Misson was for 44 l. I have the receipt here. Kendal told me some time after that I was to meet 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person398">
                  John 
                  Manoury 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person398" type="surname" value="Manoury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person398" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the Cock upon Ludgate Hill, who would shew me how to raise money. I saw him the next day at ten o'clock there, which was the second time I ever saw him; (the first time I saw him he was detected in stealing an anchor) he told me he must first see the vessel before he could raise money, and then he would endeavour to raise money soon. The vessel was then at Woolwich taking in sugar to bring up to the Keys as a lighter. She made three voyages in the time he was consulting with Wilson in Tower-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I saw him go into Wilson's house, and he shewed me Wilson, but I did not go in with him. After he came out he said he'd go and see the vessel, after which Mr. Wilson will tell me how to proceed, and then I will let you know whether he will advance money or not. When the vessel came up to the custom-house key and was delivered of her cargoe, Manoury went on board her; he viewed her and said she was a very fit vessel for some purpose which he would let me know when we came to be farther acquainted. The vessel was carried to Mr. Horn's Way according to Manoury's directions, to be repaired. After that he said to Mission and me, I'll soon show you a person that will direct you how to get money, and said, make an inventory of what is building, make it larger than the things that are on board. He made one, which came to 120 l. (the builder did not know but there were all the materials, but in fact they were not half made use of.) He carried<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250023"></xptr> it to Wilson's ; then he left me without the door. After this, Manoury brought an order from Mr. Wilson for Mr. Horne to repair her; I went with him. He told Horne, in my hearing, he was a grocer in Tower street, and he would pay him. Misson, Manoury and I were once at the Bell in Tower street, Manoury there said, gentlemen, if you'll not discover a secret.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Lundin. This was the latter part of Aug. or the beginning of Sept. I can't be particular as to the day of the month or the week. After Manoury had drank a little plentifully (he at such times is not close minded) he discovered the whole secret, he told us that he would get a charter party drawn up, and after that a bill of sale made, and Mr. Horne had valued her at 120 l. which was to be put up at 6 to the half. His first proposal was to ensure her in Holland, saying there is no danger, they can't try us there for any fault if we are in England, After that he got a charter party drawn up in 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person399">
                  Moses 
                  Moravia 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person399" type="surname" value="Moravia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person399" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's name.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him draw it up?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I did not, but he said he did. The inventory is shewn him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know this?</p>
               <p>Lundin. This is the inventory; here is Mr. Horse's name at the bottom.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Manoury's hand writing?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I do; the agreement for a charter party, (looking on it) is Manoury's hand writing, I am a witness to it, it is signed 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person400">
                  John 
                  Manoury 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person400" type="surname" value="Manoury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person400" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person401">
                  Richard 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person401" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person401" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After which a charter party was prepared, I did not see him write it; he brought it to the Bell alehouse. Mr. Greenwood that keeps the alehouse witnessed it. This was afterwards consulted, as there is an act of parliament, that no vessel under 70 Ton shall take in tobacco and snuff, for which reason Manoury contrived to get liberty to touch at Cork, for the act says, none shall carry tobacco, except to Ireland. &amp;c. After this was consulted the names were torn off. The next step was they cleared her out from the custom house for Cork and Gibraltar. Then they proceeded to have her put up upon the Change, as a general ship to make things look well. This Moravia and Manoury proposed at the Bell alehouse, it was likewise talked of at Wilson's two houses in Tower street, and at Moravia's own house in Sep. All of us talked of this matter, that we would clear her out as a general ship, and put her up upon Change.</p>
               <p>Q. Who proposed it first ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Moravia proposed it first; Manoury said that is a very artful man, and readily agreed to what he had said.</p>
               <p>Q. How often might you have meetings with Moravia and Manoury before your lading was put on board ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Very often, most days, sometimes two or three times a day.</p>
               <p>Q. From the whole conversation, do you believe Moravia understood this scheme of Manoury's?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Yes, he did. Moravia desired me to call at his house one morning, and said Manoury had been with him at his house in Aliff street, No 5, and told him if we would carry on the affair in sinking the Elizabeth and Martha he'd make it as good as 300 l. to Misson and me. I told him I would not do it, but I would keep the secret. Then on or about that time there was notice given of the first fifty pound note given, to borrow money on 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person402">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person402" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person402" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's credit, Manoury wrote it out, to purchase one half of the vessel of Misson. Misson signed it, Wilson accepted it, and I endorsed it. There were four notes in all, three of them for fifty pound, and one for fifty five, all signed by Misson, all accepted by Wilson, and one hundred pounds paid by Wilson. They were drawn payable to me. One Mr. Johnson a clerk in the India house, living near me, he lent me fifty pound on 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person403">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person403" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person403" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's credit upon one of them, which he received when due. I received also one hundred pounds of 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person404">
                  Joseph 
                  Nicholson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person404" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person404" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which he received of Wilson when it was due; and for the other Wilson paid me. I received another of Mr. Hucks, a cooper. The first fifty pound was to pay Misson for one half of the vessel, and the second fifty was to pay for the other half; then all was Wilson's property entirely. The third fifty pound was given to Moravia by order of 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person405">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person405" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person405" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and paid to him with my notes; I have general receipts from Wilson. Moravia said he had got some clothes to come on board, and he had not money enough so he had the fifty pound to pay for them. The fifty five pound was in this form, as the vessel had been a long time sitting out: it was ordered to give twelve pound to Manoury, which was done accordingly, and the rest betwixt Misson and I for my labour and some little frivolous bills and other things that we wanted.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that 12 l. given to Manoury for?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I suppose for his time, and being in the secrecy of this conspiracy. We were to deliver all our property to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person406">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person406" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person406" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was to have all. Misson and I at our coming home were to have to the amount of 240 or 50 pounds between us, in case the vessel was destroyed and sunk.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250024"></xptr>Q. Who proposed that?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Wilson, Moravia, and Manoury did; that there should be a half part police given to Misson, and a quarter part to me to keep the secret, and Manouty was to go with us, which he did a great part of the way.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had you on board?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There was 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person407">
                  John 
                  Kepling 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person407" type="surname" value="Kepling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             part of the time she lay in the river. We had locks to the hatchway, he generally kept the key; he was to take care of the hatchway and receive the goods, but he knew nothing of our secret. He took on board 33 barrels, which we called snuff, from Moravia's, but by the head of one of these casks of snuff tumbling out, when it was in the hold, it appeared to be dust; I believe it had been snuff, but then it was good for nothing. There were 4 bales put on board, marked 1. S. No from 1 to 7. on the 3d of Oct. to the best of my remembrance. Wilson and Moravia said, if we would reland those bales and boxes, they would give to Manoury. Misson and I 12 l. each for so doing; he said they were his property. Wilson generally threw it upon Moravia.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you reland them?</p>
               <p>Lundin. We did. Manoury came with an order, as he pretended, from Wilson, for 3 boxes, which he said was to pay one of those 50 l. notes, that was become almost due. Kepling was then on board, and Manoury desired me to send him out of the vessel to look for Misson, which I did. When he was gone I said to Manoury these goods will be detected by the custom-house officers. Said he, I'll say they are for 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person408">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person408" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person408" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Tower street, he is a man in great repute, church-warden of the parish ; and he said, if I tell any man that, they will really pass. After which there came an order wrote by Manoury, and signed by Misson, for me to deliver 3 of these bales to a waterman; they were safe at Ratcliff highway, as I heard Manoury say, and carried to Wilson's or Manoury's, I can't say which. I know nothing of what became of them afterwards. Wilson and Manoury went and conversed together, after which there were brought in a waterman's boat on board the vessel three other boxes, about the same bigness with the mark and number, I think, 5, 6, and 7, I. S. on them, as those had before, by Wilson's servants; Wilson said Moravia will give you the 12 guineas for so doing. I heard Manoury give orders to Wilson's servants to fill them up with brickbats and rubbish. They were put into the cabin and locked in, that Kepling might not go down to take any notice for fear of a blow. Wilson seemed very angry when I went there one day, saying, I wonder Moses does not get the bales on shore, they seem to trifle with me, and that he would take the vessel from Misson if the bales were not relanded soon. Misson came on board with a waterman, and cut the package of the fourth bale and took out ten pieces of cloth and carried them to Wilson's tallow-warehouse. Wilson bid us call at Moravia's, and we should be satisfied for our trouble, for they were about pawning these goods to raise money. We went to Moravia the latter end of Nov. or the beginning of Dec. and we received 12 l. each. When I came first to Wilson's house he desired me to go to Moravia's, in the mean time came Misson, so he desired us both to go and tell him one of the boxes had been stopped in a case by the searcher. Moravia seemed uneasy at it when we told him, so likewise was Wilson before he sent us, fearing: the thing should be discovered. Moravia desired us to go and inquire for Manoury, because he could rectify things better than they. Moravia dined at Misson's house on the Sunday, and I with him; he said then to Manoury I know how to manage that affair, and desired we would come up to the Bell alehouse the Monday following. I did; there they all consulted together what to do; there was Wilson, Manoury, Moravia, and my self. Moravia insisted upon going to the custom-house: Manoury said you must not go down to appear about these goods, saying, his character was too bad and would cause a suspicion. Said he, endeavour to get a man of clear character to own them, and he must say he had bought them of a gentleman that had defrauded him, and he'd return them from whence they came; then perhaps the searchers will take no farther notice, and which will cause no suspicion. That was resolved upon by Moravia, Manoury and Wilson, they mentioned several names that I have forgot; at last they mentioned 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person409">
                  Solomon 
                  Carolina 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person409" type="surname" value="Carolina"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person409" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I had never seen him in my life. Then they said he had a clear character, and was not known in any scenes of villasny, as Moravia was known to have been guilty of. Carolina came first to the Bell alehouse, and then went on the key and claimed the box. He said the man he bought those goods of had defrauded him, for he thought the whole quantity of stockings were in the box which he bought. A gentleman at the custom-house told me it was some die, but Manoury said it was only sawdust of wood. One Butler, a waterman, had them to carry on board.</p>

               <p>Q. What became of them?</p>
               <p>Lundin. They never came on board to my knowledge; I saw some Guernsey stockings of little or<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250025"></xptr> no value on board; they were moth-eaten, and Manoury said they were of no value, we need not take them out again. Manoury got credit with paying some money that he got upon Wilson's note from one Evans in White-chapel for 31 l. worth of stockings, which were brought down in two boxes to Wilson's tallow-warehouse ; he opened the boxes and pawned some of them by the Tyger in Tower street, the rest went on board as a venture of Manoury's, marked J. M. No. 1 and 2. The next thing that Manoury ship'd was a cask of rhubarb, so called at London; it was a large wine pipe from Moravia.</p>
               <p>Q. What cargoe was shipped in Manoury's name?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There were some shipp'd in his own name, and some in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person410">
                  George 
                  Stannerd 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person410" type="surname" value="Stannerd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person410" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Manoury asked Stannerd, in my hearing, to make him 4 ton of cordage upon Wilson's credit; he stammered and said, I am not in circumstances to make so large a quantity, I shall make no more than I think to send on board your ship as a venture, as you say you can bring it to so good a market. He shipped 23 coyles.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any application made to Wilson to see how much you were to have for your reward?</p>
               <p>Lundin. The policies and every thing were to be lodged in Wilson's hand till we came home. Wilson referred us to Manoury, saying, what he said he would stand by. We all met, Moravia, Misson, Manoury and I at Wilson's house, there our proportions were ascertained, the lotment was thus; Misson to have a half part of a policy, which is under wrote by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person411">
                  Samuel 
                  Touchet 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person411" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person411" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , delivered to him upon the destruction of the vessel, and I was to have a quarter part. Wilson kept one quarter part in his own possession; the whole insurance was 280 l. and one 150 l. Wilson's policy was 80 l. that 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person412">
                  Samuel 
                  Touchet 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person412" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person412" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             under wrote. The bill of sale that was made to me was for 80 l.</p>
               <p>There were 257 l. 10 s. in all of which 100 l. is paid.</p>
               <p>The bill of sale - 80 l.</p>
               <p>20 l. upon goods made it - 100 l.</p>
               <p>The policy of 150 l. the half part of the vessel.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went in her when she sailed from London ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There was a waterman went down with us the 14th of Dec. from Dick's shore, Limehouse, and a boy named Robins, and one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person413">
                  George 
                  Lilley 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person413" type="surname" value="Lilley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person413" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with dogs, some trunks and boxes; Misson, myself, and one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person414">
                  William 
                  Maciver 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person414" type="surname" value="Maciver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person414" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a passenger.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person415">
                  George 
                  Lilley 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person415" type="surname" value="Lilley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person415" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I don't know. He went to Bristol with the dogs to get a voyage ; we staid at Gravesend for Manoury's coming, he had the whole direction and management of every thing. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person416">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person416" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person416" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Moravia said he knew how to do things in a better manner than either of us. He appeared as a passenger and to have cargoe on board as a merchant to Cork. He broke bulk at Gravesend, and sold 7 or 8 dozen of stockings to one Mr. Blake. He went from thence to London, and ordered us to put in at Sheerness and wait his coming. We got there in 2 or 3 days; he came on board and took out a pretty many doz, of the same stockings, which he called his own, and sold there. He said it is unnecessary, as we know the design we go upon, to link any thing of value in the vessel, let us make as much money as we can. One coile of cordage was carried on shore at Queenborough, and he said to me, you being mate of the vessel must say it is a little venture of yours. I gave the receipt for the money made of it, and it was divided among us 3, Manoury, Misson and I. Manoury said on board I think the safest way to destroy the vessel, and not to endanger our lives would be to buy some pitch and tar, and get some ignorant man on board, and we will put some nastiness in the pitch pot and say some quantity of pitch near and she'll take fire, and that will recover the money the same; so there were some bought by his directions. We shipped another hand at Gravesend, one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person417">
                  Tho 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person417" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person417" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for Helping was discharged at London by Manoury's orders. When we were in the Downs Manoury ordered a vessel of strong beer to be got up, the property of a gentleman in London. There were 20 of them to be broached in the hatchway, saying it was his property, telling the innocent man the carpenter, he was a merchant bound for Cork, he passed for the owner of the greatest part of the cargoe. We went into Dover pier ; there Manoury went to an acquaintance of his, one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person418">
                  Robt 
                  Kinshin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person418" type="surname" value="Kinshin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person418" type="given" value="Robt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was a barrel of stinking anchovies and some cheese, which he carried to him, and he shipped the 13 coils of cordage which we had on board a ship going to Wales. Moravia came to Dover to us, he had a consultation with us at 2 different houses; there his pretence was to go over to France to take the benefit of an insolvent act; the chief of his intent was to take in more ballast. We have on board 7 or 8 ton from off the wharf on the top of our cargoe, that she might surely go down; he hoped he would not do as Cowey did, who undertook to sink a ship (wherein he was before concerned,) that rose up in judgment against him, by which means he lost 5000 guilders. We had taken 7 ton of ballast before, at London, by his directions. There were some watches brought down by Misson to pawn,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250026"></xptr> the property of a gentleman in London; the gentleman has them again. We had twelve chests of tea. Moravia said, you had better go over to Guernsey and dispose of that there; the others said it would make a blow if that was done, that it was a bulky commodity, we had better let the rabarb, that is not worth 40 s. and the tea sink together in the vessel. We went from Dover to Stokes Bay ; when we came there a little boy (one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person419">
                  William 
                  Robins 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person419" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person419" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was by Manoury's directions, discharged, saying he was an artful cunning boy, and he might discover things if he was continued on board. There was a case brought on deck and opened by Misson and Manoury, which were snipped as cambricks on board ; (it was set in the after hatchway on the top of all, there are three hatchways to the vessel) this was carried on shore and sold to one Mr. Briant at Portsmouth ; and also a cheese was given to the gentleman by the direction of Manoury. I received part of the money; Misson and Manoury had the rest. Manoury sold all his stockings, some at Portsmouth, and some he brought to London; I saw them in his house where he lived in the upper part of Rosemary-lane. There was nothing belonging to him in the vessel but a bed, which is all he lost for his 300 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep a journal ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the wind when you went into Stokes-Bay ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Then we had a fair wind; Manoury said, instead of that, put it W. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person420">
                  N.
                   W. 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person420" type="surname" value="W."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person420" type="given" value="N."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person420" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            &amp;c. for the gentlemen at London ( the under-writers) that sit in their white lined chambers, don't know how the wind lies at sea. He went to Portsmouth by land from Stokes-Bay two or three times ; there he left us, and said, what is the reason you don't go on board? I'll not go on board to indanger my life, for Misson must destroy her now to compleat his bills of laying, for he will have nothing to shew at Cork of any value when he comes there. The next port we were at was Cowes, where were some pieces of cambrick sent on shore and sold. Manoury got no part of that money. When the wind came fair at Cowes we proceeded to do as Manoury had directed Misson in my hearing in Stokes-Bay. If in case he would not give consent to set her on fire, said he, I believe your best method will be to take a crow and go down into the lower scuttle, (there were two good crows on board) and get the sharpest pointed and heaviest, and endeavour in the after part of the vessel to cut the double of the vessel up, and then to drive the crow plum through, so as to make many holes to let the water in, will do it as well as with an augur. When we went from Cowes we had a saint wind, and were from the Start the next morning a little to the eastward of Plymouth. Misson endeavoured to get all the people to the forecastle that he might do it. I heard him try at it, but he could not do it with the crow. Then we went into Catwater at Plymouth, pretending the ship had sprung a leak; our intent was to get an augur and gimlet to make holes in the ship. There Misson bought an inch and quarter augur, and a large gimlet which would follow it; he had it lengthened by a smith to go between the timbers, with which he bored six or seven holes; he bought two sir-mop-sticks, which he cut in pieces for plugs, that I saw him make. We were all on shore when he bored the holes in the bottom of the vessel. We hauled her on shore at Cutwater, pretending to look for a leak, for him to do it. When the wind permitted, we proceeded. We had not been many hours from Plymouth, nor above two or three leagues from shore, the wind at E. S. E. but there he pulled out the plugs, and she was not above 15 or 20 minutes before she sunk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the holes after they were bored?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I saw the plugs in the holes, there were six or seven of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when he pulled out the plugs ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I was at the helm, he pulled them out at once. The carpenter was boiling some victuals at the fire, he knew nothing of the affair; he came up and said the vessel had sprung a leak. Then we pretended to get the pumps to work. Presently up came the dogman, who was affrighted and jumped into the boat ; he endeavoured to get the casks or boxes that he had, and dogs into the boat, which he did, and they were carried safe. We also got a sail into the boat; we got to shore in our boat and went to a little village to the westward of Foy in Cornwall, from thence to Foy to make protest to a notary-publick ; then we came to Plymouth, and so to London.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there an oath made to your protest?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There was, but not at Foy. At London we applied to 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person421">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person421" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person421" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Moravia, and Manoury. Wilson would have the protest in his own hand, on purpose to recover some cloaths that he had bought of one Mr. Whitwood, as he said, Wilson and Moravia desired it might be delivered to them. Manoury scrupled that, being jealous of them. I got a copy of it and delivered it to Misson ; then they trifled with him,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250027"></xptr> and would not give the policy nor bill of sale into Misson's hand till they were sure of it. Misson and I threatened to make a blow of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you together on this affair?</p>
               <p>Lundin It was in Wilson's warehouse. Wilson, Moravia, and Manoury asked us, is the vessel sunk ? Moravia said, I hore you have not done as Cowey did. They asked us if we saw her sink, or if we were sure she sunk. Misson said, I saw her mast-head go under water, and she never will rise again, except the world turns upside down. The policy that I had was in an innocent man's hands, a friend of mine, and I had nothing to shew for it till I had a bill of sale from them; then Manoury filled up my bill of sale.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Caroline.</p>
               <p>Q. The only time you heard Carolina's name mentioned was about the stockings?</p>
               <p>Lundin. It was in order to recover them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the persons they mentioned, before Carolina was named, honest persons?</p>
               <p>Lundin. They were for what I know.</p>
               <p>Q. I think he was proposed to own the stockings as being a man of a clear character, was it so?</p>
               <p>Lundin. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. With what intent was he to own them?</p>
               <p>Lundin. That he might return them from whence they came.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they returned?</p>
               <p>Lundin. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Carolina any benefit by them?</p>
               <p>Lundin. No, not as I know of.</p>
               <p>For Manoury.</p>
               <p>Q. from Manoury's counsel. Do you know of any goods shipped on board that vessel, belonging to any person in the fleet?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There were five boxes; they were shipped from the fleet a little before the vessel failed.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the person's name?</p>
               <p>Lundin. His name was Coulestock; I never saw him in my life, I only know by seeing the name wrote.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Kendal ship any thing on board that ship?</p>
               <p>Lundin. He had some boxes, but what was in them I never saw.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you receive a letter from the fleet?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There was one signed A. B. from Mr. Badge; I have known him some time; the contents of it was wishing me a good voyage and well.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any others that shipped any thing on board?</p>
               <p>Lundin. There was one Shirley shipped a parcel of plate on board.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never declare any intention you had of sinking th is ship before the first time you saw Manoury ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. No, never in my life till I was acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or no, before you knew him, you did not persuade people to put goods on board the vessel?</p>
               <p>Lundin. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever declare you was to have 500 l. to give your evidence here?</p>
               <p>Lundin. I have said to people that came to trouble me (to make them easy, and myself too in my confinement ) that I was promised 500 l. but it was all false, for I never had a promise of any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the secret at the Bell alehouse, that was there divulged ?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Manoury said, that as the vessel was in bad repair we'll get her repaired on Wilson's credit, and held soon contrive means how to get money.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the secret?</p>
               <p>Lundin. It was about sinking the vessel.</p>
               <p>Q. Was mention made of sinking her at the first meeting?</p>
               <p>Lundin. No, it was after two or three meetings</p>
               <p>Q. Where were you when it was first mentioned</p>
               <p>Lundin. At the Bell in Tower-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person422">
                  John 
                  Kepling 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person422" type="surname" value="Kepling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person422" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a seaman; I was on board the Elizabeth and Martha ship, Misson was commander; I went on board the first of December. 50, and belonged to her twelve months and three days.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember there were four bales of goods brought on board that vessel?</p>
               <p>Kepling. I do; they were marked J. S. No. 1, 2, 3, 4. There were also three boxes J. S. No. 5, 6, 7.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of them bales?</p>
               <p>Kepling. Three of them were delivered to one 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person423">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person423" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person423" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a waterman, to be landed again; the largest of the four was left on board. The waterman said he was going to carry the three bales to Radcliff-Cross, and that he came from the captain for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who used to keep the key of the hatchway?</p>
               <p>Kepling. I mostly had that; I used to be on board alone. I remember Lundin came on board, and I was sent on shore to see for Misson, and Lundin ordered me to leave the key of the hatchway with him, which I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250028"></xptr>Q. Had Manoury used to come on board?</p>
               <p>Kepling. He had, sometimes once and sometimes twice in a week.</p>
               <p>Q When was you discharged from the ship?</p>
               <p>Kepling. I was discharged on the third of December last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person424">
                  Thomas 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person424" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person424" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I served part of my time to a ship carpenter, and was shipped on board this ship the Elizabeth and Martha at Sheerness on Saturday the 20th of December; I was shipped on shore and carried on board at night; I saw only a boy there; in the morning I saw Manoury; after we were under sail he went down to Dover with us, where we took in some ballast at the Pier, the mate said there were about seven or eight tons of it, which was flung upon the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Manoury give any directions about it?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, I did not. We got in the Downs that night. He went as far as Stokes-Bay with us; there was some cordage taken out in Dover-Pier, which was carried in a boat by Manoury's order; he said he had an order out of the custom-house. There were many coils of it carried on board a Welch sloop. There were also two horses, or small boats cables, went I believe the day before, or the same day Manoury left us at Portsmouth; I can't exactly say what day. We lay in Stokes-Bay I believe three or four days.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the wind at going in!</p>
               <p>Salmon. They said the wind was not fair; I am no great judge of it. Two or three days after that we failed into Limmington-Creek. Manoury was to have come to us there. Misson went on shore to look for him, but he did not come. After we had lain there a day or two there came a little fair wind, so we got our anchor up for Ireland, and just as we came by the Needles the wind blew very hard; the mate said to Misson, don't let us go out, it will be all our deaths. We sailed back again to Cowes, and from thence to Plymouth to stop a leak; she was pretty leaky ; we pumped her in Stokes-Bay, where we staid five or six days; I stopped the leak as well as I could; we came to anchor by the side of a custom-house sloop. From thence we went out to proceed on our voyage ; we pumped her when she went out of Catwater ; she made little or no water then. We had not been at sea above four or five hours before she sunk.</p>

               <p>Q. How many leagues were you got?</p>
               <p>Salmon. I am no judge of that. The mate said to the master, at twelve at noon, go to sleep, I'll call you at four o'clock. The mate said to me, Tom, go and look after the kettle; we had a pudding and a piece of meat boiling; I went according to his order. There was a passenger, a gentleman's servant, on board. As I was looking after the kettle I thought I heard a great crack as if it had been a breaking of a cask in the hold. Presently, Lord God, said the passenger, what is the matter? there I saw the water just in the platform of the forecastle; I jumped up to the foremast pump; said the mate, what is the matter? I replied, here is water in the forecastle ; I believe there were about four or five feet water. While we were pumping the water put the fire out; then the master said it was time to take to the boat. The gentleman's servant and Misson got their trunks into the boat. Said the master to the young man, as you have been to sea before, you know the affairs of the sea, if you don't save something that is in the vessel you'll have no wages, lend me your knife, so they cut the mainsail and took it into the vessel; we got into the boat, and in about four or five minutes we saw her go down with her crotchet-brace and jib up.</p>
               <p>Manoury. The master and mate had some words; the master was for going back to Dover, and I hoisted a flag of distress up. I reconciled them as well as I could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person425">
                  William 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person425" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person425" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was shipped the day the ship went away from London at Limehouse; the captain and mate were at the Tyger on Tower-Dock; I saw Manoury there at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any cordage carried on shore, and where?</p>
               <p>Roberts. There were 12 or 13 coils carried on shore at Dover; there we took in some more ballast, which was put on the top of the casks.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you discharged?</p>
               <p>Roberts. I was discharged at Portsmouth.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be discharged then?</p>
               <p>Roberts. Because they thought I would blow them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear them say so?</p>
               <p>Roberts. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person426">
                  John 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person426" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person426" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a factor for the west-country clothiers ; I had some dealings with Moravia in September last, for 26 or 27 pieces of cloth, value upwards of 300 l. with which I made him a bill of parcels. [He is shewn a bill of parcels, and says it is the same he gave Manoury; it is his partner's writing.] After he had satisfied him for them, my servant delivered them to the packer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your servant?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. He is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen any of the pieces of cloth since ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250029"></xptr>Whitehead. No, I have not. One Mr. Sherrard told me he had such a number of pieces in his house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person427">
                  Joseph 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person427" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person427" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a packer; I received 27 pieces of cloth of Mr. Whitehead; I was to measure them over between Mr. Whitehead and Manoury, then to put them in the press and pack them. I did 26 of them, there were 30 in all; there were eight in two packs, and ten in another, and four Yorkshires. I packed up 26, one went to Manoury's house.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they marked?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. They were marked J. S. in four several bales; they came and put the numbers on them the day they were shipped, and fetched them away in a cart. Mr. Moravia's clerk (Carolina) came and paid the carman, then went away, and said he should be at the water-side as soon as the carman was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person428">
                  Joseph 
                  Littlepear 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person428" type="surname" value="Littlepear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person428" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Moravia; I sold him some hardware, watches, and snuff-boxes, in October last for 250 l. [He produces the bill of parcels.] The goods were packed up in three boxes; I don't remember the marks now, but I think they were J. S. my man marked them, and I think the numbers on them were 5, 6, and 7. There were also other boxes packed up in these boxes, and an old repeating-watch along with them; I think there was a little parcel which he called Bezoar-stone, packed up also in those boxes. The boxes were sent down to the Key according to the order of Moravia, I think to the goldsmiths porters. Moravia applied to me after the ship was lost to make an affidavit of the sale of these goods; I did so before Sir 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person429">
                  Joseph 
                  Hankey 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person429" type="surname" value="Hankey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person429" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the porter's name, or waterman's, that carried them?</p>
               <p>Littlepear. No, I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person430">
                  John 
                  Warthin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person430" type="surname" value="Warthin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person430" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman; I carry goods on board ships for merchants; I carried goods on Mr. Wilson's account on board the Elizabeth and Martha about eight or nine months ago, I think there were four bales at one time and three boxes at another, they were all marked J. S. I think the numbers run from one to seven; one of my people carried them on board; I saw them go off in the boat. Mr. Moravia came a little time after the vessel was lost and desired to know the charges, asking me if I did not do so and so; he desired I'd make the bill in his name. He shewed me two or three affidavits from the people he bought them on, and desired I'd make an affidavit of carrying them on board, which I did before the late lord mayor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person431">
                  Benjamin 
                  Baston 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person431" type="surname" value="Baston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person431" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman; I remember shipping 33 barrels of snuff on board the Elizabeth and Martha, captain Misson, for Gibraltar and Cork, at the custom-house key. I was since requested by Moravia to make affidavit of it, which I did. My servant carried the goods on shore, and I had a receipt of Moravia.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make the affidavit?</p>
               <p>Baston. I can't justly say when it was, it was in order for him to receive the insurance money, as appeared by the affidavit. The goods were set down in Moravia's and Wilson's names. Moravia gave me three shillings, and Wilson gave me a guinea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person432">
                  George 
                  Stannerd 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person432" type="surname" value="Stannerd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person432" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There were 23 parcels of cordage of mine put on board the vessel by Manoury's order; he gave me a note to go to Wilson, who under wrote the bill; but he dying before it became due, I lost all my money. I told Manoury they were worth 70 l. as they lay, and he said he could fetch me a hundred pounds for them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Manoury?</p>
               <p>Stannerd. Only from the time the ship was upon Mr. Horne's Ways. Lundin got me acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person433">
                  John 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person433" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person433" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a merchant; I remember about November or December this ship (the Elizabeth and Martha) was put up at the Exchange as a general ship to carry general goods and passengers; I believe she had been up in October, November, and December. I sent twelve chests of tea on my own account on board this ship, to be carried to Cork, which I had bought at the East-India sale, and cost me 280 l. which money I have recovered.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person434">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person434" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman; I remember in the month of December last I took out of the Elizabeth and Martha three bales of goods; they appeared to be linen or woolen, but I could not discover which.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks on them?</p>
               <p>Wilson. There were, I remember it was about three o'clock in an afternoon; I carried them down to Radcliff-Cross to captain Misson and four other men, who received them of me.</p>
               <p>Willers Brooksby. I am a waterman; I remember in December last, about six o'clock in the evening, there were nine or ten small parcels handed out of the Elizabeth and Martha into my boat, which I carried to Tower-Wharf. Captain 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person435">
                  Misson
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person435" type="given" value="Misson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person435" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took two, and I the other, and carried them to Wilson's in Tower-street. Wilson's man came down with captain Misson, took the remainder out, and carried them up to the others.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250030"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person436">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person436" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person436" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Wilson in Dec. last, I remember 3 boxes, they were corded, being brought to his house by two watermen about the 20th of Nov. last, about 9 in the evening; they were numbered 5, 6, and 7, with J. S. Manoury and Lundin came along with them</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them opened?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember their being taken from thence?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I do. About a week or ten days after Moravia desired me to call a coach. I went down to the Tower and called one, Moravia bargained with the coachman to carry them to Gerrard street. I saw Moravia have a paper in his hand with the direction, but I did not see the gentleman's name where they were to go. I helped to put them in the coach. There were 3 empty ones brought in their room the same evening that the 3 full ones came. Lundin desired me to get them, which I did, of the same size as the 2 big ones; Lundin told me he'd make me a present of half a crown (Manoury being much in liquor he agreed to it ) if I'd put in some dirt and stones. When I had filled them Lundin took one and carried it a little way, he took up some dirt to rub over them to make them as dirty as the others were. Manoury paid me the money at the alehouse for filling them.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the 3 boxes marked ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. With the same letters and figures as the others were, 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person437">
                  J.
                   S. 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person437" type="surname" value="S."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person437" type="given" value="J."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person437" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            5, 6, and 7, and tied up as the others. Then Lundin desired me to get 2 porters, but I could not, so I carried one and my fellow-servant another; Lundin and Manoury went with us, we put them into the boat, and my fellow-servant went and fetched the other, while I was sitting by the water side. The waterman asked him where he was to go with them, he ordered him to put off, but gave him no directions before he went from us. Manoury and Lundin went in a boat with him, and Manoury said he'd take care and deliver them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Manoury, Lundin, and Moravia at Wilson's ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I have at different times. I have seen Manoury, Moravia, Lundin, and Wilson at the Bell together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Carolina there?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No, I never did. I have seen him come into Wilson's shop, and make his obeisance. He was an acquaintance of Moravia's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you take notice of these boxes being filled by their order to any body?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I mentioned it to my master Wilson that evening, but he gave me no answer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person438">
                  John 
                  Sherrard 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person438" type="surname" value="Sherrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person438" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Gerard-street St. Ann's, I keep a publick office, and lend money upon goods for the loan of money. The 28th of Nov, Moravia borrowed 150 l. of me. He left with me at that time 16 watches and some hard-ware, contained in 3 boxes, No 1, 2, and 3. These I marked myself.</p>
               <p>Q What letters were there?</p>
               <p>Sherrard. The letters were scraped off. On the 5th of Dec. 51 he had 200 l. on 30 pieces of cloth, they were brought, I think, in 3 bales, but they were taken out in order for conveniency of carrying them up into my ware room. Two of the bales came first, and the other he brought either in a cart or coach himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bales marked!</p>
               <p>Sherrard. They were, but with what I cannot say. I have some pieces of the cloth here. I thought it would answer the end as well as to bring a large bundle. The bells of parcel, are shewn him.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these bills given to you when these goods were pledged?</p>
               <p>Sherrard. They were. It was from Messieurs Lane and Lewis, I never transact any thing in my office without bills of sale. He points to a gentleman and says, that is the gentleman to whom the 30 pieces of cloth did belong. He looks at the bill of parcels, under the hand Littlepear and Co. This is the bill of parcels I took of Moravia.</p>
               <p>Q. How much is it for?</p>
               <p>Sherrard. It is for 250 l. 12 s. 3 d.</p>
               <p>Q. to Littlepear. Do you know any thing of this affair ?</p>
               <p>Littlepear. Moravia told me and Mr. Whitehead that he had pawned the goods to Mr. Sherrard, and if we would advance him a sum of money, he'd give us an order to receive them upon paying the money that was advanced upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he tell you this?</p>
               <p>Littlepear. This he told me since he has been in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Whitehead. You have heard what Mr. Littlepear has now said, did he make the same proposal to you?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. He said he had 150 l. upon the goods, and if we would advance the money we might have them again.</p>
               <p>Q. from Moravia. Did I not say Mr. Wilson received the money from me after I had pawned the goods ?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. He said something about Mr. Wilson accusing him of something, but I don't know what.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. It was in Newgate after Moravia had demanded the insurance money as his own goods from the under writer.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250031"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person439">
                  Thomas 
                  Greenwood 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person439" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person439" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Bell in Tower street, Manoury, Lundin, and Misson were at my house daily, Moravia was very seldom there. He is shewn the paper, the charter party.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whose writing this is, and the subscribing witness to it?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. I do, it is my writing as a witness to it; I saw it executed. He is shewn a parchment, and says it was signed by him up stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person440">
                  William 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person440" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person440" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the East India house, I remember one time I discounted a note for Lundin of 50 l. drawn by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person441">
                  John 
                  Misson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person441" type="surname" value="Misson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person441" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             upon 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person442">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person442" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person442" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , dated the 20th of Aug. 51. payable, to the best of my knowledge, to 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person443">
                  James 
                  Lundin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person443" type="surname" value="Lundin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person443" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; here is Lundin's receipt, he produces one. This note was paid me by Wilson in Tower street afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person444">
                  John 
                  Nicholson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person444" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person444" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I discounted a note for Lundin for 50 l. He brought it me about 4 or 5 days after the date of it; it was drawn upon Wilson in favour of Lundin for 50 l. for val. received ; this was never paid. I paid another drawn by Misson in favour of Lundin upon Wilson for 50 l. Wilson paid that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person445">
                  Samuel 
                  Hucks 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person445" type="surname" value="Hucks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person445" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I discounted a note for Lundin for 55 l. [He produced it, dated Oct. 30, 51. drawn by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person446">
                  John 
                  Misson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person446" type="surname" value="Misson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person446" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             upon 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person447">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person447" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person447" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , payable to Lundin] that I discounted but never had my money, nor never shall.</p>
               <p>Peter la Force. I am clerk to messieurs Gadin and Gyon, they are policy brokers (he holds two papers in his hands) These are two orders I apprehend left by Manoury. Carolina came Nov. 25. and left an order for 400 l. for insurance on goods. He said it was to be made in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person448">
                  Solomon 
                  Carolina 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person448" type="surname" value="Carolina"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person448" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the Elizabeth and Martha, and that he would pay for the policies, The police was made out and executed Dec. 25. (he is shewn a police made out by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person449">
                  Samuel 
                  Touchet 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person449" type="surname" value="Touchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person449" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .)</p>
               <p>Q. Whose writing is this?</p>
               <p>La Force. The body of the police is my own writing. It was to be left at Mr. Wilson's, there the premium was paid, it is for 150 l. upon a ship called the Elizabeth and Martha sloop of London to Gibraltar, and has the liberty to touch at Cork. (The first account is of London, the others are at and of London, with liberty to touch at Cork.) He looks at another.</p>
               <p>La Force. This is subscribed by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person450">
                  John 
                  Spicker 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person450" type="surname" value="Spicker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person450" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             100 l. dated Nov. 26. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person451">
                  Henry 
                  Muleman 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person451" type="surname" value="Muleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person451" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Co. 100 l. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person452">
                  Charles 
                  Pool 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person452" type="surname" value="Pool"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person452" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             100 l. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person453">
                  Peter 
                  Simon 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person453" type="surname" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person453" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             100 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Eastland. He is shewn a police.</p>
               <p>Eastland. It is subscribed by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person454">
                  John 
                  Rook 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person454" type="surname" value="Rook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person454" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person455">
                  Rob 
                  March 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person455" type="surname" value="March"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person455" type="given" value="Rob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for 100 l. each, upon the ship Elizabeth and Martha upon goods and merchandise.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person456">
                  Richard 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person456" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person456" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an insurance broker. He is shewn a police.</p>
               <p>Morris. This is subscribed by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person457">
                  John 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person457" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person457" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , John Brown, 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person458">
                  Richard 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person458" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person458" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Samuel Toucket, in 100 l. each, and 2 more a 100 l. a piece, 600 l. in all upon goods.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person459">
                  Stephen 
                  Gyon 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person459" type="surname" value="Gyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person459" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep an insurance office and am a Police broker (he produces a police.) This was brought by Carolina. We commonly go to Change about 12 o'clock. When I returned I saw an order for 400 l. for Solomon Carolina, I asked who this Carolina was, said my clerk he is recommended by Manoury, he desired it might be done upon the Eliz and Martha, and the police may be sent to Mr. Wilson's, a grocer in Tower street; accordingly it was executed, and I believe it was paid there the 29th of Nov. After the loss Mr. Moravia came into my compting house and demanded satisfaction for a loss. I said he was mistaken, for I never would have transacted any business for him. Yes Sir, said he, you have done business for me, and introduced the police signed Carolina. I asked him why he sent Carolina, &amp;c. he said he did it in order to cover some debts he owned, and added he was an honest man; finding he was at the bottom of this transaction, gave me some suspicion. Then I asked him where the bills of lading and invoyces were, and bills of parcels, of whom bought and affidavits to them. He procured every thing, and said it was very fair that gentlemen should see before they paid their money. We put it off from time to time till we had a general meeting at Lloyd's Coffee house. He brought vouchers and papers, in order to clear his loss, pretending, that these goods had been all lost, and affidavits that they were all sunk with the ship, one from the captain that there was nothing taken out of her. I put the initial letters of my name to all the bills of parcels he produced. After a time we got intelligence of these goods being pawned as has been mentioned here.</p>

               <p>Q. to Littlepear. Look at this bill of parcels, do you know it ?</p>
               <p>Littlepear. This is the bill of parcels that I delivered to Mr. Moravia, when I sold the goods. It was the same bill which was lodged with the goods when pawned, and had the initial letters on it of Mr. Gyon, marked by him, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>(There were evidences in court which were called to prove the box of stockings, and sawdust which was stopped at the custom-house, was claimed there by Carolina, as his own property. But Carolina admitted it to be truth so they were not called.) There was an affidavit of Carolina's, that he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250032"></xptr> made in order to be laid before the gentlemen of the Insurance-Office, to this purport.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person460">
                  Moses 
                  Moravia 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person460" type="surname" value="Moravia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person460" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bought of Solomon Carolina four barrels of snuff, and a receipt for 123 l.</p>
               <p>At another time, seven barrels, and a receipt for 268 l. 1 s. Sworn the 28th of May at Guildhall before alderman Asgill; and a receipt at the same time for 150 l. of rhubarb; in linen and woollen cloth 50 l. and 68 l. in cash 1 s.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lundin. Whose hand-writing is this? (putting a paper in his hand) the name 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person461">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person461" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person461" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Lundin. This is 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person462">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person462" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person462" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote the body of it?</p>
               <p>Lundin. Manoury did.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport:</p>
               <p>Feb. 4, 1752.</p>
               <p>I do hereby acknowledge to be fully satisfied for four lots amounting to 205 l. drawn by 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person463">
                  John 
                  Misson 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person463" type="surname" value="Misson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person463" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to the order of 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person464">
                  James 
                  Lundin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person464" type="surname" value="Lundin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person464" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on me Samuel Wilson, which notes I promise to deliver up to him upon demand, and likewise all tradesmen's bills from me to the Elizabeth and Martha; and do hereby promise to indemnify the said 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person465">
                  James 
                  Lundin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person465" type="surname" value="Lundin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person465" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for all draughts, excepting the policy for 80 l. in case it should not be recovered of the insurers.</p>
               <p>Moravia's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never paid a halfpenny in my life to the man. I know nothing about a conspiracy. I owe several hundred pounds to Wilson. I was forced to do as he commanded me. He ordered the goods to be brought on shore, and lent me notes to buy these goods on them.</p>
               <p>For Moravia.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person466">
                  Abraham 
                  Carcennea 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person466" type="surname" value="Carcennea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person466" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I delivered 22 barrels of snuff at the custom-house to be sent on board the Elizabeth and Martha, which belonged to 
               <persName id="t17520625-51-person467">
                  Moses 
                  Moravia 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person467" type="surname" value="Moravia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person467" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about nine months ago. When I delivered them I took two samples out of every one of the barrels, separately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person468">
                  Thomas 
                  Coppinger 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person468" type="surname" value="Coppinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person468" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw some snuff in Mr. Wilson's warehouse, but cannot say it went on board. They were left by Moravia's order. I don't know whether they were to go by the Elizabeth and Martha or not.</p>
               <p>[he knew any thing of the in Wilson's ware-house that were filed with brickbees, he said he remembered them, and that the snuff and they were not carried away together].</p>
               <p>Manoury's Defence.</p>
               <p>I acted as broker for Wilson. If there was any conspiracy I had no hand in it; if it was anywhere, it was with Lundin, Misson, and Moravia. I had no power over the ship or the master. I found they were robbing the cargoe, so I came away from them, fearing my life. I had no hand in it, nor any profit in any shape. [He produced a receipt that Wilson gave him for three boxes, and the name on the back of it]</p>
               <p>For Manoury.</p>
               <p>Manoury. I desire Mr. Godin may be examined to my character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person469">
                  Peter 
                  Godin 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person469" type="surname" value="Godin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person469" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Manoury, I believe, above 30 years ago, he had then a good character; I know little of his character now; I have seen him, but have known but little of him of late, nor do I desire to know him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person470">
                  Thomas 
                  Munit 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person470" type="surname" value="Munit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person470" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Manoury about 30 years. About that time, or 25 years ago, I was concerned with him in shipping; his character then was good, but I can't say much of it since.</p>
               <p>Q. from Manoury to Brooksby. Give an account to the court what you know about my going down with this vessel.</p>
               <p>Brooksby. I saw Mr. Newman at the ship at the Hermitage; he said he was to attend a trial, so could not go to pilot the vessel down; but Manoury went in his stead.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person471">
                  Samuel 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person471" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person471" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was spoke to, to go pilot of the vessel the Elizabeth and Martha into the Downs; but I having a ship to go into Dunkirk was forced to relinquish it; I don't know who went in my room.</p>
               <p>For Carolina.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person472">
                  Moses 
                  Argons 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person472" type="surname" value="Argons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person472" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Carolina about 20 years; I am a Jew, so is he; I always thought he had a very good character; I don't think he is very rich.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person473">
                  Isaac 
                  Argons 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person473" type="surname" value="Argons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person473" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about ten or twelve years; he used to have goods of me to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250033"></xptr> the value of 20 or 25 l. to carry out ; he has paid me honestly, or returned my goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he deal very largely?</p>
               <p>Argons. I don't know that he does.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-51-person474">
                  Daniel 
                  Peires 
               <interp inst="t17520625-51-person474" type="surname" value="Peires"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person474" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I gave Carolina notice there was a warrant against him on the 5th of August, and that Moravia was taken up that day; I told him to keep out of the way, searing (he being Mr. Moravia's broker) there should be any thing against him; he said he had done nothing that he was afraid of; he has not kept out of the way.</p>
               <p>Zac. Levi. I have known Carolina a great many years; he has worked for me at my house, and I have given him work home with him; he has always been honest to me, and never heard but that he is honest.</p>
               <p>Carolina, <rs id="t17520625-51-verdict221" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-verdict221" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Moravia,</p>
               <p>Manoury,</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-51-verdict222" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-verdict222" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-51-punish223" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish223" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish223" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend388 t17520625-51-punish223"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend390 t17520625-51-punish223"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-51-punish224" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish224" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish224" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend388 t17520625-51-punish224"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend390 t17520625-51-punish224"></join>
               
                     <note>[Pillory. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-51-punish225" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish225" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish225" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend388 t17520625-51-punish225"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend390 t17520625-51-punish225"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-51-punish226" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish226" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-51-punish226" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend388 t17520625-51-punish226"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-51-defend390 t17520625-51-punish226"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
