<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561020-34">
               <interp inst="t17561020-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-34" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561020"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-34" type="date" value="17561020"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561020-34-off159-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-34-defend247 t17561020-34-off159 t17561020-34-verdict162"></join>
         
               <p>433. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17561020-34-defend247" type="defendantName">
                  
                     James 
                     Polk 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17561020-34-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-34-defend247 t17561020-34-alias-4"></join>Pollock</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-defend247" type="surname" value="Polk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-defend247" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17561020-34-off159" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-off159" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-off159" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two locks, value 8 s. three iron keys, value 3 s. five pair of steel snuffers, value 5 s. two brass cocks, value 2 s. one iron padlock, one frame saw, four pair of tongs, four iron fire-shovels, four iron pokers, eighteen iron screws, one pair of pincers, and one hand-vice
            </rs>, the goods of of 
               
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-victim250" type="victimName">
                     Francis 
                     Barrow 
                  <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim250" type="surname" value="Barrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim250" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-victim252" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Hawkes 
                  <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim252" type="surname" value="Hawkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim252" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-victim252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17561020-34-cd160" type="crimeDate">September 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-34-off159 t17561020-34-cd160"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200018"></xptr>James Hawkes. I live at the corner of Surry-Street, and am an <rs id="t17561020-34-viclabel161" type="occupation">ironmonger and brasier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-34-victim252 t17561020-34-viclabel161"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any partner?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. I have, his name is 
               <persName id="t17561020-34-person253">
                  Francis 
                  Barrow 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person253" type="surname" value="Barrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person253" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my father-in-law.</p>
               <p>Q. What things did you lose?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. I lost two locks and three keys (there were two keys to one of them ) and five pair of steel snuffers. We found but four pair at the prisoner's house. I can't be certain, with regard to losing brass cocks out of such a shop as our's is; but they are what the prisoner confessed he took out of our shop, and likewise the frame saw.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they mark'd?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. No, they were not; I lost an iron padlock. As to the fire-shovels, tongs and pokers, and iron screws, they were found upon the prisoner; but I can't say they were mine, only the prisoner own'd they were mine, and beg'd for mercy. We search'd his house and cellar where he work'd, and found the other things. We took him before justice Welch, and there again he confessed the taking all the things.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. He had been one of our out door workmen for several years.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he work'd for you?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. I believe he has for seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved during that time ?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. As an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he industrious ?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. As to that I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be taken up?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. I missed things, and had intelligence of his being lurking about the shop in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make these sort of goods for you?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time of his confession what was said to him?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. Nothing at all. He confessed taking the things found upon him, and beg'd for mercy.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said about mercy?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. He desired we would pardon him. I can't say he used the word mercy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he then tell you he had got the other things ?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any promise made him of mercy ?</p>
               <p>Hawkes. No, none at all; since that I have been with him in prison, and desired him to be frank and free, telling him he should be the better for it; but I made him no such promise before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person254">
                  William 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person254" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person254" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a brush-maker, and live in the Strand. We used to see the prisoner about the prosecutor's door, on mornings, at five o'clock, or thereabouts. We thought he had no good design. Sometimes he'd be going in, and start back again. On the 27th of September I saw him do so, when Mr. Barrow came to the door, and call'd to him, and he went away. We had sent Mr. Barrow a letter, that there was a man used to come to his door with a bag, on mornings, and we suspected him to be a bad man. The time of this robbery, being the 27th, we workmen were all watching him, some out at a window above, and some below. One of our men push'd out, and took the prisoner. We carried him to a publick house, and sent for Mr. Hawkes. He charged the prisoner with stealing the tongs and things he had upon him, and the prisoner owned he did. I also heard him own it before the justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person255">
                  William 
                  Gee 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person255" type="surname" value="Gee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person255" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable ( producing the goods mentioned in the indictment.) These were produced before justice Welch, and the prisoner said they were the property of Mr. Hawkes and his partner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he took them out of their shop?</p>
               <p>Gee. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the confession taken in writing?</p>
               <p>Gee. There was a confession taken and read to him; he was ask'd whether he would sign it, and said no.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it was not true?</p>
               <p>Gee. No, I did not hear him say that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person256">
                  George 
                  Bason 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person256" type="surname" value="Bason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person256" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before the justice, and heard the prisoner own the goods there produced to be the property of Mess. Hawkes and Barrow.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>These were things that I had made for them, they plunder'd my shop, and took them away.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person257">
                  John 
                  Dailey 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person257" type="surname" value="Dailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the ship in Broad St. Giles's, and have lent the prisoner hundreds of pounds out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200019"></xptr>Dailey. I believe about five years, and he is to my thinking as honest a man as any in St. Giles's parish. I am a very early man, and sell purl in a morning, but could never rise early enough for him. He has a wife and family, and if he came to me to borrow 20 l. at any time, there it was for him. Upon my credit I would lend him 50 l. to-morrow morning, was he out of his trouble, tho' I were obliged to pawn my buckles out of my shoes to make up the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person258">
                  Benjamin 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person258" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person258" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a smith, and live in the Bowl yard. I work'd journeywork with the prisoner, and have known him, I believe, seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Brown. That he was always honest and just, I look upon him to be such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hope 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person259" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bridges Street, Covent-Garden, and have known the prisoner betwixt six and seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Hope. That of a very honest man, and one that strove hard for bread for his family; he has a wife and three children.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-34-person260">
                  Charles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17561020-34-person260" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person260" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Bowl-yard, St. Giles's, the prisoner was a lodger of mine. I have known him about eight years, he is a hard-working pains-taking man: I have known him up at work at four o'clock in the morning, and I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mr. Gee knows me, if he'll please to speak to my character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gee. I never knew any thing contrary to that of a good one before this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561020-34-verdict162" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-verdict162" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-verdict162" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty, 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561020-34-punish163" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-punish163" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-34-punish163" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-34-defend247 t17561020-34-punish163"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
