<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560714-30">
               <interp inst="t17560714-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-30" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-30" type="date" value="17560714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-30-off161-c262" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-30-defend312 t17560714-30-off161 t17560714-30-verdict164"></join>
         
               <p>314. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-defend312" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Robertson 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-30-defend312" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-defend312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-defend312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17560714-30-off161" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-off161" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-off161" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560714-30-victim314" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Goodlifft 
                        <interp inst="t17560714-30-victim314" type="surname" value="Goodlifft"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-30-victim314" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-30-victim314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-30-off161 t17560714-30-victim314"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17560714-30-cd162" type="crimeDate">July 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-30-off161 t17560714-30-cd162"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person315">
                  Innis 
                  Dowers 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person315" type="surname" value="Dowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person315" type="given" value="Innis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday last I was at the <placeName id="t17560714-30-crimeloc163">Jacob's Well in Barbican</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-30-crimeloc163" type="placeName" value="Jacob's Well in Barbican"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-30-crimeloc163" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-30-off161 t17560714-30-crimeloc163"></join>, the house of Mr. Westwood. 
               <persName id="t17560714-30-person316">
                  Richard 
                  Ingram 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person316" type="surname" value="Ingram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person316" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560714-30-person317">
                  James 
                  Whiticker 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person317" type="surname" value="Whiticker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person317" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were laying a bet about bowling, they quarrel'd, and went to fighting about it. The prisoner was Ingram's second, and that Goodlifft was Whiticker's. Whilst they were fighting the two seconds quarrel'd. The<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140036"></xptr> prisoner challenged the other with foul play, and they went to fighting. They fought about twenty minutes I believe. They had a great many falls, but at last the prisoner gave the deceased a blow under the left ear, on which he sat down, and never spoke any more. There was a surgeon sent for, but he was dead; he prick'd him, but he bled but little.</p>
               <p>Q. Who struck first?</p>
               <p>Dowers. The first blow I saw given was by the prisoner, but I did not take particular notice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person318">
                  George 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person318" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person318" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Ingram and Whiticker quarrelling about a wager. The deceased was second to Whiticker, and the prisoner to Ingram. In the battle I perceived the prisoner to strike the deceased, on which the deceased went and strip'd, but I was looking at the other two, and did not see the prisoner and deceased begin. I saw the deceased after he was down, and I believe I had seen them fight ten minutes. A surgeon was fetch'd, and he prick'd the deceased, but he bled but little, and never spoke more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>

               <p>I went in to see for my mate. I am a sawyer. I saw Ingram and Whiticker strike one another with their cloaths on, and then they both strip'd. I went and laid hold of Ingram, and insisted they should not fight; we work together. Then the deceased came and called me many bitter names, and said there was no reason for my preventing them if they had a mind to fight, and pull'd my arm away. They went to fighting. They had not been fighting two minutes before the deceased came and struck me, and said I used foul play. He went and strip'd, and came to me again; I was not for fighting at first, but then I pull'd off my shirt. He knock'd me down several times, and we fought many minutes before this thing happened; how I gave it him, whether by a blow or a fall, I can't say. I did not endeavour to injure him any more than a person does in common fighting. When I found he was dead, I went and a quainted my officer with it, as I am a soldier, and afterwards came and surrendered to take my trial.</p>

               <p>Q. to Dowers. Was the prisoner desirous to prevent Whiticker and Ingram from fighting ?</p>
               <p>Dowers. I did not see him forward for their fighting.</p>
               <p>Q. to Turner. You hear what the prisoner says, did you observe any unwillingness in the prisoner to fight ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I did not see that he was willing to fight.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person319">
                  Edward 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person319" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person319" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there near the beginning; it was concerning a trifling bet at nine pins, whether a person bowl'd even or odd, betwixt Ingram and Whiticker. I saw them scuffling on the ground for the money; they push'd one another, and agreed to go to fighting. The prisoner went up to Ingram, and desired him not to fight. The deceased insisted upon it that they should fight, and said to the prisoner, you are a cowardly fellow; if you will not fight, you ought to let them that will. Then the prisoner said to Ingram, Dick, if you have a mind to fight him you shall, and if you have a mind not, you shall not; notwithstanding that, to fighting they went. After a little time a dispute arose between the deceased and the prisoner concerning foul play. In the interim Whiticker was beat by Ingram. Then the deceased said to Whiticker, if you'll but fight and beat him. I will lick the soldier, (meaning the prisoner.) After that they went to fighting again, and in a few minutes Ingram gave out. A little after that I turned about, and saw the prisoner and the deceased in a sort of a scuffle, I believe there were two or three blows struck; which struck first I don't know. They parted immediately, and the deceased went down to the end of the yard to a water-tub, wash'd his face, and drank some of the water. He then pull'd off his shirt, delivered it to a woman, and went up to the ground, saying these words, if you are a man turn out and fight me, it you don't I'll lick you. The prisoner was seemingly unwilling to fight. At last he pull'd off his cloaths, upon the other's urging him. When they had been fighting five or six minutes the man that was to have been the prisoner's second was pull'd away by the populace; after that he was seconded by two or three, whoever could lay on him when he was down first. At the end of I believe eighteen or twenty minutes of very severe fighting the deceased was very weak, and the prisoner struck him a blow with his right hand on the left side his head (I can't say whether it was above or below his ear) when he made a kind of a small stagger about six foot in length, clap'd his hand to a small tree and eased himself to the ground. The prisoner walked then to the bottom of the yard to the water tub, and wash'd himself. A surgeon was sent for to bleed the deceased. He was prick'd, and bled but little. I believe at that time he was very near dead,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140037"></xptr> he never spoke afterwards. The landlord was very desirous to have them parted when they were fighting, but the friends of each were for their having it out. I have known the prisoner between four and five years, he is a very good natur'd honest man; I never heard a miss word from him, nor saw him apt to quarrel, nor heard of his fighting before this.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person320">
                  George 
                  Gaystock 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person320" type="surname" value="Gaystock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person320" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to speak to a gentleman in the neighbourhood, who not being at home I went into that ground to wait. Hearing a noise, I went towards them, and saw one man strip'd and the other pulling his shirt off. While they were fighting, I saw the deceased strike the prisoner, and call'd him blackguard or scoundrel. and said he did not shew fair play. After that they parted, the deceased went about twenty yards from the prisoner, came up to him again, and they had a fair let to as they call it. After some time the deceased received a violent blow. I was obliged to keep at a distance, having received a hurt on my foot by a piece of timber. The landlord did all in his power to prevent their fighting, but there were ill natur'd people enough to set them on. I saw the deceased fall, and thought he was beat; it was an indifferent thing to me which was beat, being strangers to me, so were the whole company. In a little time after I heard the man was dying; then a surgeon was sent for, who prick'd him, and there came about half a teaspoon full of blood out; he never spake after.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person321">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person321" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person321" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner belongs to the company where I am sergeant; he has been in it six years, and I never saw him quarrelsome, or ever heard any challenge him with being such a man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-30-person322">
                  James 
                  Tong 
               <interp inst="t17560714-30-person322" type="surname" value="Tong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person322" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between 5 and 6 years, and have been upon duty with him many times. I never knew him quarrelsome since he has been in the regiment.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560714-30-verdict164" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-verdict164" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-verdict164" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560714-30-punish165" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-punish165" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-30-punish165" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-30-defend312 t17560714-30-punish165"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
