<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-20">
               <interp inst="t17540530-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-20" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-20" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-20-off92-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-defend196 t17540530-20-off92 t17540530-20-verdict97"></join>
         
               <p>324. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-defend196" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Black 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-20-defend196" type="surname" value="Black"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-defend196" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-defend196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540530-20-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 7 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540530-20-victim198" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Darby 
                        <interp inst="t17540530-20-victim198" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-20-victim198" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-20-victim198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-off92 t17540530-20-victim198"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said Thomas, <rs id="t17540530-20-cd93" type="crimeDate">May 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-off92 t17540530-20-cd93"></join>.*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person199">
                  Thomas 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person199" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person199" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17540530-20-viclabel94" type="occupation">I keep the Crown Alehouse</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-victim198 t17540530-20-viclabel94"></join> in <placeName id="t17540530-20-crimeloc95">Cock-Alley, near Ludgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-20-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="Cock-Alley, near Ludgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-20-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-off92 t17540530-20-crimeloc95"></join>. On the 7th of this month, about a quarter before eleven o'clock, it was in a little box near the window, next the street; the prisoner was there at that timebut I did not see him take it away. I have another witness to prove that I have known the prisoner some time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person200">
                  Eleanor 
                  Clapton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person200" type="surname" value="Clapton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person200" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar was at Mr. Darby's house May the 7th; he gave me a shilling to change to fetch a pennyworth of cheese : I left the tankard before him, and when I returned he and the tankard were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen the tankard since?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person201">
                  E 
                  Clapton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person201" type="surname" value="Clapton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person201" type="given" value="E"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person201" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him confess the taking of it?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person202">
                  E 
                  Clapton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person202" type="surname" value="Clapton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person202" type="given" value="E"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person202" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person203">
                  Matthew 
                  Nelson 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person203" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person203" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the prosecutor's house; Black and another man came into our house, the other man said he would have no drams; they called for a tankard of beer, I went and fetched it, and put it on the table, and went awaythen the other man went out, and Black had got a shilling in his hand: Eleanor asked him if he wanted change; he said no, Nell, go and get a pennyworth of cheese, and when she was gone he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the tankard in his custody?</p>
               <p>NelsonNo, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him confess taking it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300011"></xptr>Nelson. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person204">
                  William 
                  Robson 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person204" type="surname" value="Robson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person204" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday the 8th of this instantabout seven in the morning, I was standing at my door, and saw the prisoner at the bar coming at a little distance on the opposite side the street with something in his hand; when he came up to my door, he said to me he wanted some money, and laid this tankard down on the counter; I having known the prisoner some time before, I asked him who that tankard belonged to; he said it was sent by a creditable person that did not care to come with it himself. I weighed the tankard, but not very exactly : he said he wanted 6 l. upon it; I said it was lending five shillings an ounce upon it; he said that the person could not do with out 6 l. and on Saturday night I should have my money again. I lent him 6 l. upon it about seven o'clock the same evening. I received an advertisement from Goldsmith's-Halland had some reason of suspicion of this being it which was lost. I went out the next morning in quest of the prisoner: he came into my shop while I was gone; I returned, and shewed him the advertisement; he said he had it from a creditable housekeeper, and if I would go along with him, I should have my money again; but I sent for the officer, and took him up.</p>
               <p>Q. After he was taken up, did you hear him confess he stole it?</p>
               <p>Robson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person205">
                  James 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person205" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person205" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. I was sent for on the 9th of this instant to Mr. Robson's the pawnbroker; he told me he had stopped a tankard, and had the person in his house, and desired me to take charge of him and the tankard, which I did. ( He produced a tankard.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Robson. Is this the tankard you gave into the care of the constable?</p>
               <p>Robson. It appears to me to be the same tankard which I received at first: when I stopped it there was the remains of the letter T on the handle, which I cannot perceive now, but by the maker's name and the rim I believe it to be the same.</p>
               <p>Q. to Darby. Look at this tankard, Is this what you lost?</p>
               <p>Darby. Yes.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you had known the prisoner at the bar some time before, What was his character?</p>
               <p>Robson. I believed him to be a very honest manor I would not have taken the tankard of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not bring it to you publickly, as though he came honestly by it?</p>
               <p>Robson. He brought it in his hand in the publick street; I saw him 40 or 50 yards distance from me with it.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the remains of the letter was on when you took it in?</p>
               <p>Robson. When I came to read the advertisementI made use of my spectacles, and thought I saw something of the remains of it, but I cannot particularly say.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the weight of it?</p>
               <p>Robson. The weight was 25 ounces one penny weight, which was in the advertisement.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the tankard weigh?</p>
               <p>Robson. It weighed 24 ounces and an half, or three quarters, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he would carry you to the housekeeper that belonged to it ?</p>
               <p>Robson. Yes, he did, but I did not go with him.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person206">
                  William 
                  Crookshanks 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person206" type="surname" value="Crookshanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person206" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar has worked for me above four years; the time he has worked for me he has behaved himself like an honest man, I never found any thing amiss by him, nor suspected him of dishonesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person207">
                  Samuel 
                  Grant 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person207" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person207" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cabinet-maker and joiner; I have known the prisoner upwards of 20 years, he always had a very good character as far as I know, and I never heard any thing to the contrary, but that he was a downright honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person208">
                  James 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person208" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person208" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four years, and take him to be a very honest man as far as ever I knew; he has had money of me, and I always found him to be so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person209">
                  Jonathan 
                  Welebel 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person209" type="surname" value="Welebel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person209" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe it is seven years since I first knew him; his general character was a very good one: I should not have scrupled to have credited him with any thing. This is the first ill thing that ever I heard of him, and was surprized when I heard of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person210">
                  John 
                  Himous 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person210" type="surname" value="Himous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner rather better than five years, he has lodged in my house, he has done a great deal of business for me, and have trusted him with several sums of money; he always behaved well at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a man that can get his bread without thieving?</p>
               <p>Himous. I am a cooper; he is a <rs id="t17540530-20-deflabel96" type="occupation">carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-20-defend196 t17540530-20-deflabel96"></join>I believe we both can.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person211">
                  Alexander 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person211" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person211" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between six and seven years, and never heard any thing against him before this in my life: I always took him to be a very sober, industrious, honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-20-person212">
                  Jonathan 
                  Hoskins 
               <interp inst="t17540530-20-person212" type="surname" value="Hoskins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person212" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seven or eight years, and have employed him several times to do business in my house, and he always behaved like a sober honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540530-20-verdict97" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-20-verdict97" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
