<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-29">
               <interp inst="t17501017-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-29" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-29" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-29-off139-c206" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-29-defend261 t17501017-29-off139 t17501017-29-verdict142"></join>
         
               <p>647. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-defend261" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Doller 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-29-defend261" type="surname" value="Doller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-defend261" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-defend261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-29-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 14 l. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17501017-29-victim262" type="victimName">
                        David 
                        Green 
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-victim262" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-29-victim262" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-29-victim262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-29-off139 t17501017-29-victim262"></join>
                     </persName>
                   ; in the dwelling house of the said David
            </rs>, <rs id="t17501017-29-cd140" type="crimeDate">Sept. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-29-off139 t17501017-29-cd140"></join>.</p>
               <p>Martha Green. I am wife to David Green; the prisoner came into my house the 17th of Sept. between seven and eight at night, and call'd for a tankard of beer; I keep the <placeName id="t17501017-29-crimeloc141">King's Head and Billiard Table, near Ratcliff Cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-29-crimeloc141" type="placeName" value="King's Head and Billiard Table, near Ratcliff Cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-29-crimeloc141" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-29-off139 t17501017-29-crimeloc141"></join>; he had another man with him; he said he did not drink beer; I carried him half a quartern of rum. He call'd the other person Bourne; then he call'd for some oysters; he had a halfpenny worth of bread,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170020"></xptr> and paid for it; then he call'd for some gin to treat a lodger of our's; then he ask'd Bourne if he'd drink any more; then he said, bring a pint of beer, and half a quartern of rum, and put them into the tankard; it was a silver 3 pint tankard; he gave me a shilling, and I gave him change. I went into the bar; all the company that had been in that room, but themselves, were gone; then I saw Bourne go out with a pipe in his mouth, about half an hour after nine o'clock; after he was gone, I saw the tankard standing upon the end of the table; then I was call'd into another room to take my reckoning; I staid about five minutes; when I came out again, the prisoner and the tankard were gone; they had had three reckonings, the time they had been there; I search'd directly for the tankard, but could not find it. When the young man came that had drank a dram with him, I ask'd him if he knew the prisoner; he told me a house where he us'd to drink, at the Blue Anchor, in Goodmans-fields ; I went there the next morning, the man said he had not been there for a fortnight, but directed me to the Crown and Thistle in Ailoffe-street. I went and got a warrant, and constable; he was taken there, and brought to the Red Lyon, in Red Lyon street; there I was sent for; he was taken before Justice Rickards, but would not confess any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-person263">
                  William 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17501017-29-person263" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to his being at the taking the prisoner; and that he went to Bridewell some time after, to see a person that owed him same money ; and there said, in the bearing of the prisoner, he supposed Bourne would be hang'd. The prisoner made answer, and said, it would not be through me, for I have been loyal enough in this affair.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going that way about a month ago; a sailor met me, and ask'd me if I would go and have some drink with him ; I said yes; he carried me to this woman's house; I said, I never drank any beer in my life; I must have a quartern of rum; I had it, and paid her for it; he went away, and Mrs. Green has sworn there were no body else in the house. I left five people in the house when I went out; particularly one was a constable. The next day they came to me at the Black Lyon in Ailoffe-street ; Mr. Harding came up first, and wanted me to make it up; and said, if I would not, he'd swear against me; I knew he was no friend of mine. I saw the constable coming towards me, I had been inform'd Mr. Newman at the Anchor and Crown had a warrant against me; so upon my seeing them I ran, and Mr. Harding came, and laid hold of me.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There was no soul in the room when he went away; the rest went away about an hour and half before.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-person264">
                  Thomas 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17501017-29-person264" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person264" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner seven years and half, he has an extreme good character as ever I heard, I have often left him alone where I have had 6, 7, 800. or 1000 l. and nobody to obstruct or molest him, and he never attempted to meddle with any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-person265">
                  David 
                  Kennear 
               <interp inst="t17501017-29-person265" type="surname" value="Kennear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person265" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seven years, he lived with a cheesemonger in Thames-street, next door to me about four or five months; he always had a very good character for what I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-person266">
                  George 
                  Darvey 
               <interp inst="t17501017-29-person266" type="surname" value="Darvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person266" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have trusted the prisoner with a great deal of money, and a number of goods divers times; I always found him the most strict, honest man, in the world.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-29-person267">
                  Peter 
                  Adkins 
               <interp inst="t17501017-29-person267" type="surname" value="Adkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person267" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about two years; I never heard any thing to his misbehaviour in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-29-verdict142" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-29-verdict142" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
