<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-24">
               <interp inst="t17580913-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-24" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-24" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-24-off119-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-24-defend211 t17580913-24-off119 t17580913-24-verdict122"></join>
         
               <p>281. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-defend211" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Folliott 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-24-defend211" type="surname" value="Folliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-defend211" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-defend211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17580913-24-deflabel118" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-24-defend211 t17580913-24-deflabel118"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-24-off119" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-off119" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-off119" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 42 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580913-24-victim213" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Rivers 
                        <interp inst="t17580913-24-victim213" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-24-victim213" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-24-victim213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-24-off119 t17580913-24-victim213"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17580913-24-person214">
                        Rebecca 
                        Avis 
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person214" type="surname" value="Avis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-24-person214" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-24-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, widow, <rs id="t17580913-24-cd120" type="crimeDate">July 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-24-off119 t17580913-24-cd120"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person215">
                  Thomas 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person215" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person215" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a finisher, and work for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person216">
                  David 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person216" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person216" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17580913-24-viclabel121" type="occupation">watchmaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-24-victim213 t17580913-24-viclabel121"></join>. I sat up late on Friday night to finish a watch, his property, against Saturday; I went out on Saturday, and when I returned I found the watch was taken out of my room. The prisoner at the bar lodg'd in a room one pair of stairs above me, in the house of 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person217">
                  Rebecca 
                  Avis 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person217" type="surname" value="Avis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person217" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I cannot say of my own knowledge that she took the watch.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you suspect one Malone to have taken this watch?</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person218">
                  Thomas 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person218" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person218" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He work'd with me, and I did not know who else could come in my room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person219">
                  Margaret 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person219" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person219" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawn-broker; this watch (producing one) was brought to me to pawn, by one Randall; I suspected it to be workmens work for some master, so I stop'd it on suspicion: I asked Randall. where, or of whom she had it? she said, that 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person220">
                  Catherine 
                  Folliott 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person220" type="surname" value="Folliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person220" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave it her to pawn. I desired her to go and fetch the prisoner, she went and brought her; she owned the gave it Randall to pawn. I stop'd the watch, and advertised it the next day. Mr. Philips came and gave such proof of it, that I made no doubt of its belonging to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner say she came by it?</p>
               <p>M. Morgan. She said, she found it in a rag upon the stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person221">
                  Anne 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person221" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person221" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person221" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar brought this watch to me and said, her spouse and she had had a few words, and she desired me to pawn the watch.</p>
               <p>Q Did she tell you where to pawn it?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person222">
                  Anne 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person222" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person222" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She directed me to go to Mrs. Morgan's with it; when I came there, Mrs. Morgan said, Randall where did you get this? I said I had it of 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person223">
                  Catherine 
                  Folliott 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person223" type="surname" value="Folliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person223" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she sent me for her, and I went and brought her, and she told Mrs. Morgan, that she found it upon the stairs in a rag. (The watch produced in court, and deposed to by Philips as his master, Mr. Rivers's property.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time did you miss the watch?</p>
               <p>Philips. On the first of July, near twelve in the day.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130018"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>On that day, being Saturday, an acquaintance of mine sent for me. I went to her, and was with her from ten till three in the afternoon. The man is a weaver, and she was sick; he has an hour-glass to watch his time by, he told me it was ten o'clock when I went in. When I came home I went into the prosecutor's room, before I went up to my own; he said, Kitty I have had a lost; I said what is that, he said, my watch; but I know well who has it; there was none in the room but 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person224">
                  Jack 
                  Malone 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person224" type="surname" value="Malone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person224" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then I said to be sure he will give it you; he said whenever he found the watch, if he could get a Tyburn ticket he would, and cant him over the water. The woman is come from out of a sick bed to give evidence for me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person225">
                  Patrick 
                  Dowds 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person225" type="surname" value="Dowds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person225" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about twelve years, I am an intimate acquaintance of hers.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Dowds. I live in Spital-fields, and Brick-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. I am an Irishman; the prisoner very often paid me visits.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she of any business?</p>
               <p>Dowds. She has at the time past been a servant; but now she and her husband keep a room together.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her in June last?</p>
               <p>Dowds. I cannot tell, I took no particular account of any day; on the first of July I saw her about nine in the morning, she was with me that day from the hour of nine in the morning, till three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she employ her self that time?</p>
               <p>Dowds. In taking care of my wife, she was taken very ill of the cholick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send for her ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. No, I did not; she came in by chance.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you name any day that she came to your house in the month of June?</p>
               <p>Dowds. She might come in the month of June, but I did not take particular notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she dine with you?</p>
               <p>Dowds. Suppose I had nothing to eat myself.</p>
               <p>Q. You can tell whether she dined with you or not ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. She had nothing all day.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell any other particular day, on which she paid you a visit ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. I have no occasion to say any other day than the day you ask me. I have no more to say.</p>

               <p>Mr. Recorder. But I have something more to say to you. Name some day when she did dine with you.</p>
               <p>Dowds. She dined with me on Easter Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. What for dinner ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. She came about ten in the morning, and brought a good leg of mutton with her to make herself welcome; and staid till about ten at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect any other time?</p>
               <p>Dowds. To make the thing particular, she took a Patrick's pot with me on St. Patrick's day. I have no more to say, these two days are so remarkable, I could not forget them.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember the first of July particularly ?</p>
               <p>Dowds. I paid the king's tax that morning, and I took care to remember the day of the month on that account, I think I had a very good reason to remember it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that receipt, have you it here?</p>
               <p>Dowds. No, I have not; if I thought I should be asked about it, I would have brought it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you was not desired by any person to remember that Saturday to distinguish it from all other days?</p>
               <p>Dowds. No, I was not; no one asked me.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not the prisoner desired you to remember where you was that day?</p>
               <p>Dowds. No, she never did.</p>
               <p>[His wife having been put out of court while he was examined; was now brought in and sworn.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person226">
                  Mary 
                  Dowds 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person226" type="surname" value="Dowds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person226" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence, I have known the prisoner ever since she was a little child.</p>
               <p>Q. How long may your husband have known her?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. He could not have known her so long as I; I cannot justly tell.</p>
               <p>Q. May he have known her more than seven years?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I do not know but he may.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he known her ten years?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I do not know but he may.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he known her twenty years ?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I cannot tell; he has known her fifteen or sixteen.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130019"></xptr>Q. Which knew her first?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I was acquainted with her first.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. In Ireland.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came to England first?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. She was here a good while before I came.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she often make you visits?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. She comes now and then.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any particular day when she came to see you?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I am no scholar, to the best of my knowledge it was in June, when I was sick and she came to see me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time in June?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I can't tell the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in the beginning of June, or the latter end?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see her in July last?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. That is the month before, I believe, never saw her in the month of July.</p>
               <p>Court. July is the month after June.</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. To the best of my knowledge it was in the month of July; but I cannot account in particular for the month. She came when I was sick.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she stay?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. She came about nine in the morning and staid till towards three.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she been at your house since?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. No, that was the last time.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her since?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give her to eat when she came to see you?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I gave her such as I had.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for dinner ?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I can't account for that now.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect whether you had a dinner that day?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. We must have some sort, but I cannot justly tell what.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you treat her with something to drink?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. The time she was with us we had some drink and victuals both; but to tell punctually I cannot. I know we had both.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which month it was, June or July?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. To the best of my knowledge it was July.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of July, the middle, the latter end, or when?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. I can't tell which it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever desired to recollect yourself what day it was that she staid from nine till three?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so particular to the hours?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. We are obliged to observe the hour by reason of the work folks, that work for us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make observations of the time she staid at any other time that she came?</p>
               <p>M. Dowds. No, none but this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person227">
                  John 
                  Adersey 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person227" type="surname" value="Adersey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mr. Philips's room door was left open that day the watch was lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person228">
                  William 
                  Speed 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person228" type="surname" value="Speed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person228" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My master ordered me to fetch a pot of beer, and in the mean time the watch was missing; it was judged that 
               <persName id="t17580913-24-person229">
                  John 
                  Malone 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person229" type="surname" value="Malone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the person that took it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person230">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bready 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person230" type="surname" value="Bready"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person230" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner nine or ten years ago; she was a woman that made a very great appearance.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her of late?</p>
               <p>Bready. I have very much.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her livelihood?</p>
               <p>Bready. She told me that since the death of her husband, she went to service.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who she lived with in service?</p>
               <p>Bready. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Bready. I keep a publick-house in Sherborn-lane in the city.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person231">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person231" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person231" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner fourteen years, she has lived very sober and very honest in her husband's time; he was an attorney, and lived in the Temple, near Fetter-lane; since he has been dead she has gone to service.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her lately?</p>
               <p>Smith. I cannot say I have seen her within this three months past.</p>
               <p>Smith. Can you tell how she has got her livelihood this twelve months last past ?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Mr. Plunket. I have known her five years; I knew her parents, they lived in Dublin, I know nothing of her, only that her relations are very honest people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-24-person232">
                  Daniel 
                  Dukes 
               <interp inst="t17580913-24-person232" type="surname" value="Dukes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person232" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years, I never heard to the contrary but that her character was extraordinary, I have supported her whenever she was out of place.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130020"></xptr>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I am a shoemaker, if she was under any distress to pawn her cloaths, I have redeemed them; her prosecutor is sensible I maintained her, when she was out of place.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Dowds and his wife?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I have known them about two years, he is a journeyman weaver, and keeps looms for men to work in, at so much per week, he has lived four years in credit.</p>
               <p>Court. He says he goes without a dinner sometimes.</p>
               <p>Dukes. Many weavers do.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman are you?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I was born in Dublin.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in England?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I have been here in London twenty years; I have worked for Mr. Welch, at the ship in Cornhill, eight years.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, I am not.</p>
               <p>Philips. This man went for the prisoner's husband, and she lives with him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-24-verdict122" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-24-verdict122" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
